import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as y,M as b,U as w,F as c,p,e as j,f,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},S={class:"review-title"},x={class:"review-content"};function N(e,a,s,m,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",S,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",x,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const T=g(q,[["render",N],["__scopeId","data-v-8ff88d12"]]),M=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"waxaad  Sheegtaa kumuu ahaa Nebigii ugu danbeeyey ee reer Banii Israa’iil?","answer":" Nebigii ugu danbeeyey ee reer Banii Israa’iil wuxu ahaa Nebi Ciise (CS)."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Toto Cutugno, född 7 juli 1943, är en italiensk artist, mest känd för omvärlden efter sin seger i","answer":"Eurovision Song Contest 1990 med låten. Han var jämte Gigliola Cinquetti programledare för Eurovision Song Contest 1991 som sändes från Rom."},{"question":"கேள்வி:கடித இலக்கியமும் நாட்குறிப்பும் தொகுத்துரைக்க? ","answer":"பதில்:                                                   1.மு.வரதராசனாரின் கடிதம்அன்னைக்கு தம்பிக்கு தங்கைக்கு நண்பர்க்கு என நான்கு கடித இலக்கிய நூல்களை எழுதியுள்ளார்.மு.வ.வின் பிறநூல்களுக்கான திறவுகோல் அவர்தம் கடித இலக்கிய நூல்களே என்பர்.நல்ல தமிழ்ப் பெயர்களைத் தன்னுடைய கடிதங்களில் அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.தம்பிக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில் அன்புள்ள அண்ணன் வளவன் தம்பி எழில் என்று தொடங்கி எழுதியுள்ளார்.“தமிழ் ஒன்றே தமிழரைப் பிணைத்து ஒற்றுமைப் படுத்த வல்லது. தமிழ் ஆட்சிமொழியாகவும் கல்வி மொழியாகவும் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும். ஆட்சி மொழி என்றால் சட்டசபை முதல் நீதிமன்றம் வரை தமிழ் வழங்க வேண்டும். கல்விமொழி என்றால் எவ்வகைக் கல்லூரிகளிலும் எல்லா பாடங்களையும் தமிழிலேயே கற்பிக்க வேண்டும்.”“திருமணம் வழிபாடுகளைத் தமிழில் நடத்த வேண்டும். ஒன்றே குலம் ஒருவனே தேவன் என்ற செம்மொழியைப் போற்று. சாதி சமய வேறுபாடுகளை மறக்கக் கற்றுக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். அல்லது புறக்கணிக்கக் கற்றுக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்.”தொண்டுக்கு முந்து தலைமைக்கு பிந்து என்பது உன் நெறியாக இருக்கட்டும்.தமிழகத்தில் தனி மரங்களாகத் தமிழர் உயர்வதையே காண்கிறோம். தேர்ப்பாகக் கூடி உயர்வதைக் காணமுடியாதது பெருங்குறை. தமிழர்கள் நான்கு பேர் சேர்ந்து ஒரு மரமாய் ஒன்றை நடத்த முடியாது. நடத்தினாலும் அது நெடுங்காலம் நீடிக்காது. நம்மிடையே பிரிக்கும் ஆற்றல் உண்டு; பிணைக்கும் ஆற்றல் இல்லை.“இந்த நாட்டில் சொன்ன படி செய்ய ஆளில்லை; ஆனால் கண்டபடி சொல்ல ஆள் ஏராளம் ஒவ்வொருவரும் ஆணையிடுவதற்கு விரும்புகிறார். தன்னை அடக்கி ஒழுகுவதற்கு யாரும் இல்லை. அதனால் தான் வீழுச்சி நேர்ந்தது என்று விவேகானந்தர் கூறுகிறார்.தமிழர்கள் கூடிக்கூடி செயல் செய்து உயரும் வல்லமை உண்டு என்பதை நாம் உலகிற்கு உணர்த்தும் நாள் வர வேண்டும். அன்று தான் தமிழ் சமுதாயம் உயர வழி பிறக்கும்.                                                                                                                                                          2.அண்ணாவின் கடிதம்“திராவிட நாடு” என்ற இதழில் கடிதங்களை எழுதினார். ‘தம்பிக்கு’ என்று விரித்து எழுதியுள்ளார்.கடித இலக்கியத்தை வளர்த்தவர்களில் பேரறிஞர் அண்ணாவிற்கு பெரும் பங்கு உண்டுஇவருடைய கடிதத்தில் தமிழ் தமிழர் தமிழ்ப்பண்பாடு தமிழர் தாழ்வும் உயர்வும் தமிழர் செய்ய வேண்டியது. பகுத்தறிவு ஆரிய எதிர்ப்பும் போன்ற கருத்துகள் பிளிர்கின்றன.தாயும் சேயும் கொஞ்சி மகிழ்வது போல நிலமடந்தையும் தன் மக்களுக்கு வளம் அளிக்கும் முன்பு விளையாட்டு காட்டுவாள். “உழைத்துப்பெறு! உரிய நேரத்ல் பெறு! முயற்சி செய்து பெறு! என்று அன்புடன் ஆணையிடுகிறாள்.தன் கடிதத்தில் கவிஞர் முடியரசன் தமிழர் திருநாளான தை முதல் நாளை “உழைப்பினை உணர்த்தும் பெருநாள்” என்றும் “புதுமை இன்பம் பூணும் நன்நாள்” என்றும் பாடியிருப்பதை எடுத்துக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.“பொங்குக இன்பம்! பொங்குக புதுமை! பொங்குக பொலிவு! வளம் பெருகிடுக! வாழ்வு சிறந்திடுக! வாழ்வு சிறந்திடு! வாழ்க தமிழ்! வாழ்க தமிழகம்!” என்று வாழ்த்துகளுடன் தம்பிகளைக் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறார்.3.ஆனந்தரங்கம் பிள்ளை நாட்குறிப்புபிறப்பு : 1709 – சென்னை பெரம்பூர்தந்தை : திருவேங்கடம்ஆசிரியர் : எம்பார்பணி : புதுவையில் அரசுப் பணியில் உதவியாளராக இருந்தார். பிறகு திவானாகப் பதவி உயர்வு பெற்றார்.துய்ப்ளெச்சு என்னும் ஆளுநரின் மொழிப்பெயர்ப்பாளர் (துபாசி) இறந்ததனால் பன்மொழியறிவு பெற்ற ஆனந்தரங்கம் அப்பணிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.நாட்குறிப்பு1736 – 1761 வரை சுமார் 25 ஆண்டுகள் நாட்குறிப்பு எழுதியுள்ளார்.தம் நாட்குறிப்புக்கு ‘தினப்படி செய்தி குறிப்பு’ ‘சொஸ்தலிகிதம்’ (சொஸ்த – தெளிவான லிகிதம் – கடிதம்) தமிழ்ப்பற்றாளர் ஆதலால் நாட்குறிப்பைத் தமிழிலேயே எழுதியுள்ளார்.நாட்குறிப்பில் இடம் பெற்ற செய்திகள்ஆனந்தரங்கரின் நாட்குறிப்புகளின் பெரும்பகுதி வணிகச்செய்திகளையே கூறுகின்றன.புதுச்சேரிக்கு கப்பல்கள் வந்த செய்தி கேட்டதும் மக்கள் நாட்பட்ட திரவியம் மீண்டும் கிடைத்தாற் போலவும் அவரவர் அளவிலே கல்யாணம் நடப்பது போலவும் சந்தோத்ததாக எழுதியுள்ளார்.வீடுகளில் தொடர்ந்து திருடி வந்த திருட்டு கும்பல் ஒன்று பிடிபட்ட போது திருடர்களுக்கு ஐம்பது கசையடிகளோடு காதுகளை அறுத்தும் மக்கள் தண்டனை வழங்கியதாகத் தனது நாட்குறிப்பில் எழுதியுள்ளார்.1746-இல் சுங்கு செட்டியாரின் பெண்கள் இருவருக்குத் திருமணம் நடந்தது.அத்திருமணத்திற்கு வருகைத் தந்த புதுச்சேரி ஆளுநர் துய்ப்ளெக்ஸ் அவர்களுக்கு ரூ.1000 அந்தரங்கத்திலே கொடுத்து பந்தலில் பாக்கு வெற்றிலை மட்டும் கொடுத்து அனுப்பினார் செட்டியார்.சிறப்பு விருந்தினராக ஆளுநர் வந்திருந்தபோது அவர் வரும்போது உட்காரும்போது – சாப்பிடும் போது – எழும்போது என ஒவ்வொரு முறையும் 21 குண்டுகள் முழங்கின.பிரெஞ்சுக்காரர்களுக்கும் இந்திய மன்னர்களுக்கும் இடையே பாலமாக இருந்தவர்.ஆனந்தரங்கம் பிள்ளை பெற்ற பெருமைகள்1749 – இல் முசபர்சங் என்பவர் ஆனந்தரங்கத்துக்கு 3000 குதிரைகளை வழங்கி ‘மன்சுபேதார்’ என்ற பட்டத்தையும் வழங்கினார்.உலக நாட்குறிப்பு இலக்கியத்தின் முன்னோடி ‘பெப்பிஸ்’ என்பார்.இந்தியாவில் பெப்பிஸ் எனப் போற்றப்படுவர் ஆனந்தரங்கம் பிள்ளை ஆவார்.இவரை “நாட்குறிப்பு வேந்தர்” எனவும் போற்றுகின்றனர்.செங்கல்பட்டு கோட்டைக்கு தளபதியாகவும் அம்மாவட்டம் முழுமைக்கும் ஜாகீர்தாராகவும் நியமனம் பெற்றார்.துய்ப்ளே ஆட்சியில் ஆனந்தரங்கர் பல்லக்கில் செல்லும் உரிமைஅவர் வரும் போது மங்கல ஒலிகள் ஒலிக்கும் உரிமை ஆளுநர் மாளிகைக்குள் செருப்பணிந்து செல்லும் உரிமை போன்ற பல தனிப்பட்ட உரிமைகளைப் பெற்றிருந்தார்.அருணாச்சல கவிராயர் தம் ராமநாடகத்தைத் திருவரங்கத்தில் அரங்கேற்றி மீண்டும் ஒருமுறை இவர்முன் அரங்கேற்றினார்.இவரின் நாட்குறிப்புகள் அவர் வீட்டில் இருப்பதை ‘கலுவாமொம்பிரேன்’ என்பவர் கண்டறிந்தார்.நாட்குறிப்பின் சில பகுதிகளை ‘குலியன் வென்சோன்’ பிரெஞ்சு மொழியில் மொழி பெயர்த்தார்.ஆனந்தரங்கர் குறித்து வெளிவந்துள்ள நூல்கள்ஆனந்தரங்கக்கோவை – தியாகராச தேசிகர்ஆனந்தரங்கன் பிள்ளைத்தமிழ் – அரிமதி தென்னகன்ஆனந்தரங்கன் தனிப்பாடல்கள்கள்வன் நொண்டிச்சிந்துஆனந்தரங்கர் புதினங்கள்ஆனந்தரங்க விஜயசம்பு – சீனிவாசக்கவி (வடமொழி)ஆனந்தரங்க ராட்சந்தமு – கஸ்தூரிரங்கக்கவி (தெலுங்கு)"},{"question":"जानकी मन्दिरको बारेमा लेख्नुहोस् |","answer":"हिन्दू र कोइरी नेपाली शैलीको वास्तुकलाको चमत्कार, जानकी मन्दिर नेपालको मिथिला जिल्लामा अवस्थित छ र देवी सीतालाई समर्पित छ। हिन्दू पौराणिक कथा अनुसार, यो त्यही ठाउँ हो, जहाँ सीताको जन्म र भगवान रामसँग विवाह भएको थियो।हिन्दू भगवान राम र उनकी पत्नी सीताको पूजा गर्न र आशीर्वाद लिनको लागि यो नेपालका सबैभन्दा प्रसिद्ध धार्मिक स्थलहरू मध्ये एक हो। जानकी मन्दिर एक सुन्दर तीन-तले संरचना हो र यसको मुख, भित्री भाग र सजावटले प्रभावित गर्दछ।"},{"question":"මට අවසන් යුරෝපීය රන් සපත්තු ජයග්‍රාහකයින් හතර දෙනාගේ ලැයිස්තුවක් ලබා දී ඔවුන් ගෝල කීයක් ලබා ගත්තාදැයි මට කියන්න.","answer":"මට අවසන් යුරෝපීය රන් සපත්තු ජයග්‍රාහකයින් හතර දෙනාගේ ලැයිස්තුවක් ලබා දී ඔවුන් ගෝල කීයක් ලබා ගත්තාදැයි පහත දැක්වේ.\\t1. රොබට් ලෙවන්ඩොව්ස්කි, 2022-2021, ගෝල 35 2. රොබට් ලෙවන්ඩොව්ස්කි, 2021-2020, ගෝල 41 3. සිරෝ ඉමොබයිල්, 2020-2019, ගෝල 36 4. ලයනල් මෙසී, එල් 30 201, 2018. 18 -2017, ඉලක්ක 34ක්"},{"question":"பகையும் உளவோ பிற? – பொருள் கூறுக.","answer":"முகமலர்ச்சியையும் அகமகிழ்ச்சியையும் கொல்லுகின்ற சினத்தை விட வேறுபகை இல்லை."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Dani Melnik, egentligen Daniel Melnik född 8 maj 1985 i Rishon LeZion, är en israelisk simmare. Han tävlar för simklubben Hapoel Jerusalem och internationellt för Israel. Melnik tävlar främst inom bröstsim. Han deltog i Europamästerskapen i simsport 2010","answer":"i Budapest, där han slutade på 34:e plats vid herrarnas 50 meter bröstsim."},{"question":"ما هي الأشعة التي تضر بالرائد الفضائي ؟ أجب على السؤال السابق بإستخدام هذا النص: تتطلب رحلات الفضاء حماية خاصة بسبب أن ضوء الشمس أكثر كثافة وضررا من الأرض حيث تقوم طبقة الأتموسفير بترشيحه. الحماية من الشمس تحتاج إلى الحماية من الأشعة فوق البنفسجية العالية وحتى الأشعة فوق الحمراء الضارة سواء داخل أو خارج المركبة الفضائية. داخل المركبة الفضائية، يرتدي رواد الفضاء نظارات شمسية بعدسات داكنة وطبقة نحيفة من الذهب الوقائي.","answer":"بالتأكيد الإجابة هي الأشعة فوق البنفسجية العالية وحتى الأشعة فوق الحمراء."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة مدح من بحر الوافر. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"عَصَينا فيكَ أَحداثَ اللَياليوَطاوَعنا المَكارِمَ وَالمَعاليوَفيكَ رَجَمتُ أَحشاءَ الأَعاديبِأَطرافِ الذَوابِلِ وَالنِصالِوَعُذتُ بِجانِبَيكَ مِنَ الرَزايامَعاذي في الهَواجِرِ بِالظِلالِدَعَوتُكَ يَومَ دافَعَ عَنكَ نَحريجِناياتِ الصَوارِمِ وَالعَواليفَما خَلِبَ النَوائِبُ مِنكَ بَرقاًيَدُلُّ عَلى الوَفاءِ إِذا بَدا ليوَما هَولُ الفُؤادِ مِنَ التَصافيبَعيدٌ مِن فُؤادٍ فيهِ خاليوَلَم أَعلَم كَعِلمِ بَني زَمانيبِأَنَّ القُربَ داعِيَةُ المَلالِوَأَنَّكَ حينَ تَطمَعُ في نِضاليوَتَعلَمُ أَنَّ لي سَبقَ النِضالِكَماشٍ في الهِياجِ بِلا حُسامٍوَساعٍ في الظَلامِ بِلا ذُبالِوَإِنّي في زَماني مِن رِجالٍمِزاجُ وِدادِهِم ماءُ التَقاليشِمالُ المالِ تَعلو عَن يَمينيوَيُمنى المَجدِ تَقصُرُ عَن شِماليأَقولُ لَهِمَّتي لَمّا أَبَت ليمُعاتَبَةَ المَلولِ عَلى الوِصالِأُعاتِبُهُ لَعَلَّ العَتبَ يَشفيوَإِن كانَ الزَعيمَ بِكَسفِ باليوَلَو لَم يَبلُغِ العُتبى بِقَولٍلَعاتَبناهُ بِالبيضِ الصِقالِرَأى العُذّالُ بَذلَ المالِ طَبعيوَأَسبابَ الشَجاعَةِ مِن خِلاليفَلَم أُعذَل عَلى خَوضِ المَناياوَلَم أُعتَب عَلى بَذلِ النَوالِأَبَت هِمَمي تَسيغُ الماءَ صَفواًإِذا ما الذُلُّ حامَ عَلى الزُلالِأُذَمُّ عَلى العُلى ظُلماً لِأَنّيأَعُلُّ بِمائِها ظَمَأَ السُؤالِوَما زِلنَ العَواطِلُ كُلَّ يَومٍمِنَ العَلياءِ يَذمُمنَ الحَواليوَلَمّا ماطَلَت بِالحَربِ سَعدٌسَنَنّا المَوتَ فيها بِالمِطالِأَثَرنا في قَبائِلِها عَجاجاًتَرَكنا مِنهُ أَثراً في الهِلالِفَمَن يُهدي لِآلِ تَميمَ عَتبيمُقيماً في ذُرى الأَسَلِ الطِوالِمَنَحتُكُمُ الوِدادَ فَلَم تَوُدّوافَأَلقَيتُ المَلامَ عَلى فِعاليوَلَستُ بِباسِطٍ كَفّي لِأَنّيأَرى الأَفلاكَ تَقصُرُ عَن مَنالي"},{"question":"Siapakah Perdana Menteri Malaysia ke-10?","answer":"Yang Amat Berhormat Dato' Seri Anwar bin Ibrahim ialah Perdana Menteri Malaysia ke-10."},{"question":"අයිවරි කෝස්ට් ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"අයිවරි කෝස්ට්, නිල වශයෙන් කෝට් ඩි'අයිවෝර් ජනරජය, කෝට් ඩි'අයිවෝර් ලෙසද හැඳින්වෙන, බටහිර අප්‍රිකාවේ දකුණු වෙරළ තීරයේ පිහිටි රටකි. එහි අගනුවර වන්නේ රට මධ්‍යයේ පිහිටි යමුසූක්රෝ වන අතර එහි විශාලතම නගරය සහ ආර්ථික මධ්‍යස්ථානය වන්නේ අබිඩ්ජන් වරාය නගරයයි. එය වයඹ දෙසින් ගිනියාව, බටහිරින් ලයිබීරියාව, වයඹ දෙසින් මාලි, ඊසාන දෙසින් බුර්කිනා ෆාසෝ, නැගෙනහිරින් ඝානාව සහ දකුණින් ගිනියා බොක්ක (අත්ලාන්තික් සාගරය) මායිම් වේ. එහි නිල භාෂාව ප්‍රංශ වන අතර බීටේ, බවුලේ, ඩියුලා, ඩෑන්, එනියින් සහ සෙබරා සෙනුෆෝ ඇතුළු දේශීය භාෂා ද බහුලව භාවිතා වේ. සමස්තයක් වශයෙන්, අයිවරි කෝස්ට්හි විවිධ භාෂා 78 ක් පමණ කතා කරයි. ඉස්ලාම්, ක්‍රිස්තියානි ආගම, සහ සෘද්ධිවාදය වැනි සම්ප්‍රදායික ඇදහිලි අනුගාමිකයින් ඇතුළු ආගමික වශයෙන් විවිධ ජනගහනයක් රට තුළ ඇත.එහි යටත් විජිතකරණයට පෙර, අයිවරි කෝස්ට්, ගයමන්, කොං අධිරාජ්‍යය සහ බවුලේ ඇතුළු ප්‍රාන්ත කිහිපයක නිවහන විය. මෙම ප්‍රදේශය 1843 දී ප්‍රංශයේ ආරක්ෂිත ප්‍රදේශයක් බවට පත් වූ අතර අප්‍රිකාව සඳහා වූ පොරබැදීම මධ්‍යයේ 1893 දී ප්‍රංශ යටත් විජිතයක් ලෙස ඒකාබද්ධ කරන ලදී. එය 1993 දක්වා රට පාලනය කළ ෆීලික්ස් හවුෆෝට්-බොයිග්නි ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් 1960 දී නිදහස ලබා ගත්තේය. කලාපීය ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුව සාපේක්ෂව ස්ථාවර, අයිවරි කෝස්ට් බටහිර අප්‍රිකානු අසල්වැසියන් සමඟ සමීප දේශපාලන-ආර්ථික සබඳතා ගොඩනඟා ගත් අතර බටහිර, විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රංශය සමඟ සමීප සබඳතා පවත්වයි. 1999 දී කුමන්ත්‍රණයකින් සහ සිවිල් යුද්ධ දෙකකින් එහි ස්ථාවරත්වය අඩු විය - පළමුව 2002 සහ 2007 අතර සහ නැවතත් 2010-2011 කාලය තුළ. එය 2016 දී නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවක් සම්මත කළේය.අයිවරි කෝස්ට් යනු ප්‍රබල විධායක බලය එහි ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පැවරී ඇති ජනරජයකි. කෝපි සහ කොකෝවා නිෂ්පාදනය හරහා, එය 1960 සහ 1970 ගණන් වලදී බටහිර අප්‍රිකාවේ ආර්ථික බලාගාරයක් වූ අතර, පසුව 1980 ගණන්වල ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දුන් අතර, 2011 දක්වා දිග්ගැස්සුණු දේශපාලන හා සමාජ කැලඹිලි සමයකට දායක විය. අයිවරි කෝස්ට් නැවතත් අත්විඳ ඇත. 2011 දී සාමය සහ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය නැවත පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඉහළ ආර්ථික වර්ධනයක් විය. 2012 සිට 2021 දක්වා, ආර්ථිකය සැබෑ ලෙස වසරකට 7.4% ක සාමාන්‍යයකින් වර්ධනය විය, අප්‍රිකාවේ දෙවන වේගවත්ම ආර්ථික වර්ධන වේගය සහ ලෝකයේ සිව්වන වේගවත්ම අනුපාතය විය. 2020 දී, අයිවරි කෝස්ට් කොකෝවා බෝංචි ලොව විශාලතම අපනයනකරු වූ අතර එහි කලාපය සඳහා ඉහළ ආදායමක් ලබා ඇත. ආර්ථිකය තවමත් කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය මත දැඩි ලෙස රඳා පවතින අතර කුඩා වතු හිමියන්ගේ මුදල් බෝග නිෂ්පාදනය ප්‍රමුඛ වේ."},{"question":"\\"বৈশাখী মেলা\\" শিরোনামে একটি অনুচ্ছেদ রচনা করো।","answer":"বৈশাখী মেলা নববর্ষের সর্বজনীন অনুষ্ঠানগুলোর অন্যতম। নববর্ষ উপলক্ষ্যে বৈশাখ মাসের প্রথম দিনেই দেশের বিভিন্ন শহর ও গ্রামের বিভিন্ন স্থানে এ মেলা বসে। এ মেলা চলার নির্দিষ্ট কোনো সময় নেই। একদিন থেকে শুরু করে মাসব্যাপী এ মেলা চলতে থাকে। নতুন বছরে মানুষের আনন্দ-অনুভূতির প্রকাশ ঘটে বৈশাখী মেলার মাধ্যমে। এটা বাঙালি সংস্কৃতির ঐতিহ্য হিসেবে প্রচলিত রয়েছে। আবহমানকাল থেকেই আমাদের দেশে বৈশাখী মেলা চলে আসছে। এ মেলা উপলক্ষ্যে বিভিন্ন উৎসব-অনুষ্ঠান ও বিভিন্ন প্রতিযোগিতামূলক খেলাধুলার আয়োজন করা হয়। তার মধ্যে বলী খেলা, ঘোড় দৌড়, নৌকাবাইচ উল্লেখযোগ্য। বৈশাখী মেলা সাধারণত খোলা আকাশের নিচে বসে। প্রতিবছর রমনার বটমূলে বসে এ মেলার প্রভাতী আসর। এছাড়া গ্রামের হাটবাজারে, নদী তীরে, মন্দির প্রাঙ্গণে এ মেলা বসে। মেলা উপলক্ষ্যে লোকে লোকারণ্য হয়ে যায়। মানুষের মাঝে প্রাণচাঞ্চল্য লক্ষ করা যায়। নিত্যপ্রয়োজনীয় পণ্য, নানা জাতের কুটিরশিল্প, খেলনাসহ হরেক রকমের পণ্যের সমাহার ঘটে এ , মেলায়। এছাড়াও থাকে যাত্রা, পুতুলনাচ, নাগরদোলা, সার্কাসসহ বিনোদনমূলক বিভিন্ন অনুষ্ঠানের আয়োজন। বিভিন্ন ধরনের মিষ্টিজাতীয় খাবারও পাওয়া যায় মেলায়। নতুনকে বরণ করার উদ্যেশ্যেই এ মেলার আয়োজন করা হয়। কোনো রকম ধর্মীয় চেতনা এ মেলায় পরিলক্ষিত হয় না। তাই এটি একটি সর্বজনীন উৎসবে পরিণত হয়েছে। মেলা উপলক্ষ্যে জাতি, ধর্ম, বর্ণ ও গোত্র নির্বিশেষে সকলের মিলনমেলায় পরিণত হয়। এতে মানুষের প্রগতিশীল চেতনা জাগ্রত হয়। তাই সব দিক থেকে এ মেলার গুরুত্ব অপরিসীম। আমরা নতুন করে বাঙালি ঐতিহ্য লালন করে বাঁচার অনুপ্রেরণা লাভ করি।"},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:“ఓ జననాథ అని శ్రీకృష్ణుడు తన మాటలను ధృతరాష్ట్రుని ఎదుట మొదలు పెట్టాడు. సమాజ సౌఖ్యాన్ని దృష్టిలో పెట్టుకొని నిర్ణయం తీసుకోవాలని సూచించాడు. నీకు తెలియని విషయాలు ఏమున్నాయి ? ఐనప్పటికీ, భరతవంశం సంతోషించేటట్లు మీ ఇరు కుటుంబాల వారికి న్యాయమూ, పరమహితమూ చెప్పటం ఉచితమని నేనిక్కడికి వచ్చాను. మీ ఇద్దరు తనకు సమానమని తెలిపాడు. పాండవులు కౌరవులు పాలూ, నీరూ లాగ కలసి మెలసి జీవించటం మంచిదని వారు కలిసిమెలసి ఉండేటట్లు నడిపించవలసిన బాధ్యత ధృతరాష్ట్రునిదని తెలియపరిచాడు. పాండవులు వేరు, కౌరవులు వేరు అనే భేదభావన చూపకూడదన్నాడు.భరతవంశం ధర్మం, న్యాయం, సత్యం, ఐకమత్యం, గౌరవం, కారుణ్యం మొదలైన సద్గుణాలు గలిగి కీర్తి పొందిందని తెలిపి దానిని కాపాడాలన్నాడు. కురు వంశములో పెద్దవాడివి కావున నీ కుటుంబంలోని వారి నడవడికల బాధ్యత నీదే అన్నాడు.యుద్ధం వస్తే అక్కడున్న భీమార్జునులను యుద్ధరంగంలో మించేవారు ఇక్కడెందరున్నారు ? ఇక్కడున్న ద్రోణ, భీష్ముల పరాక్రమాన్ని ఎదుర్కొనగలవారు అక్కడ కూడా లేరు. ఇట్లా ఉభయ పక్షాలలోని వీరులు యుద్ధంలో చావటం కన్న నీ బలగాలన్నీ కలసి మెలసి వర్తించటం మంచిదని హితవు పలికాడు. ","answer":"రాజా ! నీవు కురుపాండవుల విషయంలో శ్రద్ధ వహించకుంటే ఈ ఉభయ వర్గాలకే కాదు, పుడమిలోని జనులందరికీ హాని చేసినట్లే అవుతుందని, ఆ కీడు నీకే కలుగుతుందని హెచ్చరించాడు.రాజా ! కురు పాండవులలో ఎవరికి మరణం సంప్రాప్తించినా, బాధలు కలిగినా, నీకు దుఃఖం కలుగుతుంది. కౌరవ పాండవుల కోమలమైన శరీరాల నుండి మొనలుదేలిన బాణాలు ఆవలికి దూసుకొని వెళ్ళేటట్లు గ్రుచ్చుకోగా నేలమీద కూలటం చూచి సహించటం సరైనది కాదు కావున కురుపాండవులు సంగ్రామంలో నశించకుండా సంరక్షించుకోవాలని చెప్పాడు. పాండురాజు చనిపోయిన తరువాత వారిని చక్కగా పెంచిన నీవు ఇప్పుడు వారికి అన్యాయం చేయడం సరికాదన్నాడు. పాండవుల శక్తియుక్తులను గుర్తు చేస్తూ వారి ఔదార్యాన్ని వివరించాడు. ఉత్తమమైన ధర్మం, నిర్మలమైన సత్యం పాపం చేతను, అబద్ధం చేత లక్ష్యాన్ని చేరలేని స్థితిలో భగవంతుడు ధర్మమును ఉద్ధరించటానికి, సత్యానికి శుభం కలిగించటానికి ముందుకు వస్తాడని తెలిపాడు.నీ పుత్రుడైన దుర్యోధనుడి అకృత్యాలకు పరోక్షంగా మద్దతు తెలిపినందుకు మీకందరికి తగిన శిక్ష పడుతుందన్నాడు. దుర్యోధనుని మనసులో ఉన్న పరమ దురాశను తొలగించి, పాండవులకు రావలసిన అర్థ రాజ్యాన్ని వారికి అప్పగించేలా చూడాలని చెప్పాడు. పాండవులను నీ చెంతకు పిలిపించుకోమన్నాడు.పాండవులు ఎంతటి శాంత స్వభావులో అంతటి వీరాగ్రేసరులు. వారికి మీతో కలసి మెలసి ఉండటం ఇష్టం కాకపోతే ఈపాటికి యుద్ధానికి బయలుదేరి వచ్చేవారు. సంధి, సంగ్రామం ఈ రెండింటిలో మీకేది హితమని తోస్తుందో దానిని నిర్ణయించి వెల్లడించమని పలికాడు. ఈ విధంగా శ్రీకృష్ణుడు కౌరవ వంశ ప్రతిష్టను, దుర్యోధనాదుల దుష్టబుద్ధిని, పాండవుల పరాక్రమాన్ని, ఔదార్యాన్ని తెలిపి సంధి చేసుకోకుంటే వచ్చే అనర్థాలను తన రాయబారం ద్వారా వివరించాడు."},{"question":"Lan mooy JAVA ?","answer":"LAKK INFORMATIQUE LEU"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Bu ngeen ko deful, te du ngeen ko mën a def mukk, na ngeen ragal safara soo xam ne matt ma koy xamb nit la ak i xeer, te way weddi ya la ñu koy xaaroo.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Bu ngéen ko deful, te du ngéen ko man a def mukk, na ngéen ragal safara soo xàm ne matt ma ko'y xamb nit la ak i xeer, te wayweddi ya la ñu ko'y xaaroo."},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsoratra:Hoy ny talen’ny sekoly: « Teo aloha dia nikasa hanatanteraka hetsika ihany izahay, saingy noho ny tsy fahampian’ny enti-manana sy ny fahalalana dia tsy lasa lavitra, fa hatramin’ny nampidirana ny fandaharan’asa “mpianatra iray, hazo iray” tato amin’ny sekoly dia nahazo fiofanana sahaza anay miaraka amin'ny fitaovana ary koa ny zava-maniry izahay. Eo ihany koa ity toeram-pambolena ity izay ampiasaina amin’ny fikojakojana ireo zava-maniry tanora izay ho ampiasaina amin’ny fambolen-kazo any aoriana. Tsy mbola nahita an’izany mihitsy izahay ary tsy sahy nieritreritra an’izany akory. Tsy toy ny hitako teo aloha fa ity dia azo tsapain-tanana sy mivaingana. Mino aho fa ho afaka handroso bebe kokoa isika izao ary hiezaka hanome hasina ity hetsika ity amin'ny alàlan'ny fikojakojana sy ny fanaraha-maso… »Efa nahazo zana-kazo hafa tamin’ny alàlan’ny mpamatsy vola hafa ny sekoly, ankoatra ny efa azony teo aloha. Mampanantena fampandrosoana manome famporisihana ity hetsika ity eny anivon’ilay distrika, eny fa any amin’ireo distrika hafa aza, izay heverina ho fanombohana ihany.Ahoana ny fahitan'ny talen'ny sekoly ny hetsika?","answer":"Azo tsapain-tanana sy mivaingana ilay hetsika hoy ny talen'ny sekoly."},{"question":"तलको प्रश्नको सहि उत्तर छान्नुहोस ।बडो = बरो, डाँडो = डाँरो जस्तो उच्चारण नेपाली भाषाका कुन भाषिकाको कुन भेदसँग सम्बन्धित छ ? क) पूर्वेली भाषिकाको पर्वती भेद  ख) पूर्वेली भाषिकाको गोर्खाली भेद ग) पूर्वेली भाषिकाको खसानी भेदघ) ओरपश्चिमाको बझाङी भेद","answer":"बडो = बरो, डाँडो = डाँरो जस्तो उच्चारण नेपाली भाषाका पूर्वेली भाषिकाको खसानी भेदसँग सम्बन्धित छ । "},{"question":"ટોપ ગુજરાતી ગઝલો ની યાદી :","answer":"ગુજરાતી ગઝલો ની યાદી :1. નયન ને બંધ રાખીને2. સંઝરુખો3. કંકોત્રી4. કાજલ ભરીઓ નયન માં 5. માનવ ના "},{"question":"1.\\"Ravoravo aho handeha ho any\\" 2.\\"Malaina aho handeha ho any\\"Mitovy sa mifanipa-kevitra ireo fehezanteny roa ireo?","answer":"Mifanipa-kevitra ireo fehezanteny ireo. Ny iray milaza hafaliana ary ny iray milaza fahakamoana."},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sau:Phép tính (– 42) . (– 5) được kết quả là:A. – 210     B. 210     C. – 47     D. 37","answer":"Chọn đáp án B.Ta có: (– 42) . (– 5) = 42 . 5 = 210"},{"question":"Njengoba senizizwele osopolitiki bekhuluma nani, naphinde nezwanoDuma exolisa ngokushayisa kwakhe, manje-ke ngizonifundelaumbiko wenkosi. (alungise ipheshana aliphethe maqede aqaleafunde) Ithi inkosi yesizwe sakithi, 'Ngibingelela isikhulusikaHulumeni, osopolitiki bezinhlangano zabantu kanye nesizwesonke. Sizwe sami engisithandayo, okwenzekile kufana nentoesingeke sisakwazi ukuyiguqula. Asebefile ngeke sibavuse kodwangethemba ukuthi sifunde lukhulu kukho konke osekwenzekile.Ngabe angiyazi into engiyiphilelayo uma ngingababongi laba bantubesifazane ababili umkami uMaNgema, kanye noMaShezi,umkaDuma. Bobabili babambe iqhaza elibaluleke kakhulu ekucishenilo mlilo. Ngempela baqinisile abathi, abantu besimame bayimbokodo.Kusukela manje ikhansela lizoqhubeka nohlelo lokuletha intuthukoesizweni sami. Nalo liqaphele ukuthi lisebenzisana nabantu abanjani.Mina-ke ngizolisiza ikhansela. Njengoba alikabi nayo indluyokusebenzela, mina nginikela ngendlu elaphaya emzini wami. Leyondlu iseduze kwesango. Yiyo-ke ezoba yigunjana azohlelela kulokonke okuqondene nemisebenzi yakhe. Ngizovala ngokubongaamaphoyisa asebenze ngokuzikhandla ukubhula lo mlilo. Yiminainkosi yenu, uShandu.'1. Ukuba wena wawunguMbandlwa yiziphi izeluleko ezakhayoowawungazinikeza uDuma? Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Emhlabeni kuyahlonishwana, kuyaboniswana.√/• Akafunde ukulalela.√"},{"question":"Một số chia hết cho cả 2 và 5 thì có chữ số tận cùng là chữ số nào?","answer":"Lời giải:Ta có:+ Các số có chữ số tận cùng là 0; 2; 4; 6; 8 thì chia hết cho 2 và chỉ những số đó mới chia hết cho 2.+ Các số có chữ số tận cùng là 0 hoặc 5 thì chia hết cho 5 và chỉ những số đó mới chia hết cho 5. Ta thấy dấu hiệu nhận biết số chia hết cho 2 và 5 đều có chung số có chữ số tận cùng là 0. Vậy những số có chữ số tận cùng là 0 thì chia hết cho cả 2 và 5. "},{"question":"Манас эпосу тууралуу кандай маалыматың бар?","answer":"«Манас» эпосу дүйнөдө тендешсиз зор көлөмдүү көркөм чыгарма. Манасчы Саякбай Каралаев уулунан жазылып алынган эпостун «Манас», «Семетей» жана «Сейтек» үч бөлүмүнүн жалпы көлөмү 500 мин ыр саптарын түзөт. Бул байыркы гректердин «Иллиадасы» менен «Одиссеясын» бирге кошкон көлөмдөн 20 эседей көп. «Манастын» ошол бир эле варианты илимде узак убакыт эң көлөмдүү эпос делип келген инди элдеринин «Махабхаратасынан» эки жарым эсе, ал эми фарсы тилиндеги «Шах-наамеден» беш эсе көптүк кылат."},{"question":"اشرح الفرق بين الانحدار غير الخطي والانحدار الخطي.","answer":"\\"يشير الانحدار - في علم الإحصاء وعلم الرياضيات - إلى العلاقة بين متغيرات. يجدر التفرقة بين الانحدار الخطي والانحدار غير الخطي بالنسبة للعلاقة الموجودة بين هذه المتغيرات.1. الانحدار الخطي: يحدث الانحدار الخطي عندما يكون هناك علاقة خطية بين المتغيرات. يعني ذلك أنه إذا تغيرت قيمة واحدة من المتغيرين ، فسوف يتغير المتغير الآخر بشكل متناسب. على سبيل المثال ، إذا كانت المتغيرات هي الوزن والطول ، فإن الانحدار الخطي سيحدث إذا كان كل زيادة في الطول ترافقها زيادة مقابلة في الوزن.2. الانحدار الغير خطي:يحدث الانحدار الغير خطي عندما لا تتبع العلاقة بين المتغيرات سلوكًا خطيًا. في هذه الحالة ، يمكن أن يحدث تغير في قيمة واحدة من المتغيرات دون تأثير في المتغير الآخر ، أو أن تغيرًا في قيمة واحدة يؤدي إلى تغيير غير متناسب في القيمة الأخرى. ويتغير شكل الانحدار في الانحدار الغير خطي ويشمل الانحناء والمنحدرات الإيجابية والسلبية. ومن الأمثلة على انحدار غير خطي الكثيرة هو الانحدار الغير خطي في الوظائف الرياضية، حيث يوجد عادة ارتباط سلوكي غير موجود في الانحدار الخطي.\\""},{"question":"හින්ඩන්බර්ග් ව්‍යසනය සිදුවූයේ කුමන වසරේද?","answer":"හින්ඩන්බර්ග් ව්‍යසනය සිදු වූයේ 1937 මැයි 6 වන දින, හින්ඩන්බර්ග් ගුවන් යානය ගිනිගෙන විනාශ වූ විට නාවික ගුවන් තොටුපළ ලේක්හර්ස්ට් වෙත එහි මුරිං කුඹ තටාකයට නැංගීමට ගත් උත්සාහයේදී ය."},{"question":"තීර්ථ යනු ජීවිතයට කියන තවත් වචනයක් ද? වෙන අරුත් තියනවද?","answer":"තීර්ථ යනු ගංගක හෝ සයුරක මෙගොඩ. එය සිංහල තත්භව වනවිට තෙර ලෙස ගනී. එගොඩ පරතෙර වේ එනම් පරාතීර්ථවේ.මෙය වාච්‍යාර්ථයයි.ව්‍යංගාර්ථ ලෙස නැතහොත් රූපක අර්ථ ලෙස සසර නොයෙක් සන්ධිස්ථානන් රූපනය වී ඇත. සැළලිහිනියේ\\"තරව සිහි ඇතිව පරතෙරට යන අටින් \\" කීවිට ගග සසරටත් තෙර භවයටත් පරතෙට නිවනටත් රූපනය වේ. එමනිසා ශබ්ද කෝෂාර්ථ හා ව්‍යංගාර්ථ යනු සීමා දෙකකි."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న: భూమి యొక్క సహజ ఆవరణములలో జీవావరణము ఎలా భిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది?","answer":"భూమి యొక్క సహజ ఆవరణములలో జీవావరణము భిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది, ఎలా అంటే1. జీవంతో కళకళలాడే ఏకైక గ్రహం భూమి. భూమి యొక్క ఇతర మూడు ఆవరణలు కలిసిన చోటైన జీవావరణంలో ‘జీవం’ వర్ధిల్లుతుంది.2. ఆ జీవావరణమే తిరిగి ఈ మూడు ఆవరణాలను ప్రభావితం చేస్తుంది.3. మూడు ఆవరణాలతోనే కాకుండా వివిధ జీవరూపాల మధ్య కూడా పరస్పర సంబంధాలు ఉంటాయి.ఉదా : మొక్కలు, జంతువులు పరస్పరం ఒకదానిపై ఒకటి ఆధారపడి ఉన్నాయి."},{"question":"Apakah maksud Kaki ayam?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah Tidak memakai kasut berjalan"},{"question":"ਨਵਾਜ਼ੂਦੀਨ ਸਿੱਦੀਕੀ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਨਵਾਜ਼ੁਦੀਨ ਸਿਦੀਕੀ --ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਹਨ ਜਿਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਮੁੱਖ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ, ਬਲੈਕ ਫਰਾਈਡੇ (2004), ਨਿਊਯਾਰਕ (2009), ਪੀਪਲੀ ਲਾਈਵ (2010), ਕਹਾਣੀ (2012), ਗੈਂਗਸ ਆਫ ਵਾਸੇਪੁਰ 1 (2012), ਗੈਂਗਸ ਆਫ ਵਾਸੇਪੁਰ 2 (2012), ਮਾਂਝੀ (2013) ਅਤੇ ਤਲਾਸ਼ (2012), ਮਾਂਝੀ - ਦਾ ਮਾਉਨਟੇਨ ਮੈਨ (2015)।== ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 19 ਮਈ 1974 ਨੂੰ ਮੁਜ਼ਫ਼ੱਰਨਗਰ ਜ਼ਿਲਾ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਕਸਬੇ, ਬੁਧਾਨਾ ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਸਲਿਮ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੱਠ ਭੈਣ-ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਹਨ।ਉਸਨੇ ਗੁਰੂਕੁਲ ਕਾਂਗਰੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਵਿਦਿਆਲੇ, ਹਰਿਦੁਆਰ ਤੋਂ ਕੈਮਿਸਟਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਇੰਸ ਦੀ ਡਿਗਰੀ (ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਸ਼ਨ) ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸਨੇ ਇਕ ਸਾਲ ਲਈ ਵਡੋਦਰਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਕੈਮਿਸਟ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਨਵੀਂ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਲੱਭਣ ਲਈ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ। ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿੱਚ, ਇੱਕ ਨਾਟਕ ਦੇਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਤੁਰੰਤ ਬਾਅਦ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਇਰਾਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਸਕੂਲ ਆਫ ਡਰਾਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲੇ ਦੇ ਮਾਪਦੰਡ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ, ਉਸਨੇ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਮੂਹ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ 10 ਨਾਟਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ।== ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ==ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਸਕੂਲ ਆਫ ਡਰਾਮਾ, ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਤੋਂ ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਟ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਹ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 2004,  ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਭੈੜੇ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਇਕ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਕੋਲ  ਕਿਰਾਏ ਦਾ ਭੁਗਤਾਨ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਵੀ ਪੈਸੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ । ਉਸ ਨੇ ਐਨ.ਐਸ.ਡੀ ਦੇ ਇਕ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਉਹ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਗੋਰੇਗਾਂਵ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਅਪਾਰਟਮੈਂਟ ਸਾਂਝਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ ਜੇ ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਉਸ ਲਈ ਖਾਣਾ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੋਵੇ।ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਨੇ 1999 ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕੀਤੀ,  ਉਸਨੇ ਆਮਿਰ ਖਾਨ ਦੀ ਫਿਲਮ  ਸਰਫਰੋਸ਼ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਛੋਟੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ, ਉਹ ਫਿਲਮ ਜੰਗਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਤ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ, ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਫਿਲਮ ਸਟੂਡਿਓ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਪਰ ਸਿਰਫ ਛੋਟੇ-ਮੋਟੇ ਰੋਲ ਹੀ ਮਿਲੇ। ਉਸਨੇ ਸੁਨੀਲ ਦੱਤ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਜੇ ਦੱਤ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ 'ਮੁੰਨਾਭਾਈ ਐਮ ਬੀ ਬੀ ਐਸ' ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਕਰੀਨ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਕੀਤੀ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਹ ਸੁਨੀਲ ਦੱਤ ਦੀ ਜੇਬ ਕੱਟਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਮੁੰਬਈ ਚੱਲੇ ਜਾਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸਨੇ ਟੈਲੀਵਿਯਨ ਲੜੀ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ, ਪਰ ਬਹੁਤੀ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਈ। ਉਸਨੇ 2003 ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਲਘੂ ਫਿਲਮ 'ਦ ਬਾਈਪਾਸ' ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ  ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ 2002-05 ਦੇ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਉਹ ਕੰਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ, ਅਤੇ ਚਾਰ ਹੋਰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝੇ ਫਲੈਟ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਹਾ ਅਤੇ ਕਦੇ-ਕਦਾਈਂ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਵਰਕਸ਼ਾਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ।ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਕਸ਼ਯਪ ਦੀ 'ਬਲੈਕ ਫਰਾਈਡੇ' (2007) ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮੌਜੂਦਗੀ ਨੇ ਹੋਰ ਸ਼ਕਤੀਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਲਈ ਰਾਹ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ। ਫੀਚਰ ਫਿਲਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਂਤ ਭਾਰਗਵ ਦੀ 'ਪਤੰਗ' (2007-2008 ਵਿਚ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ) ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਗਾਇਕ ਚੱਕੂ ਵਜੋਂ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਬਰਲਿਨ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ ਅਤੇ ਟ੍ਰੈਬੇਕਾ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰੀਮੀਅਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਲਈ ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਦੀ ਕਾਰਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੀ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਸ਼ਲਾਘਾ ਹੋਈ। 2009 ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿਦੀਕੀ 'ਦੇਵ ਡੀ' ਫਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ 'ਇਮੋਸ਼ਨਲ ਅੱਤਿਆਚਾਰ' ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਉਸਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਹੋਈ।ਫਿਲਮ 'ਨਿਊਯਾਰਕ' ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਆਮਿਰ ਖਾਨ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਸ਼ਨਜ਼ ਦੀ 'ਪੀਪਲੀ ਲਾਈਵ' (2010) ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ  ਨੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਐਕਟਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਮਾਨਤਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ।ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਕਸ਼ਯਪ ਦੀ 'ਗੈਂਗਸ ਆਫ਼ ਵਾਸੇਪੁਰ' ਨਾਲ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧੀ ਮਿਲੀ। ਉਸਨੇ ਅਸ਼ੀਮ ਆਹਲੂਵਾਲੀਆ ਦੀ ਮਿਸ ਲਵਲੀ ਵਿਚ ਸੋਨੂੰ ਦੁੱਗਲ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਇਮਰੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਇਹ ਫਿਲਮ ਕੈਨਸ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ 2012 ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਹੋਈ। ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਇਸ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨੂੰ \\"ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵਧੀਆ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ\\" ਮੰਨਿਆ ਹੈ।ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਗੈਂਗਸ ਆੱਫ ਵਾਸੇਪੁਰ ਦੇ ਦੂਸਰੇ ਭਾਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। 2013 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ ਆਤਮਾ ਫਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਉਹ ਆਮਿਰ ਖਾਨ ਦੀ 2012 ਦੀ ਰਿਲੀਜ ਤਲਾਸ਼ 'ਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਇਆ। 2014 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ ਸਲਮਾਨ ਖਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਕਿੱਕ ਫਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ  ਸ਼ਿਵ ਗਜਰਾ, ਇੱਕ ਖਲਨਾਇਕ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ।2015 ਵਿੱਚ, ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਦੀ ਫਿਲਮ 'ਬਜਰੰਗੀ ਭਾਈਜਾਨ' ਅਤੇ  ਮਾਂਝੀ - ਦਾ ਮਾਉਨਟੇਨ ਮੈਨ ਰਿਲੀਜ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਲਈ ਉਸਦੀ ਦੀ ਕਾਫੀ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ। ਸਿਦੀਕੀ ਦੀ ਅਗਲੀ ਫਿਲਮ  ਹਰਾਮਖੋਰ ਵਿਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਰਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੀ ਲਈ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ 'ਨਿਊਯਾਰਕ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ' ਵਿਚ ਬੈਸਟ ਐਕਟਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਸਨਮਾਨਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"من در حین کار آسیب دیدم و پایم شکسته. یک درخواست مرخصی استعلاجی به مدت ۵ روز از تاریخ ۲ اردیبهشت ۱۴۰۲ برایم بنویس. در مدت این مرخصی همکارم وظایف من را انجام خواهد داد.","answer":"احترما اینجانب (نام خودتان) کارمند بخش (نام واحدی که در آن مشغول به کار هستید) تقاضای درخواست ۵ روز مرخصی استعلاجی به دلیل شکستگی پا حین انجام وظیفه در محل کار، از تاریخ ۱۴۰۲/۲/۲ را دارم.لذا خواهشمند است دستور فرمایید در تاریخ مقرر شده تمهیدات لازم جهت مرخصی ساعتی برای بنده صادر شود.همچنین در غیاب اینجانب، جناب آقای/سرکار خانم (نام همکار) امور محوله بنده را عهده دار خواهند بود."},{"question":"పరిశ్రమ అంటే ఏమిటి ? వివిధ రకాలైన పరిశ్రమలను సోదాహరణముగా వివరించండి.","answer":"వ్యాపారము తాలూకు ఉత్పాదనాంశమే పరిశ్రమ. వస్తువుల ఉత్పత్తికి సంబంధించిన కార్యకలాపాల సమూహాన్ని పరిశ్రమగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు. వస్తువుల సేకరణ, ఉత్పత్తి, ప్రాసెసింగ్ నిర్మాణము మొదలైన వాటికి సంబంధించిన కార్యకలాపాలనే పరిశ్రమగా నిర్వచించవచ్చు.తయారయ్యే వస్తువులు వినియోగ వస్తువులు లేదా ఉత్పాదక వస్తువులు కావచ్చు. వినియోగదారులు ఉపయోగించే వస్తువులు అనగా ఆహార పదార్థాలు, నూలు మొదలైనవి వినియోగిత వస్తువులు. ఉత్పాదక వస్తువులు అనగా ఉత్పత్తిదారులు వాటిని మరల ఉత్పత్తికి ఉపయోగించేవి. ఉదా : యంత్రాలు, పరికరాలు, ఎక్విప్మెంట్ మొ||నవి.పరిశ్రమలను సాధారణముగా దిగువ విధాలుగా వర్గీకరించవచ్చును.1) ప్రాథమిక పరిశ్రమ : ఈ పరిశ్రమ ప్రకృతి సహాయంతో వస్తువులను ఉత్పత్తి చేస్తుంది. దీనిలో మానవుని శ్రమ చాలా తక్కువ. ఇది ప్రకృతిపై ఆధారపడినది. ఉదా : వ్యవసాయము, చేపలు పట్టుట, అటవీకరణ మొ||నవి.2) ప్రజనన పరిశ్రమలు : ఈ పరిశ్రమలు వంశ క్రమానికి చెందుతాయి. కొన్ని జాతి మొక్కలను, పశువులను, పక్షులను పునరుత్పత్తి చేసి, వాటిని అమ్మడం ద్వారా లాభాన్ని ఆర్జించే కార్యకలాపాన్ని ప్రజనన పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. నర్సరీలు, కోళ్ళ పరిశ్రమ, పట్టు పురుగుల పెంపకము మొ||నవి ఈ పరిశ్రమల క్రిందకు వస్తాయి.3) ఉద్గ్రహణ పరిశ్రమలు : ప్రకృతి వనరుల నుంచి వస్తువులను వెలికితీసే. కార్యకలపాలతో ముడిపడివున్న పరిశ్రమలను ఉద్గ్రహణ పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. ఖనిజాల త్రవ్వకము, బొగ్గు ఖనిజము, నూనె, ఇనుప ఖనిజము, అడవుల నుంచి కలప, రబ్బరు వెలికితీయడము ఉద్గ్రహణ పరిశ్రమకు ఉదాహరణలు.4) వస్తుతయారీ పరిశ్రమలు : ముడి పదార్థాలు లేదా సగము తయారైన వస్తువుల నుంచి పూర్తిగా తయారైన వస్తువులను ఉత్పత్తి చేసేవాటిని వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. ఈ వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమ ప్రధానముగా కర్మాగారాలలో సాగుతూ ఉంటుంది. ఇనుము-ఉక్కు, యంత్ర పరికరాలు, సిమెంటు, వస్త్రాలు మొదలైనవాటికి సంబంధించిన పరిశ్రమలను వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలకు ఉదాహరణలుగా చెప్పవచ్చును. వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలను మరల వర్గీకరించవచ్చును.విశ్లేషణాత్మక పరిశ్రమలుప్రక్రియాత్మక పరిశ్రమలుమిశ్రమ పరిశ్రమలుజోడింపు పరిశ్రమలు.5) వస్తు నిర్మాణ పరిశ్రమలు : రోడ్లు, వంతెనలు, భవనాలు, కాలువలు, ప్రాజెక్టులు- మొదలైన నిర్మాణాలను చేపట్టేవాటిని వస్తు నిర్మాణ పరిశ్రమలుగా పేర్కొనవచ్చును. ఉద్గ్రహణ మరియు వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలలో తయారైన వస్తువులలో అధిక భాగము ఈ రకమైన పరిశ్రమలలో ముడిపదార్థముగా వాడతారు.6) సేవారంగ పరిశ్రమలు : ప్రస్తుతము సేవారంగము ఒక దేశ అభివృద్ధిలో ముఖ్యమైన పాత్రను పోషిస్తున్నది కాబట్టి దీనిని సేవారంగ పరిశ్రమగా పేర్కొంటారు. సేవారంగ పరిశ్రమలకు చెందిన ఉదాహరణలు పరిశ్రమ, టూరిజం పరిశ్రమ, వినోద పరిశ్రమ, ఆసుపత్రులు, హోటల్, కళాశాలలు మొదలైనవి."},{"question":"Cậu bé Phrăng trong bài Buổi học cuối cùng Ngữ văn lớp 7 băn khoăn điều gì về những con chim bồ câu trên mái nhà trường?","answer":"- Điều băn khoăn của Phrăng “Liệu người ta có bắt cả chúng nó cũng phải hót bằng tiếng Đức không nhỉ?” tưởng chừng như là ngây ngô nhưng ẩn sâu trong đó biết bao điều thú vị. Trong phút giây cuối cùng của buổi học dường như chú hiểu được sự yêu tổ quốc yêu quê mẹ như thế nào. Những con chim bồ câu thể hiện cho sự hòa bình, sự tự do chúng hót với những âm thanh/ tiếng riêng của chúng. Nhưng câu hỏi của chú bé làm chúng ta như sững lại. Chú hỏi như vậy như thể những con chim bồ câu kia cũng biết tiếng Pháp vậy. Điều đó đã thể hiện được tình yêu nước của chú. Chú yêu tiếng nói của mình. Chú thấy thương và thắc mắc ko biết những con chim bồ câu của nước Pháp kia có phải hót bằng tiếng Đức không nữa. Đó chính là sự yêu nước yêu tiếng Pháp mà bấy lâu nay mới dâng chào của chú bé."},{"question":"Wat is een Eustala conchlea?","answer":"Eustala conchlea is een spinnensoort in de taxonomische indeling van de wielwebspinnen (Araneidae). Het dier behoort tot het geslacht Eustala. De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort werd voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1888 door Henry Christopher McCooki. "},{"question":"Uzupełnij paragraf: Kołczak początkowo nie ufał Kappelowi, gdyż ten był wcześniej związany z tworzonym przez eserowców Komuczem. Stosunek admirała do Kappela zmienił się na początku 1919 r., wtedy też Kappelowi powierzono dowodzenie 1 Korpusem Wołżańskim, częścią Armii Zachodniej dowodzonej przez gen. Michaiła Chanżyna. W tym charakterze Kappel brał udział we","answer":"wiosennej ofensywie wojsk Kołczaka, której był przeciwny, argumentując, że jego siły powinny ruszyć do generalnej ofensywy dopiero po przeprowadzeniu pełnej mobilizacji i w koordynacji sił z innymi formacjami białych (Siłami Zbrojnymi Południa Rosji gen. Antona Denikina i oddziałami gen. Nikołaja Judenicza). Podczas ofensywy, w walkach pod Ufą w pierwszej połowie marca, wykazał się osobistą odwagą. Ofensywa wiosenna do końca kwietnia odniosła znaczne sukcesy, następnie jednak została odparta, a biali zmuszeni do wycofania się na Ural. Podczas kontrofensywy czerwonego Frontu Wschodniego korpus Kappela został skierowany na pomoc głównym siłom Zachodniej Armii pod Belebejem, zanim został w pełni sformowany i wyszkolony. Został tam zaatakowany przez przeważające siły Armii Turkiestańskiej oraz część jednostek czerwonej 1 Armii pod dowództwem Gai Gaja i poniósł klęskę. Znaczna część żołnierzy Kappela, wziętych do niewoli czerwonoarmistów zmuszonych do walki po stronie białych, zdezerterowała i wróciła na stronę czerwonych. Po serii sukcesów czerwonych na Uralu w 1919 r. (operacje złatoustowska, permska i jekaterynburska) i nieudanej kontrofensywie pod Czelabińskiem armia Kołczaka nigdy już nie odzyskała inicjatywy."},{"question":"Ibùdó Òfurufú Akáríayé","answer":"Ibùdó Òfurufú Akáríayé (International Space Station; ISS) je ile iwadi to je ti kariaye to n je sisopo ni oju-ona ayipo Aye nisale. Won bere si ni ko si oju-ona ayipo ni 1998 eto sini pe yio pari ni opin 2011. Ireti ni pe ibudo oko na yio sise titi di odun 2015, o si se e se ko di 2020. Nitoripe ipo re ju ibudo ofurufu yiowu tele lo, ISS se ri lati Aye pelue oju korokoro, be si, títí di 2010, ohun ni ateleyin oniseowo titobijulo to n yipo Aye."},{"question":"Sheeg magalada uu ku dhashe maxamed siyad bare ?","answer":"Wuxu ku dhashay magalada gal Bahare ee gobolka gado. "},{"question":"Kinsa ang misulay kang Job ug unsa ang iyang tibuok nga gisalig?","answer":"Si Satanas misulay kang Job, ug si Job nagtinuod sa iyang pagtuo sa Diyos bisan gisaligan siya."},{"question":"Автограф бул ...","answer":"Автограф (грек.— өзүм жазам) — автордун өзү жазган кол жазмасы, каты же өз китебине коюлган колу.Атактуу жазуучулардын чыгармачылыгын изилдөө ишинде автографтын мааниси чоң. Улуу адамдар — коомдук ишмерлер, окумуштуулар, искусство чыгармаларынын классиктери өз автографтарын калтырышат. Алар илим изилдөө институттарында, музейлерде, архивдерде сакталат. Мисалы, кыргыз жазуучуларынан А. Осмонов, М. Элебаев, Ж. Бөкөнбаев сыяктуулардын автографтары Кыргыз ССР илимдер академиясыиын кол жазма фондусунда сакталып турат. Автографтар жазуучулардын чыгармачылык жолун тактоо, көркөм өзгөчөлүгүн аныктоо ишинде, текстологиялык (к.) изилдөөдө чоң жардам берет, сөз чеберлеринин чыгарманы кантип жараткандыгы жөнүндө так маалымат бериши менен да пайдалуу болот."},{"question":"¿Quiénes son los mejores boxeadores en la historia de Cuba?","answer":"Cuba tiene una rica tradición en el boxeo y ha producido numerosos boxeadores de clase mundial a lo largo de su historia. Algunos de los boxeadores cubanos más destacados en la historia del boxeo incluyen:1. Teófilo Stevenson: Stevenson es ampliamente considerado como uno de los mejores boxeadores cubanos y uno de los mejores pesos pesados aficionados de todos los tiempos. Ganó tres medallas de oro olímpicas en 1972, 1976 y 1980 y se convirtió en un ícono del boxeo cubano y del amateurismo en el deporte.2. Félix Savón: Savón es otro destacado boxeador cubano que compitió en la categoría de peso pesado. Ganó tres medallas de oro olímpicas en 1992, 1996 y 2000, al igual que Stevenson, y es considerado uno de los mejores boxeadores aficionados de todos los tiempos.3. Guillermo Rigondeaux: Rigondeaux es un boxeador cubano que ha tenido éxito tanto en el boxeo amateur como en el profesional. Ganó dos medallas de oro olímpicas en 2000 y 2004 en la categoría de peso gallo, y luego se convirtió en campeón mundial en el boxeo profesional en varias divisiones."},{"question":"Misy rambo ve ny bitro voalavo :1- eny2- tsia","answer":"1- tsia . Tsy misy rambo ny bitro voalavo ."},{"question":"Ọlọpaa ṣawari awọn ọmọde mẹwaa ti wọn loyun ni Mowe, obinrin kan lo n ta awọn ọmọ ti wọn ba bi","answer":"Ile kan wa lagbegbe Ọfada si Mowe, ni ipinlẹ Ogun, awọn ọmọbinrin tọjọ ori wọn ko ju mejidinlogun si mẹrinlelogun lọ ni wọn n ṣabiyamọ nibẹ, ti iya kan ti wọn pe orukọ ẹ ni Florence Ogbonna si n ta awọn ọmọ ti wọn ba bi, to n fowo ẹ ṣararindin.Awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun lo jẹ ki aṣiri ohun ti wọn n ṣe ninu ile naa tu lọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu kejila, ọdun yii.  Wọn ya bo ile naa lẹyin ti olobo ta wọn, nibẹ ni wọn si ti ko awọn ọmọdebinrin mẹwaa ti wọn ṣe ikun kinrindin pẹlu oyun jade.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gẹgẹ bi CP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi to fi iṣẹlẹ naa sita ṣe wi ni pe iya ti wọn n pe ni Florence Ogbonna yii maa n lọọ ko awọn ọmọdebinrin ọlọmọge wa lati awọn ipinlẹ bii, Imo, Abia ati Ebonyi. Yoo sọ fawọn obi wọn labule pe iṣẹ wa l’Ekoo toun yoo fi wọn si, ko si ni i pẹ tawọn ọmọ naa yoo fi maa fowo ranṣẹ si wọn. N lawọn obi yoo ba yọnda awọn ọmọ wọn fun un.Ṣugbọn nigba to ba ko wọn de ile rẹ ni Mowe tan, ọkunrin alaabọ ara kan to mọ bi wọn ṣe n ba obinrin sun daadaa ni yoo maa ba awọn ọmọdebinrin naa sun, wọn ko ni i ṣiṣẹ kan ju ibalopọ lọ.Oyun ni yoo gbẹyin ibasun, ọmọ ni wọn yoo fi bi gẹgẹ bi alukoro ṣe wi. Ṣugbọn ki i ṣe pe wọn yoo maa tọju ọmọ naa, iya ti wọn n pe ni Florence Ogbonna yii ni yoo ta ọmọ naa fawọn onibaara rẹ to maa n ta wọn fun, yoo gbowo rẹ sapo, yoo si maa ṣe faaji tiẹ lọ.Ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ to ko de lati abule lo bimọ laipẹ yii, Chidera Onuoha lorukọ ọmọge to bimọ naa. Ọmọ to bi ni Florence fẹẹ ta bii iṣe rẹ, niyẹn ba yari pe oun ko le jiya oyun, koun ranju bimọ, kẹnikan waa fẹẹ gba ọmọ naa lọwọ oun, bo ṣe lọọ sọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ nile Florence fọlọpaa niyẹn.Lori iye ti iya yii n ta awọn ọmọ ikoko naa, Chidera sọ pe to ba jẹ ọmọkunrin ni, ẹgbẹrun lọna igba ataabọ (250,000) ni. To ba jẹ obinrin, ẹgbẹrun lọna igba naira (200,000) niyẹn.Ṣugbọn nigba tawọn ọlọpaa de lati mu Florence atawọn ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ to lodi sofin yii, iya naa sa lọ mọ wọn lọwọ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ri ọkunrin alaabọ ara to n fun wọn loyun mu, bẹẹ ni wọn mu ọmọ Florence kan toun naa jẹ obinrin.Yatọ sawọn oloyun mẹwaa ti wọn ba ninu ile yii, awọn ọmọde kan naa wa nibẹ tawọn ọlọpaa tun ko mọ wọn.Wọn ti fi awọn tọwọ ba si ahaamọ, ijẹjọ wọn yoo bẹrẹ laipẹ, bẹẹ ni Florence Ogbonna naa yoo jẹjọ lilo ọmọ nilokulo ati fifi ọmọ ikoko ṣe owo."},{"question":"tohizo ity ohabolana ity: \\"velona iray trano, ...\\"","answer":"ny tohin'ny ohabolana dia hoe: \\"velona iray trano, maty iray fasana\\"."},{"question":"¿Por qué las aves pueden volar?","answer":"Las aves pueden volar debido a una combinación de adaptaciones físicas y comportamientos específicos que les permiten generar sustentación y propulsión en el aire. Aquí están algunas de las razones clave por las cuales las aves pueden volar:1. Estructura esquelética y muscular adaptada: Las aves tienen huesos huecos y ligeros, lo que reduce su peso total y facilita el vuelo. Además, sus músculos de vuelo, como el músculo pectoral mayor, son especialmente desarrollados y se conectan a las alas para permitir el movimiento necesario para batirlas.2. Alas diseñadas para el vuelo: Las alas de las aves están diseñadas de manera única para el vuelo. Tienen una forma aerodinámica que les permite generar sustentación cuando se mueven a través del aire. El ala consta de varias partes, como las plumas, que ayudan a controlar el flujo de aire y la dirección del vuelo.3. Plumas: Las plumas son estructuras clave para el vuelo. Las plumas primarias y secundarias en las alas generan sustentación y permiten el control y la dirección durante el vuelo. Además, las plumas también ayudan a mantener la temperatura corporal y proporcionan protección.4. Huesos fusionados: Las aves tienen huesos fusionados en ciertas áreas, como la cintura pélvica, lo que aumenta la estabilidad durante el vuelo.5. Elevado metabolismo: Las aves tienen un metabolismo alto que les proporciona la energía necesaria para el vuelo. El vuelo requiere un esfuerzo considerable y una gran cantidad de energía para mantener el movimiento y la sustentación.6. Sistema respiratorio eficiente: El sistema respiratorio de las aves, que incluye sacos de aire, permite un flujo constante de aire a través de los pulmones, lo que proporciona un suministro continuo de oxígeno necesario para la alta demanda energética del vuelo.7. Comportamiento de vuelo: Las aves han desarrollado comportamientos de vuelo especializados que les permiten maniobrar, despegar y aterrizar de manera efectiva. Estos comportamientos incluyen planeo, aleteo y aleteo en picado.8. Capacidad de aprendizaje y adaptación: Las aves son capaces de aprender y adaptarse a las condiciones cambiantes del viento y el entorno, lo que les permite volar de manera eficiente y segura.9. Sistema cardiovascular eficiente: El sistema cardiovcardiovascular de las aves también   está adaptado para soportar la demanda de energía durante el vuelo.El corazón de las aves es relativamente grande  y eficiente para bombear sangre rica en oxígeno  a los músculos y otros órganos.En resumen, las aves pueden volar gracias a una combinación de características anatómicas, fisiológicas y comportamentales que les permiten generar sustentación y propulsión en el aire. Estas adaptaciones únicas les han permitido conquistar el cielo y ocupar una amplia variedad de nichos ecológicos en todo el mundo."},{"question":"O que é a teoria do Big Bang?","answer":"A Teoria do Big Bang é um modelo científico que explica a origem e a evolução do universo. De acordo com esta teoria, o universo começou como um ponto extremamente quente e denso, conhecido como \\"singularidade\\", há aproximadamente 13,8 bilhões de anos. A partir desse ponto inicial, o universo começou a expandir-se rapidamente em um evento conhecido como o Big Bang.Esta expansão inicial foi seguida por um resfriamento gradual, permitindo a formação de partículas subatômicas e, eventualmente, átomos simples. Com o tempo, esses átomos se agruparam para formar estrelas e galáxias. A teoria do Big Bang é sustentada por várias evidências observacionais, incluindo a expansão do universo, a radiação cósmica de fundo em micro-ondas (uma espécie de eco do Big Bang), e a abundância relativa de elementos leves como o hidrogênio e o hélio no universo.É importante notar que a teoria do Big Bang não descreve o que ocorreu no momento do Big Bang ou o que poderia ter existido antes dele; ela trata principalmente da evolução subsequente do universo."},{"question":"[Gb] dúró fún:","answer":"Gbágùúdá."},{"question":" शरीराच्या एकूण वजनाच्या किती टक्के वजन रक्ताचे असते?उत्तर :","answer":"8%"},{"question":"ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රූපවාහිනියට දායක වූයේ කෙසේද සහ ඔහුගේ ජනප්‍රිය රූපවාහිනී වැඩසටහන් මොනවාද?","answer":"ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි නළුවෙකු සහ රූපවාහිනී සත්කාරකයකු ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය රූපවාහිනියට සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන්නේය. \\"හපන් පැදුර\\" වැනි ජනප්‍රිය රූපවාහිනී වැඩසටහන් ඉදිරිපත් කළ ඔහු වසර ගණනාවක් ස්වර්ණවාහිනිය හරහා විකාශය වූ \\"මහ සිංහලයේ වංශ කතාව\\" සහ \\"මහ සිංහලයේ යටත් විජිත වංශ කතාව\\" වැනි වැඩසටහන් සංකල්පය සහ ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම නිසා ප්‍රශංසාවට ලක් විය. මීට අමතරව, විවිධ ප්‍රදේශ වල ඉතිහාසය සහ ශිෂ්ටාචාරය හෙළිදරව් කරන \\"ආවාරේ සිරිපා\\", \\"ගඟ දිගේ\\", \\"රෝම පුරාණය\\" සහ \\"සලං හන්තේ\\" වැනි ගවේෂණාත්මක වැඩසටහන් නිර්මාණය කර සත්කාරකත්වය ලබා දුන්නේය. රූපවාහිනියේ ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනිගේ වැඩ කටයුතු ඔහුගේ බහුකාර්යතාව සහ කතන්දර කීමේ හැකියාව පෙන්නුම් කළේය."},{"question":"\\"भर्चुअल वास्तविकता\\" (VR) को अवधारणा र गेमिङ र अन्य उद्योगहरूमा यसको प्रयोगको व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"भर्चुअल रियालिटी (VR) ले हेडसेट र सेन्सरी यन्त्रहरू मार्फत प्रयोगकर्ताहरूलाई सिमुलेटेड वातावरणमा डुबाउँछ। यो इमर्सिभ अनुभवहरूको लागि गेमिङमा प्रयोग गरिन्छ, तर यसले शिक्षा, स्वास्थ्य सेवा, र प्रशिक्षण सिमुलेशनहरूमा पनि अनुप्रयोगहरू फेला पार्छ।"},{"question":"星座の中で、唯一名前に「猫」がつくのは何座でしょう？","answer":"山猫座"},{"question":"බොරුව යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"බොරුව යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය ඇත්ත වේ. "},{"question":"Mengapakah perpaduan penting kepada negara kita yang penduduknya berbilang kaum? ","answer":" Mengukuhkan kerjasama antara kaum. Menjamin kestabilan politik dan sosial. Memakmurkan ekonomi dan keamanan dalam negeri. Menjadi contoh kepada negara luar. Mencapai kejayaan dalam pelbagai bidang. Menjadi negara yang maju dan makmur. Dihormati dan disegani oleh negara lain."},{"question":"Nơi nào đón năm mới đầu tiên trên thế giới?","answer":"Nơi đón năm mới đầu tiên trên thế giới là Đảo Kiritimati, Thái Bình Dương"},{"question":"મને ભૌતિકશાસ્ત્રી નીલ્સ બૉહર વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"નીલ્સ હેન્રિક ડેવિડ બૉહર ડેનીશ ભૌતિકશાસ્ત્રી હતા કે જેમણે ૧૯૨૨નું ભૌતિકશાસ્ત્રનું નોબેલ પારિતોષિક એનાયત થયું હતું. આ પારિતોષિક તેમને પરમાણુના બંધારણ તથા તેમાંથી ઉત્સર્જિત થતા વિકિરણના સંશોધન માટે એનાયત થયું હતું. આધુનિક પારમાણ્વિક સિદ્ધાંતનો પાયો નાખનારાઓમાંના એક તરીકે તેમની ગણના થાય છે. તેમના પુત્ર આગે બૉહરને પણ ૧૯૭૫નું ભૌતિકશાસ્ત્રનું નોબેલ પારિતોષિક એનાયત થયું હતું.હાઈડ્રોજનનો પરમાણુ સૌથી સાદો અને સરળ હોવાથી (કેમે કે તેનો પરમાણુ માત્ર એક પ્રોટોન અને એક ઈલેક્ટ્રૉનનો બનેલો છે) બૉહરે તેને ઉદાહરણ તરીકે લઈને સમજાવ્યું કે, જ્યાં સુધી ઈલેક્ટ્રૉન તેની સૌથી નિમ્ન ઊર્જા-અવસ્થામાં, એટલેકે ધરા-અવસ્થામાં હોય ત્યાં સુધી તે કોઈ ઊર્જાનું ઉત્સર્જન કરતો નથી. પરમાણુમાં આવેલી જુદા જુદા ઊર્જાસ્તર ધરાવતી શક્ય હોય તેટલી બધી કક્ષાઓમાંથી, ઈલેક્ટ્રૉન કોઈ પણ એક કક્ષામાં આવેલો હોય છે. જો પરમાણુને બહારથી ઊર્જા પૂરી પાડવામાં આવે તો ઈલેક્ટ્રૉન, ધરા-અવસ્થા કરતાં કોઈ ઊંચી ઊર્જા ધરાવતી કક્ષામાં કૂદકો મારીને સ્થાનાંતર કરે છે. આ ઈલેક્ટ્રૉન ફરી પાછો મૂળ ધરા-અવસ્થામાં પહોંચે નહિં ત્યા સુધી નિમ્ન ઊર્જા સ્તરોમાં કૂદકા મારતો રહે છે. આમ કરવામાં તે મુખ્યત્વે ઊર્જાનું પ્રકાશના 'ક્વૉન્ટા' (ફોટોન) સ્વરૂપે ઉત્સર્જન કરે છે. આ ક્વૉન્ટાનું પ્રમાણ એટલે કે ઉત્સર્જિત થતા પ્રકાશની તરંગલંબાઈ, ઈલેક્ટ્રૉન જુદા જુદા તબક્કે કૂદકા મારીને પાછો ધરા-અવસ્થામાં જાય, તે બે કક્ષાઓના ઊર્જા સ્તરના તફાવત ઉપર આધારિત હોય છે."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在化學中，什麼是化學平衡常數？","answer":"答案：化學平衡常數是在化學反應達到平衡時，反應物和生成物濃度的比值的常數。它反映了反應在平衡狀態下的相對濃度，可用於計算平衡條件下的物質濃度。"},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labarin don kanun labarai mai zuwa Tsintsiyar APC na neman wargajewa a jihar Kano","answer":"A jihar Kano da ke arewacin Najeriya, rikicin da ya biyo bayan zaben shugabannin jam\`iyyar APC na jihar ya kara jika, bayan kwamitin sauraron korafin zabe ya fayyace bangaren da zai saurari koke-kokensa. Bangarori biyu ne dai suka yi zabe a Kano, wato da tsagin gwamna Ganduje da kuma tsagin senata Ibrahim Shekarau. Amma kwamitin sauraron korafin, wanda hedikwatar jam\`iyyar APC ta kasa ta tura jihar ya ce bangaren da suka yi zabe a filin wasa na Sani Abatcha ne kadai zai saurara, inda tsagin gwamna Ganduje ya yi nasa zaben. Sai dai tsagin shekarau ya ce ko a jikinsa, saboda zaben da ya yi shi ne sahihi. Kwamitin sauraron korafin zaben wanda mista Tony Macfoy ke jagoranta ya bayyana cewa yana aikin ne da umurnin uwar jam\`iyyar APC, don haka albasar sautu ba a yanke mata ganye,  ba shi da  da hurumin sauraron korafin kowa face bangaren da ya yi zabe a filin wasa na Sani Abatcha da ke Kano, wato inda tsagin gwamna Ganduje ya gudanar da nasa zaben. Dr Aminu Waziri dan kwamitin sauraron korafin ne, ya ce duk wanda abin bai masa dadi ba, Indai har ya bi ka'idojin da kundin tsarin mulkin APC ya tanada, na neman wasu mukamai za su saurare su a kuma share musu hawaye. ''Za mu saurari wadanda suka gudanar da zabe a filin wasa na Sani Abatcha da ke kano, idan aka ce mu tattaru a wannan daki kai kuma ka fice ka yi a wani wuri na daban, ai ba ka cikin wadanda suke da karsashin abin da ya faru a dakin,'' in ji shi. Duk da cewa bangarori biyu da  suka yi wannan zabe duka suna ikirarin cewa hedikwatar APC ta kasa ta saka musu albarka kuma da amincewarta suka gudanar da zaben, wannan alkibla da kwamitin sauraron kwarafin zaben jam\`iyyar APCn ya sa a gaba, ta sa wasu na ganin cewa hediwatar jam\`iyyar a fakaice ta yi na\`am da bangaren gwamna Ganduje Kenan. Amma tsagin tsohon gwamnan jihar Kano, Senata Ibrahim Shekarau mai wadansu jiga-jigan APC bakwai, ya ce kan mutanensa a hade yake kuma bas u da korafi ballantana su bukaci mai share musu hawaye don haka can ga su gada, wai zomo ya ji kidan farauta. Honarabul  Sha\`aban Sharada jigo ne daga cikin jiga-jigana ce wannan sun zo karbar korafi amma su ba su da korafi sun gudanar da zabe halattace, kuma sun zabi Alhaji Haruna Zago,  an yi hakan ne tare da ragowar sauran jiga-jigan jam'iyyar APC maza da mata. Wannan ja-ni-in-ja-kan da ake yi a jam\`iyyar APC mai alamar tsintsinya a jihar Kano, ko shakka babu na nuna cewa tsintsiyar ta kama hanyar kuncewa, kuma lamarin ka iya munana idan ta kunce, saboda \`yan Magana kan ce tsintsiyar da ba ta da dauri ba ta shara. Wannan ne ma ya sa wasu magoya bayan jam\`iyyar ke ganin cewa karkata kwamitin sauraron korafin ga wani bangare kadai ba za ta magance matsalar ba, sai  Uwar jam\`iyyar APCn da daina noke-noke, ta hada da lalama ko tausa ga  bangaren da ya dace, kasancewar jihar Kano rumbu ce ta miliyoyin kuri\`u, ga shi har an fara kada gangar zaben 2023. Amma wasu kuma na ganin cewa jam\`iyyar ta san abin da da ta taka saboda wanda ya daure kura shi ya san yadda zai kwance ta."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人工智能如何应用于自动化工业？","answer":"答案：人工智能可以应用于自动化工业中的生产流程控制、故障诊断、优化调度等方面。"},{"question":"Correct the spelling errors in the following statement:“Hawaiian pizza is a pizza originated in Canada and is traditionally topped with pineapple, tomato sauce, cheese, and other types of toppings.”","answer":"Here is the statement with the errors corrected: “Hawaiian pizza is a pizza originating in Canada and is traditionally topped with pineapple, tomato sauce, cheese, and other types of toppings.”"},{"question":"Mbeki Mwalimu","answer":"Mbeki Mwalimu jẹ́ òṣèré ará Kenya, olùdásílẹ̀ àti olùdarí tí ó ju ọdún mẹ̀wá lọ nínú eré ìtàgé àti ìrírí TV. Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ ní ibi ìṣeré ti Kenya ní ọdún 2004 ní Mbalamwezi Players ṣaájú kí ó darapọ̀ mọ́ Festival Of Creative Arts (FCA) ní ọdún 2007 àti pé láti ìgbà náà, ó ti di orúkọ tí a mọ̀ mó ọ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òsèré orí ìtàgé àti eré oníse, olùṣàkóso ìṣelọ́pọ̀, olùdarí eré orí ìtàgé àti olùdásílẹ̀.Ò jẹ́ olókìkí fún àwọn eré orí ìtàgé làárín FCA àti fún ipa rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí Zoe Mackenzie nínú eré Swahili telenovela Selina ní ọdún 2018 lórí Maisha Magic àti pé ó tún se ìfihàn nínú eré <a href=\\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sincerely_Daisy\\" rel=\\"mw:ExtLink\\" title=\\"Sincerely Daisy\\" class=\\"cx-link\\" data-linkid=\\"8\\">Sincerely Daisy</a>, èyítí ó ṣe àfihàn lórí Netflix ní Ọjọ́ kẹ̀sán Oṣù Kẹ̀wá , Ọdún 2020.Ó ti ṣiṣẹ́ bí olùgbékalẹ̀ èto TV ní Kenya Broadcasting Corporation tí ó sì jẹ́ olóòtú èto Good Morning Kenya àti The Ultimate Choir .Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ ìpìlẹ aṣọ ìtàgé rẹ̀ Padà sí ìpìlẹ̀ ní ọdún 2018, pẹ̀lú èrò láti kópa nínú ìdàgbà sókè ìgbésí ayé eré orí ìtàgé ní Kenya.Ó tún jẹ́ ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ ìgbìmọ̀ kan ní Kenya Actors Guild (KAG).Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ The Mbeki Mwalimu Initiative (TMI), ìpìlẹ̀ kan tí ó gbèrò láti yí ìgbésí ayé àwọn ọmọ tó nílò ìrànlọ́wọ́ nípasẹ̀ ìpèse ohun èlò àti ìmọ̀ràn.Ó gba ààmì ẹ̀yẹ Olùdarí eré orí ìtàgé tí ó dára jùlọ ní ọdún 2018 - Ààmì Ẹ̀yẹ Sanaa."},{"question":"நாம் அறிவியலை எமது வாழ்வை பாதுகாக்க கூடிய ஒன்றாகவே பயன்படுத்த வேண்டுமே தவிர அழிவை தரும் விடயங்களை நாம் ஒதுக்கி விடவேண்டும் என்பதை வலியுறுத்தி கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தலைப்பில் ஒரு கட்டுரை வரைக.தலைப்பு: அறிவுக்கு விருந்தாகும் அறிவியல் கட்டுரை","answer":"முன்னுரைமனிதன் என்ற மகத்தான விலங்கு தனது சிந்தனையாலும் கடின உழைப்பாலும் இந்த உலகின் சிறந்தவர்களாக முன்னேறியிருக்கிறார்கள்.இந்த வளர்ச்சிக்கு காரணமாக இருந்தது அறிவியல் என்றால் யாராலும் மறுப்பதற்கில்லை இயற்கையினையும் பிற சக்திகளையும் கண்டு வியந்து கொண்டிருந்த மனிதன் எப்போது சிந்திக்கவும் புதிய விடயங்களையும் உருவாக்கவும் கற்று கொண்டானோ அன்றில் இருந்து பாரிய மாற்றங்கள் இந்த உலகில் உருவாக துவங்கின.அறிவியலின் ஆரம்பம்மனிதன் ஆதிகாலங்களில் காடுகளையே வீடுகளாக கொண்டான் சக விலங்குகளோடு போராடியே தனது வாழ்வை கழித்தான் இயற்கையின் கடினங்களுக்கு ஈடுகொடுத்து போராடினான். வேட்டையாடியும் மீன்பிடித்தும் தனது உணவை அவன் பெற்று கொண்டான். அந்த உணவை வேகவைக்காமலே அவன் உண்டான் பின்பு ஒரு நாளில் கல்லோடு கல்லை உரசி நெருப்பை உருவாக்க கற்று கொண்டான் இதுவே மனிதனது அறிவியலின் ஆரம்பமாக ஆய்வாளர்களால் அறியப்பட்டது.கைத்தொழில் புரட்சிபடிப்படியாக மனிதன் முன்னேறி வருகையில் மனித வராற்றில் ஒரு மிகப்பெரிய திருப்பமாக கைத்தொழில் புரட்சியானது இங்கிலாந்தில் இடம்பெற்றது. அதாவது மனித உழைப்புக்கு மாறாக இயந்திரங்களின் உதவியுடன் மனிதன் உற்பத்தி துறைகளில் பல தயாரிப்புக்களை செய்ய துவங்கினான். இந்த வளர்ச்சியானது அபரிமிதமான தொழில்நுட்பங்களை விவசாயம் போக்குவரத்து உணவுஉற்பத்தி என பல்வேறு துறைகள் உலகமெங்கும் சடுதியான வளர்ச்சியினை பெற துவங்கின இதுவே இன்றைய நவீன உலகத்தின் உருவாக்கத்துக்கு காரணமாக அமைந்தது எனலாம்.உலகினுடைய மாற்றம்மனிதன் தனது கற்றல் மற்றும் அனுபவங்கள் வாயிலாக இந்த உலகத்தை மாற்ற துவங்கினான். கற்றல் மற்றும் கற்றுகொடுத்தல் ஆகிய விடயங்கள் இந்த உலகை இன்னும் ஒரு படி முன்னேற்றமடைய செய்தது. உலகையே மாற்றிய பெருமை அறிவியல் ஞானிகள் மற்றும் அவர்கள் மேற்கொண்ட அறிவியல் கண்டு பிடிப்புகளையே சாரும். மின்சாரம், மின்குமிழ், வானொலி, தொலைபேசி, ஆகாயவிமானம், மோட்டார் என பற்பல தொழில்நுட்ப கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் இந்த உலகையே மாற்றின.இன்றைய உலகம்இன்று மனிதர்கள் எந்த கடினங்களும் இன்றி இலகுவாக வாழவும் சம்பாதிக்கவும் காரணம் நமது முன்னோர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களுடைய மகத்தான கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் தான் என்றால் மிகையல்ல. தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் அபரிமிதமான வளர்ச்சி எந்த சவால்களையும் சமாளிக்கும் அசாதாரண மனிதர்களாக இன்று எம்மை மாற்றியிருக்கிறது. இதற்கு தகுந்தாற்போல இயற்கை மாசடைவுகளை தந்திருப்பது யாராலும் மறுக்க முடியாத ஒன்றாகும்.முடிவுரைஒவ்வொரு தாக்கத்திற்கும் சமனும் எதிருமான மறுதாக்கம் உண்டு என்ற நீயுட்டனின் விதிக்கு அமைய மனிதனது அறிவியல் வளர்ச்சி ஒரு புறம் அதன் கடின விளைவுகள் நாம் வாழும் பூமியை வாழ முடியாத ஒர் இடமாகவும் மாற்றி வருவது ஆபத்தானது. ஆகவே நாம் அறிவியலை எமது வாழ்வை பாதுகாக்க கூடிய ஒன்றாகவே பயன்படுத்த வேண்டுமே தவிர அழிவை தரும் விடயங்களை நாம் ஒதுக்கி விடவேண்டும்."},{"question":"Закончи предложение: Командовал в 1778 году","answer":"при Сент-Люсии, где умело отразил нападение превосходящей по силам (12 кораблей против 7) французской эскадры д’Эстена."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න.කදුලු තිබුනාද මාවතේරුදුරු හන්දාම ජීවිතේ","answer":"කදුලු තිබුනාද මාවතේරුදුරු හන්දාම ජීවිතේවතුර හෙව්වාද හාමතේපැදුරු නැති රෑක නිදිමතේඅපි පාවෙන ලෝකේඇවිදින චාරිකාවේදවසක පාවේදෝ අහසේහද අල්ලන් ආස ගමනේපුරන් වූ දාක ආදරේපුරන් වූවාද ජීවිතේපහස දැනුනාම තනිකමේදෙබස් ඇහුනාද හදවතේඅපි පාවෙන ලෝකේඇවිදින චාරිකාවේදවසක පාවේදෝ අහසේහද අල්ලන් ආස ගමනේසතුට හෙව්වාට දස අතේකදුලු ආවාද හිතුමතේනොමැති වූ දාක කැමති දේඅදුර ගත්තා ද හිත අපේඅපි ආගිය පාරේඑනවද නෑ පේන මානේදවසක පාවේදෝ අහසේහද අල්ලන් ආස ගමනේඅපි පාවෙන ලෝකේඇවිදින චාරිකාවේදවසක පාවේදෝ අහසේහද අල්ලන් ආස ගමනේ"},{"question":"Marina sa diso, biby mitovy ihany ny ondry sy ny osy.","answer":"Tsia, tsy marina io fanambarana io. Tsy biby mitovy ihany ny ondry sy ny osy."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Soi kèo nhà cái Liverpool vs Strasbourg. Nhận định, dự đoán bóng đá Giao hữu CLB (01h30, 1/8). Dự đoán bóng đá Liverpool vs Strasbourg. Tỷ lệ kèo Giao hữu CLB. Tỷ lệ kèo, keonhacai, soi kèo nhà cái, nhận định bóng đá hôm nay 1/8, 2/8Tỷ lệ kèo, keonhacai, soi kèo nhà cái, nhận định bóng đá hôm nay ngày 1/8, 2/8. Tỷ lệ kèo nhà cái, dự đoán bóng đá giao hữu CLB, EURO nữ 2022, Siêu cúp Pháp. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});  Giao hữu CLB * 23h00, 31/7: Marseille vs Milan Xem trực tiếp Marseille vs Milan Soi kèo, nhận định Marseille vs Milan * 01h30, 1/8: Liverpool vs Strasbourg Xem trực tiếp Liverpool vs Strasbourg  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});   Nhận định Liverpool vừa có chiến thắng trước Man City. Đội quân của Klopp có chiến thắng 3-1 trước ĐKVĐ Anh để qua đó giành Siêu cúp Anh. Đó cũng là trận thắng thứ 3 trong 5 trận gần nhất. Ở loạt giao hữu mùa Hè trước đó, Liverpool đã có 2 chiến thắng và 2 trận hòa. Điều đáng ghi nhận từ Liverpool đó là việc tân binh Darwin Nunez đã càng chơi càng cho thấy sự hòa nhập. Anh mang về 1 quả 11m để Salah ghi bàn, rồi tự mình ấn định tỷ số 3-1 cho The Kop. Đó có thể coi là một tín hiệu đáng mừng đối với Lữ đoàn đỏ. Strasbourg đang có phong độ không cao. Họ chỉ thắng 2 trong 5 trận gần nhất. Vì lẽ đó, thật khó để Strasbourg có thể ngăn Liverpool chiến thắng, dù trận này Klopp nhiều khả năng sẽ sử dụng đội hình hai. * Đội hình dự kiến: Liverpool: Hughes; Gomez, Konate, Van den Berg, Milner; Jones, Morton, Keita; Carvalho, Nunez, Elliott. Strasbourg: Sels; Dagba, Djiku, Perrin, Nyamsi, Delaine; Sissoko, Bellegarde; Thomasson; Ajorque, Diallo. - Đối đầu: Hai đội chưa gặp nhau  - Phong độ Liverpool  - Phong độ Strasbourg:   * Dự đoán của TT&VH: Liverpool 3-1 Strasbourg  T.G","answer":"Soi kèo nhà cái Liverpool vs Strasbourg. Nhận định, dự đoán bóng đá Giao hữu CLB (01h30, 1/8)"},{"question":"إذا كانت 'حسنا , لقد كان الامر مثيرا للاهتمام' صحيحة فإن 'لقد كان مثيرا للاهتمام جدا .' صحيحة؟ صح أم خطأ؟","answer":"صح، الجملتان تدلان على الإهتمام بشيء معين."},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් ගම් කාරයා  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කුඹුරේ අයිතිකරු"},{"question":"Жапон эли жөнүндө факты жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Урушуп жатканда, жаман сөздөр менен урушушпайт, жөн гана үнүн жоон кылып эмоция менен билдиришет. "},{"question":"Describe Nigeria.","answer":"Nigeria is a country in West Africa. It is the most populous country in Africa, with a population of over 220 million people. Nigeria is bordered by Benin to the west, Cameroon to the east, Chad to the north, and Niger to the north-east. The Gulf of Guinea lies to the south of Nigeria."},{"question":"Hoe heet het beroemde schilderij van Vincent van Gogh dat hij maakte van een herinnering aan het uitzicht vanuit ziekenhuiskamer? ","answer":"Het beroemde schilderij is de sterrennacht."},{"question":"Inona no dikan'ny teny hoe \\"devinette\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy?","answer":"Ny teny hoe \\"devinette\\" dia midika hoe \\"ankamantatra\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy."},{"question":"पृथ्वीले एक पटक सूर्यको परिक्रमा गर्न कति समय लगाउँछ ?","answer":"३६५ दिन ५ घण्टा ५९ मिनेट १६ सेकेण्ड"},{"question":" Iza no renivohitr'i Espaina?","answer":" Ny renivohitr'i Espaina dia Madrid."},{"question":"Na mitologia egípcia quem é Sokar?","answer":"Relacionado com a morte, era um deus funerário."},{"question":"வினா:  குப்பைக்கீரையின் மருத்துவப் பயன்கள்களைக் குறிப்பிடுக.   ","answer":" விடை:  குப்பைக்கீரையின் மருத்துவப் பயன்கள்:-பெயரை மட்டுமே நினைத்து எந்த முடிவுக்கும் வந்துவிட முடியாது.. வந்துவிடவும் கூடாது.. மருத்துவமும், மகத்துவமும் இரண்டும் ஒருசேர அமைந்துள்ளதுதான் குப்பைக்கீரை.எங்கும் பரவலாகவும், இயல்பாகவும் கிடைக்கக்கூடியது இந்த கீரை.. சிவப்பு நிறத்தில் இதற்கு பூக்கள் இருக்கும். இந்த கீரையின் பெயர் குப்பை கிடையாது.. குப்பைகளில் வளர்ந்தாலும், குப்பை போன்ற உடம்பை தேற்றுவதால்தான், குப்பைகீரை என்று பெயர் வந்ததாம். குப்பைகீரைக்கு முள்ளிக்கீரை என்ற பெயரும் உண்டு. குப்பைகீரையானது தண்டுக்கீரை வகையைச் சார்ந்த கீரை வகையாகும்.வைட்டமின்கள் A, C சத்துக்கள் உள்ளதால், நோயெதிர்ப்பு செயல்பாடு சற்று அதிகமாகவே இதில் இருக்கும்.. தோல் ஆரோக்கியம் பாதுகாக்கப்படுகிறது. கண் பார்வை கூர்மையாகின்றது. உடற்சூடு தணியும்.. சொறி சிரங்குகள் அகலும்.. நுரையீரல் தொடர்பான பிரச்சனைகள்  நீங்கும். வயிற்றுப் புண்ணையும், வாய்ப்புண்ணையும் ஆற்றும்.இந்த இலைகளில் இரும்புச்சத்து, கால்சியமும் அபரிமிதமாகவே நிரம்பு உள்ளன.. ரத்தசோகை உள்ளவர்கள், அடிக்கடி இந்த கீரையை சாப்பிட்டால், ஹீமோகுளோபின் பிரச்சனை தீரும்.. அதேபோல, பற்களுக்கும், எலும்புகளுக்கும் பலத்தையும், ஆரோக்கியத்தையும் தருகிறது இந்த குப்பைக்கீரை. ஆன்டிஆக்ஸிடன்ட்கள் நிறைய உள்ளதால், வயதான தோற்றம் தள்ளிப்போடப்படுவதுடன், இளமையான தோற்றத்தை நீடிக்க வைக்கிறது.அளவுக்கு அதிகமான நார்ச்சத்துக்களை கொண்ட கீரை இதுவாகும்.. மலச்சிக்கல் இருந்தாலே, கீரையைச் சாப்பிடச் சொல்வார்கள்.. ஆனால், இந்த கீரையோ, செரிமானத்திற்குப் பேருதவி புரிவதுடன், ஆரோக்கியமான குடலையும் பராமரிக்க உதவுகிறது.உடலிலுள்ள தேவையில்லாத கெட்ட கொழுப்பைக் கரைத்து, உடல் எடையைக் குறைக்க இந்த கீரைகள் உதவுகின்றன.. தொடர்ந்து இந்தக் கீரையை சாப்பிடும்போது நரம்பு மண்டலம் வலுப்பெறும். நரம்புத் தளர்ச்சியும் நீங்கும்.. சிறுநீர் நன்றாகப் பிரியும். உடலில் கட்டிகள், தழும்பு, மரு, முகப்பரு இருந்தாலும், இந்தக் கீரையை அரைத்து தடவினால் கட்டிகள் கரைந்துவிடும். அதேபோல, உடலில் எங்காவது வீக்கம் ஏற்பட்டாலும், இந்தக் கீரையுடன் மஞ்சள் சேர்த்து அரைத்துப் பூசினால் வீக்கம் குறைந்துவிடும். விஷ ஜந்துக்களான பாம்பு மற்றும் தேள் கடிக்கு விஷ முறிவு மருந்தாக பேருதவி புரிந்து உயிரைக் காக்கிறது இந்த குப்பை கீரை."},{"question":"ディズニーアニメ「ピノキオ」でピノキオが飲み込まれた大きな生き物といえば何？","answer":"クジラです。"},{"question":"Một đoàn tàu rời London (Anh) để đi Paris (Pháp) với vận tốc 100 km/giờ. 30 phút sau, đoàn tàu khác rời Paris để đến London với vận tốc 50km/giờ. Biết hai thành phố cách nhau 200 km, hỏi khi hai đoàn tàu gặp nhau, tàu nào cách London xa hơn?","answer":"Các dữ kiện về vận tốc hai tàu cũng như khoảng cách giữa hai thành phố nhằm gây nhiễu thông tin. Khi hai đoàn tàu gặp nhau, chúng cùng cách thành phố London cùng một khoảng cách."},{"question":"క్రింది అంశాన్ని చదివి ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానము వ్రాయుము.ఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ – అత్యంత విష పదార్థముఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ ఆకులు రాలిపోయేలా చేసి మొక్కల్ని చంపే విషం. నారింజ పట్టి ఉన్న డ్రమ్ములలో నిల్వ చెయ్యటం వల్ల దానికి ఆ పేరు వచ్చింది. 1961 – 1971 మధ్య కాలంలో అమెరికా కార్గో యుద్ధ విమానాలు వియత్నాంపై 500 లక్షల లీటర్ల ఈ విషపూరిత రసాయనాన్ని చల్లాయి. అడవులను, పొలాలను నిర్మూలించటం ద్వారా ప్రజలు దాక్కోటానికి అవకాశం లేకుండా చేసి వాళ్ళని తేలికగా చంపొచ్చన్నది అమెరికా ప్రణాళిక. దేశంలోని 14 శాతం సాగుభూమి ఈ విషపూరిత రసాయనం వల్ల ప్రభావితం అయ్యింది. దీని ప్రభావం చాలా తీవ్రంగా ఉంది. ఈనాటికి కూడా ప్రజలపై దాని ప్రభావం ఉంది. ఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ లోని రసాయనిక అంశమైన డై ఆక్సిన్ పిల్లల మెదడు దెబ్బ తినటానికి, క్యాన్సర్ కి కారకం. ఈ మందు పిచికారీ చేసిన ప్రాంతాలలో పిల్లలలో అవయవ లోపాలు అధికంగా ఉండటానికి ఈ విషమే కారణమని ఒక అధ్యయనం వెల్లడి చేసింది.రసాయనిక ఆయుధాలతో సహా అమెరికా జోక్యంలో భాగంగా (ప్రధానంగా పౌరులను లక్ష్యంగా చేసుకుని) వియత్నాంపై వేసిన బాంబుల మొత్తం బరువు రెండవ ప్రపంచ యుద్ధకాలం మొత్తంలో కంటే ఎక్కువ.ప్రశ్నలు:1) ఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ అనగానేమి?2) ఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ పిల్లలపై ఏ రకమైన ప్రభావాన్ని చూపుతుంది?3) అడవులను, సాగుభూమి పొలాలను రసాయనాలు చల్లటం ద్వారా ఎందుకు నిర్మూలించారు?4) అమెరికా దేశము పైరులపైన, అడవుల పైన కాలుష్య రసాయనాలను ప్రయోగించడం సమర్థనీయమని నీవు భావిస్తావా?","answer":"ఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ అనగా ఆకులు రాలిపోయేలా చేసి మొక్కలను చంపే విషపదార్థము.పిల్లల మెదడు దెబ్బతినడానికి, క్యాన్సర్ వ్యాప్తికి మరియు అవయవలోపాలకు ఏజెంట్ ఆరెంజ్ కారణమౌతుంది.అడవులను, పొలాలను నిర్మూలించడము ద్వారా ప్రజలు దాక్కోవడానికి అవకాశం లేకుండా చేసి వాళ్ళను తేలికగా చంపడానికి.సమర్థనీయము కాదు."},{"question":"Ijamba ọkọ tun gbẹmi awọn meji n’Ikarẹ Akoko","answer":"Eeyan meji ni wọn tun padanu ẹmi wọn sinu ijamba ọkọ to waye lagbegbe Ọkọrun, niluu Ikarẹ Akoko, laaarọ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Ijamba ọkọ yii waye nibi kan naa ti ọkọ ajagbe ti tẹ awọn mẹjọ pa, ti ọgọọrọ awọn eeyan si tun fara pa lọjo diẹ sẹyin.ALAROYE gbọ pe awakọ ayọkẹlẹ Nissan Primera kan ni lo padanu ijanu ọkọ rẹ lasiko to n sọkalẹ lori oke nla to wa lagbegbe naa, to si lọọ kọlu awọn meji to wa lori ọkada Bajaj ati ẹni kan to n rin lọ lẹgb€ẹ ọna.Loju ẹsẹ lawọn meji ti ku, ti ẹni kẹta wọn si wa nibi to ti n gba itọju lọwọ nileewosan Ijọba to wa n’Ikarẹ Akoko.Wọn ni awakọ yii kọkọ yọ ori jade lẹyin to ṣakiyesi pe ijanu ọkọ oun ko ṣiṣẹ mọ, to si n ke tantan kawọn eeyan le ya kuro lọna, ṣugbọn ko ṣẹni to mọ itumọ ohun to n sọ titi ti ọkọ yii fi mu ẹni meji balẹ, ko too pada duro.Oku awọn eeyan ọhun ṣi wa ni mọsuari ileewosan ijọba niluu Ikarẹ lasiko ta a fi n ko iroyin yii jọ lọwọ."},{"question":"දෙවැනි ලෝක යුද්ධයේදී , හිට්ලර්ගේ ජයග්‍රහණයේ උච්චතම අවස්ථාව වූ ප්‍රංශය යටත්කරගැනීම සිදුවූයේ කුමන වසරේද ?","answer":"දෙවැනි ලෝක යුද්ධයේදී , හිට්ලර්ගේ ජයග්‍රහණයේ උච්චතම අවස්ථාව වූ ප්‍රංශය යටත්කරගැනීම සිදුවූයේ 1940 වසරේදී ය."},{"question":"س297- ما الإسم الحقيقي لبيليه نجم الكرة البرازيلي ؟","answer":"ج297- أديسون أريتس"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bendera putih\\"? Berilah contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengaku kalah. Contohnya, tentera musuh terpaksa mengibarkan bendera putih kerana tidak sanggup menentang serangan kerajaan Melaka yang hebat itu."},{"question":"لدينا الجملة التالية: عشرات الجرحى في احتجاجات على مشروع لأنبوب نفط في الولايات المتحدة #سبوتنيك #فلسطين #القدس. هل هي ساخرة أم غير ساخرة؟","answer":"الجملة السابقة غير ساخرة."},{"question":"Inona amin'ireto karazana zavaboary ireto no tsy tao anatin'ny finoana nentim-paharazana malagasy?1. Lolo2. Angatra3. Demony4. Avelo","answer":"Valiny 3 - Ny demony dia karazana zavaboary tsy tao anatin'ny finoana netim-paharazana malagasy. Ny demony dia karazana zavaboary avy tamin'ny finoana kristianina ka nampidirina tao anatin'ny kolontsaina malagasy."},{"question":"Chọn từ “âm”, “dương” thích hợp cho (?)a) Tích ba số nguyên âm là một số nguyên (?);b) Tích hai số nguyên âm với một số nguyên dương là một số nguyên (?);c) Tích của một số chẵn các số nguyên âm là một số nguyên (?);d) Tích của một số lẻ các số nguyên âm là một số nguyên (?).","answer":"Lời giải:a) Ta có: tích của hai số nguyên âm là một số nguyên dươngMà tích của một số nguyên dương với một số nguyên âm là một số nguyên âmNên tích của hai số nguyên âm với một số nguyên âm là một số nguyên âm.Do đó tích của ba số nguyên âm (chính là tích của hai số nguyên âm với một số nguyên âm) là một số nguyên âm. b) Tích của hai số nguyên âm là một số nguyên dương Nên tích của hai số nguyên âm với một số nguyên dương (chính là tích của hai số nguyên dương) là một số nguyên dương. c) Tích của hai số nguyên âm là một số nguyên dươngVậy tích của một số chẵn các số nguyên âm là một số nguyên dương. d) Tích của ba số nguyên âm là một số nguyên âm (câu a)Vậy tích của một số lẻ các số nguyên âm là một số nguyên âm. "},{"question":"Rabo nawa wasan Shaihu Umar na U. Ladan da D. Lyndersay ya ƙunsa?A)BiyuB)UkuC)HuɗuD)Biyar","answer":"A.Bayani:Rabo Biyu1. Labarin Haihumar Umar, Mutuwar, babansa, aure makau da fatima (wato gyatu matar Umar) makicin Kwatau do sarkin Zagi, washe gisan makaw.2. Rabo na Biyu: Labarin Umar da Abdulkarin da yadda suka fito neman mahaifiyar"},{"question":"Ч. Айтматовдун эң алгачкы чыгармасы кайсы?","answer":"«Газетчи Дзюйо» аттуу эң биринчи аңгемеси 1952-жылы жарык көргөн."},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Inoganhurana nemakwikwi ehurumende eEdmonton Centre, Edmonton Griesbach, Sherwood Park - Fort Saskatchewan, Edmonton Mill Woods, uye Edmonton Riverbend. Mutsara 2: Inoganhurana nemigwagwa yehurumende yeFort Saskatchewan, Edmonton Griesbach, Edmonton Centre - Sherwood Park, Edmonton Mill Woods uye Edmonton Riverbend. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hongu kana kuti kwete?","answer":"Hongu"},{"question":"Ya ake rubuta 66 a Hausa?","answer":"Ana rubutawa kamar haka sittin da shida"},{"question":"Maaluu mọkanlelaaadọta ku lojiji l’Akungba Akoko, n lolowo wọn ba bu sigbe","answer":"Kayeefi lo si n jẹ fawọn eeyan ilu Akungba Akoko, nijọba ibilẹ Guusu Iwọ-Oorun Akoko, lori ohun ṣe iku pa awọn maaluu bii mọkanlelaaadọta nile olowo wọn lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe iṣẹlẹ yii waye lagbegbe ileewe girama A. U. D, ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ alẹ ọjọ naa.Akọroyin wa fidi rẹ mulẹ lati ẹnu araalu kan ta a forukọ bo lasiiri pe igbe nla tawọn eeyan agbegbe naa gbọ ti ọkunrin to ni awọn maaluu ọhun, Ibrahim Saliu, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Baba Saliu, n ke ni wọn fi rọ giiri lọ sile rẹ lati mọ ohun to n pa a nigbe.O ni iyalẹnu nla lo jẹ fawọn eeyan lati ba oku awọn maaluu Fulani ọhun nilẹ rẹrẹẹrẹ ninu ọgba ile rẹ.O ni ọrọ iku awọn maaluu naa ti da jinnijinni nla bo gbogbo awọn araalu Akungba, nitori ibẹru pe o ṣee ṣe kawọn Fulani fẹẹ waa gbẹsan ohun to sẹlẹ naa lara wọn.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, Alalẹ tilu Akungba, Ọba Sunday Ajimọ, ni ilu ti n gbe igbesẹ lati mọ ohun to ṣokunfa iku to pa awọn maaluu ọhun lojiji.Ọba Ajimọ ni oun ti kilọ fun ọkunrin to ni maaluu ọhun lati ma ṣe gbiyanju ati ta a fun ẹnikẹni nitori ilera awọn araalu.O ni ẹnikẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pe o n ta ẹran eyikeyii ninu awọn maaluu ọhun fawọn eeyan ko ni i sai foju wina ofin."},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  Com passagens pelas seleções de base da Itália desde 2014, Bastoni fez sua estreia no time principal da \\"Squadra Azzurra\\" em novembro de 2020, na vitória por 4 a 0 sobre a Estônia. Bastoni foi um dos 26 convocados pelo técnico Roberto Mancini para a disputa da","answer":"Eurocopa 2020."},{"question":"ਸੈਫ਼ ਤੇ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨੇ ਮੇਲ ਕੇ ਸੈਫ਼ੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਬਾਰੇ ਚੱਲੀਆਂ ਆ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਅਫ਼ਵਾਹਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਰਦਾ ਚੁੱਕਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਤ ਤਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨ ’ਚ ਬੱਝਣਗੇ। ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਤੇ ਸੈਫ਼ ਦੀ ਏਜੰਟ ਵਿਨੋਦ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਜ਼ੋਰਾਂ-ਸ਼ੋਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਰੀ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਉਸ ਲਈ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਅਧੂਰੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਕਰੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਹਾਲੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਤਾਰੀਖ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ ਪਰ ਐਨਾ ਤੈਅ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਤ ਤਕ ਇੱਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਣਗੇ।ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਸਮਝ ਗਈ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਇਸ ਰੁਝੇਵਿਆਂ ਭਰੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ’ਚੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਲਈ ਸਮਾਂ ਕੱਢਣਾ ਹੀ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਐਨਾ ਹੀ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਾਹੀ ਖੰਨਾ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਦਬੰਗ-2 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੇ ਆਈਟਮ ਨੰਬਰ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਚਰਚੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਉਹ ਸਲਮਾਨ ਦੀ ਭਰਜਾਈ ਮਲਾਇਕਾ ਅਰੋੜਾ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਹੈ। ਸਲਮਾਨ ਨੇ ਦਬੰਗ-2 ’ਚ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਆਈਟਮ ਨੰਬਰ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਭਾਬੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਚਾਹੇ ਖਤਮ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਮਿਰ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਤੇ ਰਾਣੀ ਮੁਖਰਜੀ ਨਾਲ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਨਵੰਬਰ ’ਚ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸੰਜੇ ਲੀਲਾ ਭੰਸਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਅਗਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਰੋਮੀਓ-ਜੂਲੀਅਟ’ ’ਚ ਵੀ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ, ਰਣਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਾਲ ਮੁੱਖ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਵੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਅਤਿ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਰੌਚਿਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਜੁਲਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਰਣਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਇਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਸੋਨਾਕਸ਼ੀ ਸਿਨਹਾ ਨਾਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਲੁਟੇਰਾ’ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ   ਵਿੱਚ ਮਸ਼ਰੂਫ਼ ਹੈ।ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਮਧੁਰ ਭੰਡਾਰਕਰ ਦੀ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੋਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਉਮੀਦਾਂ ਹਨ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ  ‘ਰੋਮੀਓ-ਜੂਲੀਅਟ’ ਦੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਸੋ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਰੋਮੀਓ-ਜੂਲੀਅਟ ਦੇ  ਮੁੱਖ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਰਣਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"சாதி பேதம் ஒழிவதாலும், மேல் சாதி-கீழ் சாதி ஒழிவதாலும், ஒழிய வேண்டும் என்று கேட்பதாலும் ஒரு தேசியம் கெட்டுப் போகுமானால், சுயராச்சியம் வருவது தடைப்பட்டு போகுமானால் அப்படிப்பட்ட தேசியமும் சுயராச்சியமும் ஒழிந்து நாசமாய்ப் போவது மேல்."},{"question":"නැනෝ තාක්ෂණය ආරම්භ කළ භෞතික විද්‍යාඥයා කවුද?","answer":"නැනෝ තාක්ෂණය ආරම්භ කළේ රිච(ර්)ඩ් ෆයින්මන් (Richard Feynman) නමැති ඇමරිකානු ජාතික භෞතික විද්‍යාඥයා ය."},{"question":"Kala duwananshaha dadka iyo diinta islamka.","answer":"DIINTA ISLAAMKA IYO KALA DUWANAANTA DADKA. Islaamku wuxuu yimi Xilli ay adag tahay in dad kala Aragti duwan ay meel ku wada noolaan karaan.Ma jirin mana dhici karin Qolo aqbali karta in ay dhex daganaadaan dad ka Aragti iyo Diin duwan. Rasuulku scw wuxuu isku dayay in uu Tolkii reer maka  ka dhaadhiciyo kala duwanaanshaha wuxuuna kor iyo hoos ugu sheegay in Afkaarta xaqa ah ee uu la yimi aysan ahayn mid ay ku khasban yihiin inay qaataan. Wuxuuna yiri inagoo kala duwan aan wada noolaano:-‎“لَكُمْ دِينُكُمْ وَلِيَ دِينِ (6)”“Diintiina ayaad leedihiin anigana Diintayda”.\\"وَقُل لِّلَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ اعْمَلُوا عَلَىٰ مَكَانَتِكُمْ إِنَّا عَامِلُونَ (121).“Waxaad ku tiraahdaa kuwa aan rumeyn Risaalada aad waddo u Camal fala sida idinla quman eed doonaysaan,inaguna waxaan u Camal falaynaa sida nala faray”.‎\\"لَا إِكْرَاهَ فِي الدِّينِ ۖ قَد تَّبَيَّنَ الرُّشْدُ مِنَ الْغَيِّ \\"“Is-khasbid xagga Diinta ah ma jiro waayo Hanuunka iyo Baadidu way kala cad yihiin”.‎\\" وَقُلِ الْحَقُّ مِنْ رَبِّكُمْ فَمَنْ شَاءَ فَلْيُؤْمِنْ وَمَنْ شَاءَ فَلْيَكْفُر \\"\\"Xaqu xaga Rabigiin ayuu ka sugnaaday ee kii doona ha rumeeyo kii doonana ha iska diido\\".فَذَكِّرْ إِنَّمَا أَنتَ مُذَكِّرٌ (21) لَّسْتَ عَلَيْهِم بِمُصَيْطِرٍ (22)“Waani oo wax u sheeg adiga mid waaninaya oo kaliya ayaad tahay,wax Khasab ah dushooda kuma lihid. Ilaahay baa raali ka ahaa kala duwanaanshaha oo misana farayay Rasuulkiisa scw. ‎ - وَإِن كَذَّبُوكَ فَقُل لِّي عَمَلِي وَلَكُمْ عَمَلُكُمْ ۖ أَنتُم بَرِيئُونَ مِمَّا أَعْمَلُ وَأَنَا بَرِيءٌ مِّمَّا تَعْمَلُونَ (41).Hadday ku beeniyaan waxaad ku tiraahdaa aniga camalkayga uun baan leeyahay idinkuna camalkiina ayaad leedihiin,idinku shuqul kuma lihidiin oo laydiin raacan maayo waxaan aniga sameynayo,Anigana shuqul kuma lihi oo lay raacan maayo waxa aad idinka samaynaysaan\\".Waa iska caadi waana wax Bani Aadamka oo dhan ku dabeecaysan in ay qolo waliba jeceshahay in iyaga tabac loo noqdo oo qofku wuxuu u xamaasadaysan yahay ee uu Xaq u arko ayuun buu doonayaa in la wada qaato.Rasuulka scw in kasta oo uu Xaq ku sugnaa Rabina hagayay hadana wuxuu Tolkii la jeclaa in ay rumeeyaan oo ay xaqa raacaan arintaasna si aad ah ayuu ugu hamiyi jiray.Ilaahay sareeye wuxuu doonay inuu Rasuulkiisa dareensiiyo in aysan arintaasu ahayn Sunada Rabi ee uu aqbalo kala duwanaanshaha talada iyo hanuunkana uu Eebe udaayo. Waxaana si cad loogu sheegay inuu ku ekaado shaqadiisa gaarsiinta ah oo kaliya. 1‎ان عليك الا البلاغ. Wuxuu kaloo Alle yiri‎وَلَوْ شَاءَ رَبُّكَ لآمَنَ مَنْ فِي الأَرْضِ كُلُّهُمْ جَمِيعًا أَفَأَنْتَ تُكْرِهُ النَّاسَ حَتَّى يَكُونُوا مُؤْمِنِينَ (99)\\"Haddii Alle dooni way rumayn lahaayeen dhamaan dadka Dhulka ku sugan oo dhan ee adigu dadka ma karhaysaa oo ma khasbaysaa ilaa ay Mu’miniin wada noqdaan\\"Wuxuu mar kale Alle yiri:-‎وَإِن كَانَ كَبُرَ عَلَيْكَ إِعْرَاضُهُمْ فَإِنِ ٱسْتَطَعْتَ أَن تَبْتَغِىَ نَفَقًا فِى ٱلْأَرْضِ أَوْ سُلَّمًا فِى ٱلسَّمَآءِ فَتَأْتِيَهُم بِـَٔايَةٍۢ ۚ وَلَوْ شَآءَ ٱللَّهُ لَجَمَعَهُمْ عَلَى ٱلْهُدَىٰ ۚ فَلَا تَكُونَنَّ مِنَ ٱلْجَٰهِلِينَ. \\"Hadday kula weynaatay jeensigooda ay xaqa ka jeensanayaan bal hadaad karto waakaasee Dhulka duleesho ama Samada Sallaan u samayso si aad dadkan Aayad ugu keento ay ku qancaan.  War Haddii Alle dooni dadku hanuunka ayuu ku kulmin lahaa ee ha ka mid noqonin kuwa jaahiliinta ah\\"Walaalayaal sida aan ku arkayno Aayado badan oo Quraan ah Diintu Islaamka waxay qiraysaa in khilaafku daruuri yahay oo uu imanayo lkn loo baahan yahay inaan lagu kala tagin oo laysugu dulqaato oon laysku colaadin. ‎وَلَوْ شَاءَ رَبُّكَ لَجَعَلَ النَّاسَ أُمَّةً وَاحِدَةً وَلَا يَزَالُونَ مُخْتَلِفِينَ (118) إِلَّا مَنْ رَحِمَ رَبُّكَ وَلِذَلِكَ خَلَقَهُمْ وَتَمَّتْ كَلِمَةُ رَبِّكَ لَأَمْلَأَنَّ جَهَنَّمَ مِنَ الْجِنَّةِ وَالنَّاسِ أَجْمَعِينَ (119) Haddii Alle dooni dadku hal Ummad ayuu ka dhigi lahaa'kama suulayaan inay is khilaafaan ilaa in Eebe  u naxariistay mooyee,waayo sidaa ayaaba loo abuuray'waxana  Kalimadda Rabigaa ku dhamaystiran in uu Jahana ka buuxin doono Jini iyo Insi dhamaantood wixii dariiqa khilaafka iyo kala tagga qaada. Mar haddii khilaafku khatartaas leeyahay waxaa haboon in laga digtoonaado in lagu kala tago   Waxaa haboon in laysugu dulqaato kala aragti  duwanaanta taasaana mar kasta laga milicsan karaa isugaynta Nusuusta Diinta ee diidaysa in khilaafka lagu kala tago amaba uu sababo Nacayb iyo gacan ka hadal. Dadka ilaahay baa sidaa u abuuray isaga uun ayaana kala saari doona ee Adiga sidaad fahamtay uun ku soco Adiga oon Adyad gaysan oo Afkaaga iyo Adinkaaga laga Nabad galay. ‎ - قُلْ كُلٌّ يَعْمَلُ عَلَىٰ شَاكِلَتِهِ فَرَبُّكُمْ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ هُوَ أَهْدَىٰ سَبِيلًا (84)Waxaad ku tiraahdaa Qof kasta ha u camal falo siday la tahay toosnaanta,Rabigiin uun baa og midka jidka toosan haya. Waxaa kaloo Quraanka ku badan Aayadaha muujinaya in laysu dulqaato oo khilaafka laysku mari waayay Rabi lala sugo Maalinka uu dadka kala xisaabin doono. ‎ - قُلْ يَجْمَعُ بَيْنَنَا رَبُّنَا ثُمَّ يَفْتَحُ بَيْنَنَا بِالْحَقِّ وَهُوَ الْفَتَّاحُ الْعَلِيمُ (26)Waxaad ku tiraahdaa Rabigayo ayaa na kulmin doona markaas ka dibna Xaqa inagu kala saari doona. ‎ - ثُمَّ إِلَيَّ مَرْجِعُكُمْ فَأَحْكُمُ بَيْنَكُمْ فِيمَا كُنْتُمْ فِيهِ تَخْتَلِفُونَ ﴿٥٥ آل عمران﴾Intaa ka dib xagayga ayaa laydiin celinayaa markaasaan dhexdiina kala xukminayaa wixii aad isku khilaafi jirteen. ‎إِلَى اللَّهِ مَرْجِعُكُمْ جَمِيعًا فَيُنَبِّئُكُمْ بِمَا كُنْتُمْ فِيهِ تَخْتَلِفُونَ .Alle xagiisa ayaa laydiin celinayaa dhamaantiin markaasuu idinkaga warami doonaa wixii aad isku khilaafi jirteen. Walaalayaal waa muhiim inaan wax ku qaadanaa Nusuusta Diinta ee aadka oga tirada badan intan aan tusaalaha usoo qaatay waxay inoo diidan tahay inaan khilaafka ku kala tagno sidaas darteed miyaysan inoo haboonayn inaan inta goori goor tahay garano Maqsadka diinteena oon aqbalno kala duwanaanta Nabada ku dhisan,oo aan isu dulqaadano iskana dayno Nacaybka iyo Colaada. aan waxba inagu soo kordhinaynin wax ay inoo dhinto mooyee."},{"question":"ਏ. ਦਾਲ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਦੋ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਅਵਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦੱਸੋ।ਬੀ. ਦਾਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਸਲ ਦਾ ਮਹੱਤਵ ਦੱਸੋ।c. ਦਾਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਫਸਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਰੋਟੇਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਉਂ ਉਗਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"a ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼, ਰਾਜਸਥਾਨ, ਮਹਾਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ, ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਅਤੇ ਕਰਨਾਟਕ।ਬੀ. ਦਾਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ :ਸ਼ਾਕਾਹਾਰੀ ਭੋਜਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰੋਟੀਨ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਸਰੋਤ।ਫਲੀਦਾਰ ਫਸਲਾਂ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ, ਦਾਲਾਂ ਹਵਾ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਨਾਈਟ੍ਰੋਜਨ ਨੂੰ ਠੀਕ ਕਰਕੇ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਦੀ ਉਪਜਾਊ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ (ਅਰਹਰ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ) ਬਹਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਦਾਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਘੱਟ ਨਮੀ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਖੁਸ਼ਕ ਸਥਿਤੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਬਚੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ।c. ਦਾਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾਤਰ ਹੋਰ ਫਸਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਰੋਟੇਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਗਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਫਲੀਦਾਰ ਫਸਲਾਂ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਦਾਲਾਂ ਹਵਾ ਤੋਂ ਨਾਈਟ੍ਰੋਜਨ ਨੂੰ ਠੀਕ ਕਰਕੇ (ਅਰਹਰ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ) ਮਿੱਟੀ ਦੀ ਉਪਜਾਊ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਬਹਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Iyiphi i-albhamu kaRihhana edayise kakhulu kuyilokhu aqala endimeni yomculo?","answer":"ialbhamu litiGood Girl Gone Bad"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවද අයත්වන , උතුරු ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපයේ ඇතිවන සුළිකුණාටු ( වාසුළි ) හඳුන්වන නම කුමක්ද ?","answer":"නිවර්තන වාසුළි"},{"question":"በጋና ከ1662 እስከ 1949 ዓም የቆየው መንግሥት ምን ተብሎ ይጠራ ነበር?","answer":"በጋና ከ1662 እስከ 1949 ዓም የቆየው መንግሥት የአሻንቲ መንግሥት ተብሎ ይጠራ ነበር"},{"question":"¿Cuál es la nacionalidad de Pablo Neruda?","answer":"El poeta Pablo Neruda nació en Chile. Si quieres saber más sobre este personaje, puedes leer nuestro artículo: “50 frases de Pablo Neruda (con gran valor romántico)”"},{"question":"Sheeg Qofkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Nabiga (NNKH) Salaanta Islaamka Ku Salaama?","answer":"Waxaa La Sheegaa Inuu Yahay Abuu Darr Al Qafaari RC."},{"question":"Hãy viết tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra khi gieo một con xúc xắc 6 mặtA.1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6B.Y = 6C.6D.Y = {1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6}","answer":"Trả lời:Các kết quả có thể xảy ra khi gieo một con xúc xắc 6 mặt là: 1 chấm, 2 chấm, 3 chấm, 4 chấm, 5 chấm, 6 chấm.Vậy tập hợp cần tìm làY = {1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6}Đáp án cần chọn là: D"},{"question":"இப்போதெல்லாம் – இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ……………………………அ) இப்போது + எல்லாம்ஆ) இப்போ + எல்லாம்இ) இப்போதே + எல்லாம்ஈ) இப்போ + வெல்லாம்","answer":"அ) இப்போது + எல்லாம்"},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 中国の四川料理で有名な陳建一さんが、3月11日に亡くなりました。67歳でした。陳さんは、日本に四川料理を広めたと言われている陳建民さんの息子で、父の店で料理を習いました。四川料理はとても辛いので、日本人が食べやすいように、香辛料の使い方などを変えました。特にマーボー豆腐が有名で、日本の「現代の名工」に選ばれました。日本の政府から黄綬褒章ももらいました。陳さんはテレビの料理番組でも人気になりました。NHK「きょうの料理」では日本の家庭でも作りやすいレシピを紹介しました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe vokatra azo averina?","answer":"Ny vokatra azo averina dia vokatra azo averina sy ovaina ho akora hanamboarana vokatra vaovao aorian'ny fampiasana azy, ka manampy amin'ny fampihenana ny fako sy ny fampiasana ny harena voajanahary."},{"question":"Descreva um jantar em família com muitos parentes.","answer":"A casa está cheia de parentes animados e o aroma de comida caseira enche o ar. Mesas compridas estão repletas de pratos tradicionais, desde lasanha e assados até sobremesas caseiras. Risos e conversas preenchem o ambiente, e todos compartilham histórias e laços familiares em uma noite alegre."},{"question":"ايش معنى أكَّه، هَكَّه باللهجة التعزية؟","answer":"معناتها هكذا أو مثل كذا"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Neville Chamberlain. ","answer":"Polaiteoir Briotanach ab ea Arthur Neville Chamberlain, (18 Márta 1869 – 9 Samhain 1940) agus Príomh-aire na Ríochta Aontaithe idir 1937 agus 1940.Bhí saol fada i bpolaitíocht ag Chamberlain, ach bhí deireadh dona aige nuair a bhris amach an Dara Cogadh Domhanda i 1939."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--केळीला नारळी अन घर चंद्रमौळी","answer":"अत्यंत दारिद्र्याची अवस्था येणे."},{"question":"iza no nanatontosa ilay horonantsary \\"2001: l'Odyssée de l'espace\\"?","answer":"i Stanley Kubrick no nanatontosa ilay horonantsary \\"2001: l'Odyssée de l'espace\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam kena kepala\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak dapat berbuat apa-apa lagi；bingung."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : నేటికాలంలో అశోకధర్మం యొక్క ప్రాముఖ్యతను వివరింపుము. అశోకధర్మం యొక్క గొప్పతనాన్ని వర్ణింపుము.","answer":"నేటి కాలంలో అశోకధర్మం యొక్క ప్రాముఖ్యత ఎంతైనా ఉంది.అశోకధర్మం యొక్క ప్రధాన సూత్రాలు :జంతువుల పట్ల దయ కలిగి ఉండాలి.తల్లిదండ్రుల పట్ల విధేయత కలిగి ఉండాలి.పేదల పట్ల సానుభూమి కలిగి ఉండాలి.పెద్దలను గౌరవించవలెను.ఇతర మతాలను విస్మరించరాదు.మానవజాతి సంక్షేమానికి కృషి చేయాలి.అశోకుని ధర్మం ప్రజలకు అనుకూలము ఆచరణీయము అయిన నైతిక సూత్రాలను కల్గి ఉంది.ఉన్నతమైన జీవన విధానాన్ని అందించటమే అశోకుని ధమ్మ ఉద్దేశము.ధర్మాపేక్ష, శ్రద్ధ, విధేయత, పాపభీతి, సామర్థ్యము లేకపోతే ఇహపరలోక సుఖాలను పొందలేరని బోధించాడు.నేటి సమాజంలో వివిధ రూపాలలో జరుగుతున్న ‘హింసకు’ అశోకుని (అహింస) ధర్మము చక్కని పరిష్కారం.అలాగే ‘పరమత సహనం’ అనే సూత్రం నేడు ఎంతో అవసరం. అనేక అల్లర్లకు, హింసకు, యుద్ధాలకు మత మౌఢ్యమే కారణం.ఈ విధంగా అశోకుని క్క గొప్ప ధర్మం నేటికాలంలో ప్రాముఖ్యత కలిగి ఉంది."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgamagi  Xalane, meesha uu ku  dhashay iyo sanadki u dhashay ? ","answer":"Waxa weye Maxamed Cabdulle xalane , wuxu dhashay 1939 dogmada Ceel-buur e gobalka Galgudud. "},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Kto otrzymał Nagrodę Nobla z Literatury w 2007 roku?","answer":"Oto odpowiedź na to pytanie. W 2007. roku Nagrodę Nobla z dziedziny literatury otrzymała Doris Lessing (Wielka Brytania). W uzasadnieniu napisano: \\"jej epicka proza jest wyrazem kobiecych doświadczeń. Przedstawia je z pewnym dystansem, sceptycyzmem, ale też z ogniem i wizjonerską siłą\\"."},{"question":"Apa soalan kepada: \\"Kematiannya menerima reaksi yang bercampur-aduk\\"? Topiknya ialah George O'Malley.","answer":"\\"Apa yang berlaku kepada George O'Malley dalam Grey's Anatomy?\\""},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yaz: Dıbenko Mart 1921'de Mihail Tuhaçevski komutasındaki birliklerle Kronstadt Ayaklanmasının bastırılmasında yer alır. Ayrıca bu dönemde çıkan Tambov Ayaklanması","answer":"'nın bastırılmasında da görev yapar. Başarılarından dolayı Kızıl Bayrak Nişanı ile üç kez ödüllendirilir. Dıbenko devrim öncesinde ve sırasında yaşadıklarına dair çok sayıda eser yazar. Kitaplarındaki yüksek kalite onun gibi eğitim seviyesi düşük birisinin gerçek yazar olmadığına dair şüphelere yol açmıştır. 1922 yılında Genelkurmay Askerî Akademisini bitirir. Bu dönemde Kollontay ile ayrılacaklardır. Dıbenko ayrılık yüzünden intihara kalkışır, Kollontay ise ondan uzaklaşabilmek için yurtdışı elçilik görevi talep ederek ülke dışına çıkar. Dıbenko, Kollontay'dan sonra iki kez daha evlenecektir. Dıbenko Akademiden mezun olduktan sonra yeniden komutanlık görevi alır ve partiye yeniden kabul edilir. 1925 – 1928 yılları arasında Kızılordu Genelkurmay Başkanlığı Topçu ve İstihkam Komutanlığında görev alır. 1928 yılından sonra Orta Asya'da görevlendirilir. Burada sınır birliklerine komuta eder. 1930 yılında görevli olarak diğer subaylarla beraber Almanya'ya gönderilir."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Som komediförfattare gjorde sig Kleist ett namn med \\"Den sönderslagna krukan\\", en pjäs vars genretillhörighet dock varit föremål för diskussion. Den handlar om domaren Adam som steg för steg tvingas tillstå att det är han själv som är förbrytaren. Bland hans övriga dramer märks \\"Die Herrmannschlacht\\", ett historiskt drama inspirerat av slaget i Teutoburgerskogen med åtskilliga referenser till den politiska situationen i Kleists samtid, framför allt Napoleon I:s ockupation av diktarens hemland. Tillsammans med dramat \\"Prins Friedrich von Homburg\\" (om Fredrik II av Hessen-Homburg och Slaget vid Fehrbellin","answer":"), som räknas till hans främsta verk publicerades den först 1821 av Ludwig Tieck i en utgåva med efterlämnade skrifter. \\"Robert Guiskard\\", ett planerat storskaligt drama, blev aldrig mer än ett fragment."},{"question":"دولت تعریف کړئ او له څو قواوو تشکيل شوی ؟","answer":"له حقوقي نظره دولت له هغه سیاسي سازمان څخه عبارت ده چي د جغرافیای ي موقعیت او نړیوالو ټاکلیو سرحدونو لرونکی وي او دیو عالیه قدرت تر ادارې لاندې وي .دولت له دریو قواوو څخه تشکيل شوی .۱- مققنه قوه . ۲- اجرایه قوه . ۳- قضایه قوهدولت یو سیاسي ارګان دی چې د یوې ټاکل شوې خاورې، دایمي نفوس، دولت او د نورو دولتونو سره د اړیکو د ننوتلو وړتیا لري. دا یوه خپلواکه اداره ده چې په خپله خاوره او نفوس باندې کنټرول او حکومتداري کوي، د قانون او نظم ساتنه کوي، د چارو تنظیموي، او په نړیواله کچه د خپلو اتباعو د ګټو استازیتوب کوي. دولت اکثرا په خپلو پولو کې ترټولو لوړ واک ګڼل کیږي، او مشروعیت یې د تاریخي، قانوني، یا اساسي قانون له لارې د حکومت یا تاسیس شوي رضایت څخه اخیستل کیږي. دولت، د دولت د اداري ماشین په توګه، د پالیسیو جوړولو او پلي کولو، د قوانینو پلي کولو او د خپلو اتباعو د هوساینې د تامین مسولیت لري.په یوه دولت کې دننه ځواکونه په پراخه کچه په دوه عمده برخو ویشل کیدی شي: داخلي ځواکونه او بهرني ځواکونه. داخلي ځواکونه دولت، بنسټونه او ادارې د نظم ساتلو، عامه خدماتو وړاندې کولو، او د قانون حاکمیت ساتلو مسولیت لري. پدې کې د قانون پلي کونکي ادارې، قضایي ارګانونه، مقرراتي ادارې او مختلف دولتي وزارتونه شامل دي. بهرني ځواکونه له نړیوالې ټولنې سره د دولت په تعامل کې شامل دي، چې د ډیپلوماتیکو، اقتصادي او نظامي ځواکونو لخوا استازیتوب کیږي. ډیپلوماټیک ځواکونه په بهرنیو اړیکو او خبرو اترو کې ښکیل دي، اقتصادي ځواکونه د نړیوالې سوداګرۍ او سوداګرۍ اداره کوي، او نظامي ځواکونه د ملي دفاع لپاره چمتو کوي. د دې داخلي او بهرنیو ځواکونو ترکیب د یو دولت څو اړخیز جوړښت جوړوي، چې دا توان ورکوي چې په ګډه کار وکړي او په نړیواله ټولنه کې برخه واخلي."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de Uganda?","answer":"Kampala, la capital y ciudad más grande de Uganda, está situada a orillas del lago Victoria, en el centro-sur del país. Tiene 1,6 millones de habitantes y está dividida en cinco regiones. La región central incluye el principal distrito comercial, casinos, hoteles y campos de golf."},{"question":"ప్రవచనం P: sin α = cos β అయిన α + β = 90° (α, β లు అల్పకోణాలు)ప్రవచనం – Q : sec θ = m, tan θ = n అయిన m^2 – 12 = 1 (0° < θ < 90°)(A) P సత్యం, Q అసత్యం(B) P సత్యం, Q సత్యం(C) P అసత్యం, Q సత్యం(D) P అసత్యం , Q అసత్యం .","answer":"(B) P సత్యం, Q సత్యం"},{"question":"What is the color of the most poisonous frog in the world?","answer":"Yellow"},{"question":"எலிசா சோதனை எந்த நோயைக் கண்டறிய உதவும்? \\t1. காலரா2. பிளேக்3. மஞ்சள் காமாலை4. எயிட்ஸ்","answer":"4. எயிட்ஸ்."},{"question":"中国の三国志で劉備に仕えた五虎将軍は関羽、超雲、馬超、黄忠とあと一人は誰でしょう？","answer":"張飛です。"},{"question":"குறியீட்டு உத்தியின் அடிப்படை இலக்கணங்களை எழுதுக.","answer":"குறிப்பாக உணர்த்தும் பொருள் அல்லது சொல் குறியீட்டு உத்தி என்பர். சுட்டிய பொருளுக்கும் குறியீட்டுப் பொருளுக்கும் ஏதேனும் ஒரு தொடர்பு இருத்தல் வேண்டும். சுட்டும் பொருள் என்பது எல்லோரும் அறிந்த ஒன்றாக இருத்தல் வேண்டும். இத்தொடர்பின் வாயிலாகக் குறியீட்டுப் பொருள் நுண்ணிய முறையில் வெளிப்படுத்த வேண்டும். எ.கா. தராசு – நீதி."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ലൂക്ക് സ്കൈവാക്കറെ പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കുന്ന ബുദ്ധിമാനും ശക്തനുമായ ജെഡി മാസ്റ്റർ ആരാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: യോഡ."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Cuba?","answer":"0,764."},{"question":"Tivibu Süper Lig maçlarını veriyor mu?","answer":"Tivibu Spor Uydu Açık Kanalı Frekans Bilgileri:Liglerden heyecan dolu karşılaşmalar Tivibu Süper Paket üyelerine özel Tivibu Spor 2 ve Tivibu Spor 3 kanallarından yayınlanmaktadır. Her hafta farklı liglerden seçilen iki karşılaşma ise Tivibu Spor uydu açık kanalından yayınlanmakatadır."},{"question":"Inona no mety maharatsy ny valin-tanana? ","answer":"Tsy misy maharatsy ny valin-tanana fa ny fisainan’ny olona ankehitriny no mihevitra hoe efa lany andro izy io ka aleony mampiasa ny volany hanatanterahany ny asany ka zary nampihen-danja azy."},{"question":"เวลาหนึ่งโมงเช้าหมายถึงเวลาเท่าไร","answer":"หมายถึงเวลา 7:00 นาฬิกา"},{"question":"මෙම ප්‍රකාශය හරිද වැරදිද?\\"සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ද්‍රවයක උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි වන විට ඝනත්වය වැඩි වන අතර, උෂ්ණත්වය අඩුවිමේදී ඝනත්වය අඩු වේ.\\"","answer":"මෙය වැරදි ප්‍රකාශයකි.උෂ්ණත්වය සහ ඝනත්වය අතර ඇති සම්බන්ධය ප්‍රතිලෝම වේ. එම නිසා නිවැරදි ප්‍රකාශය වනුයේ, \\"සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ද්‍රවයක උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි වන විට ඝනත්වය අඩු වන අතර, උෂ්ණත්වය අඩුවිමේදී ඝනත්වය වැඩි වේ.\\""},{"question":"จงเขียนประโยคที่มีคำว่า \\"นอน\\"","answer":"เขากำลังจะเข้านอน"},{"question":"Ny vanim-potoana ny fanalalahana dia nanomboka ny taona 1991 hatramin'ny 2002.Inona avy ireo vokatra naterak'izany fanalalahana izany teo amin'ny Malagasy?","answer":"Niditra tao anatin'ny repoblika fahatelo i Madagasikara ny taona 1991 saingy nisy tranga goavana nitranga teto amin'ny firenena, dia ny fitakiana fahalalahana izany indrindra ny demokrasia. Ny vokatr'izany teo amin'ny lafiny maro:\\t\\t- niorina tetsy sy tero ireo orinasa afaka haba\\t\\t- niroborobo ny fitrandrahana harena ambanin'ny tany\\t\\t- Nivoatra ny famokarana tao zavatra\\t\\t- fihetseham-bahoaka notarihan'ny hery velona noho ny tsy fihetezam-pitatanana\\t\\t- nihanatanjaka ny hetsi-bahoaka ary nirohitra teny Iavoloha ny vahoaka nitokona(betsaka ireo maty, sy ireo naratra tamin'izany) \\t\\t- may ny rova ny 06 novambra 1996."},{"question":"Who starred as Juno MacGuff opposite Michael Cera in the 2007 film Juno?","answer":"In the film Juno, Elliot Page stars as the title character, an independent-minded teenager confronting her unplanned pregnancy and the subsequent events that put pressures of adult life onto her."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa ilaha laga hello dawada gaar ahaan synthetic sources?","answer":"Waxaa   laga   sameeyaa   waxyaabo   dabiici   ah   ayadoo   loo adeegsanayo sheeybaar Waayadaan  inta   ugu badan   daawada   waa   kuwo   aadanuhu ku sameeyaan hab sheeybaar kudhisan  Synthetic   sources. Waa   marka   daawada   gabi   ahaan   lagu sameeyo  isbadal  sida  bu.da  daawada  iyo  qaab  dhismeedka kiimikada ee daawada. Sami  synthetic  drug.  Waa  markii  aan  daawada  isbadal  aan lagu   sameen   oo   dhanka nucleus   ka   ah   iyo chemical stractureka waxaa kaliya lagu sameeyaa naash naash. Sida   lawada   qabo   daawooyinka   sanaacig   ah   waa   kuwo waxyeelo yar markii loo eego nuucyada ilaha kale ee daawada laga  helo.daawooyinka  sanaaciga  waxa  ay  ka  kooban  yihiin qeeb  waxtar  leh  iyo  kiimikaal  oo  ku  yar.  Dawooyinkaan sanaaciga ah waxaa ugu caansan Aapirin.quaniin. chloromphinecol. "},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"நம் பெண்களை மனித சமுதாயத்திற்குத் தொண்டாற்றவும், புகழ்பெறும் பெண்மணியாக்கவும் வேண்டும். அவர்கள் புது உலகம் சித்தரிக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Ubwino ndi kuipa kwa utsogoleri wachikhalidwe","answer":"Atsogoleri m'dera lililonse amabwera mosiyanasiyana komanso kukula kwake, koma opambana kwambiri amakhala ndi chinthu chimodzi chofanana: amadziwa kutsogolera bwino. Anthu ena angakhale atsogoleri obadwa mwachibadwa, pamene ena angafunikire kuphunzira zingwe asanatenge ulamuliro. Ziribe kanthu kuti mumalowa m'gulu liti, ndikofunikira kudziwa zabwino ndi zoyipa za utsogoleri wachikhalidwe. Kudziwa zomwe zimagwira ntchito - ndi zomwe sizi - kungapangitse kusiyana kulikonse ikafika nthawi yoti mutenge bizinesi kapena bungwe lanu kupita kumalo atsopano.Ubwino wina wa utsogoleri wa chikhalidwe ndi chiyani?Ubwino wina wa utsogoleri wa chikhalidwe ndi monga:1. Atsogoleri omwe amaphunzitsidwa mwachikhalidwe amadziwa momwe angayendetsere machitidwe ovuta ndikupanga zisankho zovutaUbwino umodzi wa utsogoleri wachikhalidwe ndikuti iwo omwe adachita maphunziro a utsogoleri wachikhalidwe amadziwa momwe angayendetsere machitidwe ovuta. Amamvetsetsa kufunikira kopanga zisankho zolimba ndipo nthawi zambiri amakhala ndi chidziwitso chothandizira zisankhozi. Chotsatira chake, amatha kupereka bata ndi chitsogozo panthawi zosatsimikizika kapena kusintha.2. Atsogoleri achikhalidwe nthawi zambiri amalemekezedwa kwambiri ndi otsatira awoUbwino wina wa utsogoleri wa chikhalidwe ndi woti iwo omwe ali ndi maudindo nthawi zambiri amalemekezedwa kwambiri ndi otsatira awo. Ulemu umenewu umachokera pa luso la mtsogoleri kupanga zisankho zomveka, komanso luso lawo ndi nzeru. Anthu amathanso kukhulupirira ndi kumvera mtsogoleri yemwe adaphunzitsidwa mwamwambo, kusiyana ndi amene sanaphunzitsidwe."},{"question":"溫哥華有多少年歷史？","answer":"據考古學界的發現，原住民族在8000至10000年前已於溫哥華一帶出沒。"},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-center","answer":"மையம்/நடுவம்"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'macam orang biduk'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang makan dan minum bersama-sama tetapi bayar sendiri-sendiri."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഷിബ് സിബുകളുടെ വംശീയ പശ്ചാത്തലം എന്താണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"അവർ ജാപ്പനീസ് വംശജരാണ്."},{"question":"Goorma ayuu dhacay dagaalkii la magac baxay Jidbaale ee u dhaxeeyey Dhaqdhaqaaqii daraawiishta  iyo gumeystihii Ingiriiska?","answer":"Waxa uu dhacay sanadkii 1904."},{"question":"Tụgharịa asụsụ a na olu ndị. Igbo Izugbe: Nkume","answer":"Azịz:Olundi - okwute"},{"question":"ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ගස් ගහනය ඇති රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"කැනඩාව: ලෝකයේ වනාන්තරවලින් 30%ක නිවහන භූමි ස්කන්ධය අනුව ලොව දෙවන විශාලතම රට ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ගස් ගහනය ද හිමිකර ගනී. කැනඩාවේ දළ වශයෙන් ගස් බිලියන 318 ක් ඇති අතර එය රටෙන් 40% ක් පමණ ආවරණය කරයි."},{"question":"மரத்தின் பழங்கள் _____________ (குரைவாக / குறைவாக)உள்ளன.","answer":"குறைவாக"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Hà Nội huy động gần 2.000 mét vòi chữa cháy nhà dân trong ngõ chợ Khâm Thiên.","answer":"Vào khoảng thời gian trên, Trung tâm chỉ huy Công an thành phố nhận được tin báo cháy tại ngõ chợ Khâm Thiên đã nhanh chóng điều động lực lượng cứu hoả tiếp cận hiện trường. Ngay sau khi có mặt, lực lượng Công an quận Đống Đa xácđịnh ngôi nhà xảy cháy nằm sâu trong ngõ nhỏ, phương tiện chữa cháy không thể tiếp cận được. Thao tác nhanh trong vòng vài phút gần 2.000m đường ống vòi chữa cháy đã đến ngôi nhà đang ngùn ngụt lửa. Trong quá trình triển khai, lực lượng Công an đã nhận được sự giúp đỡ tận tình của người dân để thực thi nhiệm vụ. Nhờ triển khai kịp thời, chỉ trong vòng 10 phút đám cháy đã được khống chế. Đến 21h20 đám cháy đã được dập tắt hoàn toàn. "},{"question":"Àmì ẹ̀yẹ góòlù Olympic mélòó ni Usain Bolt ní lápapọ̀?","answer":"Mẹ́jọ"},{"question":"\\"Ịchụ́chụ ọnụ n'ala\\" bụ akpalaokwu pụtara gini?","answer":"Ìhè Akpalaokwu \\"Ịchụ́chụ ọnụ n'ala\\" putara bụ \\"i mesi mmadụ ike\\""},{"question":"元々は砂鉄を採る「土壌すくい」の作業を真似た踊りであった、島根県の民謡は何でしょう？","answer":"『安来（やすぎ）節』です。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada hati\\". Berikan contoh ayat untuk peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud menaruh keinginan. Contoh ayat: Walaupun berpendapatan kecil, Jaya ada hati hendak membuka perniagaannya sendiri suatu hari nanti."},{"question":"Кайра жаралуучу жана кайра жаралбаган энергия булагынын ортосунда кандай айырма бар?","answer":"Күн жана шамал энергиясы сыяктуу кайра жаралуучу энергия булактары табигый жол менен толукталышы мүмкүн, ал эми кайра жаралбаган булактар, мисалы, казылып алынган отундар, алар колдонулган сайын чектүү жана түгөнүп калат."},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ kọmíṣọ́nà ọlọpa ti Ìpínlẹ̀ Ondo ní ọdún 2023?","answer":"Táíwò Jesubiyi ni."},{"question":"Fulani yii pa ẹni to jigbe l’Ọyọọ, lo ba sa wa sipinlẹ Ogun","answer":"Ki i ṣe pe ọkunrin Fulani tẹ ẹ n wo fọto rẹ yii jiiyan gbe nipinlẹ Ọyọ nikan kọ, niṣe lo tun pa ẹni to ji gbe naa lẹyin to gbowo nla lọwọ awọn eeyan ẹni naa. Ipinlẹ Ogun to sa wa lẹyin iṣẹ laabi naa lọwọ ti ba a laipẹ yii, Usman Hassan lorukọ ẹ.Ogbologboo ajinigbe ni Usman bi Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, ṣe wi, ti oun funra rẹ paapaa si fẹnu ara ẹ ṣalaye fun wọn lẹyin tọwọ ba a tan.Usman yii ki i da iṣẹ ijinigbe naa ṣe gẹgẹ bi alukoro ṣe wi, o ni ikọ ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ naa, ọwọ si ti ba awọn iyẹn lẹyin ti wọn ji agbẹ kan gbe l’Abule Ṣolalu, n’Ibadan, ipinlẹ Ọyọ.Wọn ti gbowo lọwọ awọn eeyan oloko ti wọn ji gbe naa, awọn iyẹn si ti ro pe wọn yoo yọnda ẹ fawọn ni, ṣugbọn niṣe ni wọn pa a lẹyin ti wọn gbowo tan, wọn ni nitori pe ọkunrin naa da awọn mọ lawọn ṣe gbẹmi ẹ.Nigba ti wọn mu awọn ọmọọṣẹ Hassan nipinlẹ Ọyọ, wọn ko ri oun mu ni tiẹ nitori o sa wa sipinlẹ Ogun, o si fara pamọ.Ṣugbọn bo ṣe de ipinlẹ yii naa lo tun bẹrẹ si i ko ikọ ajinigbe mi-in jọ, to n pe awọn Fulani ẹgbẹ ẹ pe ki wọn jẹ kawọn jọ maa ji awọn eeyan gbe, kawọn maa fiyẹn ṣe ọna ọla awọn.Ninu awọn to n pe si iṣẹ naa lo ko ba a, ti wọn ta awọn ọlọpaa lolobo nipa iṣẹ buruku to fẹẹ maa fi wọn ṣe. Bo ṣe bọ sọwọ awọn agbofinro niyẹn.Nigba to n ṣalaye ara ẹ fawọn ọlọpaa, Usman sọ pe oun ati ọmọ iya oun to n jẹ Tahiru Usman pẹlu awọn kan lawọn jọ ji agbe oloko nla kan gbe lagbegbe Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan.O lawọn gbowo lọwọ awọn eeyan ẹ lati tu u silẹ, ṣugbọn nigba tawọn mọ pe ọkunrin naa ti da awọn mọ lawọn pa a.Ṣa, Fulani yii ti wa lẹka to n ri si ijinigbe, gẹgẹ bi CP Edward Ajogun ṣe paṣẹ, nibẹ ni wọn yoo ti taari ẹ si ipinlẹ Ọyọ ti yoo ti jẹjọ ẹsun ti wọn ka si i lẹsẹ."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Манас эпосунун жанрдык белгиси кайсы?а) оозекилиги б) тарыхыйлуулугув) синкреттүүлүгү г) түбөлүктүүлүгү ","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚а) оозекилиги "},{"question":"ايه السؤال اللي بيقول: \\"الكاردينال الشمالي (كارديناليس كارديناليس) هو طائر من أمريكا الشمالية في جنس كارديناليس ؛ وهو معروف بردو بالعامية باسم الطائر الأحمر أو الكاردينال العادي\\".؟ الموضوع هو كاردينال الشمال.","answer":"السؤال هو: \\"ما هو الاسم العلمي للطير الكاردينال؟\\""},{"question":"මැදපෙරදිග කලාපයේ පිහිටා ඇති , ස්වභාවික සෞන්දර්‍යයෙන් පරිපූර්ණවූ සුන්දර දේශය ( රට ) කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ලෙබනනය"},{"question":"Euskal kulturako musika-hauek aniztasuna dute. Trikitixa zein musika-tresna da?","answer":"Trikitixa akordeoi txiki bat da."},{"question":"గాంధీజి జన్మదినోత్సవం ఎప్పుడు?","answer":"గాంధీజి జన్మదినోత్సవం అక్టబరు 2 న జరుపుకుంటారు. \\"మోహన్ దాస్ కరంచంద్ గాంధీ\\" 1869 అక్టోబరు 2 వ తేదీన (శుక్ల నామ సంవత్సరం బాధ్రపద బహుళ ద్వాదశి శనివారం) గుజరాత్ లోని పోర్ బందర్లో ఒక సామాన్య సాంప్రదాయక కుటుంబములో జన్మించాడు. అతని తండ్రి పేరు కరంచంద్ గాంధీ. తల్లి పుతలీ బాయి."},{"question":"नेपाली भाषाको पहिलो पत्रिका कुन हो ?","answer":"नेपाली भाषाको पहिलो पत्रिका गोरखा भारत जीवन हो। यो मासिक पत्रिका भारतको बनारसमा छापिने गर्थ्यो। "},{"question":"ما هي الشجرة التي ذكرت في آيات القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"شجرة الزيتون."},{"question":"ഭൂമി ഒരു വൃത്താകൃതിയിലുള്ള വസ്തുവായി കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. ഏത് ഓപ്ഷനാണ് ഭൂമിയെക്കുറിച്ച് തെറ്റായി കണക്കാക്കുന്നത്.1. ഭൂമി കൂടുതലും ജലമാണ്. 2.ഭൂമി മിക്കവാറും ഉരുണ്ടതാണ്. 3. ഭൂമി പരന്നതാണ്.","answer":"3. ഭൂമി പരന്നതാണ്."},{"question":"Soalan: Mana satu ayat yang tidak masuk akal? Pilihan: - Ayat A: \\"Piranha ialah ikan yang tenang\\". - Ayat B: \\"Piranha ialah ikan yang ganas\\".  Huraikan.","answer":"Piranha mempunyai rahang dan gigi yang kuat menjadikannya spisis ikan yang ganas. Jawapannya ialah ayat A."},{"question":" O que é a Teoria da Relatividade Geral, de Albert Einstein?","answer":"A Teoria da Relatividade Geral, de Albert Einstein, publicada em 1915, é uma teoria física, que descreve a gravidade como a curvatura do espaço-tempo, causada pela presença de massa e energia. Ela amplia a Teoria da Relatividade Restrita e é fundamental para a nossa compreensão do universo, incluindo a previsão de fenômenos, como a curva da luz ao redor de objetos massivos (lentes gravitacionais) e a expansão do universo."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Séamas Ó Raghaill. ","answer":"Is iomáinaí Éireannach é Séamas Ó Raghaill, nó James Ryall as Béarla (rugadh i nDroichead Binéid, Contae Chill Chainnigh ar an 14 Samhain, 1980). Imreoir rathúil atá ann, ina chúlaí leis a chlub áitiúil Gráig/Baile Uí Challáin agus foireann idirchontae Chill Chainnigh ón bhliain 2003 go dtí an lá inniu.D'imir Ó Raghaill san fhoireann a bhuaigh Craobh Iomána Sinsearach na hÉireann 2006. Ainmníodh é ina Shárimreoir na Bliana sa bhliain seo freisin. "},{"question":"請回答這個問題：魚類是如何呼吸的？","answer":"答案：大部分的魚類通過鰓來呼吸。鰓是魚類身體側面的一系列結構，可以提供氧氣的交換。魚類通過張開嘴巴，將水進入鰓裂，然後鰓上的血管會吸收水中的氧氣，同時將二氧化碳排出體外。"},{"question":"Sheeg burta Somalia Ogunquit deer magaceyda?","answer":"Waxaa la dhaha surad."},{"question":"S(සල්ෆර්) 64g ක ඇති S මවුල ගණන  කොපමණ ද? (S = 32)","answer":"S = 32යන්නෙන් S වල සා.ප.ස් 32 ලෙස අදහස් කරයි. එහි අගය S වල මවුලික ස්කන්ධයට සමාන වේ. එමනිසා S වල මවුලික් ස්කන්ධය 32 gmol-1   විය යුතුය.මවුල ගණන  =    ස්කන්ධය/(මවුලික ස්කන්ධය)මවුල ගණන  =    (64 g)/(32 gmol^(-1) )         =    2 mol"},{"question":"ගුරු තලාව යන්නෙහි අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"සාමුද්‍රිකා ශාස්ත්‍රයේ එන හස්ත රේඛා විෂයෙහි කුජ තලාව බුද තලාව ගුරු තලාව ගුරුතලාව ආදී වශයෙන් අල්ලේ කොටස් බෙදා වෙන්කරයි..ඊට අනුව තලාව යන්නෙන් අදහස් කරනුයේ භූමිය යන්නයි..කුජගේ භූමිය බුධගේ භූමිය ආදී වශයෙනි..තැනිතලාව ආදී නම් ද විමසා බැලීම වටී.."},{"question":"من الذي عدلت شهادته شهادة الرجلين ؟\\t","answer":"خزيمة بن ثابت رضي الله عنه"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jika tidak kerana angin masakan pokok bergoyang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud jika perkara itu tidak berlaku, masakan ada orang yang berkata-kata tentang hal itu."},{"question":"小室哲哉プロデュースのダンスボーカルユニット「ｄｏｓ」でデビュー。ＳＭＡＰの振り付け師でも有名なタレントは？","answer":"ＫＡＢＡ．ちゃんです。"},{"question":"అన్నపూర్ణ స్తోత్రం రాయండి","answer":"నిత్యానందకరీ వరాభయకరీ సౌందర్య రత్నాకరీనిర్ధూతాఖిల ఘోర పావనకరీ ప్రత్యక్ష మాహేశ్వరీప్రాలేయాచల వంశ పావనకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 1 ||నానా రత్న విచిత్ర భూషణకరి హేమాంబరాడంబరీముక్తాహార విలంబమాన విలసత్-వక్షోజ కుంభాంతరీకాశ్మీరాగరు వాసితా రుచికరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 2 ||యోగానందకరీ రిపుక్షయకరీ ధర్మైక్య నిష్ఠాకరీచంద్రార్కానల భాసమాన లహరీ త్రైలోక్య రక్షాకరీసర్వైశ్వర్యకరీ తపః ఫలకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 3 ||కైలాసాచల కందరాలయకరీ గౌరీ ఉమా శాంకరీకౌమారీ నిగమార్థ-గోచరకరీ ఓంకార బీజాక్షరీమోక్షద్వార-కవాటపాటనకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 4 ||దృశ్యాదృశ్య-విభూతి-వాహనకరీ బ్రహ్మాండ-భాండోదరీలీలా-నాటక-సూత్ర-ఖేలనకరీ విఙ్ఞాన-దీపాంకురీశ్రీవిశ్వేశమనః-ప్రసాదనకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 5 ||ఉర్వీసర్వజయేశ్వరీ జయకరీ మాతా కృపాసాగరీవేణీ-నీలసమాన-కుంతలధరీ నిత్యాన్న-దానేశ్వరీసాక్షాన్మోక్షకరీ సదా శుభకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 6 ||ఆదిక్షాంత-సమస్తవర్ణనకరీ శంభోస్త్రిభావాకరీకాశ్మీరా త్రిపురేశ్వరీ త్రినయని విశ్వేశ్వరీ శర్వరీస్వర్గద్వార-కపాట-పాటనకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 7 ||దేవీ సర్వవిచిత్ర-రత్నరుచితా దాక్షాయిణీ సుందరీవామా-స్వాదుపయోధరా ప్రియకరీ సౌభాగ్యమాహేశ్వరీభక్తాభీష్టకరీ సదా శుభకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 8 ||చంద్రార్కానల-కోటికోటి-సదృశీ చంద్రాంశు-బింబాధరీచంద్రార్కాగ్ని-సమాన-కుండల-ధరీ చంద్రార్క-వర్ణేశ్వరీమాలా-పుస్తక-పాశసాంకుశధరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 9 ||క్షత్రత్రాణకరీ మహాభయకరీ మాతా కృపాసాగరీసర్వానందకరీ సదా శివకరీ విశ్వేశ్వరీ శ్రీధరీదక్షాక్రందకరీ నిరామయకరీ కాశీపురాధీశ్వరీభిక్షాం దేహి కృపావలంబనకరీ మాతాన్నపూర్ణేశ్వరీ || 10 ||అన్నపూర్ణే సాదాపూర్ణే శంకర-ప్రాణవల్లభేజ్ఞాన వైరాగ్య సిధ్ధ్యర్థం భిక్షాం దేహీ చ పార్వతీ|| 11 ||మాతా చ పార్వతీదేవీ పితాదేవో మహేశ్వరఃబాంధవా: శివభక్తాశ్చ స్వదేశో భువనత్రయమ్ || 12 ||సర్వ-మంగల-మాంగల్యే శివే సర్వార్థ-సాధికేశరణ్యే త్ర్యంబకే గౌరి నారాయణి నమో‌உస్తు తే || 13 ||"},{"question":"Wace addu’a ce addu’ar tashi daga bacci ?","answer":"Babu wata addu'a guda da aka sani a duniya a matsayin \\"addu'ar tashi daga barci.\\" Addinai daban-daban da al'adu na ruhaniya sun bambanta addu'o'i da ayyuka masu alaƙa da tashi da fara ranar.Ga wasu misalai:Kiristanci: \\"Na wayi gari a cikin makwancinka, Ya Allahna, ikonka ya kiyaye ni, rahamarKa ta lullube ni. Ka ba ni yau, ya Ubangiji, abincin yau da kullum, kuma Ka gafarta mini laifofina, Ya Ubangiji Mai jin ƙai. , Mafi rahamah.\\"Musulunci:“ Alhamdu lillaahil-lathee ahyaanaa ba da maa amaatanaa wa'ilayhin-nushoor.”Yana da kyau a lura cewa waɗannan misalan kaɗan ne, kuma takamaiman addu'a da ake amfani da su don tashi daga barci zai bambanta dangane da imani da al'ada."},{"question":"Quem foi que descreveu a estrutura do DNA?","answer":"James Watson e Francis Crick"},{"question":"Afaka mitia olona ve nefa tsy manintona ara-batana izy?","answer":"Azo atao ny mitia olona iray noho ny toetrany, ny soatoavina ary ny maha-izy azy."},{"question":"Mene ma’anar chair?","answer":"Chair wani abu ne da mutane suke amfani dashi wajan zama."},{"question":"Por quem e quando foi fundado o reino do Ndongo?","answer":"O Reino do Dongo, Andongo (em quimbundo: Ndongo) ou Angola (Ngola) foi o Estado pré-colonial africano no território da atual Angola, criado pelos ambundos, e cujo nome inspirou o nome do atual país.Foi fundado em cerca de 1300, acredita-se por Ngola Mbandi ou Ngola Inene. \\"Ngola\\" era o título usado para os governantes do reino (o título completo era \\"Ngola a Kiluanje\\")."},{"question":"２００３年元旦に行なわれた「ニューイヤー駅伝」で、史上初の３連覇を達成したチームといえばどこでしょう？","answer":"コニカ"},{"question":"Kíni a ń pe ọba Abẹ́òkúta?","answer":"Aláké tí ìlú Ẹ̀gbá. "},{"question":"من هو الفارابي؟","answer":"الفارابي وعُرِف بأبي نصر واسمه الأساسي محمد، وُلد عام 260 هـ(874 م)، في فاراب في إقليم تركستان (كازاخستان حاليًا) وتُوفي عام 339 هـ(950م). لُقب باسم الفارابي نسبةً للمدينة التي ولد فيها وهي فاراب. يعُتبر الفارابي فيلسوفاَ ومن أهم الشخصيات الإسلامية التي أتقنت العلوم بصورة كبيرة مثل الطب والفيزياء والفلسفة والموسيقى وغيرها."},{"question":"Ọwọ tẹ ajinigbe meji nibi ti wọn ti fẹẹ gbowo itusilẹ lori ọmọ ọdun meje l’Agbara","answer":"Ajinigbe lawọn ọkunrin meji yii, orukọ wọn ni Muhammed Abubakar; ẹni ọdun mejilelogoji (42), ati Clinton Niche; ẹni ọdun mejidinlogun (18). Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ti i ṣe ọjọ kẹta, oṣu kẹwaa yii, lọwọ ba wọn nibi ti wọn ti fẹẹ gbe miliọnu kan naira owo itusilẹ ti wọn fẹẹ gba lori ọmọ ti wọn ji gbe. Àgbárá, nipinlẹ Ogun, lọwọ ti ba wọn.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an gẹgẹ bi baba ọmọ ti wọn ji gbe, Ọgbẹni Stephen Ajibili, ṣe ṣalaye fawọn ọlọpaa ni pe iya ọmọ naa lo ran an niṣẹ ni nnkan bii aago mọkanla kọja ogun iṣẹju ọjọ naa, n lawọn ajinigbe ba ji ọmọ ọhun torukọ ẹ n jẹ Daniel Ajibili, gbe.O ni ko pẹ ti wọn fi pe oun pe boun ba fẹẹ ri ọmọkunrin tọjọ ori rẹ ko ju ọdun meje lọ naa gba pada laaye, afi koun fi miliọnu kan naira ranṣẹ sawọn.Eyi lo mu Baba Daniel lọọ sọrọ naa fun wọn ni teṣan ọlọpaa Agbara, CSP Kayode Shedrack, Adele ọlọpaa agbegbe naa, si ko awọn eeyan rẹ sodi, wọn bẹrẹ iwadii lori ibi ti awọn ajinigbe naa sọ pe ki wọn gbe owo ọhun wa.Nigba ti Ọlọrun yoo si ba wọn ṣe e, ajinigbe to n ba awọn obi ọmọ naa sọrọ jade wa pẹlu ẹnikeji rẹ lati gbe owo ti wọn fẹẹ gba, awọn ko mọ pe awọn ọlọpaa ti lugọ de wọn nibi kan.Nibi ti awọn meji yii ti fẹẹ gbe owo naa lawọn ọlọpaa ti bo wọn, ni wọn ba mu wọn ṣinkun.Awọn meji yii, Muhammed Abubakar ati Clinton Niche, ni wọn mu awọn ọlọpaa lọ si ibi igi ti wọn de ọmọ kekere naa mọ.  Aṣe mẹta tilẹ ni awọn ajinigbe naa, wọn fi ẹni kan ṣọ ọmọ ti wọn ji gbe, awọn meji jade lati lọọ gbe owo ni.Nigba ti ẹni ti wọn fi ṣọ ọmọ naa kofiri pe wọn ti mu awọn eeyan oun silẹ loun ti sa lọ ni tiẹ, awọn ọlọpaa ko ti i ri i mu titi ta a fi pari iroyin yii.Ṣugbọn awọn meji tọwọ ba yii jẹwọ ṣa, wọn ni mẹta lawọn, ara lo fu ẹnikẹta to fi sa lọ.Adele ọlọpaa agba nipinlẹ Ogun, DCP Abiọdun Alamutu, paṣẹ pe ki wọn gbe awọn meji yii lọ sẹka to n ri si ijinigbe nipinlẹ yii, ki wọn si wa ẹnikẹta to sa lọ naa ri nibi yoowu ko sa lọ."},{"question":"Magbigay ng halimbawa ng Python code na kino-convert ang kilometro papuntang milya.","answer":"Ang sumusunod na Python code ay kino-convert ang kilometro papuntang milya:kilometers = float(input(\\"Magbigay ng halaga sa kilometro: \\"))conv_fac = 0.621371miles = kilometers * conv_facprint('Ang %0.2f kilometro ay %0.2f na milya' %(kilometers,miles))"},{"question":"බු.ව. 1 හි විශේෂත්වය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගෞතම බුදුන් වහන්සේගේ පරිනිර්වාණයෙන් පසුව ගතවූ මුලිම වසරයි. ප්‍රථම ධර්ම සංගායනාව මෙම වසරේදී පවත්වන ලදී."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Мээ - жаш өткөн сайын жеңилдей баштайт."},{"question":"مضمون جو خلاصو:  ڪينساس جو هڪ شخص برف ۾ هڪ ڪلاڪ ڊريس جوتا پائي هلڻ کانپوءِ پنهنجي سڀني ڏهن پيرن جون ٽنگون ڪٽائي ڇڏيون - ۽ هن کي هاڻي ٻيهر هلڻ سکڻو پوندو. ايون هارٽر ، 22 ، پلاٽسبرگ کان ، گذريل ڊسمبر ۾ آرڪٽڪ جي حالتن ۾ گهر سان وڙهندي وڙهندي هن جي ڪار خراب ٿيڻ کانپوءِ رات جي ماني جي پارٽي لاءِ مناسب لباس پائي  ۽ قيمت ادا ڪئي. هو پنهنجي گندي جرابين پائي بستر تي ويو ۽ جاڳڻ سان هن جي ٽنگون ۽ پيرن جا رنگ ڳاڙها ٿي ويا. ويڊيو لاءِ هيٺ لٿو. سبق سکيو: ايون هارٽر کي پنهنجي سڀني پيرن کي ڪٽڻو پيو هو برف ۾ گهر وڃڻ کانپوءِ لباس جي جوتن ۾. هن ڪي سي ٽي وي کي ٻڌايو: مون کي گهر هلڻ ۾ اٽڪل هڪ ڪلاڪ لڳو. مون کي ڊريس جا چپل پيل هئا، هڪ سهڻي قميص، هڪ جيڪٽ، ڊگهي انڊر ويئر، نه دستانا ۽ حقيقت ۾ نه ڪيپ. منهنجا پير ٽنگ کان وٺي پيرن تائين ڳاڙها هئا.  هارٽر جا ناخن به ڪارا ٿي چڪا هئا. هن ڪي ايم بي سي کي ٻڌايو ته هو هڪ پارٽي ۾ شرڪت ڪرڻ کان پوءِ پلاٽزبرگ جي مرڪز کان گهر هليو ويو - اٽڪل ٻه ميل جو فاصلو. ڊاڪٽر رچرڊ ڪورينٽاجر ، يونيورسٽي آف ڪنساس اسپتال مان ، چيو: 'اهو چئلينج جي زندگي آهي. هن کي تمام گهڻو ڪم ڪرڻ گهرجي، ۽ اهو اسان جو مقصد آهي. هن سان معاملا ڪرڻا پوندا آهن، پر اهو هن لاءِ هڪ ڊگهو رستو هوندو. چوڻ جي ضرورت ناهي، هارٽر هاڻي واضح طور ڏسي سگهي ٿو ته هن کي صحيح طرح سان پيڪيج ڪرڻ گهرجي ها. درد: هارٽر جي آ fingersريون به سختي سان متاثر ٿيون. هن وڌيڪ چيو:هميشه پنهنجي ڪار ۾ اضافي ڪپڙا رکندا رهو قطع نظر ڪو مسئلو ناهي. منجمد گرمي پد جي هيٺان منفي 0.55oC (31oF) جي دوران حملو ڪري ٿو ۽ جسم جي ڪنهن به حصي کي متاثر ڪري سگهي ٿو، جيتوڻيڪ اهو عام طور تي هٿن، پيرن، ڪنن، نڪ ۽ چپن وانگر آهي، جيڪو برطانيه جي اين ايڇ ايس ويب سائيٽ جي مطابق آهي. پهرين علامتون ٿڌي ۽ ڏکوئيندڙ ٿانون ۽ چمڙي جو احساس آهن، جنهن جي پٺيان پن ۽ سوئي ۽ پوءِ numbness.","answer":"ايون هارٽر هڪ ڪلاڪ تائين برف ۾ هلندو رهيو، رسمي جوتن ۾، گندي جرابين ۾ سمهندو رهيو ۽ ڳاڙهن پيرن سان جاڳندو رهيو. هن جي پيرن جون ٽنگون ڪٽڻ کان پوءِ ، 22 سالن جو ، پلاٽسبرگ کان ، هاڻي ٻيهر هلڻ سکڻو پوندو."},{"question":"\\"Matetika ny fanambadiana no fiandohan'ny zava-niainana vaovao ho an'ny mpivady, voamariky ny fananganana fianakaviana sy fifampizarana andraikitra. Ny mpivady dia manolo-tena hanohana ny nofinofin'ny tsirairay sy ny tanjon'izy ireo, mamorona ekipa matanjaka hiatrika ireo fanamby eo amin'ny fiainana. Ny fifankatiavana sy ny fifankahazoana dia singa fototra amin’ny fanambadiana mahomby. Ny fitsingerenan'ny fampakaram-bady dia fotoana iray hankalazana ny taona iarahana, hahatsiaro ireo fahatsiarovana ankamamiana sy hanamafisana ny fifamatorana. Raha fintinina, ny fanambadiana dia dia feno fitiavana, fanoloran-tena ary fitomboana manokana ho an'ireo mpivady izay manomboka izany.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny fanambadiana."},{"question":"Sheeg tirada cidamadi dagalki badar?","answer":"Waxay tirada cidamadi badar 950 nin 110 faras ah io 700 oo geel ah ."},{"question":"ভাইরাসের সংজ্ঞা দাও।","answer":"ভাইরাস হলো নিউক্লিক অ্যাসিড (কেন্দ্রীয় অংশ) ও প্রোটিন (আবরণ) দিয়ে গঠিত অকোষীয়, অতি-আণুবীক্ষণিক, বাধ্যতামূলক পরজীবী বস্তু যা জীবদেহের অভ্যন্তরে সক্রিয় হয়ে রোগ সৃষ্টি করে কিন্তু জীবদেহের বাইরে নিষ্ক্রিয় অবস্থায় বিরাজ করে।"},{"question":"Manana teny mikorontana ianao: naatorokimOmeo ary ny teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"mikorotana\\""},{"question":"ミッキーマウスの恋人はミニーマウスですが、ドナルドダックの恋人は何でしょう？","answer":"デイジーダックです。"},{"question":"Given the below title and summary of an article, generate a short article or the beginning of a long article to go along with them. Title: పుల్వామా దాడి: రెఫరెండాన్ని భారత్ ఎందుకు వ్యతిరేకిస్తోంది?nSummary: 1947లో అప్పటి జమ్మూకశ్మీర్ మహారాజు తన రాజ్యాన్ని భారత్‌లో విలీనం చేయడానికి అంగీకరించినప్పుడు అప్పటి గవర్నర్ జనరల్ లార్డ్ మౌంట్ బాటన్ ఓ సలహా ఇచ్చారు... \\"కశ్మీర్ కోసం పాకిస్థాన్, భారత్‌ల మధ్య ఏకాభిప్రాయం లేదు కాబట్టి, అది ఎవరికి చెందాలనేదానిపై ప్రజాభిప్రాయ సేకరణ, ఎన్నికలు నిర్వహించాలి\\" అని.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"కానీ, ప్రజల ఆకాంక్షలను తెలుసుకునే ప్రజాభిప్రాయ సేకరణ అనేది రానురాను చాలా క్లిష్టమైన అంశంగా మారింది.1949లో ఇరు దేశాల మధ్య జరిగిన యుద్ధంలో కశ్మీర్లోని మూడొంతుల్లో లద్ధాక్, జమ్ము, కశ్మీర్ లోయలతో కూడిన రెండొంతుల భూభాగం భారత్ నియంత్రణలోకి రాగా, ఒక వంతు అంటే ప్రస్తుతం ఆజాద్ కశ్మీర్ అని పాకిస్తాన్ పిలుచుకునే భాగంతో పాటు, ఉత్తర ప్రాంతం అంతా పాకిస్తాన్ అధీనంలోకి వెళ్లింది.రాష్ట్రమంతా ఎవరి అధీనంలో ఉండాలో నిర్ణయించడానికి భారత్, పాకిస్థాన్ నాయకులు గతంలో అంగీకరించినట్టుగా ప్రజాభిప్రాయ సేకరణ నిర్వహించాలని సూచి0చారు. "},{"question":"Kodwa nithi uza lapha ekhaya lo muntu?Sengathi. Kodwa uyambona baba ukuthi ubani?Sengathi umuntu omdala nje?Ngabe kushone bani pho?Uza lapha impela. Hawu nkosi yami. Kodwa ngabe ukufa kusifunanilapha ekhaya?Sengathi umamezala lo? Uyena impela.UMaMbatha?Uyena kanye baba.(Amemeze) Siphuthume bo! Sekugadlephi ukufa na?(Ebalisa) Yeka ngengane yami. Nokwenza isisele yodwa vo.Iyiphi-ke leyo ngane?(Ekhala) UDumisani (Hhi … hhi) zimgwazile izigebengu zikamakoti.(Hhi … hhi)Umakoti waphi?Yena (Hhi … hhi) lo. (Akhombe uThenjiwe)Zimgwaza kuphi? Nini? Hhawu weSimakade! Uyaphila?Kahle ngemibuzo eminingi kangaka. Ngeke siluzwe kahle udaba.Ugwazwe ubani uDumisani?(Hhi … hhi) Isoka likaThenjiwe (Hhi …)Hhayi bo! Anginasoka mina. (Ethukile)Kodwa yini le oyenzayo Thenjiwe? Usuhambe wafuna abantuukuba bagwaze umfowabo kamkhwenyana. Khona ungamfuniusungambulala pho?Hhawu Sebawoti. Kanti umuntu uyophumula nini emhlabeni. Ushonileyini umfana?1. Ukuzwelana kukaNondumiso noThenjiwe kwaba namphumela muniebudlelwaneni bakhe nobaba wakhe?","answer":"Uyise wamxosha kubo wathi angaphinde eze ngoba wonisa uThenjiwe."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 日本郵便は1日、来年の年賀状に使うはがきを売り始めました。年賀状は、新しい年をお祝いしてあいさつをするために送ります。はがきには、来年の十二支のうさぎの絵がかいてあります。東京の千代田区にある郵便局では、近くの小学校の子どもたちがはがきを買って、住所や名前の書き方などについて説明を聞きました。最近はメールなどであいさつをする人が増えています。このため日本郵便は、来年の年賀状のはがきを今年より10%ぐらい少なくして、16億4000万枚用意しました。日本郵便は「スマートねんが」も始めます。「LINE」で、年賀状のはがきのようにメッセージを送ることができます。105種類のデザインがあります。年賀状は、12月15日からポストや郵便局に出すことができます。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"Gani Adams, Sunday Igboho atawọn OPC fẹẹ ṣewọde ta ko maaluu jijẹ nilẹ Yoruba","answer":"Bi gbogbo nnkan ba lọ bo ṣe ye, ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii, ni Aarẹ Ọnakakanfo ilẹ Yorùbá, Iba Gani Adams, Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ atawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC yoo jade lati ṣewọde ta ko jijẹ maaluu nilẹ Yoruba.Ninu ikede ti wọn ṣe sinu iwe iroyin kan ni Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Sunday Igboho ati Iba Gani ti sọrọ yii pẹlu ajọṣepọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC, labẹ akoso Ọmọoba Ṣẹgun Ọsinbọtẹ, wọn si ti ya ọjọ kan sọtọ lati fi ṣewọde.Wọn ni awọn gbe igbesẹ yii lati fẹhonu han lori bi ẹgbẹ awọn to n ta maaluu atawọn ohun jijẹ loke ọya ṣe paṣẹ fawọn eeyan wọn ki wọn ma ṣe ko ounjẹ ati maaluu wa si ilẹ Yorùbá atawon ibomi-in lagbegbe apa Guusu orilẹ ede yii mọ.Ni bayii, o ti di ọjọ kẹrin ti ẹgbẹ awọn olokoowo ẹran maaluu ti paṣẹ ọhun.Igbesẹ awọn Hausa yii ko sai ba ibinu awọn eeyan orilẹ ede yii pade nitori kaakiri ori ikanni ayélujára lawọn èèyàn ti n bu ẹnu atẹ lu igbesẹ ọ̀hún.Ẹgbẹ awọn olounjẹ ati maaluu nilẹ Hausa sọ pe ileeṣẹ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ DSS, niluu Abuja ti pe awọn lori idi ti awọn ṣe gbe ìgbésẹ ọhun.Akọwe ẹgbẹ naa, Ahmed Alaramma, sọ pe titi di asiko yii ni Aarẹ ẹgbẹ naa, Mohammed Tahir, ṣi wa lọdọ awọn DSS.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, awọn eeyan yìí naa lo n béèrè ẹgbẹlẹgbẹ biliọnu lọwọ ijọba àpapọ gẹgẹ bíi owo gba ma binu pe wọn pa awọn eeyan awọn lasiko rogbodiyan to waye ni Shasha."},{"question":"Waa maxay Calaamadaha lagu garan karo in jidhka ingag ka jiro?","answer":"Marka uu ingagga uu jidhku dareemayaa yar yahay, waxa uu qofku isku arkaa calaamad ay ka mid tahay dibnaha oo ingaga, hurdo badan, wahsi iyo firfircoonida oo ku yaraata, harraad, kaadida oo yaraata, madax xanuun, iyo maqaarka oo qallayl badan laga dareemo.Laakiin haddii ay biyo la’aanta jidhku sii badato waxa si kordha xaaladaha ka dhalanaya iyo calaamadaha uu qofku ku fahmi karayo in uu hoos u dhacay heerka biyaha jidhkoodu. Waxaa ka mid ah dhidid, kaadi la’aan, dhiigga oo hoos u dhaca, neefsiga iyo garaaca wadnaha oo inta caadiga ah ka dheereeya iyo mararka qaarkood in uu qofku miyir beelo."},{"question":"A qual categoria essa pergunta pertence: Quantos países existem na Costa Oeste dos Estados Unidos?.","answer":"Geografia."},{"question":"inona no fanalavana ny hoe VVS?","answer":"ny fanalavana ny hoe VVS dia Vy Vato Sakelika"},{"question":"\\"क्वान्टम डट्स\\" को अवधारणा र डिस्प्ले, सोलार सेल, र मेडिकल इमेजिङमा तिनीहरूको प्रयोगको व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"क्वान्टम डटहरू नैनोस्केल अर्धचालक कणहरू हुन् जसले विशिष्ट रंगहरूको प्रकाश उत्सर्जन गर्न सक्छ। तिनीहरू जीवन्त रंगहरूको लागि प्रदर्शनमा प्रयोग गरिन्छ, सौर्य सेलहरू बढ्दो दक्षताको लागि, र सटीक निदानको लागि मेडिकल इमेजिङ।"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: \\"Ngày 31/7, thông tin từ Cục Quản lý Thị trường (QLTT) Đắk Lắk cho biết, sau khi cây xăng dầu N.S (xã Pơng Đrang, huyện Krông Búk) bị khách hàng tố đổ dầu có lẫn nước lã, Cục QLTT đã phối hợp Sở Khoa học - Công Nghệ Đắk Lắk niêm phong, lấy mẫu xăng dầu tại 3 bồn chứa của cây xăng để kiểm định. Theo kết quả kiểm định, cả 3 mẫu của 3 bồn, bể tại cây xăng N.S đều đảm bảo chất lượng, tiêu chuẩn của nhà sản xuất, nhưng trong bồn có chứa một ít nước. Việc lẫn nước vào dầu được xác định do vô ý trong quá trình lau dọn bể, bồn. Trước đó, ngày 5/7, ông T.N.H. (trú thị xã Buôn Hồ, tỉnh Đắk Lắk) phản ánh đến Cục QLTT Đắk Lắk về việc sáng 2/7, ông đến cây xăng dầu N.S, đổ 500.000 đồng tiền dầu.\\"","answer":"Ông H. đi được khoảng 15-20 km thì xe tắt máy. Ông phải thuê thợ kéo xe về gara kiểm tra. Tại đây, thợ sửa xe phát hiện 4 béc dầu bị hư hỏng, tháo dầu trong xe ra thì có lẫn nhiều nước. Số tiền ông phải bỏ ra để sửa 4 béc dầu kèm chi phí khác hết khoảng 52 triệu đồng. Theo ông H., thời điểm xảy ra vụ việc, ông gọi điện cho chủ cây xăng, người này bảo không có mặt tại Đắk Lắk nên nhờ nhân viên cây xăng đứng ra xử lý, ký giấy cam kết. Chủ cây xăng nói ông H. đưa xe đi sửa, đem hóa đơn về để thanh toán lại. Tuy nhiên, đến nay, ông chưa được trả lại số tiền đã bỏ ra. Đại diện cây xăng dầu N.S cho rằng, trước đây, hai bên có thỏa thuận xem xét giải quyết với nhau. Tuy nhiên, chủ xe báo với lực lượng chức năng nên cứ để pháp luật giải quyết. Từ trước đến nay, cửa hàng của ông đã đổ rất nhiều xăng dầu cho khách hàng nhưng chưa ai phản ánh, chỉ mỗi trường hợp ông H. Chủ cửa hàng N.S. cũng cho hay, nếu chủ xe muốn kiện thì chấp nhận. Nếu bản án xác định nguyên nhân do lỗi cây xăng, cửa hàng sẽ đền."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai limau masam sebelah\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud hukuman atau pertimbangan yang kurang adil."},{"question":"Teoman ne zaman müziği bıraktığını açıkladı?","answer":"Ünlü şarkıcı Teoman, kendi resmi sitesinden 4 Ağustos 2011 tarihinde müziği bıraktığını açıkladı, ancak kendisi 4 Kasım 2012 tarihinde aynı siteden müziğe geri döndüğünü de açıkladı."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk sayur taugeh goreng dengan kobis dan udang? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 300 gm taugeh, 100 gm kobis bulat, 100 gm (1/2 batang) lobak merah, 100 gm udang segar, 5 ulas bawang putih, 1 cm halia, 1 biji cili hijau, 1 biji cili merah, 3 sudu besar minyak masak, Garam dan serbuk perisaCara penyediaan:1. Bersihkan kemudian bilas taugeh. Tuskan.2. Bersihkan udang.3. Mayang bawang putih dan halia.4. Kupas lobak merah, belah dua kemudian potong serong nipis-nipis.◦ Potong serong cili hijau dan cili merah.5. Potong kasar kobisCara memasak:1. Panaskan kuali, kemudian masukkan minyak.2. Apabila minyak mula berasap, masukkan bawang putih dan halia. Tumiskan sehingga bawang putihkekuningan.3. Kemudian masukkan udang.4. Apabila udang bertukar warna kemerahan, masukkan carrot, kemudian kobis.5. Apabila kobis layu masukkan taugeh, garam dan serbuk perisa,6. Teruskan mengacau goreng selama seminit dua, kemudian angkat dan hidangkan panas-panas"},{"question":"I wonder 2018 నాటికి దూసి గ్రామంలో ఓటర్Topic: దూసిArticle: దూసి శ్రీకాకుళం జిల్లా, ఆమదాలవలస మండలంలోని గ్రామం.  ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన ఆమదాలవలస నుండి 10 కి. మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 747 ఇళ్లతో, 2539 జనాభాతో 641 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 1251, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 1288. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 180 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 0. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 581408[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 532484.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ఒక ప్రైవేటు బాలబడి ఉంది. ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు నాలుగు, ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి , ప్రభుత్వ మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల ఒకటి ఉన్నాయి.సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల తొగరగాంలోను, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల, ఇంజనీరింగ్ కళాశాల‌లు శ్రీకాకుళంలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల, పాలీటెక్నిక్ శ్రీకాకుళంలో ఉన్నాయి.సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల శ్రీకాకుళంలో ఉన్నాయి.వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యందూసిలో ఉన్న ఒకప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రంలో ఒక డాక్టరు, నలుగురు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బందీ ఉన్నారు. ఒక ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రంలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ఒకరు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు.సంచార వైద్య శాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 కి.మీ. లోపు దూరంలో ఉంది. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, డిస్పెన్సరీ, పశు వైద్యశాల, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి.ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యంగ్రామంలోఒక ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యం ఉంది. డిగ్రీ లేని డాక్టరు ఒకరు ఉన్నారు.తాగు నీరుగ్రామంలో కుళాయిల ద్వారా రక్షిత మంచినీటి సరఫరా జరుగుతోంది. బావుల నీరు కూడా అందుబాటులో ఉంది. గ్రామంలో ఏడాది పొడుగునా చేతిపంపుల ద్వారా నీరు అందుతుంది. బోరుబావుల ద్వారా కూడా ఏడాది పొడుగునా నీరు అందుతుంది. కాలువ/వాగు/నది ద్వారా గ్రామానికి తాగునీరు లభిస్తుంది.పారిశుధ్యంమురుగునీరు బహిరంగ కాలువల ద్వారా ప్రవహిస్తుంది. మురుగునీటిని నేరుగా జలవనరుల్లోకి వదులుతున్నారు. గ్రామంలో సంపూర్ణ పారిశుధ్య పథకం అమలవుతోంది. సామాజిక మరుగుదొడ్డి సౌకర్యం లేదు. ఇంటింటికీ తిరిగి వ్యర్థాలను సేకరించే వ్యవస్థ లేదు. సామాజిక బయోగ్యాస్ ఉత్పాదక వ్యవస్థ లేదు. చెత్తను వీధుల పక్కనే పారబోస్తారు.సమాచార,...","answer":"None"},{"question":"ලෝක පොත් දිනය පවත්වන්නේ කුමන මාසය තුළද?","answer":" මාර්තු"},{"question":"国民栄誉賞の受賞者のうち、役者の「一夫」と漫画家の「町子」に共通する苗字は何でしょう？","answer":"長谷川です。"},{"question":"Nitori owo atunṣe oju-ọna, kọmiṣanna Arẹgbẹṣọla ati ti Oyetọla gbena woju ara wọn l’Ọṣun","answer":"Owo tijọba apapọ san pada funjọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun lori atunṣe awọn ojupopo to jẹ tijọba apapọ ti da ariyanjiyan silẹ laarin awọn ọmọ-ẹyin gomina ana, Ọgbẹni Rauf Arẹgbẹṣọla, ati ti Gomina Gboyega Oyetọla bayii.Nibi eto kan ni kọmiṣanna fun ọrọ idile (Home Affairs) laye ijọba Arẹgbẹṣọla, Ọmọọba Sikiru Ayedun, ti sọ laipẹ yii pe biliọnu mejidinlaadọta naira (#48bn) ni Gomina Oyetọla ti gba pada latọdọ ijọba apapọ lori awọn oju-ọna ti wọn ti ṣe.Ayedun ṣalaye pe owo yii, eleyii to ni Arẹgbẹṣọla ṣiṣẹ rẹ silẹ fun un, ni Oyetọla n lo lati fi san ẹkunrẹrẹ owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ, to si pa aṣiri yii mọ fun awọn araalu.Ṣugbọn Kọmiṣanna feto iṣuna lọwọlọwọ bayii, Ọmọọba Bọla Oyebamiji, ko jẹ ki ọrọ naa tutu rara, o ni aturọta bii elubọ ni Ayedun, nitori ohun ti ko ridi lo n sọ fun awọn araalu.O ni irọ to jinna soootọ ni ọrọ ti Ayedun sọ ọhun, eleyii to si le ṣi awọn araalu lọna, to si tun le da wahala ati iyapa silẹ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC.Oyebamiji ṣalaye pe biliọnu lọna mejidinlogoji naira (#38bn) gan-an ni gbogbo owo awọn oju-ọna ijọba apapọ tijọba Arẹgbẹṣọla ṣe, bawo waa ni ijọba Ọṣun yoo ṣe gba ju owo iṣẹ to ba ijọba apapọ ṣe lọ?O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe, lọwọlọwọ bayii, ẹẹmẹta ọtọọtọ nijọba apapọ ti fi lara owo naa ranṣẹ sijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun, apapọ mẹtẹẹta si jẹ biliọnu mejila o din miliọnu kan naira (#11.9bn), eyi to si jẹ owo awọn iṣẹ ti awọn kọngila ti ṣe yọri.O ni ori awọn oju-ọna mẹrin ọtọọtọ tijọba Oyetọla jogun latọdọ ijọba Arẹgbẹṣọla ni awọn na owo ọhun le lori yatọ si owo-oṣu ti Ayedun sọ.Oyebamiji waa ke si gbogbo awọn araalu lati maa wadii ohun gbogbo dajudaju, ko too di pe wọn aa di eyi to jẹ otitọ mu, ti wọn aa si maa polongo rẹ kaakiri ki alaafia le tubọ maa jọba nipinlẹ Ọṣun."},{"question":"اكتب كمالة للجملة دي: اسم ليجييه ظهر اخر مرة في الفورمولا واحد في جائزة اليابان الكبرى 1996","answer":". في نهاية الموسم تم بيع الفريق لألين بروست وبقى بروست غراند بريكس في سنة."},{"question":"\\" මලින්දි දේශය \\" නමින් අතීතයේදී හැඳින්වූ , අප්‍රිකානු රාජ්‍යය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"කෙන්‍යාව"},{"question":"Gịnị bụ ọrịa Ọrịa Pakịnsịn (Parkinson's Disease)?","answer":"Ọrịa pakịnsọn bụ mgbe ike malitere ịgwụ ụbụrụ mmadụ ma onye ahụ kawa nka na-akpata ya.Ọ bụ ma mmadụ kawa nka ka ya bụ ọrịa na-apụtakarị ihe.Otu ihe e ji ama ya bụ aka ịma mmadụ jijiji n'ihi na ike agwụla njikọ ọkpụkpụ nakwa anụahụ.Ndị nnyocha kwuru na ọrịa a ka njọ na nwoke karịa na nwaanyị.Muhammad Ali bụ ọpịa ọkpọ bụ otu onye a ma ama rịara ọrịa a tupu ọ nwụọ.Ruo ugbua ọrịa a enwebeghi ngwọta, mana a na-enye ndị mmadụ ọgwụgwọ na-enyere ha aka ibi ndụ ha, site n'ịṅụ ụfọdụ ọgwụ nakwa ịwa ahụ nakwa nke Bekee kpọrọ \\"physiotherapy\\"."},{"question":"کچھ انوکھی اور مزے دار خبریں سنایے","answer":"جی ضرور، یہ رہے کچھ انوکھی خبریں: • دنیا کا سب سے لمبا پہاڑی سلسلہ کوہ انڈیز ہے جو جنوبی امریکہ میں واقع ہے۔ • ایڈا لولیس کو دنیا کی سب سے پہلی کمپیوٹر پروگرامر کے طور پر جانا جاتا ہے۔ • دنیا کا بدترین زلزلہ 1556ء کو چین میں آیا جس کے نتیجے میں 8 لاکھ 30 ہزار افراد ہلاک ہو ئے۔ • آرمینیا 301 عیسوی میں عیسائیت کو مذہب کے طور پر قبول کرنے والا پہلا ملک تھا۔ • اسنوکر کی ابتدا 1875ء میں ہندوستان سے شروع ہوئی۔"},{"question":"Irọ ni, awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba ko ko ounjẹ korona pamọ o – Akeredolu","answer":"Alaga ẹgbẹ awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba, Rotimi Akeredolu, ti sọ pe ko si ootọ ninu ohun ti awọn kan n gbe kiri pe awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba tọju ounjẹ to wa fun korona pamọ.Akeredolu ṣalaye ọrọ yii nibi isin pataki kan ti wọn ṣe lati ṣami ọdun kẹta ti Biṣọọbu ilu Ọwọ, Stephen Fagbemi, ti wa nipo, eyi to waye ni All Saints Church, Idasẹ, niluu Ọwọ.Gomina ni ohun to jẹ ki o pẹ ki awọn too pin awọn ounjẹ naa faraalu ni pe awọn gomina kan ṣi n duro de awọn ounjẹ mi-in to yẹ ko wọle, ati ipinnu awọn lati ṣefilọlẹ eto pinpin ounjẹ naa ko too di pe awọn berẹ si i pin in.Arakunrin ni o jẹ ohun to ṣe ni laaanu pe awọn eeyan ja awọn ibi ti wọn ko ounjẹ naa si, ti wọn si n pin in. Bẹẹ lo ni eyi ko ṣẹlẹ nipinlẹ Ondo, nitori bawọn ṣe n gba ounjẹ naa lawọn n pin in faraalu.O waa ṣeleri iṣẹ takuntakun ni saa keji ijọba rẹ yii."},{"question":"Beschrijf de belangrijkste verschillen tussen de katholieke en protestantse geloven.","answer":"De twee belangrijkste takken van het christendom, het katholicisme en het protestantisme, verschillen in hun overtuigingen over veel belangrijke onderwerpen. Katholieken erkennen de paus als de hoogste autoriteit in de kerk, terwijl het protestantisme verdeeld is in een breed scala aan denominaties die andere vormen van autoriteit erkennen, zoals de bijbel of kerkelijke raden. Katholieken erkennen zeven sacramenten, terwijl protestanten slechts twee erkennen, namelijk de doop en het avondmaal. Katholieken geloven ook in transsubstantiatie, de overtuiging dat brood en wijn tijdens het sacrament van het avondmaal het letterlijke lichaam en bloed van Jezus Christus worden."},{"question":"' ත්‍රී' යන තනි අකුරේ වචනය,එකම අර්ථයක් ඇතිව, සිංහල සහ ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂා වලට එකතු වූයේ කෙසේද?","answer":"ඉන්දු යුරෝපීය භාෂා, එකම මූලයකින් ඇතිවී විකාශනය වී ගොස් තිබීම, මීට හේතුව නොවේද? මෙවැනි වචන බොහොමයක් තිබෙනවා.නැහැ, නැත (සිංහල), නත්ථි (පාලි), නහීං (හින්දි), No, Not (ඉංග්‍රීසි), න්‍යත් (රුසියානු)මව, පියා, රජ , යන වචන සම්බන්ධයෙනුත්, පෙරදිග හා අපරදිග භාෂාවන් ගණනාවක් අතර මෙවැනි සමානතාවක් තිබෙනවා.Five -පහEight - අටTwo/ Dwe- ද්වේ- දෙකThree - ත්‍ර - තී - තුනNine - නව- නවයRase -රශ්මි/රැස්ආදි වශයෙනි. ඉන්දියාවේ විනිශ්චයකාර තනතුරකට පත් ඉංග්‍රීසි ජාතිකයෙකු නඩු විසඳීමේ පහසුව සඳහා ඉන්දීය භාෂා ඉගෙනීමට යාමේ දී ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂාව හා සමාන වචන හින්දි ආදි භාෂාවන්හි තිබෙනු දැක ඒ ඔස්සේ පර්යේෂණ කිරීමට යාම මෙහි මූලාරම්භය යි. එය දිගු කතාවක්. කෙසේ වුව ද ලෝකයේ භාෂා පවුල් අතර පෙරදිග - වෛදික - සංස්කෘත - පාලි - සිංහල ආදි භාෂා ද, බටහිර ග්‍රීක්, ලතින් - ඉංග්‍රීසි ආදි භාෂාවන් ද ඉන්දු ආර්ය භාෂා, ඉන්දු යුරෝපීය පවුලට අයත් භාෂාවල මූලය මධ්‍ය ආසියාවේ එක් ප්‍රදේශයක විසූ එඬේර ජනතාව තෘණ භූමි සොයා යන ගමනේ කාලයාගේ ඇවෑමෙන් එක් පිරිසක් බටහිර දෙසට ද තව පිරිසක් පෙරදිග බලා ද ගමන් ඇරඹූ පසු මුලින් කතා කළ එක ම භාෂාව වෙනස් රූපවලට පත්වීම විය. ඒ අනුව සිංහල ද භාෂාවක් වශයෙන් එකී ආර්ය පවුලට අයත් භාෂාවක් බව 1800ගණන්වල මුල් භාගයේ දී හෙළි වී තිබේ. වැඩි විස්තර සඳහා සිංහල භාෂාවේ පරිණාමය පිළිබඳ ලියැවුණු කෘති කියවන්න."},{"question":"RISC-V teknolojisi nedir? ","answer":"RISC-V, açık kaynaklı bir işlemci tasarımı ve mikroişlemci mimarisidir. RISC-V, \\"Reduced Instruction Set Computing (Azaltılmış Komut Seti Bilgisayarları)\\" teriminin kısaltmasıdır.RISC-V'nin en önemli özelliklerinden biri, lisanslama ücretlerinin olmamasıdır. Diğer işlemci tasarımlarının aksine, RISC-V kullanımı için herhangi bir lisans ücreti ödenmesi gerekmez. Bu nedenle, RISC-V, özellikle küçük ve orta ölçekli işletmeler ve geliştiriciler tarafından tercih edilmektedir.RISC-V ayrıca, birçok farklı uygulama alanı için özelleştirilebilir ve ölçeklenebilir olması ile de dikkat çeker. Bu, farklı işlemci tasarımlarının kolayca oluşturulabilmesini sağlar ve özellikle entegre devreler (IC'ler) için özelleştirilmiş çözümler sunar.Sonuç olarak, RISC-V açık kaynaklı bir işlemci tasarımı olarak hem kullanıcıların hem de işletmelerin ihtiyaçlarını karşılayabilecek bir seçenek sunar ve gelecekte daha yaygın olarak kullanılması beklenmektedir."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Fangirifiriana\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Fangirifiriana\\" dia \\"Fanaintainana\\" "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Giám đốc CDC Cà Mau bị bắt","answer":"Chiều 31/7, Công an tỉnh Cà Mau khởi tố bị can, bắt tạm giam ông Đặng Hải Đăng (56 tuổi, Giám đốc Trung tâm Kiểm soát bệnh tật tỉnh Cà Mau) về tội Vi phạm quy định về đấu thầu gây hậu quả nghiêm trọng. Cùng bị bắt tạm giam về tội này còn có ông Hồ Quang Nhu, Phó trưởng Phòng Kế hoạch - Nghiệp vụ CDC Cà Mau và Lê Ngọc Định, Trưởng Phòng Kế hoạch - Tài chính thuộc Sở Y tế tỉnh Cà Mau. Kết quả điều tra xác định từ tháng 1/2020 đến tháng 10/2021, Sở Y tế, CDC Cà Mau và Bệnh viện Đa khoa tỉnh Cà Mau thực hiện 11 gói thầu mua kít xét nghiệm Covid-19, máy tách chiết DNA/RNA tự động, hóa chất, sinh phẩm và thiết bị phục vụ công tác phòng chống dịch của Công ty Việt Á với số tiền 49,47 tỷ đồng. Trong đó, Sở Y tế Cà Mau mua kít xét nghiệm Covid- 19 của Công ty Việt Á cao hơn so với chi phí sản xuất (đã bao gồm 5% lợi nhuận và chi phí khác), dẫn đến thiệt hại khoảng 9,156 tỷ đồng; còn lại gói thầu 40.000 kít chưa thanh quyết toán. Đối với CDC Cà Mau, đơn vị này mua kít xét nghiệm Covid- 19 của Công ty Việt Á cao hơn so với giá của chi phí sản xuất (đã bao gồm 5% lợi nhuận và chi phí khác) gây thiệt hại hơn 3 tỷ đồng. Theo cơ quan điều tra, khi thực hiện hồ sơ đấu thầu mua kít xét nghiệm Covid-19, các bị can đã thực hiện không đúng quy định về đấu thầu, không bảo đảm công bằng, minh bạch. Việc làm này là vi phạm các hành vi bị cấm trong đấu thầu quy định tại Khoản 6 Điều 89 Luật Đấu thầu, gây thiệt hại cho ngân sách Nhà nước hơn 12,2 tỷ đồng."},{"question":"ஓடையில கருப்பு மீனு துள்ளி விளையாடுது அது என்ன ?","answer":"விடை: கண்"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકના એક લેખનના શરૂઆતના ફકરા નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"નાના કાકા: “ભઈ, હવે રાગડો તાણતો રહીશ ? ત્યાં તને તે કાંઈ કચેરીમાં લઈ જાય છે કે ? ત્યાં કચેરીમાં છોકરાંનું શું દાટ્યું હોય ?”⁠“એં...એં...એં...મારે બાપુ પાસે જાવું છે. એં...એં...એં...!”⁠નાના કાકા :“છાનો રે'છે કે નહિ ? હું વાંચુ છું તે મને ગડબડ થાય છે. ચુપ !”⁠નાની કાકી : “એમ એને ન થાય. છોકરું છે તે રડે. ભઈજી સાથે લઈ ગયા હોત તો શું થાત ? ત્યાં બેઠું બેઠું રમત.”⁠“લે રાખ, બહુ ડહાપણ છે તે.” ​⁠“બાપુ રમણ ! આમ આવ પેંડો આપું.”⁠“મારે પેંડો નથી ખાવો. મારે બાપુ પાસે જાવું છે. એં...એં...એં...!”⁠“ઈ એમ માને એવો નથી. એમ તો ઊંધી ખોપરીનો છે. કેમ અલ્યા મૂંગો રે'છે કે નહિ ? આ લાકડી લીધી સમજજે. ત્યાં મારા આગળ નહિ ચાલે. ઈ બધું તારી બા ને બાપા આગળ ચાલે.”\\"આ લેખને પૂરો કરો.","answer":"⁠રમણ રડે છે, વધારે રડે છે, ભેંકડો તાણીને રડે છે.⁠કાકી: “તમે એમ કરો મા. તમારી ભાભી હમણાં આવશે તો વળી કે'શે કે છોકરાને ઘઘલાવે છે. બાપુ રમણ ! આમ આવ, આપણે ઘઉં વીણીએ. લે હું તને કાંકરા દેતી જાઉં.”⁠રમણ : “ એં...એં...એં... મારે બાપુ પાસે જાવું છે. એં...એં...એં...”⁠રમણ પગ પછાડે છે. ત્યાં બા આવે છે. “શું કામ રડે છે, બેટા ?”⁠“બાપુ પાસે જાવું છે. મને હારે ન લઈ ગ્યા. મારે જાવું છે. એં...એં...એં...”⁠“તે તારા બાપુ કચેરીમાં ક્યારે ગયા ?”⁠“હમણાં ગ્યા. મારે જાવું છે. એં...”⁠“પણ રમણ ! આપણે તો માશીને ત્યાં જાવું છે ને ? માશીને આપણે નો'તુ કીધું કે અમે તમારે ત્યાં આવશું ? ચાલ, ઝટઝટ લૂગડાં પહેરી લે; આપણે જઈએ.”⁠“એં...એં...એં... અમારે આ ચોરણી નથી પે'રવી, ઓલી પે'રવી છે. એં...” ​⁠“ઠીક ઈ પહેરાવું. ઓલી ટોપી પહેરીશ કે આ ?”⁠“આ.”⁠“ઠીક, ઈ લે. લ્યો ચાલો હવે આપણે માશીને ત્યાં ઊપડીએ.”⁠“બા, રસ્તામાં કચેરી આવે છે કે નહિ ?”⁠“હા, હા, આવે છે તો ખરી. આઘેથી હું તને તારા બાપુ ક્યાં બેસે છે તે બતાવીશ.”"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा कोरड्याबरोबर ओले ही जळते","answer":"निरपराध्याची अपराध्यासोबत गणना करणे"},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Japon?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Japon mu ngi tudd Tokyo."},{"question":"১৯৬৯-এর গণঅভ্যুত্থানের ফলে 'ক' অঞ্চলে সংঘটিত হয়। মুক্তিযুদ্ধ এবং ঐ অঞ্চলটি স্বাধীন হয় ১৯৭১ এর ডিসেম্বরে। কিন্তু ১৯৭৫-এ 'ক' অঞ্চলের সরকার প্রধানকে সপরিবারে হত্যা করা হয় এবং ঐ অঞ্চলে ১৯৭৫-১৯৯০ পর্যন্ত বেসামরিক আদলে সেনাশাসন অব্যাহত থাকে। অবশেষে ১৯৯০-এর গণঅভ্যুত্থানের ফলে 'ক' অঞ্চলে গণতন্ত্রের পুনর্যাত্রা হয়।উদ্দীপকে উল্লেখিত ১৯৭৫-১৯৯০ পর্যন্ত কাদের শাসন আমলকে নির্দেশ করছে? ব্যাখ্যা কর।","answer":"উদ্দীপকে উল্লেখিত ১৯৭৫-১৯৯০ পর্যন্ত সময়কাল সেনা শাসন আমলকে নির্দেশ করছে।১৯৭৫ সালের ১৫ই আগস্টের পর থেকে ১৯৯০ সালের ৬ই ডিসেম্বর পর্যন্ত বাংলাদেশে সেনা শাসন বহাল ছিল। দেশের সংবিধানকে উপেক্ষা করে খন্দকার মোশতাক, বিচারপতি সায়েম, জেনারেল জিয়াউর রহমান, বিচারপতি আহসান উদ্দীন এবং জেনারেল এরশাদ ক্ষমতায় অধিষ্ঠিত হন। তারা নানাভাবে ক্ষমতায় বহাল থাকার চেষ্টা করলেও শেষ পর্যন্ত ক্ষমতায় টিকতে পারেননি।উদ্দীপকে দেখা যায়, ১৯৭১ সালের ডিসেম্বরে 'ক' অঞ্চল স্বাধীন হয়। কিন্তু ১৯৭৫ সালে এই দেশের সরকার প্রধানকে সপরিবারে হত্যা করা হয়। এরপর ১৯৭৫-১৯৯০ পর্যন্ত বেসামরিক আদলে সেনাশাসন অব্যাহত থাকে। কিন্তু ১৯৯০ গণঅভ্যুত্থানের ফলে পুনরায় গণতন্ত্র প্রতিষ্ঠা পায় । এখানে বাংলাদেশে বঙ্গবন্ধুকে সপরিবারে হত্যার পর দীর্ঘ সময় ধরে সেনা শাসন বহালের চিত্র প্রতিফলিত হয়েছে। ১৯৭৫ সালের ১৫ই আগস্ট বঙ্গবন্ধু সপরিবারে নিহত হওয়ার পর খন্দকার মোশতাক সংবিধান লঙ্ঘন করে নিজেকে রাষ্ট্রপতি পদে অধিষ্ঠিত করেন। কিন্তু খন্দকার মোশতাক, বিচারপতি সায়েম, বিচারপতি আহসান উদ্দিন এদের কারোরই শাসনামল দীর্ঘস্থায়ী হয়নি। জেনারেল জিয়াউর রহমান এবং জেনারেল এরশাদ দীর্ঘ সময় ধরে ক্ষমতায় অধিষ্ঠিত ছিলেন। দেশে সেনা শাসন বহাল রেখে সুবিধামতো সময়ে জেনারেল জিয়াউর রহমান এবং জেনারেল এরশাদ নির্বাচন সম্পন্ন করে বেসামরিক শাসন চালু করেন। কিন্তু অগণতান্ত্রিক সেনা শাসনের বিরুদ্ধে দীর্ঘ আন্দোলন সংগ্রামের পর অবশেষে ১৯৯১ সালে গণতন্ত্রের পুনর্যাত্রা শুরু হয়। তাই বলা যায়, ১৯৭৫-১৯৯০ পর্যন্ত সেনাশাসন বহাল ছিল।"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 忘年会の予約　新型コロナが広がる前の69％に戻る","answer":"12月は忘年会の季節です。レストランの予約をするウェブサイトによると、12月の予約は、新型コロナウイルスが広がる前の69％に戻りました。11月23日までに入っている予約です。4人以下で予約するグループが、2019年は30.3％でしたが、今年は58.1％に大きく増えました。調べた会社は「新型コロナが広がる前の大勢の忘年会ではなくて、少ない人数で楽しむ人が多くなりました。しかし、テーブルを消毒するなどの店の仕事も増えています。予約が増えても、働く人が足りないことが問題です」と話しています。"},{"question":"Gade pasaj ki anba a epi reponn kesyon an apre nan menm lang ak pasaj la:  Pasaj: Yon mwa pita, li Secker te batize li piblikman nan Norfolk House. Papa ak manman li te wa nan peyi Laswèd (pou ki moun Lord Baltimore te kanpe pwokire), tonton li Duke nan Saxe-Gotha (pou ki moun Lord Carnarvon te kanpe pwokire) ak matant-grann li Rèn nan Prusy (pou ki moun Lady Charlotte Edwin te kanpe pwokire). Prince George te grandi kòm yon timoun ki an sante, men rezève ak timid. Fanmi an te deplase nan Leicester Square, kote George ak pi piti frè l 'Prince Edward, Duke nan York ak Albany, yo te edike ansanm pa pwofesè prive. Lèt fanmi montre ke li te kapab li ak ekri nan tou de angle ak Alman, osi byen ke kòmantè sou evènman politik nan tan an, pa laj la nan uit. Li te premye monak Britanik ki te etidye syans sistematikman. Apa de chimi ak fizik, leson li yo enkli astwonomi, matematik, franse, Latin, istwa, mizik, jewografi, komès, agrikilti ak lwa konstitisyonèl, ansanm ak espò ak reyalizasyon sosyal tankou dans, kloti, ak monte cheval. Edikasyon relijye li te antyèman Anglikan. Nan laj 10, George te patisipe nan yon pwodiksyon fanmi nan jwe Joseph Addison a Cato e li te di nan pwolog la nouvo: \\"Ki sa, tho 'yon ti gason! Li ka avèk verite dwe di, yon ti gason nan Angletè fèt, nan Angletè elve. \\" Istoryen Romney Sedgwick te diskite ke liy sa yo parèt \\"yo dwe sous la nan fraz la sèlman istorik ak ki li se ki asosye\\". Granpapa George a, wa George II, pa t'renmen Prince Wales la, e li te pran ti enterè nan pitit pitit li yo. Sepandan, nan 1751 Prince de Wales mouri sanzatann nan yon aksidan nan poumon a laj de 44, ak George te vin eritye nan fòtèy la. Li eritye tit papa l 'nan Duke nan Edinburgh. Koulye a, plis enterese nan pitit pitit li, twa semèn pita wa a te kreye George Prince of Wales (tit la pa otomatikman akeri).  Kesyon: Ki kalite timoun Prince George te ye?","answer":"yon timoun ki an sante men ki rezève e ki timid"},{"question":"شكون اكبر بلد في افريقيا؟","answer":"الجزائر"},{"question":"Буламык деп эмнени айтабыз?","answer":"Буламык 🤱наристеге бөбөктөргө бир жолу жегидей курсагы тоё тургандай бышырылып берилчү 🍚тамак.Жасалышы сары майга унду кызартып кууруп алып муздаган соң бир идишке салып коёбуз. Бир өлчөмдөгү куурулган унга сүт кошулуп бөлтөксүз чайып алып жай отко 5-10 мүнөт аралаштырып бышырып алабыз. Бир аздан кийин жылуу болгондо балага берилет🧑‍🍼.Тамак жей албаган карыяларга да тамак жей албай калгандарга да жасап беришет."},{"question":"Sei iyo SEC iri yakanakisa nhabvu musangano muAmerica?","answer":"Iyo SEC ndiyo yakanakisa musangano wezvikonzero zvakati wandei. Mutambo weNyika wakabva kuSEC 13 nguva kubva 2006. Zvigadziko zvevateveri hazvifananidzi mukuda kwavo kwebhola uye chokwadi chakatendeseka ndechokuti bhora inzira yehupenyu muSEC."},{"question":"“బ్రిటీష్ పాలకులను తరిమివెయ్యటానికి అతడు రహస్యంగా జర్మనీకి, అక్కడి నుండి జపానుకు వెళ్ళి 1942లో భారతీయ సైనికులతో ఒక సైన్యాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేశాడు.” ఈ వాక్యంలో చర్చించబడిన జాతీయ నాయకుడు ఎవరు?","answer":"సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్."},{"question":"ચાના પ્રકાર જણાવો","answer":"ચા ના અલગ અલગ પ્રકારો: અમુક પ્રખ્યાત ચા ના પ્રકાર બ્લેક ટીહર્બલ ટી ગ્રીન ટીજાસ્મિન તીજીંજર ટીએલચી ટી"},{"question":"Gieo ngẫu nhiên xúc xắc một lần. Tính xác suất của mỗi biến cố sau:a) “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là ước của 6”;b) “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là số chia 3 dư 2”.","answer":"Lời giải:Tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra khi gieo xúc xắc một lần là:A = {1 chấm; 2 chấm; 3 chấm; 4 chấm; 5 chấm; 6 chấm}.Số phần tử của tập hợp A bằng 6.a) Từ 1 đến 6 có các ước của 6 là: 1; 2; 3; 6.Do đó có 4 kết quả thuận lợi cho biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là ước của 6”.Khi đó xác suất của biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là ước của 6” bằng 4/6 = 2/3b) Từ 1 đến 6 có các số chia 3 dư 2 là: 2; 5.Do đó có 2 kết quả thuận lợi cho biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là số chia 3 dư 2”.Khi đó xác suất của biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là số chia 3 dư 2” bằng 2/6 = 1/3"},{"question":"テレビや映画の内容を小説化することを英語で何というでしょう？","answer":"ノベライゼーション"},{"question":"\\"සැළලිහිණි කොවුල් හඬ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"සැළලිහිණි කොවුල් හඬ රැව් දෙන්නාමහ උයනක සිරි ඉතිරේමුවරැල අතරේ වග වළසුන්ගේරඟ මඬලකි මේ උයනේනීල කොබෝ රෑන ගිරාපිල් විදහා රඟනා මොණරාකට ඇද කිරළා සහ වලි කුකුළාහොට දිග පිළිහුඬුවාඅප දැකලා බිය වැදිලා තරගෙට හඬ නැගුවාකොළ දිවියා රළු කොටියාකපටි රජා නම් ලද හිවලාවිසකුරු පොළඟා මිනි කන කිඹුලාපොතුහැර කබරගොයාරට පිඹුරා ළඟම නයා දරණ ගසා සිටියාසී. ටී. ප්‍රනාන්දු, ලතා වල්පොලසරත් විමලවීරසී. ටී. ප්‍රනාන්දු"},{"question":"السؤال: من مؤلف رواية آنا كارنينا؟","answer":"الإجابة: ليو تولستوي"},{"question":"كمل الحكي:مش فاهم شو الفرق بين القعده هناك والقعده هون؟ ليش مصرين تروحه هناك.","answer":"المكان فاضي ما فيه جنس الحضاره."},{"question":"هيٺ ڏنل بيت ڏانهن اشارو ڪريو ۽ پوءِ ساڳئي ٻوليءَ ۾ سوال جو جواب ڏيو:  گذرڻ: بنيادي طور تي سلائيٽ پٿر ۽ لوهه جو ٺهيل آهي ، آئو ٻاهران شمسي نظام جي ٻين سيٽلائيٽن جي ڀيٽ ۾ زميني سيٽن جي ڀيٽ ۾ وڌيڪ ويجهو آهي ، جيڪي گهڻو ڪري پاڻي جي برف ۽ سلائيٽس جي ميلاپ مان ٺهيل آهن. آئيو جي کثافت 3.5275 g / cm3 آهي ، جيڪا شمسي نظام ۾ ڪنهن به چنڊ کان تمام گهڻي آهي ؛ ٻين گليليائي سيٽلائيٽ کان خاص طور تي وڌيڪ (گنيميڊس ۽ ڪليسٽو خاص طور تي ، جن جي کثافت 1.9 g / cm3 جي چوڌاري آهي) ۽ چنڊ جي 3.344 g / cm3 کان ٿورو وڌيڪ (~ 5.5٪) آهي. ووئجر ۽ گليلو جي ماپ جي ماپ تي ٻڌل ماڊل Io جي ماس، ريڊيس، ۽ چوٿون ڪشش ثقل جي گنجائش (شمارياتي قدر هڪ اعتراض جي اندر ڪئين ماس کي ورهايو ويو آهي) اهو مشورو ڏئي ٿو ته ان جي اندروني هڪ سلائيٽ جي مالدار ڪروٽ ۽ منٽ ۽ هڪ لوهه يا لوهه سلفائيڊ جي مالدار ڪور جي وچ ۾ فرق آهي. Io جي ڌاتوءَ جو مرڪز تقريبن 20 سيڪڙو ان جي ڪاميٽي جو آهي. ڪور ۾ سلفر جي مقدار تي منحصر آهي ، ڪور جي شعاع 350 ۽ 650 ڪلوميٽر ( 400- 200 ميل) جي وچ ۾ آهي جيڪڏهن اهو تقريبن مڪمل طور تي لوهه جو ٺهيل آهي ، يا 550 ۽ 900 ڪلوميٽر (560 -340  ميل) جي وچ ۾ آهي. گليلو جي ميگنيٽوميٽر آئو تي هڪ اندروني ، اندروني مقناطيسي ميدان کي ڳولڻ ۾ ناڪام ٿي ويو ، اهو مشورو ڏئي ٿو ته ڪور  نه آهي. آئو جي اندروني ساخت جي ماڊلنگ اهو مشورو ڏئي ٿي ته منٽلي گهٽ ۾ گهٽ 75 سيڪڙو مگنيشيم سان مالا مال معدني فارسٽرائٽ مان ٺهيل آهي ، ۽ ان جي بلڪ ساخت ايل-چونڊرائٽ ۽ ايل ايل-چونڊرائٽ ميٽورائٽس جي برابر آهي ، چنڊ يا زمين جي ڀيٽ ۾ لوهه جو مواد وڌيڪ آهي (سلائيڪن جي مقابلي ۾) ، پر مريخ کان گهٽ آهي. Io تي مشاهدو ڪيل گرمي جي وهڪري جي حمايت ڪرڻ لاءِ ، Io جي منٽ جو 20-10 گھٽ ٪ پگھريل ٿي سگھي ٿو ، جيتوڻيڪ علائقن ۾ جتي تيز درجه حرارت وارو آتش فشاں مشاهدو ڪيو ويو آهي شايد پگھلڻ جا وڌيڪ حصا آهن. بهرحال ، 2009 ۾ گليليو ميگنيٽوميٽر جي ڊيٽا جو ٻيهر تجزيو ظاهر ڪيو ته گھٽ هڪ گھٽ  متاثر ٿيل مقناطيسي ميدان جي موجودگي ، سطح کان 50 ڪلوميٽر (31 ميل) هيٺ هڪ مگما سمنڊ جي ضرورت آهي. 2011 ۾ شايع ٿيل وڌيڪ تجزيو اهڙي سمنڊ جو سڌو ثبوت فراهم ڪيو. اها پرت 50 ڪلوميٽر ٿلهي هجڻ جو اندازو آهي ۽ آئي او جي تقريبن 10 سيڪڙو ٺاهي ٿي...  سوال: لو جي ڪور جو ڪيترو حصو ماس جو ٺهيل آهي؟","answer":"20 سيڪڙو"},{"question":"(x-y)(x-y) ගුණිතය ප්‍රසාරණය කළ විට ලැබෙන පිළිතුර කුමක්ද?","answer":"එම ගුණිතය ප්‍රසාරණය කළ විට ලැබෙන පිළිතුර x^2 - 2xy + y^2 වේ."},{"question":"Sarotra aminao ny mitantana ny fotoananao sy manatanteraka ny fe-potoana farany. Ahoana no ahafahanao manatsara?Manana safidy roa ianao.Safidy 1: Miezaka miasa aingana kokoa mba hahatratrarana ny fe-potoana farany.Safidy 2: Mandamina sy mandrindra ny fotoana amin'ny fomba mahomby kokoa amin'ny fampiasana fitaovana fitantanana fotoana.","answer":"Safidy tsara indrindra: Safidy 2 no tsara indrindra. Mandamina sy mandrindra ny fotoana amin'ny fomba mahomby kokoa amin'ny fampiasana fitaovana fitantanana fotoana. Ny fitantanana fotoana mahomby dia zava-dehibe kokoa noho ny miasa aingana."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இனமானம் தன்மானத்திலும் பெரிது. உண்மையிலும் பெரிது, பட்டம் பெற்ற கல்வியிலும் பெரிது, பண ஊற்றுள்ள உத்தியோகத்திலும் பெரிது."},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং হ্যাঁ বা না দিয়ে প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিন। উত্তর দেওয়া সম্ভব না হলে উল্লেখ করুন |প্রশ্ন :তিব্বতী বৌদ্ধধর্মের অন্যতম প্রধান ধর্মসম্প্রদায় দ্গে-লুগ্স ধর্মসম্প্রদায়ের প্রথম দলাই লামার নাম কী ?অনুচ্ছেদ :তিব্বতের ইতিহাস মূলত তিব্বতী বৌদ্ধধর্মের ইতিহাস ও বিবর্তনের সঙ্গে ওতপ্রোত ভাবে জড়িত। এই ধর্ম শুধুমাত্র তিব্বতী সংস্কৃতি নয়, মঙ্গোল ও মাঞ্চু জাতির গৌরবোজ্জ্বল সংস্কৃতি গড়ে তুলতে সহায়ক হয়ে ওঠে। ভারত ও চীনের মতো দুইটি সুপ্রাচীন সভ্যতার মধ্যবর্তী স্থানে তিব্বতী সভ্যতার বিস্তার ঘটে। তিব্বত মালভূমির পূর্বে অবস্থিত পর্বতশ্রেণী তিব্বত ও চীনের মধ্যেকার সীমান্ত হিসেবে দীর্ঘকাল অবস্থান করেছ, অপরদিকে হিমালয়ের সুউচ্চ পর্বতশ্রেণী ভারত ও নেপালের রাজ্যগুলি থেকে তিব্বতকে পৃথক করে রেখেছে। এই দুই সভ্যতার মধ্যে মূলতঃ ভারত থেকে শান্তরক্ষিত, কমলশীল, বিমলমিত্র, অতীশ দীপঙ্করের মতো বহু বিখ্যাত মহাযানী বৌদ্ধ পন্ডিত এবং পদ্মসম্ভবের মতো বিখ্যাত তান্ত্রিক তিব্বতের দুর্গম পথে যাত্রা করে তিব্বতী শাসককদের পৃষ্ঠপোষকতায় তন্ত্রসমৃদ্ধ তিব্বতী বৌদ্ধধর্মের সূচনা ও প্রসার করলে তিব্বতে একটি ধর্ম ও তন্ত্রকেন্দ্রিক সংস্কৃতি গড়ে ওঠে।তিব্বত সাম্রাজ্যতিব্বত একটি শক্তিশালী সাম্রাজ্য হিসেবে গড়ে ওঠে যখন গ্নাম-রি-স্রোং-ব্ত্সন[1]:২৯৮ নামক ইয়ার্লুং উপত্যকার একজন গোষ্ঠীইপতি আনুমানিক ৬০০ খ্রিষ্টাব্দে ঐ উপত্যকা এবং তার পার্শ্ববর্তী অঞ্চলের সমস্ত গোষ্ঠীদের একের পর এক যুদ্ধে পরাজিত করে সমগ্র মধ্য তিব্বত নিজের অধিকারে নিয়ে আসেন এবং এক শক্তিশালী কেন্দ্রীয় শাসনব্যবস্থা গঠন করতে সক্ষম হন, যার ফলে তিব্বত মালভূমির বিভিন্ন গোষ্ঠী একত্রিত হয়।[2]:৫ ৬১৮ অথবা ৬২৯ খ্রিষ্টাব্দে বিদ্রোহীদের দ্বারা বিষক্রিয়ার মাধ্যমে হত্যা গ্নাম-রি-স্রোং-ব্ত্সনকে হত্যা করা হলে, তাঁর পুত্র স্রোং-ব্ত্সন-স্গাম-পো এই বিদ্রোহ দমন করে একটি শক্তিশালী সাম্রাজ্য হিসেবে দেশকে গড়ে তোলেন। [3]:১৯ [4]:৪৪৩ তিনি সুমপা জাতি[5]:১৩০,১৪৭, ঝাংঝুং রাজ্য[1]:৫৯[6]:৩০[7]:১২৭,১২৮, তুয়ুহুন রাজ্য এবং ট্যাং সাম্রাজ্যের সীমান্তপ্রদেশ সোংঝৌ আক্রমণ করেন[8]:১৬৮,১৬৯ তাঁর রাজত্বে তিব্বতে প্রথম বৌদ্ধ ধর্ম প্রবেশ করে। তিনি লাসা শহরে জোখাং সহ বহু বৌদ্ধ মন্দির স্থাপন করেন।[9][10] ও লাসা শহরকে তিনি সুসজ্জিত করে রাজধানীর মর্যাদা দেন।[11][12] তাঁর মন্ত্রী থু-মি-সাম-ভো-তাকে তিব্বতী ভাষার জন্য লিপি প্রস্তুত করলে তিব্বতে বৌদ্ধ ধর্মগ্রন্থগুলি সংস্কৃত থেকে তিব্বতী ভাষায় অনুবাদ[13] ও সংবিধান রচনা শুরু হয়।[14] তাঁর পৌত্র সম্রাট খ্রি-মাং-স্লোন-র্ত্সান পশ্চিম তুর্কী খাগানাতের সাথে বন্ধুত্ব স্থাপন করে এই দুই শক্তি ৬৬৩...","answer":"প্রদত্ত প্রসঙ্গের উপর ভিত্তি করে সঠিক উত্তরটি কী হওয়া উচিত তা আমি নিশ্চিত নই।"},{"question":"‘Kinni’ ọlọpaa dun mọ Mariam, lo ba kọ ọkọ ẹ silẹ n’Ibadan","answer":"Owe awọn agba kan lo sọ pe tojú bọlé ló mọ ibi ọbẹ̀ ti dùn. Awọn Yoruba yii kan naa ni wọn powe mi-in pe bọ́mọdé ba róyin a sàkàrà nù. Ati ikinni ati ikeji owe yii lo ṣe wẹ́kú mọ iyawo ile kan lara pẹlu bo ṣe deede kọ ọkọ ẹ silẹ lẹyin to ti tọ́ kinni ọlọpaa wo, to si ri i pe o dun ju tọkọ oun lọ.Ọdun kejila ree ti obinrin yii, Mariam Adewọyin, pẹlu ọkọ ẹ, Saheed Adewọyin, ti ṣegbeyawo. Ṣugbọn lati bii ọdun meji ti obinrin oniṣowo yii ti bẹrẹ si i yan ọlọpaa lale, to si ti n tọ kondo ọlọpaa wo, to ri i pe kinni ọhun dun labẹ ju ti ọlọkada to gbe oun sile lọ, ni igbeyawo ọhun ti fori ṣanpọn.Gẹgẹ bii iwadii ALAROYE, nigba ti Mariam kọkọ pade agbofinro, ti  iyẹn ti n la kondo nla mọ ọn labẹ, lo ti bẹrẹ si i fi ọkọ ẹ ṣe faari nigbakuugba ti iyẹn ba fi oorun lọ ọ gẹgẹ bii ololufẹ. Ṣugbọn nigba ti kinni ọlọpaa dun mọ ọn pata, niṣe lo kuku yari fun ọkọ ẹ kanlẹ, o loun ko le fara oun silẹ fun un mọ, nitori oun ko gbadun kinni ẹ mọ o jare.Ṣugbọn bo ṣe wà ní lìkì, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà ló wà ní gbàǹja. Bi kinni agbofinro ṣe da ile ọlọkada ru ni tobinrin oniṣowo yii paapaa da ile ọlọpaa ru. Ọkunrin ta a forukọ bo laṣiiri yii naa ti niyawo atawọn ọmọ nile, ṣugbọn lati igba to ti ṣalabaapade Mariam lo ti pa iyawo atawọn ọmọ ẹ ti patapata, ṣe wọn ko kuku jọ gbe papọ tẹlẹ, owo lo fi n ranṣẹ si wọn lati maa fi jẹun ni tiwọn. Iyawo oniyawo to mọ ere e ṣe daadaa lo ku to n fi aaye silẹ fun lojoojumọ.Bi ọrọ ba fara sin ní kọ̀kọ̀ títí, bó pẹ́ bó ya, a máa jáde sí gbangba. Awọn ololufẹ ikọkọ yii ba ọrọ ara wọn debi ti aṣiri wọn tu si ọkọ iyawo lọwọ. Iyẹn sọ ọ dija, o si lọọ fẹjọ ọga políìsì sun awọn agbofinro ẹgbẹ ẹ ki wọn le da a lẹkun iwa ibajẹ to n hu.Ko pẹ ko jinna ni wọn gbe agbofinro yii kuro n’Ibadan, o di jùà, niluu Ìgànnà, lagbegbe Oke-Ogun, ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ kan naa. Ṣugbọn kaka ki eyi jẹ oore-ọfẹ fun Saheed lati gbadun iyawo ẹ, nnkan ibanujẹ lo tun jẹ nitori niṣe niṣẹlẹ naa mu un padanu obinrin naa patapata. Idi ni pe bi wọn ṣe gbe ale iyawo ẹ lọ si ilu to jinna yii lọkunrin agbofinro naa ti n ronu bi oun ko ṣe ni i padanu adun to n ri lara iyawo oniyawo. Awọn mejeeji jọ gbadun ara wọn ju ololufẹ kaluku wọn lọ ni. Aṣẹyinwa aṣẹyinbọ, iyawo ọlọkada to ti bimọ mẹta s’Ibadan sa ba ọga políìsì lọ. Lasiko yii, awọn mejeeji ko ṣe ọrọ ifẹ wọn ni bòńkẹ́lẹ́ mọ, wọn kuku ṣegbeyawo alarinrin niluu Ìgànnà ti iṣẹ ijọba gbe ale to pada di ojulowo ọkọ lọ.Iya ọlọmọ mẹta n’Ibadan pada di iyawo aṣẹṣẹgbe ti wọn n fi oju ọmọge wo n’Ígànnà, ko kuku si ẹni to mọ pe o ti bimọ ri, oun naa ko si sọ fẹnikan pe iyawo to ti ni iriri ọpọlọpọ ọdun lọọdẹ ọkunrin kan n’Ibadan ri loun yatọ si ọkọ rẹ tuntun to mọ gbogbo bo ṣe n lọ.Ni bayii ti iyawo tuntun n’Ígàngán ti n gbadun oorun bo ṣe wu u pẹlu ọkọ ẹ, ko fẹ ohunkohun to le da igbadun ọhun duro mọ bo ti wù kó mọ. N lo ba gba kootu ibilẹ Ọja’ba, n’Ibadan lọ, o loun fẹẹ kọ ọkọ oun aarọ silẹ, ki ile-ẹjọ ba oun fopin si igbeyawo ọlọdun mejila to wa laarin awọn.Awijare olupẹjọ ni kootu ni pe olujẹjọ ki i tọju oun, ati pe ija lawọn maa n ja ṣaa lojoojumọ. Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Ọdaju ọkunrin ni. Ki i tọju mi rara.  Mo jẹ ẹnikan lowo, ọkọ mi waa lọọ sọ fun ẹni yẹn  pe ko ja mi sihooho. Iya ẹ naa mọ nipa ọrọ yii, wọn jọ gbimọ-pọ pẹlu awọn to ja mi sihooho ni. Nibi ti mo ti n gbowo lọwọ ẹni ti mo tajà fun lọwọ ni wọn ti ja mi sihooho nita gbangba.“Iṣẹlẹ yẹn wa lara idi to jẹ ki n kuro nile ẹ fun ọdun kan ati oṣu mẹjọ. Abikẹyin wa nikan ni mo gbe dání lọ, awọn mejeeji ta a bi ṣaaju nikan ni mo fi silẹ pẹlu ẹ. Igba Naira (N200) lo si n fun mi gẹgẹ bii owo ounjẹ ọmọ to wa lọdọ mi lojumọ.“O maa n bẹ mi pe ki n pada sile oun nitori awọn ọmọ. Mo pada sibẹ ninu oṣu karun-un, ọdun yii, ṣugbọn gbogbo ẹru mi lo ti ta tan ki n too de.“Gbogbo ọna lo n wa ki n fi loyun foun lẹyin ti mo pada de, ṣugbọn mi o jẹ ki ọrọ oyun waye. Nitori pe mo kọ lati loyun fun un lo ṣe n sọ pe mo n yan ọlọpaa lale.”Olupẹjọ waa rọ ile-ẹjọ naa lati fopin si ibaṣepọ to wa laarin oun ati ọlọkada naa nitori ifẹ ẹ ti yọ kuro lọkan oun patapata. Bẹẹ lo sọ pe oun fara mọ kile-ẹjọ yọnda itọju awọn ọmọ mẹtẹẹta ti oun bi fun baba wọn. Gegẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, nigba ti awọn ẹbi ọkọ gbọ pe iyawo awọn ti ṣegbeyawo bonkẹlẹ pẹlu ọlọpaa lẹyin odi ni wọn gbe igbesẹ lati da sẹria fun un, ti wọn si ja a sihooho nita gbangba.Ọkan ninu awọn ẹgbọn Saheed, ẹni to fara han nile-ejọ lati jẹrii ta ko olupẹjọ sọ pe iya awọn ko mọ nipa bi wọn ṣe ja Mariam sihooho. Ṣugbọn oun lo oore-ọfẹ ihoho ti wọn ja a si ọhun lati gba ẹrọ ibanisọrọ rẹ lọwọ ẹ nitori o jẹ oun lẹgbẹrun marundinlaaadọta Naira (N45,000).Obinrin oniṣowo yii sọ pe nitori owo ti iyawo aburo oun ya lọwọ oun, ṣugbọn to kọ lati da pada yii  loun ṣe gba foonu ẹ, oore-ọfẹ asiko ti wọn ja a sihooho yii loun lo lati gba foonu lọwọ ẹ titi digba ti yoo fi sanwo gbese to jẹ ounNinu ọrọ tiẹ, Saheed sọ pe oun fara mọ kile-ẹjọ fopin si ibaṣepọ oun ati olupẹjọ nitori obinrin naa ki i ṣe obinrin ti wọn n firu ẹ tọrọ niyawo.Ọkunrin ọlọkada yii ṣalaye pe “Baba nla oniranu lobinrin tẹ ẹ n wo yii. Ọlọpaa lo n yan lale. Koda, mo ti ka awọn mejeeji mọ ori ara wọn ri. Lanlọọdu ọlọpaa yẹn gan-an ti lu mi nigba ti mo sọ ọrọ yẹn di wahala ko too mọ pe iyawo mi ni tẹnanti oun n ba laṣepọ.“Mo fẹjọ ọlọpaa yẹn sun lagọọ ọlọpaa. Ẹyin igba yẹn ni wọn gbe e lọ siluu Iganna, to si lọọ ṣegbeyawo pẹlu iyawo mi nibẹ.“Ohun to tiẹ maa n dun mi ni bi iyawo mi ṣe maa n fi ale rẹ halẹ mọ mi. Aa ni ọrẹ oun ọlọpaa ti di mòpóòlù, ki n jẹ ma ṣe mọnamọna pẹlu ẹ ko ma lọọ yinbọn pa mi.”O ni oun fara mọ kile-ẹjọ tu igbeyawo oun pẹlu obinrin naa ka, ṣugbọn ki wọn ma gba a laye lati mu awọn ọmọ sọdọ, nitori ki i ṣe obinrin to raaye ọrọ ọmọ rara.Ninu idajọ wọn, igbimọ awọn adajọ kootu naa, labẹ akoso Oloye Ọdunade Ademọla, Alhaji Suleiman Apanpa ati Alhaji Rafiu Raji ti fopin si igbeyawo ọlọdun mejila to seso ọmọ mẹta naa.Olujẹjọ ni wọn yọnda awọn ọmọ wọn mẹtẹẹta fun. Ṣugbọn wọn ni ko san ẹgbẹrun meji Naira (N2,000) fun olupẹjọ lati ko ẹru rẹ lọ sibi to ba fẹẹ lọ nigboro ilu Ibadan."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"தீண்டாமை என்பதே சாதி காரணமாக ஏற்பட்டதே தவிர, அதற்கு வேறு காரணமே ஆதாரமே இல்லை. சாதியை வைத்துக்கொண்டு தீண்டாமை ஒழிய வேண்டும் என்பது சிறிதும் அறிவுடைமையாகாது."},{"question":"Saya mempunyai hubungan yang rumit dengan fasilitas penyeberangan. Saya senang menggunakannya tiap hari, tetapi sekaligus juga membencinya. Dengan gerigi lantainya yang aus, jembatan penyeberangan jadi licin ketika hujan sehingga harus berjalan dengan sangat berhati-hati di atasnya.Apakah sentimen dari kalimat di atas? (Positif/Negatif/Netral) Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya. Sebutkan juga aspek sentimen dari kalimat ulasan tersebut.Jawaban:","answer":"Kalimat tersebut merupakan kalimat bersentimen negatif karena disusun dari aspek sentimen yang kategorinya negatif. Selain itu, ulasan tersebut juga meggunakan kata-kata bermakna negatif, seperti: membencinya; gerigi lantainya yang aus; jadi licin. Aspek sentimennya antara lain: 1. kondisi dan keamanan --> sentiment negatifKalimat: Dengan gerigi lantainya yang aus, jembatan penyeberangan jadi licin ketika hujan sehingga harus berjalan dengan sangat berhati-hati di atasnya."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--उतावळा नवरा गुडघ्याला बाशिंग","answer":"अतिशय उतावीळपणाचे वर्तन करणे."},{"question":"How does Sri Lanka's traditional \\"Pun Kalasa\\" or decorative water vessel positively contribute to rituals and ceremonies, and what rare designs, occasions, and spiritual contexts distinguish these lesser-known water vessels?","answer":"Sri Lanka's traditional \\"Pun Kalasa,\\" decorative water vessel, positively contributes to rituals and ceremonies with rare designs, occasions, and spiritual contexts that distinguish these lesser-known water vessels. These vessels are adorned with intricate carvings and are used to hold sanctified water during religious ceremonies. The positive impact lies in their role as vessels of purity and auspiciousness, enhancing the spiritual ambiance of rituals. \\"Pun Kalasa\\" becomes a symbol of reverence, preserving rare designs that often depict cultural symbols, religious motifs, and auspicious animals. Embracing these decorative water vessels ensures the continuation of traditional practices that blend artistry with spiritual significance."},{"question":" உலகப் புகழ் பெற்ற டைம் பத்திரிக்கையின் அட்டையில் இருமுறை இடம்பெற்ற முதல் இந்திய கிரிக்கெட் விளையாட்டு வீரர் யார்?","answer":"உலகப் புகழ்பெற்ற டைம் இதழின் அட்டைப்படத்தில் இரண்டு முறை இடம்பெற்ற முதல் இந்திய கிரிக்கெட் வீரர் சச்சின் டெண்டுல்கர் ஆவார்."},{"question":"Noem twee manieren om armoede in een gemeenschap te verminderen.","answer":"Twee manieren om armoede in een gemeenschap te verminderen zijn het ontwikkelen van economische ontwikkelingsinitiatieven om banen en zakelijke kansen te creëren, en het vergroten van de toegang tot gezondheidszorg en onderwijs om mensen de kans te geven die ze nodig hebben om te slagen."},{"question":"There are different types of spatial phenomena and spatial relationships that may be involved in spatial data analysis.These are basically:","answer":"There are different types of spatial phenomena and spatial relationships that may be involved in spatial data analysis.These are basically:1) Entity view of the space2) Field view of the space"},{"question":"جمله اول: در میان فرزندانشان ریچارد ویور ، عضو مجلس بود و توماس ویور ، عضو مجلس و سنای ویسکانسین بود. جمله دوم: فرزندانش \\" توماس ويور \\" ، عضو مجلس ، و \\" ريچارد ويور \\" ، عضو مجلس و سنا در \\" ويسکانسن \\" بودند. سوال: آیا جمله 1 و جمله 2 همان معنی را بیان می کنند؟ بله یا نه؟","answer":"خیر این دو جمله هم‌معنا نیستند. جای شغل‌های دو فرزند با هم عوض شده است."},{"question":"Afaka mahazo VIH ve ny olona iray amin'ny fampidiran-dra?","answer":"Tena azo antoka ny fampidiran-dra ankehitriny, ary ambany dia ambany ny risika hifindran'ny VIH amin'ny alalan'io lalana io any amin'ny faritra misy fanaraha-maso tsara."},{"question":"Атадан калган нарктарыбыз дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"-жуучулукка \\rбаруу-жуучулукка баруу-кудалардын алгачкы \\rтааныштыгын ишке ашырган, «куда болгочо, кул-бийиӊди сураш, куда \\rболгон соӊ, кул да болсо сыйлаш» деген ошондон;\\r-жаш келин келгенде көшөгө тартуу-албетте, бул келин келгендеги ага \\rжасалган алгачкы урмат-сый, болбосо, жайдак жерге отургуса салуу-ыксыз \\rжорук, уялып-тартынып турган жаш келинди тоо шартында көшөгө тартып \\rкиргизүү- ылайыктуу иш болгон;\\r"},{"question":" Qual é a capital da Islândia?","answer":"Reykjavík."},{"question":"ලෝක කාළගුණ දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"ලෝක කාළගුණ දිනය මාර්තු විසි තුනයි. (23)"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut:  Apakah tindakan yang diambil apabila terkena silaun cahaya lampu semasa memandu pada waktu malam?A. Menutup mataB. Memakai kanta mata hitamC. Perlahankan kenderaan","answer":"Jawapannya ialah C. Perlahankan kenderaan"},{"question":"*ما الإسم الحقيقي لأبو لهب ؟","answer":"عبد العزى بن عبد المطلب"},{"question":"\\"CRISPR-Cas12\\" जीन-सम्पादन प्रविधि र बायोटेक्नोलोजीमा यसको प्रयोगहरू व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"CRISPR-Cas12 एक जीन-सम्पादन गर्ने उपकरण हो जुन विशिष्ट जीनहरूलाई लक्षित र परिमार्जन गर्न प्रयोग गरिन्छ। यसमा रोग उपचार र आनुवंशिक ईन्जिनियरिङ् सहित बायोटेक्नोलोजीमा अनुप्रयोगहरू छन्।"},{"question":"Idę do parku. Pada deszcz. Czy powinienem wziąć parasolkę? Dlaczego?","answer":"Tak, bo pada deszcz, a parasolka pozwoli Ci nie zmoknąć.  "},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Comores","answer":"Péeyum réwum Comores mu ngi tudu Moroni"},{"question":"ග්‍රීක දෙවිවරුන්ගේ නිවහන ලෙස ප්‍රකට ග්‍රීසියේ කුමන කන්දද?","answer":"මැසිඩෝනියාවේ ඔලිම්පස් කන්ද ග්‍රීක දෙවිවරුන්ගේ නිවහන ලෙස ප්‍රසිද්ධය. එය ග්‍රීසියේ උසම කන්ද වන අතර ඔවුන් ජීවත් වූ සහ පාලනය කළ දෙවිවරුන්ගේ වාසස්ථානය ලෙස සැලකේ. එය මීටර් 2,917 ක උසකට ළඟා වේ. පුරාවෘත්තයට අනුව, ඔලිම්පස් කඳු මුදුන වලාකුළු සහ මීදුමෙන් වැසී ඇති අතර, මිනිසුන්ගේ ඇස්වලින් දෙවිවරුන් ආරක්ෂා  කර ඇත. මෙම පුරාවෘත්ත කන්ද බොහෝ ග්‍රීක මිථ්‍යාවන්හි ප්‍රධාන භූමිකාවක් ඉටු කළ අතර දිව්‍ය බලයේ සහ අභිරහස සංකේතයක් ලෙස ගෞරවයට පාත්‍ර විය."},{"question":"Who directed the Sri lankan stage play \\"Debidio\\"?","answer":"The Sri Lankan stage play \\"Debidio\\" was directed by Dharmasiri Bandaranayake. Bandaranayake is a renowned figure in Sri Lankan theater, known for his impactful and thought-provoking productions. \\"Debidio\\" is one of his notable works in the realm of stage drama."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de São Cristóvão e Neves?","answer":"Em 2021 o IDH de São Cristóvão e Neves foi de 0,777."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Чоюке Өмүр уулунун устаты ким болгон? а) Тыныбек манасчы б) Шапак манасчы в) Сагынбай манасчы г) Чоң манасчы Акылбек","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚г) Чоң манасчы Акылбек."},{"question":"Ποιος ήταν ο διευθύνων σύμβουλος της δεύτερης μεγαλύτερης εταιρείας ενοικίασης αυτοκινήτων στις ΗΠΑ από πωλήσεις;","answer":"Ρόμπερτ Λ. Στόουν"},{"question":"O ma waa ga o, wọn tun ṣa iya oniyaa ladaa pa l’Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan","answer":"Nigba ti ọkan awọn ara Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan, ti balẹ pe ọwọ awọn agbofinro ti tẹ awọn afurasi ọdaran to n pa awọn eeyan nipakupa kaakiri adugbo awọn, ti alaafia si ti jọba lagbegbe naa, biri lọrọ tun yi lojiji nigba tawọn ẹruuku tun ṣa iya kan ladaa pa lagbegbe yii kan naa l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii.Iya ọhun, Abilekọ Oluwafunmilayọ, ni wọn lọọ ka mọle ẹ to wa laduugbo ti wọn n pe ni Ori Oke-Ọlọrunkọle, l’Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan, ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an alẹ ti wọn si ṣa a ladaa yannayanna.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ni nnkan bii oṣu kan aabọ sẹyin, iyẹn ninu oṣu kẹfa si ibẹrẹ oṣu keje, ọdun 2020 yii, lawọn ọbayejẹ eeyan ti fi ada ati ṣọ́bìrì ṣa eeyan bii mẹwaa pa.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn iranṣẹ iku wọnyi ko ri Abilekọ Oluwafunmilayọ pa lẹsẹkẹsẹ nigba ti wọn ba a lalejo lalẹ ana, nitori ti awọn alabaagbe ẹ sare gbe e lọ sọsibitu nigba ti wọn gbọ to n keboosi irora, irora oju ọgbẹ nla ọhun lo pada pa a nibi ti wọn ti n tọju ẹ lọwọ nileewosan UCH ti wọn gbe e lọ fun iwosan.Nitori bi awọn ẹlẹ́gírí ti ṣe pa ọpọ eeyan nipakupa nijọba ibilẹ Akinyẹle ṣaaju lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii, pẹlu ibinu lawọn ọdọ agbegbe naa fi ya sigboro laaarọ yii (Furaidee) lati fẹhonu han.Awọn ọdọ wọnyi fibinu kọ lu agọ ọlọpaa ijọba ibilẹ naa to wa ni Mọniya, n’Ibadan, wọn ṣe awọn ọlọpaa kan leṣe, bẹẹ ni wọn ba nnkan jẹ ni teṣan naa.Bakan naa la gbọ pe wọn ba awọn nnkan jẹ lawọn ibomi-in lagbegbe ọhun ko too di pe awọn ọlọpaa adigboluja da wọn lẹkun Ibinu.Nigba to n fidi iṣelẹ yi mulẹ, agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, SP Olugbenga Fadeyi, fi aidunnu eẹ han si bi awọn ọdọ ṣe lọọ kọ lu agọ ọlọpaa agbegbe naa, o ni bi iwọde wọn ọhun ṣe la yanpọnyanrin lọ ko tọna rara.O waa fi da gbogbo araalu loju pe laipẹ lọwọ awọn agbofinro yoo tẹ awọn ọdaju eeyan to ṣeku pa iya oniyaa naa, nitori awọn ọlọpaa ti bẹrẹ iwadii lori iṣẹlẹ naa."},{"question":"બાળરમત: \\"કેપ્ટન કેપ્ટન સાઈન બદલ\\" આ નામ ની રમત વિશે જણાવો.","answer":"આ રમતમાં પણ બાળકની સજાગતા વિકસે છે.થોડા બાળકો બેસીને આ રમત રમે.એક બાળક કેપ્ટન બને. આ બાળક જે કોઈ સાઈન કરે એવી જ સાઈન અન્ય બાળકોએ પણ કરવાની - જેમકે કેપ્ટન માથા પર હાથ મુકે તો અન્ય બાળકો પણ માથા પર હાથ મુકે. કેપ્ટન તાલી પડે તો અન્ય બાળકો પણ તાલી પડે...વિ.બાળકો કેપ્ટન સામે જોઈ એ જેવી સાઈન કરે એવી જ સાઈન કરે અને સાથે સાથે બોલે: \\"કેપ્ટન કેપ્ટન સાઈન બદલ..\\"કેપ્ટન જેવી સાઈન કરવામાં કોઈ બાળક ભૂલ કરે (કેપ્ટને સાઈન બદલી હોય છતાં કોઈ બાળકનું ધ્યાન ન રહ્યું હોય) તો એ આઉટ ગણાય.આમ આ રમતમાં બાળકે સજાગ રહીને કેપ્ટન સામે જોઇને એ જે પ્રમાણે સાઈન બદલે એ પ્રમાણે સાઈન બદલવાની હોય છે એટલે એની સજાગતા અને ચપળતા વિકસે છે."},{"question":"Haley Lu Richardson","answer":"Haley Lu Richardson (ti a bi ni 7 March 1995) jẹ oṣere ara ilu Amẹrika kan. Ni atẹle awọn ipa tẹlifisiọnu ni kutukutu lori Disney Channel sitcom Shake It Up (2013) ati eré elere ABC Family Ravenswood (2013 – 2014), o ṣe ni fiimu ti n bọ ti ọjọ-ori The Edge of Seventeen (2016) ati fiimu ibanilẹru ọpọlọ Pipin (2016).Richardson ni ipa breakout rẹ ninu eré ominira Columbus (2017) fun eyiti o gba Aami Eye Fiimu Independent Gotham fun yiyan oṣere ti o dara julọ . O tẹsiwaju lati farahan ni awọn fiimu ominira ti o ni iyin gẹgẹbi Atilẹyin Awọn ọmọbirin (2018), Unpregnant (2020), ati Lẹhin Yang (2022). Ni ọdun 2022, o ṣe irawọ ninu jara anthology HBO The White Lotus (2022).Haley Lu Richardson ni a bi ni Phoenix, Arizona, ọmọbinrin Valerie, onijaja ati alamọja iyasọtọ, ati Forrest L. Richardson, ayaworan papa golf kan. Richardson lọ si Villa Montessori nipasẹ ile-iwe arin, lẹhinna Ile-iwe giga Arcadia . O jẹ deede ni awọn iṣelọpọ iṣere ati awọn idije ijó agbegbe jakejado Iwọ oorun guusu. Lati ọdun 2001 - 2011 o jẹ onijo asiwaju ni Ile-iṣẹ Dance Cannedy ti Phoenix. Ni ọdun 2011, o gbe lọ si Hollywood, California.Ni 2013, Richardson bẹrẹ ipa loorekoore bi Tess ninu jara idile ABC Ravenswood. O ti farahan bi alejo lori Disney Channel 's Shake It Up ati pe o jẹ irawọ kan ni iṣelọpọ awaoko ABC ti “Ti gba”. O ṣe Juliana ni igbesi aye atilẹba fiimu abayo lati ilobirin pupọ, lẹgbẹẹ Jack Falahee . Ni ọdun 2016, o ni ipa loorekoore bi Ellie ni ọna ere Imularada Freeform . Iṣẹ fiimu akọkọ rẹ pẹlu ipa asiwaju ninu Awọn iyokù ti o kẹhin ati awọn iṣẹ atilẹyin ni Edge ti Seventeen ati Pipin.Aṣeyọri rẹ wa ni ọdun 2017 nigbati o ṣe irawọ idakeji John Cho ni Columbus . Fun iṣẹ rẹ ninu fiimu o jẹ yiyan fun 2017 Gotham Independent Film Award fun oṣere ti o dara julọ. Atunwo Columbus ni The New Yorker, Richard Brody yìn iṣẹ rẹ: \\"Richardson ni pato awọn ifinkan si iwaju awọn oṣere iran rẹ pẹlu iṣẹ yii, eyiti o fẹrẹ kọrin pẹlu itara ẹdun ati ọgbọn.\\"Ni ọdun 2019, Richardson ṣe irawọ ninu ere ere ifẹ Five Feet Apart idakeji Cole Sprouse . Ninu fiimu o ṣe alaisan cystic fibrosis ti o ṣubu ni ifẹ pẹlu ọmọkunrin kan ti o ni arun kanna.Ni ọdun 2022 o ṣe irawọ bi Portia ni akoko keji ti awada anthology HBO The White Lotus .Richardson ti n crocheting lati ọdun mẹjọ, ati pe o ni ile itaja Etsy nibiti o ti n ta awọn ẹya ẹrọ ati awọn aṣọ crocheted ti a ṣe lati awọn aṣa tirẹ."},{"question":"Odnieś się do poniższego fragmentu, a następnie odpowiedz na pytanie w tym samym języku, co ten fragment:  W styczniu 1981 roku MOS Technology, Inc., spółka zależna Commodore zajmująca się projektowaniem układów scalonych, zainicjowała projekt projektowania układów graficznych i dźwiękowych dla konsoli gier wideo następnej generacji. Prace projektowe nad chipami, nazwanymi MOS Technology VIC-II (Video Integrated Circuit for graphics) i MOS Technology SID (Sound Interface Device for audio), zostały zakończone w listopadzie 1981 roku. Następnie Commodore rozpoczął projekt konsoli do gier, która użyłaby nowych chipów, zwanych Ultimax lub Commodore MAX Machine, zaprojektowanych przez Yasha Terakura z Commodore Japan. Projekt ten został ostatecznie odwołany po wyprodukowaniu zaledwie kilku maszyn na rynek japoński. Jednocześnie Robert \\"Bob\\" Russell (programista systemu i architekt VIC-20) i Robert \\"Bob\\" Yannes (inżynier SID) krytykowali obecną linię produktów Commodore, która była kontynuacją linii Commodore PET skierowanej do użytkowników biznesowych. Z pomocą Ala Charpentiera (inżyniera VIC-II) i Charlesa Winterble'a (menedżera MOS Technology) zaproponowali dyrektorowi generalnemu Commodore'a Jackowi Tramielowi prawdziwy, tani kontynuacja VIC-20. Tramiel podyktował, że maszyna powinna mieć 64 KB pamięci RAM. Chociaż 64-bitowe dynamiczne układy pamięci DRAM kosztowały wówczas ponad 100 USD (odpowiednik 232,95 USD w 2018 r.), wiedział, że ceny DRAM spadają i spadną do akceptowalnego poziomu przed osiągnięciem pełnej produkcji. Zespół był w stanie szybko zaprojektować komputer, ponieważ, w przeciwieństwie do większości innych firm produkujących komputery domowe, Commodore posiadał własną fabrykę półprzewodników do produkcji chipów testowych; ponieważ fabryka nie działała w pełnej mocy, koszty rozwoju były częścią istniejących kosztów korporacyjnych. Chipy były gotowe do listopada, kiedy to Charpentier, Winterble i Tramiel postanowili kontynuować pracę nad nowym komputerem; ten ostatni wyznaczył ostateczny termin na pierwszy weekend stycznia, aby zbiegać się z targiem Consumer Electronics Show (CES) w 1982 roku. Produkt otrzymał nazwę kodową VIC-40 jako następca popularnego VIC-20. Pytanie: Co oznacza RAM?","answer":"Pamięć o dostępie swobodnym."},{"question":"Dapọ Abiọdun kilọ fẹgbẹ awakọ ero ipinlẹ Ogun, o ni wọn ko gbọdọ de gareeji gbowo ita","answer":"Ijọba Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun ti kilọ fẹgbẹ awakọ ero NURTW, nipinlẹ Ogun, lati yago lawọn gareeji kaakiri ipinlẹ yii, bi wọn ko ba fẹẹ jiya lọdọ ìjọba.Kọmiṣanna feto iroyin nipinlẹ Ogun, Alaaji Waheed Oduṣile, lo fi atẹjade to kede eyi sita lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ti i ṣe ọjọ keje, oṣu keji, ọdun 2021.Atẹjade naa ṣalaye pe dandan ni kijọba tete kilọ fawọn ẹgbẹ naa bayii, nitori awọn ẹṣọ alaabo ti fi to ijọba leti pe awọn NURTW ipinlẹ yii ti n ṣeto bi wọn yoo ṣe tun lọọ maa gbowo kiri ni gareeji lorukọ ijọba. Bẹẹ, eyi ta ko aṣẹ ijọba to wa nilẹ, eyi to fofin de ẹgbẹ yii lati maa gbowo orita ati ti gareeji lọwọ awọn awakọ lorukọ ijọba.Ẹ oo ranti pe ija agba to bẹ silẹ ninu ẹgbẹ NURTW nipinlẹ Ogun lo fa a ti ile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ yii ṣe fofin de wọn loṣu kẹfa, ọdun 2020. Ija naa lagbara debii pe ẹmi ati dukia awọn to n ba ara wọn ja naa wa ninu ewu. Eyi lo fa a tijọba ṣe fofin de wọn latigba naa.“A ti fun awọn agbofinro laṣẹ lati mu ọmọ ẹgbẹ NURTW ati ẹnikẹni tabi ẹgbẹkẹgbẹ tijọba ko ba fun laṣẹ lati ṣiṣẹ, ṣugbọn to fẹẹ gbowo ni gareeji lorukọ ijọba”Bẹẹ ni atẹjade naa wi."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸ੍ਰੀਰਾਗ ਬਾਣੀ ਭਗਤ ਬੇਣੀ ਜੀਉ ਕੀ ॥ਪਹਰਿਆ ਕੈ ਘਰਿ ਗਾਵਣਾ ॥ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਰੇ ਨਰ ਗਰਭ ਕੁੰਡਲ ਜਬ ਆਛਤ ਉਰਧ ਧਿਆਨ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਗਾ ॥ਮਿਰਤਕ ਪਿੰਡਿ ਪਦ ਮਦ ਨਾ ਅਹਿਨਿਸਿ ਏਕੁ ਅਗਿਆਨ ਸੁ ਨਾਗਾ ॥ਤੇ ਦਿਨ ਸੰਮਲੁ ਕਸਟ ਮਹਾ ਦੁਖ ਅਬ ਚਿਤੁ ਅਧਿਕ ਪਸਾਰਿਆ ॥ਗਰਭ ਛੋਡਿ ਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਮੰਡਲ ਆਇਆ ਤਉ ਨਰਹਰਿ ਮਨਹੁ ਬਿਸਾਰਿਆ ॥੧॥ਫਿਰਿ ਪਛੁਤਾਵਹਿਗਾ ਮੂੜਿਆ ਤੂੰ ਕਵਨ ਕੁਮਤਿ ਭ੍ਰਮਿ ਲਾਗਾ ॥ਚੇਤਿ ਰਾਮੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਜਮ ਪੁਰਿ ਜਾਹਿਗਾ ਜਨੁ ਬਿਚਰੈ ਅਨਰਾਧਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਬਾਲ ਬਿਨੋਦ ਚਿੰਦ ਰਸ ਲਾਗਾ ਖਿਨੁ ਖਿਨੁ ਮੋਹਿ ਬਿਆਪੈ ॥ਰਸੁ ਮਿਸੁ ਮੇਧੁ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਬਿਖੁ ਚਾਖੀ ਤਉ ਪੰਚ ਪ੍ਰਗਟ ਸੰਤਾਪੈ ॥ਜਪੁ ਤਪੁ ਸੰਜਮੁ ਛੋਡਿ ਸੁਕ੍ਰਿਤ ਮਤਿ ਰਾਮ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਅਰਾਧਿਆ ॥ਉਛਲਿਆ ਕਾਮੁ ਕਾਲ ਮਤਿ ਲਾਗੀ ਤਉ ਆਨਿ ਸਕਤਿ ਗਲਿ ਬਾਂਧਿਆ ॥੨॥ਤਰੁਣ ਤੇਜੁ ਪਰ ਤ੍ਰਿਅ ਮੁਖੁ ਜੋਹਹਿ ਸਰੁ ਅਪਸਰੁ ਨ ਪਛਾਣਿਆ ॥ਉਨਮਤ ਕਾਮਿ ਮਹਾ ਬਿਖੁ ਭੂਲੈ ਪਾਪੁ ਪੁੰਨੁ ਨ ਪਛਾਨਿਆ ॥ਸੁਤ ਸੰਪਤਿ ਦੇਖਿ ਇਹੁ ਮਨੁ ਗਰਬਿਆ ਰਾਮੁ ਰਿਦੈ ਤੇ ਖੋਇਆ ॥ਅਵਰ ਮਰਤ ਮਾਇਆ ਮਨੁ ਤੋਲੇ ਤਉ ਭਗ ਮੁਖਿ ਜਨਮੁ ਵਿਗੋਇਆ ॥੩॥ਪੁੰਡਰ ਕੇਸ ਕੁਸਮ ਤੇ ਧਉਲੇ ਸਪਤ ਪਾਤਾਲ ਕੀ ਬਾਣੀ ॥ਲੋਚਨ ਸ੍ਰਮਹਿ ਬੁਧਿ ਬਲ ਨਾਠੀ ਤਾ ਕਾਮੁ ਪਵਸਿ ਮਾਧਾਣੀ ॥ਤਾ ਤੇ ਬਿਖੈ ਭਈ ਮਤਿ ਪਾਵਸਿ ਕਾਇਆ ਕਮਲੁ ਕੁਮਲਾਣਾ ॥ਅਵਗਤਿ ਬਾਣਿ ਛੋਡਿ ਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਮੰਡਲਿ ਤਉ ਪਾਛੈ ਪਛੁਤਾਣਾ ॥੪॥ਨਿਕੁਟੀ ਦੇਹ ਦੇਖਿ ਧੁਨਿ ਉਪਜੈ ਮਾਨ ਕਰਤ ਨਹੀ ਬੂਝੈ ॥ਲਾਲਚੁ ਕਰੈ ਜੀਵਨ ਪਦ ਕਾਰਨ ਲੋਚਨ ਕਛੂ ਨ ਸੂਝੈ ॥ਥਾਕਾ ਤੇਜੁ ਉਡਿਆ ਮਨੁ ਪੰਖੀ ਘਰਿ ਆਂਗਨਿ ਨ ਸੁਖਾਈ ॥ਬੇਣੀ ਕਹੈ ਸੁਨਹੁ ਰੇ ਭਗਤਹੁ ਮਰਨ ਮੁਕਤਿ ਕਿਨਿ ਪਾਈ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 93 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਬੇਣੀ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ! ਜਦੋਂ ਤੂੰ ਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੇਟ ਵਿਚ ਸੈਂ, ਤਦੋਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ੳੱੁਚੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਧਿਆਨ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਸੀ;(ਤੈਨੂੰ ਤਦੋਂ) ਸਰੀਰ ਦੀ ਹੋਂਦ ਦਾ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ, ਦਿਨੇ ਰਾਤ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ (ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਸੈਂ), (ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਅਗਿਆਨ ਦੀ ਅਣਹੋਂਦ ਸੀ (ਹੇ ਮਨੱੁਖ !) ਉਹ ਦਿਨ ਹੁਣ ਚੇਤੇ ਕਰ (ਤਦੋਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ) ਬੜੇ ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਤੇ ਤਕਲੀਫ਼ਾਂ ਸਨ; ਪਰ ਹੁਣ ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਜੰਜਾਲਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਬਹੁਤ ਫਸਾ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ ਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਪੇਟ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਦਾ ਤੂੰ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਆਇਆ  ਹੈਂ, ਤਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਭੁਲਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ ! ਤੂੰ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਮੱਤੇ, ਕਿਹੜੇ ਭੁਲੇਖੇ ਵਿਚ ਲੱਗਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈਂ ? (ਸਮਾ ਹੱਥੋਂ ਗਵਾ ਕੇ) ਫੇਰ ਹੱਥ ਮਲੇਂਗਾ,ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ, ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਜਮਪੁਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਧੱਕਿਆ ਜਾਏਂਗਾ, (ਤੂੰ ਫਿਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕੋਈ ਅਮੋੜ ਬੰਦਾ ਫਿਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਪਹਿਲਾਂ) ਤੰੂ ਬਾਲਪੁਣੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਦੇ ਧਿਆਨ ਤੇ ਸੁਆਦ ਵਿਚ ਲੱਗਾ ਰਿਹਾ, ਤੇ ਸਦਾ (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹੀ) ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਿਆ ਰਿਹਾ(ਹੁਣ ਜਦੋਂ) ਤੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ-ਰੂਪ ਵਿਹੁ ਨੂੰ ਰਸਦਾਇਕ ਤੇ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਚੱਖਿਆ, ਤਦੋਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਪੰਜੇ (ਕਾਮਾਦਿਕ) ਖੁਲੇ੍ਹ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਸਤਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਜਪ ਤਪ ਸੰਜਮ ਤੇ ਪੁੰਨ ਕਰਮ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਬੁੱਧ ਤੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈਂ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ(ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਕਾਮ ਜ਼ੋਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੈ, ਭੈੜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਬੱੁਧੀ ਲੱਗੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, (ਕਾਮਾਤੁਰ ਹੋ ਕੇ) ਤੂੰ ਇਸਤਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਲਿਆ ਗਲ ਲਾਇਆ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਜੁਆਨੀ ਦਾ ਜੋਸ਼ ਹੈ, ਪਰਾਈਆ ਜ਼ਨਾਨੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰੰਹ ਤੱਕਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਵੇਲਾ ਕੁਵੇਲਾ ਭੀ ਤੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੇ ਕਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਹੋਏ ਹੋਏ ! ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਬਲ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਭੁੱਲੇ ਹੋਏ ! ਤੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿ ਪਾਪ ਕੀਹ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਪੁੰਨ ਕੀਹ ਹਪੱੁਤਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਧਨ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਤੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ; ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਵਿਸਾਰ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈਂਹੋਰਨਾਂ (ਸੰਬੰਧੀਆਂ) ਦੇ ਮੋਇਆਂ ਤੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਜਾਚ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ) ਕਿਤਨੀ ਕੁ ਮਾਇਆ (ਮਿਲੇਗੀ); ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ੳੱੁਤਮ ਤੇ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ (ਮਨੁੱਖਾ) ਜਨਮ ਅਜਾਈਂ ਗਵਾ ਲਿਆ ।੩।ਤੇਰੇ ਕੇਸ ਚਿੱਟੇ ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲ ਤੋਂ ਭੀ ਵਧੀਕ ਚਿੱਟੇ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ, ਤੇਰੀ ਆਵਾਜ਼ (ਡਾਢੀ ਮੱਧਮ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ, ਮਾਨੋ) ਸਤਵੇਂ ਪਾਤਾਲ ਤੋਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਸਿੰਮ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਤੇਰੀ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਵਾਲੀ ਬੱੁਧ ਕਮਜ਼ੋਰ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਭੀ ਕਾਮ (ਦੀ) ਮਧਾਣੀ (ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਪੈ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਅਜੇ ਭੀ ਕਾਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਾਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਜ਼ੋਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹਨ)ਇਹਨਾਂ ਹੀ ਵਾਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਤੇਰੀ ਬੁੱਧ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਝੜੀ ਲੱਗੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, ਤੇਰਾ ਸਰੀਰ ਰੂਪ ਕੌਲ ਫੱੁਲ ਕੁਮਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਹਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਕੇ ਤੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਭਜਨ ਛੱਡ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈਂ; (ਸਮਾ ਵਿਹਾ ਜਾਣ ਤੇ) ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਹੱਥ ਮਲੇਂਗਾ ।੪।ਨਿੱਕੇ ਨਿੱਕੇ ਬਾਲ (ਪੁੱਤਰ ਪੋਤਰੇ) ਵੇਖ ਕੇ (ਮਨੱੁਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਲਈ) ਮੋਹ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ, ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ (ਇਹ) ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ (ਕਿ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਛੱਡ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੈ)  ਅੱਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਦਿੱਸਣੋਂ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਫਿਰ ਭੀ ਮਨੱੁਖ) ਹੋਰ ਜੀਊਣ ਲਈ ਲਾਲਚ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਖ਼ਰ) ਸਰੀਰ ਦਾ ਬਲ ਮੱੁਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਤੇ ਜਦੋਂ) ਜੀਵ ਪੰਛੀ (ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ੳੱੁਡ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤਦੋਂ ਮੁਰਦਾ ਦੇਹ) ਘਰ ਵਿਚ, ਵਿਹੜੇ ਵਿਚ, ਪਈ ਹੋਈ ਚੰਗੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦੀ ।ਬੇਣੀ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ—ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ ! (ਜੇ ਮਨੱੁਖ ਦਾ ਸਾਰੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਵਿਚ ਇਹੀ ਹਾਲ ਰਿਹਾ, ਭਾਵ ਜੀਊਂਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੇਲੇ ਭੀ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੇ ਮੋਹ ਤੋਂ ਮੁਕਤ ਨਾਹ ਹੋਇਆ, ਜੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਮੁਕਤ ਨਾਹ ਹੋਇਆ, ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਸੱਚ ਜਾਣੋ ਕਿ) ਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਮੁਕਤੀ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦੀ ।੫।\\""},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: NTV var ursprungligen ett dotterbolag till Vladimir Gusinskijs företag Media-Most, och var en pionjär inom oberoende television i den postsovjetiska eran. I samband med parlamentsvalet 1999 och presidentvalet 2000","answer":"var NTV mycket kritiska mot Vladimir Putin, hans dåvarande parti Enhet och Andra Tjetjenienkriget. Detta ledde till kraftiga reaktioner från Putin-vänliga kretsar."},{"question":"Rujuk petikan di bawah dan jawab soalan dalam bahasa yang sama seperti petikan:  Marga Faulstich (16 Jun 1915 hinggs 1 Februari 1998) adalah seorang ahli kimia kaca Jerman. Dia bekerja untuk Schott AG selama 44 tahun. Dalam tempoh ini, dia bekerja pada lebih daripada 300 jenis cermin mata optik. Empat puluh paten didaftarkan atas namanya. Beliau adalah eksekutif wanita pertama di Schott AG.  Soalan: Apakah profesion Marga Faulstich?","answer":"ahli kimia kaca"},{"question":"మీకు తెలిసిన భారతీయ స్వాతంత్ర యోధుల గురించి మాట్లాడండి. ","answer":"నేతాజీ సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్ :ఈయన 1897 జనవరి 23వ తేదీన కటక్ లో జన్మించాడు. భారత జాతీయ ఫార్వర్డ్ బ్లాక్ స్థాపించాడు. ఆయన తల్లిదండ్రులు జానకీనాథబోస్, ప్రభావతీ దేవి. 11 సార్లు స్వాతంత్ర్య సంగ్రామంలో ఆంగ్లేయులచే కారాగారంలో నిర్భందించబడ్డాడు. జపాన్ సహాయంతో భారత యుద్ధ ఖైదీలు, రబ్బరుతోట కూలీలు ఔత్సాహికులతో భారత జాతీయ సైన్యాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేసాడు. బ్రిటిష్ వారితో యుద్ధాన్ని జర్మనీ, జపాన్ల సాయంతో సాగించాడు. 1945 ఆగష్టు 18న తైవాన్లో జరిగిన విమాన ప్రమాదంలో బోస్ మరణించాడంటారు. కానీ ప్రమాదం నుండి బయటపడి అజ్ఞాతంలోకి వెళ్ళాడని పలువురు నమ్ముతారు.ఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయి :ఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయి 1828 నవంబరు 19న మహారాష్ట్రలో సతారలో జన్మించింది. ఆమె తల్లిదండ్రులు మోరోపంత్ తాంబే, భాగీరథీబాయి. వీరిది . సంప్రదాయ బ్రాహ్మణ కుటుంబం. ఆమె చిన్నప్పటి పేరు మణికర్ణిక. ముద్దుగా ‘మను’ అని పిలిచేవారు. ఆమె 4వ ఏటనే తల్లి మరణించింది. చిన్నతనంలోనే గుర్రపు స్వారీ, కత్తియుద్ధం నేర్చుకొంది.ఆమెను 13వ ఏట ఝాన్సీ రాజు గంగాధరరావు ఆమెను పెండ్లాడాడు. గంగాధరరావు మరణానంతరం ఝాన్సీని బ్రిటిషువారు కైవసం చేసుకోవాలనుకొన్నారు. కాని లక్ష్మీబాయి అంగీకరించలేదు. తిరుగుబాటు చేసింది. బ్రిటిషువారికి కంటిమీద కునుకు లేకుండా గెరిల్లా పోరాటాలు చేసింది. చివరకు బ్రిటిషువారి దుర్మార్గానికి 1858 జూన్ 18న గ్వాలియర్లో మరణించింది. ఆమె తండ్రిని బ్రిటిషువారు ఉరితీశారు. ఆమె వారసుడిగా దామోదర్ రావుని ప్రకటించారు."},{"question":"క్రింది సమాస పదాలకు విగ్రహవాక్యాలు రాసి, సమాసాలు గుర్తించండి.అ) జీవధనములుఆ) యువతీయువకులుఇ) దశదిక్కులుఈ) భూతప్రేతములు","answer":"అ) జీవధనములు – జీవమును, ధనమును (ద్వంద్వ సమాసము)ఆ) యువతీయువకులు – యువతియును, యువకులును (ద్వంద్వ సమాసము)ఇ) దశదిక్కులు – దశ సంఖ్యగల దిక్కులు (ద్విగు సమాసము)ఈ) భూతప్రేతములు – భూతమును, ప్రేతమును (ద్వంద్వ సమాసము)"},{"question":"Inona ilay zavatra tsy atoraka tsy avily nefa mahatonga lavitra?","answer":"Ny maso no zavatra tsy atoraka tsy avily nefa mahatonga lavitra."},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira da Arábia Saudita.","answer":"A bandeira da Arábia Saudita é verde com uma inscrição em árabe em estilo caligráfico, que inclui a Shahada, o testemunho de fé islâmica, em branco. É um símbolo importante do Islã."},{"question":"2021 සාහිත්‍ය සදහා වූ නොබෙල් සම්මානය දිනාගත් අබ්දුල් රසාක් ගුර්නා කුමන ජාතිකයෙක්ද ?","answer":"ටැන්සානියානු"},{"question":"من هو الخليفة الذي أتم بناء المسجد الأقصى على صورته القائمة سنة 66هـ؟","answer":"الوليد بن عبد الملك"},{"question":"Wayengathethi manga okaNdabaNgesikhathi ethi ziyofa izinsizwa kusale izibongo.Kulamathafa ezwe lethu kwake kwaphila izinsizwa,Ezazigijima mzila munye nezinyoka ezibulalayo,Zibhukuda mfula munye nezingwenya ezibulalayo,Zibanga amaqele namabhubesi abulalayo,Zidwanguza amahlathi nezingwe ezibulalayo.1. tomula imigqa EMIBILI enokuxhumanamaphakathi bese udwebela amagama akhombisa ukuxhumana.","answer":"Ezazigijima mzila munye nezinyoka ezibulalayo,Zibhukuda mfula munye nezingwenya ezibulalayo."},{"question":"س162- ما هو أصل الشاعر عمر الخيام ؟","answer":"ج162- فارسي"},{"question":"నిత్యజీవితంలో ద్రవాభిసరణ జరిగే 3 సన్నివేశాలను తెలపంది. ","answer":"మొక్కల వేర్లలోనికి నీరు ద్రవాభిసరణ ద్వారా చేరుతుంది.కణాల మధ్య నీరు ప్రవహించడానికి కారణం ద్రవాభిసరణం.పత్రరంధ్రాలు మూసుకోవడం, తెరచుకోవడం ద్రవాభిసరణ వల్ల జరుగుతుంది.ద్రవాభిసరణం మొక్కలలో నీరు, లవణాల కదలికలకు సహాయపడుతుంది.రక్తంలో మలినాలు వడపోయడానికి ద్రవాభిసరణం అవసరం.మన శరీరానికి కావలసిన నీరు మరియు లవణాలు పునఃశోషణం చేసుకోవడానికి ద్రవాభిసరణం ఉపయోగపడుతుంది.వాడిపోయిన క్యారెట్ ను నీటిలో ఉంచిన, ద్రవాభిసరణ ద్వారా నీరు ప్రవేశించి క్యారెట్ తాజాగా అవుతుంది."},{"question":"Millainen on hyvä ukkosenjohdatin?","answer":"Rakennusten ukkossuojaus perustuu siihen, ettei iskun kohteeksi joutumista voida estää, mutta iskun osuessa salamavirta pyritään johtamaan mahdollisimman turvallisesti maahan. Tähän tarkoitukseen tarvitaan rakennuksen katolle ns. salamasieppari, esim. televisioantenni tai vastaava metallipiikki, joka 'houkuttelee' lähelle iskevän salaman. Siepparista viedään johtimet vastakkaisia räystäitä ja nurkkia pitkin maahan. Lisäksi talon ympärillä maan alla tulisi olla rengasmainen johdin, johon katolta tulevat johtimet sekä sähkömaadoitus yhdistetään. Tämä järjestely toimii erittäin hyvänä maadoituksena salamalle.Jos salama iskee esim. rakennuksen kattoon, jota ei ole maadoitettu, kulkeutuu salamavirta rakenteiden läpi. Tällöin seurauksena voi olla tulipalo tai ihmisten loukkaantuminen rakennuksen sisällä.Salamavirta saattaa kulkeutua myös sähkö- tai puhelinjohtoja pitkin hyvin etäältä. Tämä ylijännite saattaa hajottaa sähkölaitteita tai pahimmassa tapauksessa sytyttää tulipalon. Sähköjärjestelmään on saatavissa ylijännitesuojia, jotka ehkäisevät ainakin hieman tätä riskiä."},{"question":"Haa, odo gbe tiṣa lọ l’Ọmi-Adio, wọn ni biriji lo wo lojiji","answer":"Ibanujẹ nla lo ṣẹlẹ niluu Ọmi-Adio nijọba ibilẹ Ido niluu Ibadan nipinlẹ Ọyọ nigba ti odo gbe tiṣa kan to ti fẹyinti lẹnu iṣẹ lọ.Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, yii ni wọn sọ pe iṣẹlẹ ọhun waye nigba ti biriiji to wa niluu Igisogba ja lulẹ lasiko ti ojo nla kan rọ.Nureni Adejumọ ni wọn pe orukọ olukọ to ti fẹyinti ọhun. Oko ni wọn sọ pe o ti n bọ lọjọ naa. Ile ana ẹ gan-an lo fẹẹ ya to fi gbe ọkada ẹ sẹgbẹẹ kan, to si gun biriji onipako to fẹẹ fi sọda sibi to n lọ. Aarin biriji ọhun ni wọn lo rin de, ti biriji onipako yii fi ja mọ ọn lẹsẹ, bi Adejumọ ṣe re sinu odo niyẹn, ti omi si gbe e lọWọn ni gbogbo igbiyanju awọn omuwẹ lati yọ ọ ni ko so eso rere, ti wọn ko si ti i ri titi di asiko yii.Alaga awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC agbegbe naa, Muri Adekọla, sọ pe loootọ niṣẹlẹ ọhun waye ni deede aago mẹjọ aṣalẹ ọjọ Aje, bẹẹ lo rọ ijọba ko ṣeto bi biriiji gidi yoo ṣe wa lagbegbe naa, ki irufẹ iṣẹlẹ bẹẹ le ma waye mọ."},{"question":"Astaamaha qofka hanka sare leh?","answer":"Astaamaha qofka hanka sare leh?Halkaas ayuu ku dhamaaday kitaabkii aan u diyaariyay dhallinyarada soomaaliyeed, kitaabkaas oo aan ugu talagalay inuu u noqdo mid ay sahay ka dhigtaan inta ay hiigsanayaan yolalkooda . Waxaanna gunaanad uga dhigayaa kitaabkan, maqaal uu diyaariyay Dr Saadiq Enaw, maqaalkaas oo uu ku qoray website-ka somalitalk.com, sababta aan maqaalkan u doortay waxaa weeye inuu Dr Saaqdiq sifiican uga hadlay marxalada dhalin yaradnimda iyo inay dhalin yaradu yihiin udub dhexaadka ummad kasta oo hormar gaarta. Haddaba waakan maqaalkii oo bilawday :-  Facii is-Beddelka Qof walba wuxuu nolosha ku lee-yahay sad u gaar ah. Cimrigu waa midka ugu milgaha culus oo lagu dheefsado nolosha. Calafka cimriga, xumaantiisa iyo samaantiisa waxaa qofka la wadaaga dadka la faca ah ee xillidhalashadooda ay isku dhowdahay. Waxaa kaloo ku weheliya faco ka yar-yar iyo faco ka waaweyn. In-kasta oo ay yihiin saddex fac oo isa-soo gaaraya, misana wadar u-jooggoodu si siman uma muddeysna. Faca dhallinyarada ah oo iyagu leh xilliga, ayaa waxay yihiin tamarta jaheysa bulshada. Faca ka yar-yar waxay yihiin magan u dabran wixii sooryo-gal ah oo ay helaan. Faca ka waaweyn ayaa iyaguna waxay matalayaan bakhaaro ay ku keydsan yihiin khibrad iyo waayo-aragnimo laga doonayo inteeda wanaagsan in ay u gudbiyaan faca dhallinyarada ah.   Nolosha waxay aadamiga bartey, aabihii aanan caruurtiisa u diyaarin in ay isaga ka wanaagsanaadaan, caruurtaasi mooryaan ayay noqonayaan oo iyaga ayaa silcinaya waalidkood. Waxaa lamid ah macallinkii aanan ardeydiisa u diyaarin in ay ka wanaagsanaadaan, ardeydaasi mooryaan ayay noqonayaan oo iyaga ayaa silcinaya kuwii wax barey. Sidaas oo kale waxaa ah faca waaweyn ee dhallinyaradooda aanan diyaarin u diyaarin in ay ka wanaagsanaadaan, facaasi dhallinyarada ah mooryaan ayay noqonayaan oo iyaga ayaa silcinaya facii ka waaweynaa. Facaadda dhallinyarada ah, waa xilli qofka aadamiga ahi uu ku sugan yahay heerkii noloshiisa ay ugu wacnaansho badan-tahay. Waa xilliga uu qofku ugu xooggan yahay, ugu fir-fircoon yahay, ugu waxbarasho badan yahay uguna wax-qabad badan yahay. Waa xilli uu yahay gaashaanqaad oo noloshu ay u kala-guureyso. Wuxuu ka soo gudbayaa xaalad caruurnimo oo uusan lahayn faham nolosha uu ku qiimeeyo. Wuxuu u tallaabayaa muqdarnimo garaad uu ku fahmo qiimeynta nolosha. Xilligaas kala-guurka ah, waxaa lagu xisaabiyaa xilliyada qofka soo mara xilliga ugu milgaha culus. Sababtu waxay tahay waa xilliga uu qofku si buuxda u hana-qaadayo oo ay ku bilaabaneyso dareenka ah in uu nolosha wax ku leeyahay. Wuxuu bilaabayaa in uu dibadda soo dhigo qaabkii uu ku midabeyn lahaa khibradihii yaraa iyo aqoontii uu nolosha ku kasbadey, isla-markaas uu raadinayo aqoon dheeri ah. Wuxuu markaas adeegsanayaa awoodda caqliga ee curdanka ah iyo awoodda jirka ee xooggan, isaga oo marka hore baadi-goobaya kororsi waaya-aragnimo, marka xigana fayiigsi iyo ficil wada -jira ku tiigsanaya timaaddada. Isla-xilligaas qofka dhallinyarada ah wuxuu bilaabayaa guda-galka dhisid qoys si uu uga qeyb-qaato tallaalka abuurkii uu kaga qeyb-geli lahaa nolosha bulshadiisa. Xilligaas hore, gudaha jirka qofka dhallinyarada ah waxaa ku dhacaya is-beddello xooggan. Waxay ka muuqanayaan naqshadda xubnaha iyo qaabka uu jirku u shaqeynayo (physical & physiological changes). Meesha u horeysa ee laga dheehanayo waa kala duwanaanshaha jinsiga lab iyo dheddig, kuwaas oo maraya laba marxaladood (primary & secondry). Dhecaanada (hormons) jirka gudihiisa ku qubanaya ee ku howlan is-beddelka la xiriira koritaanka xubnihiisa, waxay raad ku yeelanayaan qaab-dhaqanka iyo fekerka qofka dhallinta-yar. Dhallinyaradu waxay la gaar yihiin, faca ka waaweyn in ay ka tira badan yihiin, ka xoog weyn yihiin, kana dadaal badan yihiin. Waxaa intaas u dheer, baxsadka uu sabab u yahay ka carar ciilkii caruurnimo oo ay tagtadooda ka soo mareen. Iyo u farabaxsiga timaaddada oo ay sabab u tahay dheygag leh fayiigsi xooggan iyo dheehasho damac weyn oo xiiso iyo xaraka miiran ah si ay joogtadooda uga yeelaan sahaydii timaaddadadooda. Nolosha qiimaheeda waa xilliga dhallinyarada la yahay. Macna weyn ma ayan lahaateen haddii uusan xilligaas jireen. Waa xilli ayan riyada noloshu ka dhamaan, noloshuna xushmad dheeri ah ayay u heysaa qofka dhallinyarada ah. Waa ay soo dhoweysaa hadba inta uu isaguna soo dhoweeyo nolosha. Taasi waxay ku abuurtaa dhallinyarada, iyaga oo dhiirran in ay mar-walba doonaan guul. Meel -kasta waa ay u maraan iyaga oo u huraya qaali iyo raqiis. Guushuna waxay saaxiib la tahay oo ay soo dhoweysaa kuwa iyada raadinaya. Marka ay dhallinyaradu caafimaad qabaan, waa ay u hunguri dheer-yihiin nolosha. Hal-abuurka wanaagsan iyo hanqal-taagga miisaaman ee dhallinyarada waxaa ka faa´iideysta bulshada. Awooddaas ayaa bulshadu waxay kaga gudubtaa nolol harraad, halamash iyo hagardaamo badan oo ay hamuunyona u dheer-tahay. Waxay u gudbaan nolol leh hiraal wacan iyo hillaac hal-dhisyo lagu doogsado. Ooraah ayaa jirta: \\" Noloshu waxay isu kaa tusineysaa sida aad adigu u dooneyso iney kuugu muuqato ee isu kaa tusi-meyso sida ay iyada u dooneyso in ay kuugu muuqato ”. Qosolka iyo farxaddu waa ay ku badan tahay nolosha dhallinyarada, maxaa yeeley nolosha ayaa waxay ka doonayaan in ay ka helaan qosol iyo farxad. Sidaa darteed, iyaga waxaa u muuqata fursadaha nolosha. Haddii ay gartaan in fursadahaasi ay iyagu lee-yihiin, markaas waxay ku dadaalaan sidii ay u laaci lahaayeen. Haddii ay dhallinyaradu yihiin kuwo ka badbaada-qaba aragtida cunsuriyadda ah (fir-sooc) iyo midda curyaannimada ah (saama-jiid) waxay jecleystaan in ay magac hagaagsan sameystaan, intii magac loo sameyn lahaa ama ay dhaxli lahaayeen magac fac ka horeeyey ay ka tageen. Faca dhallinyarada ah waxaa mar-walba ku tallaalan doonis in ay dhanka wanaagsan u midab-beddelaan nolosha facii ka horeeyey, intii ay dhex-fadhiyi lahaayeen nolol ah soo arag ku -joog. Waxay jecel yihiin in ay fir-fircooni muujiyaan, intii ay noqon lahaayeen xan iyo xin u-joog. Dhallinta caafimaadka qabta waxaa ku yar tilmaamaha guracan oo bulshada ka dila han-tiigsiga nolosha, kuwaas oo damaca khariban iyo fuleynimada ay ugu horeeyaan. Xasuusta dhallinyaradu waa ka maran-tahay dhacdooyinkii lurka badnaa ee xilligii caruurnimada. Indhahooduna maahan kuwo qabanaya xaaladda lahanka badan ee xilliga waayeelnimada. Noloshooda waxaa u badan dareen la xiriira timaaddada, kaas oo ay uga dhexmuuqdaan nolol ku asqeysan nayaayiro iyo naallood. Maxaa yeeley waa faca ay noloshu u qosleyso ayna soo dhoweeneyso. Iyagu waxay lee-yihiin awood ay ku gaaraan har-gal nololeed iyo qurux walba oo ay jantaan. Shidaalka xooggan oo korkoodu uu sahayda u wato wuxuu sabab u yahay, in dhallinyaradu ay yihiin kuwa libta u keena bulshadooda. Aamusnaantooda waxaa ku naaxa gafanayaal aanan arxan lahayn ee bulshada gaarsiiya nabarro xanuun badan. Guuxa dhallinyaradu waxaa ku nasta maatada ku liidata nolosha. Dhallinyaradu waa matoorkii nolosha iyo tamartii dhismaha bulshada. Xooggoodu wuxuu lamid yahay tamarta korontada ee gidaarrada qolalka lagu diyaariyo. Tamartaas ayaa waxay tahay mid ka shaqeysiisa firinjiteer (qaboojiye) iyo kaawiyad (kululeyso) hadba kii la-doono. Waxay ka shaqeysiisaa idaacad (maqal-tebiye) iyo telefishan (muuqaal-tebiye) hadba kii la-doono. Waxay ka shaqeysiisaa taleefan (hadal-tebiye) iyo kombyuter (maqal- iyo muuqaal-tebiye) hadba kii la-doono. Waxay ka shaqeysiisaa marwaxad (bankad) iyo saacad (gooreyso) hadba kii la-doono.  Waxaa jirta ooraah oraneysa:- \\" Kala-garo in noloshu ay tahay qaddar jaango´an iyo dhacdooyin leh sababo. Qaddartana aamin, dhacdooyinkana wax iska-weydii ” Tamarta korontada ah, awood mid ah ayay ku sahleysaa adeegsiga dhamaan agabkaas kala duwan in si kala duwan, oo nafac kala duwan leh loogu intifaacsado dhacdooyin kala duwan. Dad sababaha dhacdooyinka isweydiiyey ayaa hal-abuurey. Xoogga dhallinyarada waa ceynkaas oo kale. Waa tamar bulshadu lee-dahay oo meel u yaal. Marka qaddarta la rumeeyo, sababaha dhacdooyinkana leys-weydiiyo, xoogga dhallinyarada, bulshadu waxay uga faa´iideysan kartaa qaab walba oo maslaxaddeeda ah. Bulshadu markii ay aragti haboon curiso, dhallinyaradu waa xoogga waaqica u beddela. Markii ay bulshadu dagaal curiso, dhallinyaradu waa kuwa gulufka hor-kaca. Markii ay bulshadu nabad curiso, dhallinyaradu waa kuwa hubka dhiga. Markii ay bulshadu hiraal curiso, dhallinyaradu waa kuwa suragal ka dhiga. Waxaa xeerarka nolosha kamid ah in xilli qof lee-yahay uusan gooreysankarin qof kale. Sidaas si lamid ah ayaa facna uusan u bililiqeysan karin xilli uu lee-yahay fac kale. Haddeyse dhacdo waxaa u sabab ah nabarro ay la curyaameen ee weheliya faca la bililiqeystey. Waxaa hubaal ah in faca howl-gabka ah ay lamid yihiin qorrax ka soo baxdey cirifyada adduunka, xilli qaboobe ah iyada oo dhulku uu baraf ceegaago. Qorraxdaasi waa suuragal in laga helo kaahii maalinnimo. Laakiin waxaan laga helynin tamartii iyo kuleylkii socod-siin lahaa nolosha dhulka oogadiisa ah. Dhallinyaradu waa rajo kunool iyo timaaddo-sugayaal ah. Waayeelkuse waa xusuus iyo tagto ku-nool, rajaduna ka madowdahay. Haddaba bulshadii ay dhallinyaradeedu ku wareeraan aragti madhaleys ah ee aan waaqic ahayn, wakhtigaa ka dayacma. Bulshadii dhallinyaradeedu ay guul-wadayaal u noqdaan kuwo daneystayaal ah, waa ay halaagsantaa. Bulshadii dhallinyaradeedu ay is kooxeeyaan, dabadeedna koox waliba ay dhankeeda ka raadiso in ay kooxda kale ka guuleysato, waxaa ka baaba´a awooddii ay kula tartami lahayd dhiggooda.  Xilligii dhallinyarada Soomaaliyeed ay caafimaadka qabeen waxaa ereyadoodii kamid ahaa :- 1. Aboorkuba alleylkuu dhisaa aqallo waaweyne 2. Markuu ururey daartuu ebyaa la ashqaraaraaye 3. Ilkuhuba wada-jirkey hilbaha adag ku gooyaane 4. Haddii iniba meel taagan tahay adhax ma fiinteene 5. Itifaaq la´aan laguma helo lib iyo iimaane 6. Indhahaad isku arkeysaan cadaawaha isaga eega 7. Ha ordina´e xaajada sidii aydinta u raaca 8. Ha ekaanina´e talo ninkii odhan karow dhiibta 9. Abtirsiimo reer hebel iyo odey ku faan daaya 10. Indho-fura hurdada waa waxaad ku ibtilowdeene, (Xaaji Aadan Af-qallooc).Halkaas ayuu ku dhamaaday maqaalkii Dr Saadiq. Taariikhdii aan dhameeyay kitaabkan waxay ahayd 1/10/2013."},{"question":"Quantos países existem dentro do Reino Unido?","answer":"Quatro. Inglaterra, País de Gales, Escócia e Irlanda do Norte."},{"question":"K: Kur galima rasti amfibijų, kurie juda kaip kirmėlės? Pasirinkimai: - (A) drėgnas kūnas - (B) kūno vanduo - (C) vandens saugojimas - (D) per dieną - (E) keturios galvos - (F) drėgnas dirvožemis - (G) sausos zonos - (H) dideli aukštai Pagalvokime žingsnis po žingsnio žemiau.","answer":"Tropiniuose regionuose cecilijos auga drėgnoje dirvožemyje, šalia upių ir upelių. Cecilijos yra amfibijos, kurios juda kaip ir kirmėlės. Anfibijos, kurios juda kaip sliekai, gyvena drėgname dirvožemyje šalia upių ir upėlių tropiniuose regionuose. Taigi atsakymas yra (F)."},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut: Pada 5 Jun 2022, Persatuan STEM SMK Tunku Alang telah mengadakan lawatan sambil belajar ke Pulau Langkawi. Lawatan itu berlangsung selama 3 hari 2 malam. Seramai 35 orang murid menyertai lawatan itu. Bilangan murid perempuan yang menyertai lawatan itu adalah 5 orang kurang daripada bilangan murid lelaki. Berapa orang murid lelaki yang menyertai lawatan itu?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah 20 orang murid lelaki. Murid lelaki =xMurid perempuan=x-5Jumlah murid=352x-5=35x=20"},{"question":"Сабактын айрым багыттары боюнча берилген анализ кайсы анализ?а)Аспектүүб)Кыскачав)Аналитикалык","answer":" Тураа жообу:а)Аспектүү"},{"question":"കേരളത്തിൽ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ കയർ ഫാക്ടറികളുള്ള ജില്ല ഏത്?","answer":"കേരളത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ കയർ ഫാക്ടറികളുള്ള ജില്ലയാണ് ആലപ്പുഴ."},{"question":"Ziemię uważa się za obiekt kulisty. Która opcja jest uważana za błędną w odniesieniu do Ziemi.1. Ziemia składa się głównie z wody.2. Ziemia jest w większości okrągła.3. Ziemia jest płaska.","answer":"Niepoprawna opcja to opcja 3."},{"question":"nyati mwana wayo anonzii?","answer":"ngavidiki"},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital del Nariño Colombia?","answer":"La capital es Pasto"},{"question":"maji ni nini?","answer":"maji ni kimiminika. maji ni muhimu kwa matumizi mbalimbali ya mwanadamu, wanyama na mimea. maji hutumika katika mazingira ya nyumbani, viwandani, hospitali, gereji n.k Mwili wa mwanadamu unahitaji maji ili uweze kufanya kazi vizuri, hivyo asilimia sabini na tano za mwili wa mwanadamu ni maji. pia maji hutumika kupozea mashine za viwandani na magari. maji hutumika katika shughuli za kilimo. watu husema kuwa maji ni uhai."},{"question":" Waa maxay maahmaah? ","answer":" Maahmaahdu waxay bilaan hadalka, sidoo kale waxay xoojiyaan Fahmidda dulucdiisa. "},{"question":"ヒロイン、ブリジット・フォッセーの演技や、ナルシソ・イエペスが奏でるギターの旋律が印象的な、ルネ・クレマン監督の映画は何でしょう？","answer":"禁じられた遊び"},{"question":" مامور د ندي په جریان کي څو موقفه لري ؟","answer":"ځواب مامور د دندي په جریان کي لاندې موقفه لري !۱ – اصلي موقف ، ۲ – خدمتي موقف ، ۳ – عسکري موقف ، ۴ – تحصیلي موقف ، ۵ – د مؤقت انفصال موقف "},{"question":"Oha Soup","answer":"Ọbẹ̀ Oha jẹ́ ọbẹ̀ tó wọ́pọ̀ ní apá gúúsù mọ́ ìlà-oòrùn orílẹ̀-èdè NàìjíríàỌbẹ̀ oha jẹ́ ọbẹ̀ agbègbè Ìlà-oòrùn, tó sì jẹ́ pé àwọn ará Íbò ni wọ́n sábà máa ń sè é, láti ará igi ewébẹ̀ láéláé tí orúkọ sáyẹ́ńsì rẹ̀ ń ṣe Pterocarpus mildraedii ni ọbẹ̀ náà ti ṣẹ̀.Èròjà tó ṣe pàtàkì jùlọ fún ọbẹ̀ náà ni ewébẹ̀ oha, àwọn mìíràn tún ni úsísá, áṣí( amọ́bẹ̀ kí), ẹran, edé, epo pupa àti iyọ̀. Àwọn orúkọ mìíràn tí wọ́n tún ń pe ọbẹ̀ náà ni uha àti ọbẹ̀ ora.Àwọn Oúnjẹ Tí Ẹ Le Fi Jẹ OhaỌbẹ̀ oha/Uha dára jù lọ pẹ̀lú fùfú. Iyán, sẹ̀mó, ọlá àti ẹ̀bà gbogbo àwọn wọ̀nyí náà ni wọ́n dára pẹ̀lú ọbẹ̀ oha."},{"question":"Inona no renirano lehibe mamakivaky an’i Ejipta ary mifandray amin’ny tantaran’io firenena io?","answer":"Mamakivaky an'i Ejipta ny Neily ary mifandray amin'ny tantaran'ny firenena fahiny. Nitana anjara toerana lehibe teo amin’ny fampivoarana ny sivilizasiona Ejiptiana izy io tamin’ny fanomezana rano hanondrahana ireo tany lonaka manamorona ny morony."},{"question":"ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਵਪਾਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਵਪਾਰ ਦੀ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਅਨੁਕੂਲ ਹੈ । ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਤੱਥ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਦੀ ਪੁਸ਼ਟੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ –* ਦੱਖਣੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਪਾਸਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਨਾਲ ਘਿਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦਾ 96 ਪ੍ਰਤੀਸ਼ਤ ਅੰਤਰ-ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਵਿਉਪਾਰ ਸਮੁੰਦਰੀ ਮਾਰਗ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।* ਪੂਰਬ ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਮੁੰਦਰੀ ਮਾਰਗ ਵੀ ਹਿੰਦ ਮਹਾਂਸਾਗਰ ‘ ਤੋਂ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਗੁਜਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।* ਰਤ ਸੁਏਜ਼ ਮਾਰਗ ਅਤੇ ਆਸ਼ਾ ਅੰਤਰੀਪ ਮਾਰਗ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਯੂਰਪ, ਉੱਤਰੀ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।* ਭਾਰਤ ਦਾ ਵਪਾਰ ਲਗਪਗ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ ਸਾਡਾ ਦੇਸ਼ ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਰਾਜ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ, ਕੈਨੇਡਾ, ਯੂਰਪ ਮਹਾਂਦੀਪ, ਦੱਖਣੀ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣੀ-ਪੂਰਬੀ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੇ ਲਗਪਗ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਵਪਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।* 1869 ਵਿੱਚ ਸੁਏਜ਼ ਨਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਣ ਨਾਲ ਯੂਰਪ ਅਤੇ ਅਮਰੀਕੀ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਹੋਰ ਵੀ ਮਜ਼ਬੂਤ ਹੋ ਗਏ ।"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para este parágrafo - Na sequência da pandemia COVID-19, o Grande Prémio de Portugal voltou a ser o final da época com um calendário alterado no Campeonato do Mundo de MotoGP de 2020. O local escolhido para a realização da prova foi o Autódromo Internacional do Algarve, que é circuito reserva desde 2017. A prova decorreu sem espectadores devido à falta de distanciamento social nas arquibancadas da prova de Fórmula 1","answer":"realizada um mês antes. Em 2021, a corrida originalmente única foi trazida de volta como a terceira prova da temporada."},{"question":"O que acontece se um jogador de futebol derruba o atacante do time adversário dentro da grande área?","answer":"O juiz e, caso necessário, o árbitro de vídeo analisam a jogada e pode ser marcado um pênalti para o time que estava atacando."},{"question":" Sheeg, Wax Marka Ay Siyaadaan Sii Naaqusa","answer":" Waa Dayaxa."},{"question":"Cho số 982434.  Làm tròn số này đến hàng nghìn ta được sốA. 983000B. 982C. 982000D. 98200","answer":"Trả lời:Số 982434 có chữ số hàng trăm là 4 < 5 nên làm tròn số này đến hàng nghìn ta được 982434 ≈ 982000Đáp án cần chọn là: C"},{"question":"Vamos conversar sobre biologia e envelhecimento. Qual a diferença entre senescência e senilidade?","answer":"A senescência é o processo natural de envelhecimento que ocorre ao longo da vida, envolvendo mudanças celulares e biológicas.  A senilidade se refere ao estado final de envelhecimento avançado, definido por limitações físicas e mentais associadas à idade avançada. A senilidade é o resultado das mudanças ao longo da vida devido à senescência."},{"question":"演劇用語で､幕を閉めずに照明を暗くして場面の切り替えを行うことを､漢字２文字で何というでしょう？","answer":"暗転"},{"question":"Pergunta: de onde vem o sobrenome Galvez? Resposta:","answer":"O sobrenome e a família Galvez é originária da Espanha. A história da família Galvez é longa e complexa, mas a origem da família pode ser rastreada até o século 11. A família Galvez é uma das famílias mais antigas da Espanha e tem um importante legado na história do país. A família Galvez é conhecida por seus membros notáveis, incluindo o General José de Galvez, um importante líder político e militar durante a Guerra de Sucessão Espanhola. A família Galvez também é conhecida por sua contribuição para a literatura, artes e ciências. Alguns dos membros mais famosos da família Galvez incluem o escritor Miguel de Cervantes, o pintor Diego Velázquez e o cientista Miguel de Unamuno."},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsortra:Nanomboka nanao fanentanana i Albertine ary dia nifantoka tanteraka tamin’ireo akora nampirantiana teo ambony latabatra ny maso rehetra. « Araka izao hitanareo izao, dia ilaina ny sakafo samihafa sy maro karazany ho fihinanareo sy ny zanakareo. Tena ilaina koa ny fampinonoan-dreny mba hahafahan’ny zanakareo mitombo », hoy izy.Teo akaikin’i  Albertine koa i Mario, mpanentana ara-piarahamonina, tonga nanohana sy nanatanteraka ny hetsika. « Hanomboka ny fandanjana ny zanakareo sy ny fakana ny refin-tsandriny ary aloha isika », hoy izy tamin-pahavitrihana. Nifanampy izy mianadahy raha nanomboka nikarakara ny sakafo nentin’ny mpiaramonina kosa i Olidée, izay mpahandro, sy ireo namany anankitelo. Nanolo-tena an-tsitrapo hanao io asa io izy satria isan’ireo tratry ny tsifanjarian-tsakafo ny zanany.Inona no ahafahan'ny zaza mitombo hoy i Albertine?","answer":"Ny fampinonoan-dreny no ahafahan'ny zaza mitombo hoy i Albertine, ankoatra ny sakafo maro karazany."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'langit berkelikir bumi bertemberang, salah-salah fikir, jadi hamba orang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud fikiran yang mengikut hawa nafsu itu akhirnya membawa kepada kehinaan"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa dhibaatooyinka daacuunka (Shuban Biyoodka) Iyo qataraha Ka dhalan Kara?","answer":"Daacuunka waa xaalad halis ah oo ay sababto bakeeriya, xaaladaan ayaa sababta shuban daran iyo fuuqbax. Cudurkaan wuxuu caadi ahaan ku faafaa biyo wasakheysan. Xaaladaha daran waxaa lagama maarmaan ah daweyn degdeg ah, sababtoo ah waxaa suurto gal ah iney dhimasho ku dhacdo saacado gudahood. Tani waxay ku dhici kartaa xitaa dadka caafimaadka uu caafimaadkoodu wanaagsanaa inta uusan haleelin dacuunka.Wasakh mareenada casiriga ah iyo daweynta lagu sameeyo biyaha lacabo ee wadamada horumaray waxay si guul ah uga takhaluseen daacuunka, hasa yeeshee daacuunka wuxuu wali dhibaata ku hayaa wadamada ku yaala Afrika, Aasiya iyo Latiin Ameerika. Khaas ahaan wadamada dagaalada aafeeyeen iyo sabool nimada iyo musiibooyinka dabiiciga ah.Maxaa sababa daacuun?Daacuunka waxaa sababo bakteeriya loo yaqaano Vibrio Cholerae, saameynta halista ah ee cudurkaan waxay ka dhalataa sunta ay soo deyso bakteeriyadaan, suntaan waxay khalkhal gelineysaa macdanada jirka ku jira sida sodium iyo chloride, waana arin sababeysa in jirka uu saaro biyo badan taas oo dhalineysa shuban iyo lumista cusbada iyo biyaha jirkaIsticmaalidda biyo wasakheysan waa arinta ugu badan ee sababto daacuun, qudaarta aan si fiican loo karin iyo cunooyinka kale.Daacuunka ma ahan mid la isgu gudbiyo taabashada.Waa maxay astaamahaShuban degdeg ahLalaboMatagFuuqbax udhexeeya khafiif iyo mid daranFuuqbaxa uu sababo daacuunka waa mid daran inta badan, waxay sababi kartaa isu dheeli tirnaan la’aanta macdanada ku jira dhiigga. Caruurta waxay la wadaagaan astaamaha dadka waa weyn. Waxaa kaloo udheer iney dareemaanLulmo daranQandhoQallalKooma."},{"question":"Wie lautet die Antwort auf diese Frage: Hat J.K. Rowling \\"The Casual Vacancy\\" geschrieben?","answer":"Die korrekte Antwort lautet \\"Ja\\"."},{"question":"அகம் இச்சொல்லின் எதிர்ச்சொல் ……………………………..உள்ளேதனியேபுறம்சிறப்பு","answer":"விடை : அகம் இச்சொல்லின் எதிர்ச்சொல் …………………புறம்"},{"question":"问题：水的熔点和沸点分别是多少？","answer":"回答：水的熔点是0摄氏度，沸点是100摄氏度（在常压下）。"},{"question":"Crie um verso contendo a palavra: Sorriso","answer":"Verso: Um simples sorriso, gesto de gratidão,Ilumina nossos dias, trazendo alegria ao coração."},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Kin-in-ni)","answer":"Ki i ṣe gbogbo eeyan lo mọ Maman Daura, baba kan to sun mọ Buhari ju ẹnikẹni lọ ni Naijiria loni-in yii ni. Ko gba iṣẹ ijọba o, ki i ṣe minisita, ki i ṣe gomina, ki i ṣe oluldamọran, sibẹ, inu Aso Rock lo n gbe pẹlu Buhari. Wahala baba naa pọ debii pe ija rẹpẹtẹ ni iyawo Buhari ati oun Daura n fi ọpọ ọjọ ja, ija naa si ti de ori awọn ọmọ wọn. Daura yii ni olori awọn mẹta ti wọn n dari Buhari lati igba to ti n ṣejọba rẹ. Awọn meji to ku, Abba Kyari ati Ismail Issa Funtua, ti ku bayii o, o waa ku oun nikan ati eti rẹ, ṣugbọn pẹlu pe oun nikan lo ku yii naa, o ṣi n fẹẹ maa dari Buhari, bẹẹ lo fẹ ki awọn Fulani ẹlẹgbẹ wọn mọ pe oun ni aṣoju wọn. Baba yii sọrọ kan lọsẹ to kọja, ọrọ naa si ti di ariwo rẹpẹtẹ. O ni ki Naijiria yee lo eto pe bi awọn Hausa-Fulani Ariwa ba jẹ Aarẹ tan, ki awọn ara Guusu (Ibo tabi Yoruba) naa tun jẹ. O ni bo ba jẹ ọmọ Hausa lo kun oju oṣuwọn ju, to mọwe, to si ni iriri ju, oun ni ki wọn jẹ ko ṣejọba, bo ba si jẹ Ibo tabi Yoruba ni, oun naa ni ki wọn yan sile ijọba.Pe ẹni to ba mọ eto ijọba ni ka gbe e fun, ki a ma fi ẹlẹyamẹya ṣejọba Naijiria mọ. Ọrọ naa dara daadaa, o si dun leti, bo si ṣe yẹ ki o ri gan-an niyẹn. Ṣugbọn alaboosi lawọn eeyan bii Daura yii, wọn kan fẹẹ da nnkan ru ni, nitori ẹ ni ko ṣe si ẹni to gba ọrọ naa gbọ, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i pariwo pe ki baba arugbo yii gbẹnu sọhun-un jare. To ba jẹ bi awọn Hausa-Fulani ti n ṣe lati ọjọ yii wa niyi ni, to ba jẹ ọrọ ti Daura sọ yii, o ti n sọ iru rẹ lọjọ to ti pẹ, ati nigba ti Buhari ti gbajọba yii, gbogbo ohun buruku to n ṣẹlẹ ninu ijọba yii ko ni i ṣẹlẹ, ohun gbogbo iba si dara fun Naijiria ju bayii lọ. Ẹgbọn ati ọrẹ timọ timọ Buhari ni Daura yii, ṣugbọn awọn ni wọn n gba Buhari nimọran debii pe ti wọn ba yọ ọmọ Yoruba tabi Ibo to ni iriri, to mọwe, to si ti pẹ lẹnu iṣẹ ijọba kan kuro nipo giga, puruntu ọmọ Mọla ti ko mọ kinni kan, apa amuṣua, ati eeyan ti ko si iwa ọmọluabi kan lara ẹ ni wọn yoo lọọ fi rọpo eeyan gidi ti wọn yọ kuro nipo kan, ko si si ohun ti wọn yoo ṣe gbe e lọ sibẹ ju pe o jẹ ọmọ Hausa-Fulani lọ. Ṣebi awọn Daura yii ni wọn wa nidii iwa raurau bẹẹ. Ki lo de ti Daura ko sọ nigba ti Yoruba tabi Ibo n ṣejọba pe ki wọn ma fi ọrọ ẹlẹyamẹya ṣe e, ṣebi oun naa wa ninu awọn ti wọn maa n pariwo pe Hausa lo kan, ilẹ Hausa ni wọn gbọdọ gbe ipo Aarẹ wa, awọn Yoruba ati Ibo ti ṣe tiwọn. Bo ba ṣe pe ni asiko awọn Yoruba tabi Ibo ni Daura jade, to ni ki wọn mu ọlọgbọn ati ẹni to ni iriri jade waa ṣejọba, ki wọn ma mu eeyan nitori pe o jẹ ọmọ Hausa, gbogbo aye ni yoo kin in lẹyin, ti wọn yoo si mu eeyan gidi kan jade. Ṣugbọn Hausa wo ni wọn gbe si ile iṣẹ ijọba Naijiria ti ki i ṣe pe o ba ibẹ jẹ ni. Wọn yoo ba ibẹ jẹ, tabi ki wọn jẹ ileeṣẹ naa pa. Ṣebi oun Daura yii naa ṣe olori ileeṣẹ ijọba ri, ki lo ṣẹlẹ si ileeṣẹ ti wọn fi i ṣe olori ẹ, ṣebi o parẹ naa ni. Ki lo de ti wọn n rọ awọn ọmọ Hausa-Fulani wọ inu iṣẹ ologun, wọn mọwe, wọn o mọwe, ki lo de ti o jẹ ọmọ Hausa-Fulani ni wọn n ko si ileeṣẹ ijọba gbogbo, nigba ti gbogbo aye mọ pe wọn ko ni iriri, bẹẹ ni wọn ko kawe debi ti wọn yoo fi le di iru awọn ipo bayii mu. O daa ti ijọba Buhari tete jade pe ọrọ ẹnu Daura funra ẹ lo n sọ, ki i ṣe ọrọ ijọba, nitori ko si ẹni ti yoo gba fun wọn o. Ni 2023, Guusu ilẹ Naijiria lo kan lati mu Aarẹ wa, boya lati ilẹ Yoruba ni o, tabi lati ilẹ Ibo. Ṣugbọn pe boya Hausa ni yoo tun ṣejọba Naijiria lẹyin Buhari, tawọn adaluru bii Daura yoo sọ pe o ni iriri, o si mọwe, iyẹn ko ni i ṣee ṣe, afi ka kuku da gbogbo ẹ ru lẹẹkan.Dajudaju, asasi awọn Boko Haram yii ti mu Buhari, o si mu awọn eeyan rẹ ti wọn jọ n ṣejọba. Bi ko ba ṣe bẹẹ ni, awọn eto to n jade lati ọdọ wọn yii lori ọrọ awọn Boko Haram ko ni i jade rara. Ijọba Buhari ko awọn Boko Haram jade, wọn ni wọn ti yipada, wọn lawọn ko paayan mọ, wọn kọ wọn niṣẹ baaba, wọn fun wọn ni ogun ẹgbẹrun pe ki wọn maa fi ṣe aye wọn. Ṣugbọn ọlọgbọn eeyan yoo mọ pe eleyii ko ṣee ṣe, nitori ko ni i mu oore kankan wa fun ilu. Awọn ọlọgbọn, onilaakaye, si sọ fun ijọba yii to o, ṣugbọn wọn ko gba, awọn ni oun to dara ju loju awọn niyẹn. Awọn ti awọn Boko Haram pa iya wọn, ti wọn pa baba wọn, ti wọn sọ di alaabọ ara, ti wọn le ni ibugbe wọn, ti wọn di isansa ati alarinkiri, awọn yẹn wa nibẹ o, ijọba Buhari ko ya si wọn. Kaka bẹẹ, awọn apaayan yii gan-an ni ijọba yii waa mu, ti wọn sọ di ọmọ tuntun, ti wọn si n gbe wọn gẹgẹ, ti wọn ni wọn ti yiwa pada. Gbogbo bawọn eeyan ti n sọ pe iru awọn afẹmiṣofo bayii ki i yipada bọrọ, bii ase lasan lo n jọ loju wọn. Oun naa lo ti n ṣẹlẹ yii o. Aṣofin Ndume lati ipinlẹ Borno ni ninu awọn ọmọ ti wọn lo ti yipada yii lọọ ka baba ẹ mọle, o si ṣa a pa, o si ko gbogbo maaluu ẹ sa lọ, bẹẹ lo wọ inu igbo tẹnikan ko ri i mọ. O ni ọpọlọpọ awọn ọmọ naa ni wọn n ṣe aṣemaṣe oriṣiiriṣii, ti wọn si n sa pada sinu igbo lẹsẹkẹsẹ, ibi ti wọn n sa lọ ko ye ẹnikan. Nibo ni wọn tun fẹẹ sa lọ ju inu igbo lọdọ awọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn ti wọn jẹ Boko Haram yii lọ, tabi ki wọn lọọ da ẹgbẹ janduku, ẹgbẹ ajinigbe tiwọn silẹ, ki wọn si bẹrẹ si i da ilu laamu kaakiri. Ni gbogbo aye loni-in, bi wọn ba mu awọn afẹmiṣofo yii nibi kan, kia ni wọn n pa wọn, tabi ki wọn ko wọn kuro niluu, ti wọn yoo si mọ pe awọn apaayan yii n dinku diẹ diẹ lawujọ wọn. Ṣugbọn ni Naijiria, bi ijọba tiwa ba ti mu awọn Boko Haram, wọn yoo bẹrẹ si i ṣe wọn bii ọmọ tuntun ti wọn bi, wọn yoo maa ra miliiki fun wọn, wọn yoo maa fun wọn lounjẹ ti awọn ti wọn ko paayan ri ko ri jẹ, awọn yẹn ni yoo si jẹun wọn yo titi ti wọn yoo fi ju wọn silẹ pe wọn ti yipada, wọn yoo si pada saarin awọn eeyan wọn ninu igbo. Iru ijọba wo leleyii bayii Olodumare! Tabi loootọ lasasi awọn Boko Haram ti mu wọn ni!Bi ko ba jẹ pe Ọlọrun wa lẹyin Gomina Zulum, ti ipinlẹ Borno, wọn iba pa a danu lọsẹ to kọja yii. Awọn Boko Haram ni, wọn iba ti yanju rẹ lẹẹkan. Awọn eeyan royin pe ninu awọn gomina to ti n jẹ nipinlẹ Borno, ọga lọkunrin yii, pe loootọ loootọ lo mura lati mu idagbasoke ba awọn eeeyan rẹ. Ṣe ipinlẹ yii, Borno, ni ogun Boko Haram pọ si ju lọ. Titi di bi a ṣe n wi yii ni wọn ṣi n gbe awọn eeyan, ti wọn si n pa awọn mi-in, awọn abule mi-in si ti wa to jẹ Boko Haram yii lo n paṣẹ ibẹ, wọn ti gba ibẹ lọwọ ijọba Naijiria patapata. Meloo meloo lawọn eeyan ti wọn ti le nile wọn, ati awọn ti wọn ti gba gbogbo ohun-ini wọn. Lati mu nnkan bọ sipo, Gomina Zulum ni oun yoo da awọn yẹn pada si aaye wọn, oun yoo si mọ bi oun yoo ṣe pese iṣẹ ti awọn ti Boko Haram yii ti pa saye yoo ṣe bẹrẹ igbe-aye tuntun. Nidii eyi, gbogbo ibi ti wọn ba ti ko awọn eeyan pamọ si, awọn abule ti wọn ti le wọn nibẹ tẹlẹ tawọn yẹn tun ṣẹṣẹ n pada si, gbogbo ibi ti ọkunrin gomina yii n ṣe abẹwo si niyẹn. Bo ba ti debẹ, yoo ba wọn sọrọ pe ohun gbogbo yoo daa laipẹ, yoo si fun wọn ni ounjẹ ati owo ti wọn yoo maa na, pẹlu awọn nnkan mi-in ti wọn nilo gidi. Ọsẹ to waa kọja yii lo lọ si Baga, ibi ti wọn ti mọ tẹlẹ pe awọn Boko Haram lo gbajọba ibẹ. Ṣugbọn ki i deede lọ, awọn ọga ṣọja ti wọn ti ko sibẹ lati ọjọ yii wa ni wọn fọkan ẹ balẹ pe nibi yoowu ni ipinlẹ Borno, ko si awọn Boko Haram ẹyọ kan bayii mọ. N loun ba gbera, o ku dẹdẹ ki wọn wọ Baga ni wọn da ina ibọn bo o, bi ko si jẹ pe o rakoro kuro nibẹ ni, ibẹ ni wọn iba pa a si. Inu bi gomina naa, o fibinu sọrọ sawọn ṣọja. Ṣugbọn ṣe awọn ṣọja yii ni yoo ba wi ni abi ijọba Buhari, abi Buhari to ko awọn olori ologun sibẹ lati ọjọ yii ti wọn ko ṣiṣẹ wọn bii iṣẹ, ti ko si le wọn kuro, bẹẹ lo si mọ pe apa wọn ko ka iṣẹ ti wọn gbe fun wọn ṣe. Afi bii epe nijọba yii, Ọlọrun nikan lo mọ ohun tawọn ọmọ Naijiria ṣe to fi ran iru ẹ si wọn.Oniranu kan ṣaa lawọn Ijẹbu n pe ni alaraka, iru wọn lawọn eeyan ti a si ko kun ile ijọba wa. Nitori ẹ ni wọn ṣe fẹẹ yagbẹ sara, wọn fẹẹ daku lọsẹ to kọja yii, koda, eeyan ko ro pe iru ariwo bẹẹ le ti ẹnu wọn jade. Ọkunrin kan lo ko wahala yii si wọn lagbada o, ni wọn ba bẹrẹ si i sare kiri, ti wọn n fooro ẹmi ara wọn. Chidi Chukuanyi, olori ẹgbe oṣelu ADP, lo sọ pe asiko ti to ni Naijiria ki wọn lo iru eto ti Jerry Rawlings lo fun gbogbo awọn oloṣelu ilẹ Ghana lọdọ wa ni Naijiria naa. N lawọn Buhari ati awọn eeyan rẹ ba fẹẹ fori sọlẹ, ibi ti ọrọ naa gba lara wọn ko dara rara. Olori ijọba ilẹ Ghana ni Rawlings nigba kan. Ijọba ologun lo ṣe. Asiko ti wahala ati ikowojẹ awọn oloṣelu to jẹ olori ijọba alagbada ilẹ naa pọ ju lo gbajọba, n lo ba wadii gbogbo awọn oloṣelu naa awọn to si kowo jẹ ninu wọn, wọn yinbọn pa wọn ni gbangba ode ni. Iru ẹ ni Chidi ni ko ṣẹlẹ ni Naijiria nitori ikowojẹ buruku to n lọ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹyin Buhari wọnyi nile ijọba. Bi awọn ọmọ Buhari ṣe gbọ ọrọ naa ni wọn wọ ṣokoto ija, Lai Muhammed sare jade, o ni ko si ijọba kan to n gbogun ti iwa ibajẹ ju ijọba Buhari yii lọ. Lo ṣaa lọgun titi, lo fi ọwọ luwọ, lo fi ete lu ete, ṣugbọn nigba ti pupọ ninu awọn eeyan mọ pe irọ a maa pọ ninu ọrọ ọkunrin naa ju, wọn ko ka ọrọ rẹ si nnkan gidi kan. Afi bi awọn olori ologun ilẹ wa ṣe sare jade, ti wọn bẹrẹ si i ke ewi gidi. Wọn ni ṣọja kan ko gbọdọ gbajọba, gbogbo ṣọja gbọdọ mọ pe ka fi ibọn gbajọba lodi sofin, wọn ko gbọdọ dan an wo, wọn gbọdọ duro lẹyin ijọba Buhari yii ni. Wọn ṣaa n pariwo oriṣiiriṣii bẹẹ, nitori ọrọ ti ọkunrin yii sọ. Aṣe bayii ni wọn bẹru iku to, ti wọn si n fi iku pa awọn araalu. Aṣe bayii ni wọn bẹru iya to, ti wọn n fiya jẹ gbogbo wa. Bi iwọ ba ṣe rere, ara ki o ha ya ọ. Bi ijọba Buhari ba mọ pe awọn ṣe daadaa to fawọn araalu, kin ni wọn n bẹru bi ṣọja yoo gbajọba tabi ko ni i gbajọba si. Iyẹn ni pe awọn naa mọ pe ohun tawọn n ṣe yii ko dara. Eeyan kọ ni yoo da ẹjọ eleyii o, Ọlọrun funra rẹ ni yoo da a. Ẹ maa rẹ wa jẹ niṣo, Ọlọrun n bọ ti yoo fi iya to tọ jẹ gbogbo ẹyin ọjẹlu ati ẹyin oloṣelu oniṣẹ ibi."},{"question":"దాతృత్వమే నేటి సమాజానికి అవసరం. వివరించండి.","answer":"1. నేటి సమాజంలో ఒకరినొకరు పట్టించుకోవడం తగ్గుతోంది.2. ఈ పరిస్థితిలో మార్పు రావాలంటే దానగుణం రావాలి.3. దానగుణం వలన ఆపదలో ఉన్నవారికి సహాయం దొరుకుతుంది.4. మోసం తగ్గుతుంది. దొంగతనాలు తగ్గుతాయి.5. మనిషిలో స్వార్థం తగ్గుతుంది.6. సమాజంలో క్రూరత్వం తగ్గుతుంది.7. స్నేహం పెరుగుతుంది.8. కలిసిమెలసి ఉంటారు. ఒకరి కష్టసుఖాలలో ఒకరు పాలుపంచుకొంటారు.9. ప్రపంచమంతా ఒకే కుటుంబం. అందరూ నావాళ్ళే అనే భావాలు పెంపొందుతాయి.10. అవిద్య, పేదరికం, రోగాలు, యుద్ధాలు మొదలైనవి అంతమౌతాయి. సంపద, ఆరోగ్యం, శాంతి మొదలగునవి పెరుగుతాయి.11. పగ, ప్రతీకారం, ద్వేషం మొదలైనవి పోతాయి.12. గౌరవం, ప్రేమ, వాత్సల్యం, అభిమానం, బంధుత్వాలు, స్నేహాలు మొదలైనవి పెరుగుతాయి."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Atoandro mampitorovoka, alina mampitsikasina.\\"","answer":"Valiny : tsihy. Milaza ny hampiasana ny tsihy rehefa andavanandro."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Nabiga (NNKH) Iyo Abuu-Bakar Ninkii Ceersaday Markii Ey Hijroonaayeen?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu Ahaa Suraaqa Bin Maalik."},{"question":"Qual é a maior elevação da maré na costa norte-americana?","answer":"A Baía de Fundy, na costa leste do Canadá, costuma ser considerada como tendo as marés mais altas do mundo por causa de sua forma, batimetria e distância da borda da plataforma continental. Medições feitas em novembro de 1998 em Burntcoat Head na Baía de Fundy registraram uma amplitude máxima de 16,3 metros (53 pés) e um extremo mais alto previsto de 17 metros (56 pés)."},{"question":"வினா: இந்திய துணைக்கண்டத்தில் காணப்படும் பழமையான நாகரீகத்தின் பெயர் என்ன?","answer":"விடை: சிந்து சமவெளி நாகரிகம்"},{"question":"Суроо: Америка Кошмо Штаттарынын 44-президенти ким?","answer":"Жооп: Барак Обама."},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį sudėtingą klausimą: kuri Pietų Korėjos aktorė, gimusi 1979-aisiais, pasirodžiusi Pietų Korėjos televizijos seriale \\"Šnabždėjimas\\"?","answer":"Lee Bo-young"},{"question":"نئی دہلی کے بارے میں بتایے:","answer":"نئی دہلی حکومت بھارت کا دار الحکومت اور قدیم شہر ہے۔ یہ پہلے بھی بادشاہوں کی دار الحکومت ہو کرتا تھا اور آج بھی یہ اس ملک کا دار الحکومت ہے مغلوں کے زمانے میں تعمیر شدہ عمارتین آپ کو اس شہر میں بھی کافی تعداد میں ملتی ہیں جنمیں دہلی کا لال قلعہ، جامع مسجد اور قطب الدین کی تعمیر کردہ قطب مینار سر فہرست ہے۔ملک\\t بھارتریاست/عملداری\\tدہلیقائم شدہ\\t1911افتتاح\\t1931رقبہ[1] • شہر و دارالحکومت\\t1,484 کلومیٹر2 (573 میل مربع)بلندی\\t216 میل (709 فٹ)آبادی (2011)[2] • شہر و دارالحکومت\\t249,998 • کثافت\\t5,854.7/کلومیٹر2 (15,164/میل مربع) • میٹرو\\t21,753,486زبانیں • دفتری\\tہندی، انگریزی • دوسری سرکاری زبانیں\\tاردو، پنجابی[3]منطقۂ وقت\\tبھارتی معیاری وقت (UTC+5:30)ڈاک اشاریہ رمز\\t110xxxٹیلی فون کوڈ\\t+91-11گاڑی کی نمبر پلیٹ\\tDL-1x-x-xxxx to DL-13x-x-xxxxویب سائٹ\\twww.ndmc.gov.in"},{"question":"නාහිමියෝ  දහම් දෙසූ ය.නිවැරදි ද ?","answer":"වැරදි ,⁣ දෙසූ ය. -> දෙසූහ.නාහිමියෝ (ඕ) ප්‍රත්‍ය යෙදෙන විට ආඛ්‍යාතය බහුවචන විය යුතුයි"},{"question":"inona no mahatonga ny olon-droa hifankatia?","answer":"ny fitiavana no mahatonga ny olon-droa hifankatia"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kuih kayu keramat yang merupakan kuih-muih tradisional Melayu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 500 g tepung gandum, 1 atau 2 sudu kecil soda bikarbonat, 1 sudu kecil yis, 6 sudu besar gula pasir,1 sudu besar marjerin, 230 ml air (boleh lebihkan)Cara-cara:1. Uli semua bahan dan masukkan ke dalam peti ais semalaman supaya adunan naik.2. Ambil sedikit adunan dan tarik adunan tersebut secara memanjang.3. Gorengkan adunan dalam api sederhana dan sedia untuk dihidang."},{"question":"Жөнөкөй жана татаал сүйлөм деген эмне?","answer":"Бир сүйлөмдөн туруп, бүткөн айрым бир ойду билдирсе, жөнөкөй сүйлөм болот.Мисалы: Күз келди.Эки же андан ашык мааниси жагынан байланышкан жөнөкөй сүйлөмдөрдөн куралып, бүткөн бир ойду түшүндүргөн сүйлөмдү татаалсүйлөм дейбиз.Мисалы: Күз келип, жыйым-терим башталды"},{"question":"\\"Ndiudze nezve album The Any Day Now The Any Day Now The Any Day Now EP ndiyo yechitatu kubudiswa kweElbow. Iyi EP yakabudiswa kuburikidza neElbow yekutanga rekodhi rekodhi Ugly Man Records, pamwe neyechipiri rekodhi rekodhi V2 Records. MaEP ese ari maviri ane track yakasiyana. listing.Rwiyo \\"\\"George Lassoes the Moon\\"\\" paiyo Ugly Man Records vhezheni yeEP inosiyana neshanduro paThe Noisebox EP. Haisi kungopfupika kweminiti chete, asi zvakare inogadzirwa mumhanzi kupfuura yakaoma yekutanga vhezheni. \\"\\"Wurzel\\"\\" rwiyo runobatsira.\\"","answer":"\\"The Any Day Now EP ndiyo yechitatu yekubudiswa kweElbow. Iyi EP yakabudiswa kuburikidza neElbow's first record label Ugly Man Records, pamwe chete neyechipiri rekodhi rekodhi V2 Records. Zvose EPs imwe neimwe ine zvakasiyana-siyana zvekutsvaga.Rwiyo \\"\\"George Lassoes the Moon\\"\\" paiyo Ugly Man Records vhezheni yeEP inosiyana neshanduro paThe Noisebox EP. Haisi kungopfupika kweminiti chete, asi zvakare inogadzirwa mumhanzi kupfuura yakaoma yekutanga vhezheni. \\"\\"Wurzel\\"\\" rwiyo runobatsira.\\""},{"question":"شنو كايتسمى الصوت ديال الماء ؟","answer":"كيتسمى الخرير"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn 200 chữ về SỰ LỰA CHỌN THẦN TƯỢNG CỦA GIỚI TRẺ.","answer":"Sự lựa chọn thần tượng của giới trẻ thường phản ánh tầm quan trọng của việc tìm kiếm nguồn cảm hứng và hình mẫu. Đối với họ, thần tượng không chỉ là những người nổi tiếng trên sân khấu, màn ảnh, mà còn có thể là những nhân vật trong sách, những nhà lãnh đạo, hoặc thậm chí là người thầy giáo. Việc lựa chọn thần tượng không chỉ dựa trên vẻ ngoại hình, mà còn trân trọng những phẩm chất như lòng kiên nhẫn, tinh thần sáng tạo và đạo đức lành mạnh.Thần tượng giúp giới trẻ học cách đặt ra mục tiêu và nỗ lực hướng đến chúng. Họ nhận ra rằng thành công đến từ sự cống hiến và không ngừng phấn đấu. Thần tượng cũng khơi gợi niềm tin vào bản thân, giúp họ vượt qua khó khăn và tự tin khám phá tiềm năng bản thân.Tuy nhiên, sự lựa chọn thần tượng cũng cần được xem xét cẩn thận, tránh việc theo đuổi mù quáng mà bỏ qua những giá trị cốt lõi. Quan trọng nhất, giới trẻ cần nhớ rằng mỗi người đều có hành trang riêng trong cuộc hành trình, và thần tượng chỉ là nguồn cảm hứng, chứ không phải mục tiêu cuối cùng."},{"question":"都道府県の面積で１番広いのは北海道。では２番目はどこ？","answer":"岩手県です。"},{"question":"Con trai tôi 12 tuổi bị cận 1 bên 3,75 độ, 1 bện 1.75 độ (cận lúc 9 tuổi). Xin cho biết với kỹ thuật tiên tiến hiện nay con tôi có điều trị tật khúc xạ mắt được không, nếu được thì chi phí bao nhiêu? ","answer":"Chào bạn, cháu dưới 18 tuổi nên chưa thực hiện được các biện pháp phẫu thuật tật khúc xạ mắt. Tuy nhiên, ngoài đeo kính gọng, bạn có thể sử dụng thêm biện pháp khác cho con như đeo kính áp tròng cứng ban đêm. Để biết con có phù hợp với phương pháp này không, bạn cần đưa con đến các cơ sở chuyên khoa mắt khám, xác định số kính chính xác, đo công suất giác mạc, chụp bản đồ giác mạc từ đó có sự tư vấn cụ thể của bác sĩ. Chi phí cho phương pháp đeo kính áp tròng sẽ dao động tùy thuộc vào bệnh viện."},{"question":"به متن زیر مراجعه کنید و سپس به همان زبانی که در متن آمده است به سوال بعد پاسخ دهید:گذرگاه: بیشتر این قطعات در آثار مربوط به قرون وسطی هند ، تقریباً بین قرون هشتم و دوازدهم ، یافت می شوند. رساله گسترده قرن 14 در فلسفه هند توسط مادوا ویدارانی Sarvadarshanasamgraha ، شرح مفصل کارواکا را ارائه می دهد ، اما به طور مستقیم از متون کارواکا نقل قول نمی کند ، در عوض این نظریه را با توجه به درک یک ویدانتین تحصیل کرده قرن 14 تفسیر می کند. بهتاچاریا 68 مورد را در 9 صفحه ذکر کرده است. سوال: آثار از چه دوره ای هستند؟","answer":"آثار ذکر شده مربوط به قرون وسطی هند یعنی مابین قرن هشتم و دوازدهم هستند."},{"question":"ഈ വാചകം ഏത് പ്രധാന സംഭവത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്: ബ്രിട്ടീഷ്‌ ഭരണകാലത്ത്‌ മലബാറിലുണ്ടായ അസ്വസ്ഥതകൾ നിയന്ത്രിക്കുന്നതിനു വേണ്ടി 1881-ൽ മലപ്പുറം സ്പെഷ്യൽ പോലീസ്‌ സ്ഥാപിതമായി. പിന്നീട്‌ 1921-ൽ മലബാർ കലാപം പൊട്ടിപ്പുറപ്പെട്ടപ്പോൾ അത്‌ അമർച്ച ചെയ്യുന്നതിനു വേണ്ടി മലപ്പുറം സ്പെഷ്യൽ പോലീസ്‌, പുന:സംഘടിപ്പിക്കുകയും മലബാർ സ്പെഷ്യൽ പോലീസ്‌ (MSP) എന്ന് പുനർ നാമകരണം ചെയ്യപ്പെടുകയും ചെയ്തു. 1921 സെപ്റ്റംബർ 30-ന് ആറ് കമ്പനി അംഗബലവുമായി മലബാർ സ്പെഷ്യൽ പൊലീസ് നിലവിൽ വന്നു. 1932-ൽ സേനയുടെ അംഗബലം 16 കമ്പനി ആയി ഉയർത്തി. കേരളം നിലവിൽ വന്നതോടെ എം.എസ്.പി.യെ രണ്ടായി വിഭജിച്ചു. എം.എസ്‌.പി.യുടെ ആദ്യത്തെ കമാന്റന്റ് ച്ചാദഡ് ഹോവദഡ് ഹിച്ച്‌കോക്ക് ആയിരുന്നു.","answer":"ഈ ഭാഗം മലബാർ കലാപത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് പറയുന്നത്. "},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kas yra IPv6?","answer":"Atsakymas: Tai yra atnaujinta interneto protokolo (angl. IP) naudojama adresacijos versija, kuri pakeitė ankstesnę IPv4 dėl besibaigiančio unikalių IP adresų, kuriais identifikuojami interneto  mazgai ir į juos/ iš jų nukreipiamas duomenų srautas, erdvės (angl. address space). Adresų stoka pradėjo jaustis vis daugiau atsirandant \\"daiktų interneto\\" (IoT) mazgų. Po laipsniškai įvykusio protokolo adresacijos pakeitimo, kuris reikalavo tiek techninės, tiek programinės įrangos atnaujinimų interneto tiekėjų ir naudotojų įrenginiuose, adresų erdvė tapo pakankama priskirti adresą kiekvienam žemės atomui, ir tai pakartoti 100 kartų."},{"question":"Cahaya matahari jelas kelihatan ____________________ kaki langit pada waktu senjadi Pantai Cherating","answer":"di"},{"question":"\\"Vaovao sy matsiro hatrany ny voankazo eto amin’ity tsena ity.\\" Inona ny fihetseham-po raketin'io fanambarana io?","answer":" Ity fanambarana ity dia maneho fihetseham-po tsara. Mankasitraka ny kalitaon'ny vokatra eny an-tsena ilay olona."},{"question":"చిన్నతరహా సంస్థలను నిర్వచించండి.","answer":"ఉత్పత్తి సంస్థలు అయితే యంత్రపరికరాలలో పెట్టిన పెట్టుబడి 25 లక్షల రూపాయల కంటే ఎక్కువగా ఉండి, 5 కోట్ల రూపాయలకు మించకపోతే దానిని చిన్నతరహా సంస్థ అంటారు.సేవాసంస్థలయితే పరికరాలలో పెట్టిన పెట్టుబడి 10 లక్షల రూపాయల కంటే ఎక్కువగా ఉండి, 2 కోట్ల రూపాయలకు మించకపోతే దానిని చిన్నతరహా సంస్థ అంటారు."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'putih hati'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud ikhlas dan jujur. Contoh ayat: Semenjak kecil Arief telah dididik dengan sikap putih hati."},{"question":"香港的文化特色是什么？","answer":"答：香港文化深受中西文化影响，是东西方文化交融的重要地方。在电影、音乐、美食等方面都有独特的文化表现。"},{"question":"Paano ginagamit ang \\"rin\\" at \\"din\\" sa wikang Filipino?","answer":"Ginagamit ang “rin” kapag ang pangungusap ay nagtatapos sa mga patinig (a, e, i, o, u), o sa mga mala-patinig na “w” at “y.” Sa kabilang banda, ginagamit ang “din” kapag ang sinusundang salita nito ay nagtatapos sa mga katinig, maliban sa mga katinig na “w” at “y.” Ang sumusunod ay halimbawa ng wastong paggamit ng \\"rin\\" at \\"din\\" sa pangungusap:1. Nagbabasa rin siya ng libro.2. Ako rin ay naglinis ng kwarto.3. Si Ana rin ay may dalawang kapatid.4. Gusto ko rin ng pizza tulad mo.5. Maglilinis din ako ng bahay mamayang hapon.6. Tara, maglakad din tayo sa park.7. Masarap din ito.8. Naghanap din siya ng libro sa bookstore.9. Lumabas din siya ng bahay kanina. Sumama rin siya sa akin."},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para o parágrafo a seguir - O \\"Scirocco\\" teve um início de carreira tranquilo, mas ajudou na intervenção italiana na Guerra Civil Espanhola ao escoltar navios de transporte de voluntários. Na Segunda Guerra Mundial, participou de várias operações de escoltas de comboio para a Campanha Norte-Africana e também esteve presente na Batalha da Calábria em julho de 1940 e na Segunda Batalha de Sirte","answer":"em março de 1942. A frota italiana foi pega por uma grande tempestade ao retornarem deste último confronto e o navio ficou para trás e acabou afundando na manhã do dia 23 de março. Houve apenas dois sobreviventes."},{"question":"Amin'ny fampifangaroana mena sy fotsy, inona no loko azonao?a) Mangab) Mavokelyd) Mavoe) volontany","answer":"b) Mavokely  no loko azo amin'ny fampifangaroana mena sy fotsy"},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي \\"من هو مكتشف كوكب أورانس ؟\\".","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي \\"وليم هرشن\\"."},{"question":"Zer da kultura?","answer":"Kultura gizaki talde batentzako ideiak, ohiturak, balioak, arteak, teknologia, hizkuntza eta beste elementu sozial batzuen multzoa da."},{"question":"السؤال: من مكتشف قارة أمريكا؟","answer":"الإجابة: كريستوفر كولومبوس"},{"question":"கேள்வி:மொழியின் விரல் பிடித்து நடக்க பழகிக் கொண்டிருக்கும் தன் மகனுக்கு நா. முத்துக்குமார் எழுதியுள்ள கடிதச் செய்திகளைத் தொகுத்து எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில் :முன்னுரை:கடித செய்தி என்பது உயிர்ப்புள்ள மொழி. செய்தியை அளிப்பவருக்கும், பெறுபவருக்குமான உறவுப் பாலத்தை உறுதியாக்குகிறது. தாயுமானவனாகத் திகழ்ந்த முத்துக்குமார் அவர்கள் தம் மகனுக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள செய்திகளை அறிவோம்.குழந்தைப் பருவமும் – உலக வாழ்வும்:என் செல்லப் பூங்குட்டியே! நீ குழந்தையாய் இருந்தாய்; அழுதாய்; சிரித்தாய்; குப்புறக்கவிழ்ந்து தலைநிமிர்ந்து, சாகசம் கொண்டாடினாய். தரையெல்லாம் உனதாக்கித் தவழ்ந்தாய்; எழுந்தாய்; விழுந்தாய்; நடந்தாய்; ஓடினாய்.இந்த உலக வாழ்வும் இப்படித்தான். சிரிக்க வேண்டும், சிணுங்க வேண்டும், குப்புறக்கவிழ்ந்தும், தலைநிமிர்ந்தும் சாகசம் செய்தல் வேண்டும். தவழ வேண்டும், எழவேண்டும், விழவேண்டும், மீண்டும் எழ வேண்டும், இந்த நாடகத்தை நீ வெவ்வேறு வடிவங்களில் உலக வாழ்வில் நடிக்கத்தான் வேண்டும்.அனுபவமே கல்வி:கல்வியில் தேர்ச்சி கொள்ள வேண்டும், அதே நேரம் அனுபவங்களிடம் இருந்து அதிகம் கற்றுக் கொள். தீயைப் படித்துத் தெரிந்து கொள்வதை விட தீண்டிக் காயம் பெறு. அந்த அனுபவக் கல்வியே இவ்வுலகில் வெற்றியுடன் வாழ பயன்படும் சூத்திரம் ஆகும்.அன்பாக இரு:எங்கும், எதிலும் எப்போதும் அன்பாய் இரு. அன்பை விட உயர்ந்தது இவ்வுலகில் வேறு எதுவுமே இல்லை. உன் பேரன்பால் இந்தப் பிரபஞ்சத்தை நனைத்துக் கொண்டே இரு. உறவுகளை விட மேன்மையானது நட்பு மட்டுமே, உன் அன்பால் நல்ல நண்பர்களைச் சேர்த்துக் கொள். உன் வாழ்வு அன்பாலும், நட்பாலும் நேராகும்.உனக்கான காற்றை நீயே உருவாக்கு:என் மகனே மாநகரத்தில் நீ வாழ்க்கை முழுக்கக் கோடைகாலங்களையும், வெவ்வேறு வடிவங்களில் கொடிய தேள்களையும் சந்திக்க வேண்டியிருக்கும். எப்போதும் உன் தகப்பன் உன் அருகில் அமர்ந்து விசிறி கொண்டிருக்க முடியாது. உனக்கான காற்றை நீயே உருவாக்கு.புத்தகங்களை நேசி:புத்தகங்களை நேசிக்கத் தவறாதே. ஒரு புத்தகத்தைத் தொடுகிறபோது நீ ஓர் அனுபவத்தைத் தொடுவாய். உன் பாட்டனும் தகப்பனும் புத்தகங்களின் காட்டில் தொலைந்தவர்கள் உன் உதிரத்தில் காகித நதி ஓடிக்கொண்டே இருக்கட்டும்.முடிவுரை:இக்கருத்துக்கள் அனைத்தும் முத்துக்குமாரின் மகனுக்கு மட்டுமல்ல. இதனைப் படிக்கின்ற ஒவ்வொரு மாணவனுக்கும், ஒவ்வொரு குழந்தைக்கும், வளர்வதற்கும், உயர்வதற்கும், ஏற்ற கருத்துக்கள் ஆகும் என்பதை எவராலும் மறுக்க இயலாது.நா. முத்துக்குமார்கருவிப் பெட்டிகட்டற்ற கலைக்களஞ்சியமான விக்கிப்பீடியாவில் இருந்து.நா. முத்துக்குமார்பிறப்பு\\tசூலை 12, 1975 காஞ்சிபுரம், தமிழ் நாடு, இந்தியாஇறப்பு\\t14 ஆகத்து 2016 (அகவை 41)சென்னைஇறப்பிற்கானகாரணம்\\tமஞ்சள் காமாலைபணி\\tபாடலாசிரியர், கவிஞர், எழுத்தாளர், நாவலாசிரியர்வாழ்க்கைத்துணை\\tஜீவலஷ்மிபிள்ளைகள்\\tமகன் ஆதவன், மகள் யோகலஷ்மிநா. முத்துக்குமார் (Na. Muthukumar; 12 சூலை 1975 – 14 ஆகத்து 2016), தமிழ்நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த தமிழ் திரைப்படப் பாடலாசிரியரும் கவிஞரும் ஆவார். பல்லேலக்கா, என் காதல் சொல்ல, ஒரு கல் ஒரு கண்ணாடி ஆகியவை இவரின் பாடல்களுள் சில. தங்க மீன்கள், சைவம் திரைப்படப் பாடல்களுக்காக தேசிய விருது பெற்றவர்.வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்புகாஞ்சிபுரம் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள கன்னிகாபுரத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர் இவர்.நான்கு வயதில் தாயை இழந்தவர்.சிறு வயதில் இருந்தே புத்தகங்களை உலகமாகக் கொண்டார்.கல்விகாஞ்சிபுரம் ஆண்டர்சன் மேல்நிலைப்பள்ளியில் 12ஆம் வகுப்பு வரைப் படித்துத் தேறினார். பின்னர் காஞ்சிபுரம் பச்சையப்பன் ஆடவர் கல்லூரியில் இயல்பியல் பயின்று 88% மதிப்பெண் பெற்று அறிவியல் இளவர் பட்டமும் சென்னை பச்சையப்பன் கல்லூரியில் தமிழ் இலக்கியம் பயின்று கலைமுதுவர் பட்டமும் பெற்றார். இவர் எழுதிய தூர் என்ற கவிதையே முதுகலையில் இவருக்குப் பாடமாக இருந்தது. பின்னர் \\"தமிழ்த் திரைப்படப் பாடல்கள் 1990 முதல் 2000 வரை\\" என்ற தலைப்பில் ஆய்வுசெய்து முனைவர் பட்டமும் பெற்றார்.பணிதொடக்கத்தில் திரைப்பட இயக்குநராக சென்னை தமிழ்நாடு திரைப்படக் கல்லூரியில் இயக்குநர் பிரிவில் இணைய விண்ணப்பத்தார். ஆனால், இடங்கிடைக்கவில்லை.எனவே, இயக்குநர் பாலுமகேந்திராவிடம் நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் பணிசெய்தார். இயக்குநர் சீமானின் வீரநடை என்ற படத்தில் பாடல் எழுதினார். கிரீடம் (2007),வாரணம் ஆயிரம் (2008) ஆகியன போன்ற சில படங்களுக்கு வசனம் எழுதினார். இதுவரை கிட்டதட்ட 1500 பாடல்களுக்கு மேல் எழுதியுள்ள இவர் [7], 2016 வரை தமிழ்த் திரையுலகின் முன்னணி பாடலாசிரியராக இருந்தார். “பட்டாம்பூச்சி பதிப்பகம்” என்ற பெயரில் பதிப்பகம் தொடங்கி நடத்தினார்.இவர் 2006ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆனி மாதம் 14 ஆம் தேதி, வடபழனியில் ஜீவலட்சுமி என்பவரை திருமணம் செய்தார். இவர்களுக்கு ஆதவன் என்ற மகனும் யோகலட்சுமி என்ற மகளும் உள்ளனர்.மறைவு2016 ஆகத்து 14 அன்று காலையில் தனது 41வது வயதில் காலமானார். மஞ்சள்காமாலையால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு, காய்ச்சல் முற்றிய நிலையில் இறந்தார்."},{"question":"கேள்வி : புவி வெப்பமயமாதல் என்றால் என்ன?","answer":"பதில்  :புவி வெப்பமயமாதல்புவி வெப்பமயமாதல் என்பது புவி மேற்புற பகுதியின் சராசரி வெப்பநிலையில் ஏற்பட்டிருக்கும் சீரான வெப்பநிலை உயர்வை குறிக்கிறது. 20 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் இரண்டாம் பாதியில் புவியின் வளிமண்டலத்தின் சராசரி வெப்பநிலை கூடியிருப்பதும் தொடர்ந்து கூடிவருவதுமான நிகழ்வு புவி வெப்பமயமாதல் எனப்படுகிறது. சென்ற நூற்றாண்டில் புவியின் மேற்பரப்பு வெப்பநிலை கூடியிருக்கிறது. இருபதாம் நூற்றாண்டின் நடுவிலிருந்து தற்போது வரையான வெப்பநிலை கூடுவதற்கு புதைபடிவ எரிமங்களின் எரிப்பு, காடழிப்பு, போன்ற மனித செயற்பாடுகளே காரணமென தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாற்றத்திற்கான அரசிடைக்குழு முடிவு செய்துள்ளது. இந்த அடிப்படையான முடிவுகள், ஜி8 நாடுகளில் அறிவியல் கழகங்கள் உட்பட 70க்கும் கூடுதலான அறிவியல் சமூகங்களாலும் அறிவியல் கழகங்களாலும் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டிருக்கின்றன.தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாற்றத்திற்கான அரசிடைக்குழுவின் அறிக்கையில் தொகுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாதிரிகளின் எதிர்காலா மதிப்பீடுகள் இருபத்தொறாம் நூற்றாண்டில் புவி மேற்பரப்பு வெப்பநிலை மேலும் 1.1 தொடக்கம் 6.4 ° வரை (2.0–11.5 °) கூடலாம் என்பதைச் சுட்டிக் காட்டுகின்றன. ஒவ்வொரு தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாதிரியும் வெவ்வேறான அளவு வெப்பம் சிக்குறுத்தும் வளிமங்களின் வெப்பநிலை கூட்டும் திறனையும் எதிகால உற்பத்தி அளவுகளையும் பயன்படுத்துவதால் தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாதிரிகளின் மதிப்பீடுகள் மாறுபடுகின்றன. புவி சூடாதல் புவியின் எல்லா இடங்களிலும் ஒரே அளவில் இருக்காது என்பது உட்பட பல நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மைகளும் இந்த தட்பவெப்பநிலை மாதிரிகளின் மதிப்பீடுகளில் காணப்படுகிறன. கூடுதலான ஆய்வுகள் 2100 ஆம் ஆண்டு வரை கருதியே செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன எனினும், வெப்பம் சிக்குறுத்தும் வளிமங்களின் உமிழ்வு முற்றாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டாலும் பெருங்கடல்களின் பாரிய வெப்பக்கொள்ளளவு, வளிமண்டலத்தில் கரியமில வளிமத்தின் நீண்ட ஆயுட்காலம் என்பவற்றைக் கருதும் போது 2100 ஆம் ஆண்ட்டுக்கு அப்பாலும் புவி சூடாதல் தொடரும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.கூடிவரும் புவி வெப்பநிலை கடல் மட்டத்தை உயரச் செய்து வீழ்படிவு கோலத்தை மாற்றிவிடும், மேலதிகமாக இதில் மிதவெப்ப மண்டல பாலைவனப் பகுதிகள் விரிவடைவதும் அடங்கலாம். பனியாறுகள், நிலை உறை மண், கடல்ப் பனி என்பவை துருவங்களை நோக்கிப் தொடந்ந்து பின்வாங்கும் என் எதிர்வுக்க்கூறப்படுகிறது. சூடாதல் விளைவு ஆர்க்டிக் பகுதியில் கூடுதலாக காணப்படும். சீரற்ற தட்பவெப்பநிலை நிகழ்வுகளின் கடுமை கூடுதல், உயிரின அழிவு வேகம் கூடுதல், வேளாண்மை விளைச்சளின் மாற்றங்கள் என்பவை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் சில விளைவுகளாகும்.புவி சூடாதலினைக் குறித்தும் அதைத் தடுப்பதற்கான நடைமுறைகள் குறித்தும் கருத்துப் பரிமாற்றங்கள் தொடர்ந்துக் கொண்டிருக்கின்றன. புவி சூடாதல் விளைவுகளை தடுப்பதற்கு இப்போதைக்குள்ள முறைகளாக வெப்பம் சிக்குறுத்தும் வளிமங்களின் உமிழ்வைக் குறைத்தல், சூடாதல் காரணமாக ஏற்படும் விளைவுகளிற்கு ஏற்வாறு மாறிக்கொள்ளல் என்பன முக்கியமானவையாகும். வெப்பம் சிக்குறுத்தும் வளிமங்களின் உமிழ்வைக் குறைக்கும் நோக்குடைய கியோத்தோ நெறிமுறையில் பல நாடுகள் கைச்சாத்திட்டு நடைமுறைக்கு கொண்டுவந்துள்ளன."},{"question":"Một hộp có 1 quả bóng xanh và 1 quả bóng đỏ; các quả bóng có kích thước và khối lượng như nhau. Lấy ngẫu nhiên một quả bóng trong hộp.Những kết quả nào có thể xảy ra?","answer":"Lời giải:Sau bài học này ta sẽ trả lời được, hoặc dựa vào thực tế thực hành rút ra được những kết quả có thể xảy ra là: quả bóng lấy ra có thể là quả bóng màu xanh hoặc quả bóng màu đỏ."},{"question":"Wie heißen die Zwillingsschwestern von Marge Simpson aus der TV-Serie \\"Die Simpsons\\"?","answer":"Die Namen der Schwestern sind Patty und Selma."},{"question":"Симбиоз  деген эмне ?","answer":"Симбиоз - эки организмдин биригип,жабышып алып бири-бирине пайда келтирип жашашы."},{"question":"VaMongolia vakanga vasiri kurwisa rudzi rupi? Tichifunga nezvemubvunzo wapfuura, nyora mashoko akapoteredza mhinduro yacho. Inogona kuva mitsara 1 - 20. Mashoko akapoteredza:","answer":"Shi Tianze akanga ari muChinese wechiHan uyo akararama muumambo hwaJin. Kuroorana kwemarudzi pakati pevaHan nevaJurchen kwakava kwakajairika panguva ino. Baba vake vaiva Shi Bingzhi (史秉直, Shih Ping-chih). Shi Bingzhi akaroora mukadzi weJurchen (zita rekuti Na-ho) uye mukadzi wechiHan Chinese (zita rekuti Chang); hazvizivikanwe kuti ndiani wavo aive amai vaShi Tianze. Shi Tianze akaroorwa nevakadzi vaviri veJurchen, mukadzi wechiChinese wechiChinese, uye mukadzi wechiKorea, uye mwanakomana wake Shi Gang akaberekwa nemumwe wevakadzi vake veJurchen. Zita remadzimai ake echiJurchen raiva Mo-nien naNa-ho; zita remadzimai ake echiKorea raiva Li; uye zita remadzimai ake echiHan Chinese raiva Shi. Shi Tianze akapandukira mauto eMongolia pakupinda kwavo muumambo hwaJin. Mwanakomana wake Shi Gang akaroora mukadzi weKerait; vaKerait vakanga vari vanhu veMongol Turkic uye vaionekwa sechikamu che\\"rudzi rweMongol\\". Shi Tianze (Shih T'ien-tse), Zhang Rou (Chang Jou,), uye Yan Shi (Yen Shih) nevamwe vakuru vakuru vechiChinese vaishumira muumambo hweJin uye vakatiza vachienda kuvaMongol vakabatsira kuvaka chimiro chehutongi hwenyika itsva. Chagaan (Tsagaan) naZhang Rou pamwe chete vakatanga kurwisa umambo hweSong hwakarairwa naTöregene Khatun."},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 岡山県瀬戸内市で、刀の職人の川島一城さんが、神社の神様のために日本刀を作っています。今月、刀の刃に美しい模様をつける技術を神社でみんなに見せました。","answer":"川島さんは、火がついた炉の中に長さ80cmの刀を入れました。そして、赤くなった刀の色をよく見ながら、760°Cぐらいまで熱くしました。そのあと、刀を冷たい水に入れると、刀は反った形になって、刃には美しい模様がつきました。見ていた人たちは拍手をしていました。 川島さんは「見ている皆さんから力をもらうことができて、とてもうれしいです」と話しました。 刀は、これから研いだあと12月に神社に届ける予定です。"},{"question":"Quais são os principais pratos da culinária brasileira?","answer":"A culinária brasileira é rica e diversificada. Alguns pratos emblemáticos incluem a feijoada (um ensopado de feijão preto com carne de porco), a coxinha (um salgado recheado com frango), o acarajé (um bolinho frito de feijão), o churrasco (um método de grelhar carne) e o açaí (uma fruta típica da região amazônica)."},{"question":"س128 - كم دقيقة في الساعة ؟","answer":"ج128 - 60 دقيقة"},{"question":"कृपया निम्नलिखित वाक्य को पूरा करें: \\"तकनीकी उन्नति के...\\"","answer":"तकनीकी उन्नति के समय में, हमें सुनिश्चित करना होगा कि हम अपने पर्यावरण का ध्यान राख रहे हैं। सुरक्षित और सहायक संसाधनों का उपयोग करके हमें विकास की दिशा में कदम बढ़ाना होगा, परंतु प्राकृतिक संसाधनों का सही तरीके से प्रबंधन भी महत्वपूर्ण है।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਰਸਨਾ ਸਚਾ ਸਿਮਰੀਐ ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਮਾਤ ਪਿਤਾ ਸਾਕ ਅਗਲੇ ਤਿਸੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ ਜੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਚਸਾ ਨ ਵਿਸਰੈ ਸੋਇ ॥੧॥ਮਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਚਾ ਸੇਵਿ ਜਿਚਰੁ ਸਾਸੁ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਚੇ ਸਭ ਕੂੜੁ ਹੈ ਅੰਤੇ ਹੋਇ ਬਿਨਾਸੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਮੇਰਾ ਨਿਰਮਲਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਰਹਣੁ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਮੇਰੈ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਭੁਖ ਅਤਿ ਅਗਲੀ ਕੋਈ ਆਣਿ ਮਿਲਾਵੈ ਮਾਇ ॥ਚਾਰੇ ਕੁੰਡਾ ਭਾਲੀਆ ਸਹ ਬਿਨੁ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥੨॥ਤਿਸੁ ਆਗੈ ਅਰਦਾਸਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੋ ਮੇਲੇ ਕਰਤਾਰੁ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਨਾਮ ਕਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਜਿਸੁ ਭੰਡਾਰੁ ॥ਸਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਸਾਲਾਹੀਐ ਅੰਤੁ ਨ ਪਾਰਾਵਾਰੁ ॥੩॥ਪਰਵਦਗਾਰੁ ਸਾਲਾਹੀਐ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਚਲਤ ਅਨੇਕ ॥ਸਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਆਰਾਧੀਐ ਏਹਾ ਮਤਿ ਵਿਸੇਖ ॥ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਮਿਠਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਲਗੈ ਜਿਸੁ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਲੇਖ ॥੪॥੧੯॥੮੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 49 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਜੀਭ ਨਾਲ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਮਨ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਸਰੀਰ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਮਾਂ ਪਿਉ (ਆਦਿਕ) ਬਥੇਰੇ ਸਾਕ-ਅੰਗ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ (ਸਦਾ ਨਾਲ ਨਿਭਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੰਬੰਧੀ) ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ(ਸਿਮਰਨ ਭੀ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ), ਜੇ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ, ਤਾਂ ਉਹ (ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ) ਰਤਾ ਭਰ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਭੁੱਲਦਾ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਜਿਤਨਾ ਚਿਰ (ਤੇਰੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ) ਸਾਹ (ਆਉਂਦਾ) ਹੈ (ਉਤਨਾ ਚਿਰ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰਾ ਝੂਠਾ ਪਰਪੰਚ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਆਖ਼ਰ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ (ਮੇਰੀ) ਮਾਂ ! ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ-ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਥੋਂ ਰਿਹਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ(ਉਸ ਦੇ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਤਨ ਵਿਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਤਾਂਘ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਮਾਂ ! ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਤੜਪ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਕੋਈ (ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਲਿਆ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਾ ਦੇਵੇ ਮੈਂ ਚਾਰੇ ਕੂਟਾਂ ਭਾਲ ਵੇਖੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਖਸਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ (ਸੁੱਝਦਾ) ।੨।(ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ !) ਤੂੰ ਉਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਅਰਦਾਸ ਕਰ, ਜੇਹੜਾ ਕਰਤਾਰ (ਨੂੰ) ਮਿਲਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਮ (ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ) ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ (ਗੁਰੂ) ਦਾ (ਨਾਮ ਦਾ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਅਮੁੱਕ ਹੈ(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ) ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਅੰਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਦਾ ਉਰਲਾ ਤੇ ਪਾਰਲਾ ਪੰਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ) ਉਸ ਪਾਲਣਹਾਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਕੌਤਕ (ਦਿੱਸ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ) ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਚੰਗੀ ਅਕਲ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉੱਤੇ (ਚੰਗੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਦਾ) ਲੇਖ (ਉੱਘੜ ਪਏ), ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੯।੮੯।\\""},{"question":"नेपालीमा योमरी पुन्ही भनेको के हो ?","answer":"योमरी पुन्ही नेवारी समुदायको एक चाड हो । यस दिन काठमाडौं उपत्यकाका बासिन्दाले अन्नपूर्ण बाली र अन्नकी देवी अन्नपूर्णको पूजा गर्ने र राम्रो धान फसलको कामना गर्ने गर्दछन् ।"},{"question":"موارد کاربرد فعل مجهول در زبان فارسی چیست؟","answer":"1- وقتی که فاعل معلوم نباشد. مثال: ماشین آرش دزدیده شده است.2- وقتی که فاعل اهمیتی ندارد. مثال: خیابان کنده شده است.3- گوینده عمدا نخواهد نام فاعل را بیاورد. مثال: حسین کشته شد."},{"question":"كلمنى عن مكانة القطط عند المصريين القدام.","answer":"القطط كان ليها مكانه عاليه جدا عند المصريين القدام اللى قدسوها و حنطوها و سموها اله باستت اللى كانت بتحمى البيوت و الغيطان و اعتقدو انها بنت الاله رع. هيرودوت (ح. 484 ق.م – ح. 425 ق.م) اللى زار مصر من قرون طويله وصف فى كتابه \\" التواريخ \\" حب المصريين الكبير للقطط. مع تطور الدين المصرى القديم بقت آلهة للحرب."},{"question":"Kí ni a ń pe Ọba Ọ̀yọ́?","answer":"Aláàfin Ọ̀yọ́ ni."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Phải đến năm 2025, Avengers: The Kang Dynasty và Avengers: Secret Wars mới chính thức ra mắt, khép lại hành trình đa vũ trụ giàu cảm xúc của MCU. Tuy nhiên, tương tự như các bom tấn Avengers khác, Marvel Studios đã chuẩn bị cho 2 dự án này từ nhiều năm trước, với những chi tiết \\"nhá hàng\\" mà không phải ai cũng có thể nhận ra. Cả 2 bộ phim Avengers mới đều được đặt tên theo những bộ truyện tranh kinh điển của Marvel. Avengers: The Kang Dynasty chuyển thể từ tác phẩm của Kurt Busiek, ra mắt vào năm 2001 - 2002, xoay quanh cuộc chiến giữa Kang the Conqueror và Biệt đội Báo thù - những siêu anh hùng can trường nhất Trái Đất. Với vốn kiến thức đồ sộ về du hành thời gian, Kang đã dễ dàng đánh bại Avengers, buộc cả thế giới phải quy phục hắn. Tuy nhiên sau tất cả, các Avengers vẫn quyết tâm không bỏ cuộc và vùng lên để lật đổ hắn ta. Trong khi đó, Avengers: Secret Wars được chuyển thể từ bộ truyện của Jonathan Hickman, ra mắt vào năm 2015 ( và là phiên bản Secret Wars thứ 2 trong vũ trụ truyện tranh Marvel ). Trong bộ truyện này, mọi dòng thời gian của đa vũ trụ va chạm với nhau, mọi thực tại đứng trước nguy cơ bị hủy diệt, tương tự như hiện tượng xâm lấn đã được giới thiệu trong Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness. Ngoài ra, Secret Wars còn nhấn mạnh vào những xung đột cá nhân giữa Reed Richards/Mr. Fantastic và Doctor Doom. Đây có lẽ cũng là lý do vì sao Marvel Studios quyết định mở màn giai đoạn thứ 6 bằng bom tấn Fantastic Four. Dưới đây là những \\"viên gạch\\" mà Marvel đã lát sẵn cho con đường dẫn đến 2 bom tấn này. Ant-Man và thành phố bí ẩn trong thế giới lượng tử Trong Ant-Man & the Wasp, Scott Lang đã có cơ hội khám phá thế giới lượng tử (Quantum Realm), được Hank Pym mô tả là \\"nơi mọi khái niệm về thời gian và không gian đều trở nên vô nghĩa\\". Trong một khoảnh khắc thoáng qua, nếu tinh mắt, chúng ta có thể nhận ra hình ảnh một thành phố đổ nát nằm trong thế giới này. Đối chiếu với nguyên tác truyện tranh, chỉ có 1 thành phố hiện đại duy nhất có cùng số phận đó - chính là Chronopolis. Chronopolis được xem là thủ phủ của Kang the Conqueror, nằm tại thế giới có tên Limbo - nơi mà tất cả những nhà du hành thời gian đều phải đi qua. Chính điều này đã đặt ra giả thuyết về việc thế giới lượng tử là chìa khóa quan trọng trong việc du hành thời gian, cả trong phiên bản truyện tranh lẫn trên màn ảnh lớn. Bên cạnh đó, vì Janet Van Dyne đã mắc kẹt tại đây trong suốt 30 năm, có lẽ bà cũng có một chút kiến thức về Chronopolis để có thể trợ giúp cho Ant-Man và Wasp khi đối đầu với Kang sắp tới trong bom tấn điện ảnh Quantumania. Thế giới lượng tử mở khóa du hành thời gian trong Avengers: Endgame Avengers: Endgame là hồi kết dành cho Thanos, phản diện chính trong 3 giai đoạn đầu tiên của MCU. Tuy nhiên, bộ phim này còn đóng vai trò quan trọng trong việc đưa Kang the Conqueror, phản diện lớn của các giai đoạn tiếp theo, lên màn ảnh lớn, đồng thời xác nhận thế giới lượng tử có thể giúp con người du hành thời gian, giống như trong truyện tranh. Endgame đã đặt ra những quy luật du hành thời gian đầu tiên của MCU, và được phát triển thêm bởi những series trên Disney . Mặc dù bản thân những quy luật","answer":"đó vẫn có nhiều mâu thuẫn khiến cho các đạo diễn của Marvel cũng phải bất đồng quan điểm, thế nhưng Endgame vẫn mang đến một thông điệp quan trọng không sai vào đâu được: \\"Chúng ta náo loạn thời gian, thời gian sẽ khiến chúng ta phải hoảng loạn\\". Loki chính thức đưa Kang và đa vũ trụ đến với MCU Series Loki là tác phẩm đầu tiên trực tiếp khai thác ý tưởng về đa vũ trụ thông quan Time Variance Authority (TVA) - tổ chức được thành lập để đảm bảo dòng thời gian chính của MCU không bị phân nhánh. Theo đó, chỉ cần một cá nhân đưa ra quyết định trái với tự nhiên, ví dụ như đi làm muộn, cũng có thể tạo ra một dòng thời gian mới. Và khi con người tại các vũ trụ khác nhau nhận thức được về sự tồn tại của những thực tại khác, chiến tranh đa vũ trụ sẽ nổ ra và có thể hủy diệt tất cả. TVA làm việc cho He Who Remains, một biến thể của Kang the Conqueror, người đã đánh bại tất cả những phiên bản khác của chính mình trong cuộc chiến đa vũ trụ, hủy diệt những dòng thời gian khác và quyết giữ gìn sự bình yên cho dòng thời gian chính của MCU. Loki khép lại với cái chết của He Who Remains, đồng thời giải phóng cho đa vũ trụ, còn bản thân vị thần lừa lọc bị đẩy đến một dòng thời gian nơi Kang đã đánh chiếm thành công TVA. Rất nhiều người hâm mộ đã đặt ra thuyết về việc trụ sở của TVA lúc này chính là thành phố bí ẩn trong Ant-Man & the Wasp mà chúng ta đã phân tích ở trên. Dòng thời gian thây ma trong What If…? Quá trình xây dựng cho Avengers: The Kang Dynasty và Avengers: Secret Wars tiếp tục với series hoạt hình đầu tiên của Marvel Studios, What If…?, đưa khán giả đến rất nhiều dòng thời gian khác nhau. Trong đó, đáng chú ý nhất chính là thực tại \\"Marvel Zombie\\", nơi mà gần như cả thế giới đã biến thành xác sống sau khi nhiễm 1 loại virus bí ẩn từ thế giới lượng tử. Bộ truyện tranh \\"Marvel Zombies\\" có ảnh hưởng rất lớn đến sự kiện Secret Wars, và không phải ngẫu nhiên Marvel Studios lại muốn làm riêng 1 series phim mới dành cho dòng thời gian này. Theo dự kiến, Marvel Zombies sẽ lên sóng trên Disney vào năm 2024, 1 năm trước khi The Kang Dynasty và Secret Wars ra mắt. Biến thể của Kang trong Moon Knight Cho đến hiện tại, Moon Knight có thể xem là series khá độc lập và lạc lõng so với cốt truyện chung của MCU. Tuy nhiên, Marvel Studios đã khéo léo lồng vào rất nhiều easter egg tinh tế để khẳng định series này vẫn nằm trong vũ trụ điện ảnh của mình. Trong đó bao gồm cả việc Rama-Tut, Pharaoh Ai Cập, là một biến thể của Kang, cho thấy hắn đã hoạt động trên Trái Đất từ hàng nghìn năm trước. Ngoài ra, nếu để ý kỹ, chúng ta có thể thấy chiếc logo có liên quan đến Kang in trên áo của một tên tay sai của ác thần Ammit. Chính những chi tiết nhỏ như vậy có thể sẽ đóng vai trò quan trọng để đưa Moon Knight đến gần hơn với Multiverse Saga và MCU. Một số fan thậm chí còn đặt giả thuyết rằng Rama-Tut/Kang thực chất chính là Alexander Đại đế, người từng là thế thân của Ammit nhưng đã quyết định phản bội bà ta. Doctor Strange 2 và hiện tượng xâm lấn - tiền đề của cuộc chiến đa vũ trụ Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness đã theo chân Stephen Strange chu du qua một số thực tại, gây rối tại vũ trụ Earth-838, và cuối cùng là đẩy chính vũ trụ của anh (Earth-616) đến bên bờ vực diệt vong. Bộ phim này cũng cho thấy việc náo loạn đa vũ trụ có thể để lại hậu quả nặng nề ra sao. The Doctor Strange 2 cho biết, nếu một cá thể đến từ vũ trụ này gây rối tại 1 vũ trụ khác sẽ gây ra hiện tượng xâm lấn, và kết quả là khiến cho cả 2 thực tại đều bị phá hủy hoàn toàn. Điều đó lý giải một cuộc chiến tranh đa vũ trụ có sức hủy diệt khủng khiếp đến mức độ nào. Mỗi khi một biến thể của Kang tương tác với vũ trụ khác, nguy cơ xảy ra chiến tranh lại càng tăng cao, kéo theo đó là sự sụp đổ của nhiều dòng thời gian khác nhau. "},{"question":"「InternetExplorer」や「NetscapeNavigator」など、インターネットの情報を閲覧するためのソフトを総称して何というでしょう？","answer":"ブラウザです。"},{"question":"महाराष्ट्राच्या वायव्य भागात कोणत्या राज्याच्या किव्हा केंद्रशासीत प्रदेशाच्या सीमारेषा आहेत?","answer":"गुजरात राज्य व दादरा-नगर हवेली"},{"question":"సీలియేట్ల సంయుగ్మాన్ని నిర్వచించండి. రెండు ఉదాహరణలు రాయండి.","answer":"సంయుగ్మమనేది శైలికామయ ప్రోటోజోవన్ల జీవులు తాత్కాలికంగా జతకట్టి ప్రావాసి ప్రాకేంద్రకాల వినిమయము, పిదప స్థిర, ప్రావాసిక కేంద్రకాల కలయిక కోసం జరిగే ప్రక్రియ. ఉదా : పారమీషియం, వర్టిసెల్లా."},{"question":"ਮਹਾਕਾਲੀ ਝੀਲ ਬਾਰੇ ਦਸੋ। ","answer":"ਮਹਾਕਾਲੀ ਝੀਲ ਇੱਕ ਉਚਾਈ ਵਾਲੀ ਝੀਲ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਹਿਮਾਚਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼, ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੰਬਾ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਦੇ ਸਨੋ ਅਤੇ ਗੁਡਿਆਲ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਲਗਭਗ 4,080 metres (13,390 ft) ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤਲ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਪਰ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਝੀਲ ਨਵੰਬਰ ਤੋਂ ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ ਤੱਕ 6 ਮਹੀਨੇ ਜੰਮੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.අගුරු කකා වතුර බිබී කොළඹ දුවන යකඩ යකා ","answer":"දුම්රිය"},{"question":"Ami-ẹyẹ ko ti i tọ si mi bayii, mi o ti i gbija Yoruba debi aṣeyọri – Sunday Igboho","answer":"Nitori ipa takunakun to n ko lati gba gbogbo ilẹ Yorùbá silẹ lọwọ awọn apanijaye Fúlàní, apapọ ẹgbẹ awọn ọdọ Yorùbá, ìyẹn Yoruba Youth Socio-Cultural Association, YYSA, lọọ gbe àmì-ẹyẹ nla kan ka Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo aye mọ̀ si Sunday Igboho mọle nirọlẹ ọjọ Àbámẹ́ta, Sátidé, to kọja.Ṣugbọn sí iyalẹnu awọn adari ẹgbẹ naa, akínkanjú ọmọ Yorùbà yii kọ àmì-ẹyẹ naa, o ni oun ko ti i ṣàṣeyọrí nipa ominira gbogbo ọmọ Yorùbá tí oun n wá.ALAROYE gbọ pe eyi kọ nigba akọkọ ti Sunday Ìgbòho yoo kọ àmì-ẹyẹ sí àwọn tó fẹẹ fi imọriri wọn hàn nípa ijijagbara rẹ lọrun.Ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹyìn Igboho fìdí ẹ mulẹ fakọroyin wa pe “Eyi ki i ṣe igba akọkọ ọga, bẹẹ náà ni wọn kọ amì-ẹyẹ ‘Ogo Ọmọ Yorùbá’ tí àwọn ẹgbẹ kan naa fún wọn lọjọ kẹwàá, oṣù kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021 yii.”Nigba to n dupẹ fún ìmọ riri ẹgbẹ awọn ọdọ naa lori akitiyan rẹ̀, Sunday Igboho sọ pé “Mi o ti i nilo ami-ẹyẹ bayii. Asiko ti gbogbo wa ni iṣẹ lati ṣe ka tóo lè máa sun oorun àsùn-han-an-run la wa yii, kì í ṣe asiko lati máa kan saara sí mi pé mo ṣiṣẹ takuntakun.“Nigba ta a ba ṣàṣeyọrí lori iṣẹ ta a dawọ le yii, nigba naa, a le waa máa fúnra wa lami-ẹyẹ ba a bá ṣe fẹ.“Lọwọlọwọ yii, adua ni mo fẹ ki ẹyin ọdọ ati gbogbo ọmọ Yorùbá máa fi ran mi lọwọ ká lè ṣaṣeyọri lori ominira Yoruba ta a fẹ.Ààrẹ ẹgbẹ YYSA, Ọgbẹni Habib Ọlálékan Hammed, atawọn eeyan rẹ waa ṣèlérí atilẹyin gbogbo ọdọ Yorùbá fún Sunday Igboho, nigba yoowu to ba nilo wọn."},{"question":"ලොව පැරණිම ජාතික ගීය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලොව පැරණිතම ජාතික ගීය ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ ක්‍රි.ව. 794-1184 කාලයේ දී රචිත \\"කිමිගායෝ\\" නොහොත් ජපාන ජාතික ගීය යි. මෙහි වර්තමාන ස්වර රචනය ක්‍රි.ව. 1880 දී සම්පාදනය කරනු ලැබී ය."},{"question":"Gịnị bụ Osu?","answer":"Osu bu ndi nyefere onwe ha n'aka arusi( Alusi ) n'ala Igbo; a na-ewere ha dị ka ndị dị ala ma na-ekewakarị ha na Nwadiala ma ọ bụ diala ( Igbo : ezigbo amuru).Usoro nke Osu bụ omenala ochie n'ala Igbo nke na-akụda mmekọrịta mmadụ na ibe ya na alụmdi na nwunye nke a na-akpọ Osu ( English: outcast)"},{"question":"In which Ghanaian university did Kosi Kedem study?","answer":"Kosi Kede studied at Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology"},{"question":"Tóm tắt đoạn văn bản sau: Nhà bất đồng Trung Quốc Trần Quang Thành đã gửi thư cho Thủ tướng Ôn Gia BảoTrong đó, ông trực tiếp kêu gọi và yêu cầu Thủ tướng mở một cuộc điều tra bộ máy an ninh địa phương, mà ông nói đã hành hung, sách nhiễu và thực hiện nhiều hành vi ngược đãi khác với ông và gia đình của ông.Ông cũng yêu cầu Thủ tướng bảo đảm để mẹ, vợ và con gái của ông được an toàn, cũng như yêu cầu lãnh đạo chính phủ điều tra xem việc giám sát đối với ông đã được tài trợ ra sao và liệu có tham nhũng trong việc đó hay không.Nhà bất đồng chính kiến khiếm thị kết thúc cuốn băng video dài 15 phút của ông bằng thông điệp: \\"Nếu chúng ta điều tra kỹ lưỡng và nói sự thật với quần chúng, kết quả sẽ là rõ ràng, nhưng nếu ông tiếp tục nhắm mắt làm ngơ, người dân sẽ nghĩ gì?\\"Việc ông Trần Quang Thành lựa chọn nói trực tiếp với Thủ tướng Ôn Gia Bảo chứ không phải là với Chủ tịch Hồ Cẩm Đào hay các lãnh đạo khác, cho thấy rõ một mong muốn thách thức ông Ôn Gia Bảo thực hiện những lời kêu gọi được Thủ tướng lặp đi lặp lại nhiều lần về cải cách chính trị và nhổ tận gốc tệ tham nhũng chính quyền.Ông Ôn thường xuất hiện như một nhà lãnh đạo quan tâm tới dân, hay xuất hiện ở những vùng bị thiên tai và đổ nước mắt vì những đau khổ của người dân. Trong trường hợp này, tuy vậy có vẻ không chắc chắn rằng Thủ tướng hay bất cứ ai trong giới lãnh đạo Trung Quốc, sẽ đáp ứng yêu cầu của ông Trần.Đưa ra ánh sángÔng Trần đã yêu cầu đích thân Thủ tướng Ôn Gia Bảo phải mở điều tra công khaiTuy nhiên, vụ đào thoát táo bạo của ông Trần và cuốn băng video của ông đã một lần nữa đưa tình trạng và vụ việc của ông ra ánh sáng. Sẽ lại xuất hiện các câu hỏi vụng về với các quan chức Trung Quốc tại các cuộc họp báo, và các tổ chức nhân quyền có thể sẽ lại gây áp lực đối với chính phủ Trung Quốc để ngăn chặn ngược đãi tàn nhẫn đối với ông Trần Quang Thành và gia đình của ông.Ông Trần đã và đang đơn thương độc mã chiến đấu chống lại chế độ trong hơn một thập niên qua. Bị khiếm thị bẩm sinh, ông đã tự học về luật, và một trong các cuộc đấu tranh luật pháp ấn...","answer":"Nhà bất đồng trung quốc Trần Quang Thành gửi thư kêu gọi thủ tướng mở cuộc điều tra về hành vi ngược đãi."},{"question":"Kailan naging malaya ang Pilipinas?","answer":"Pormal na kinilala ng Estados Unidos ang kalayaan ng Pilipinas noong Hulyo 4, 1946. Gayunpaman, simula noong 1962 ayon sa deklerasyon ni Diosdado Macapagal, ipinagdiriwang ang Araw ng Kalayaan ng Pilipinas tuwing Hunyo 12. Ito ang petsa na ipinahayg ni Emilio Aguinaldo ang kalayaan ng Pilipinas mula sa Espanya noong 1898."},{"question":"महाराष्ट्रात संपूर्ण विद्युतीकरण झालेला प्रथम जिल्हा कोणता आहे?","answer":"वर्धा"},{"question":"ජනාධිපති ධූරය රටක රාජ්‍ය නායක ධූරය ලෙසත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා  රටේ රාජ්‍ය නායකයා  ලෙසත් ලොව මුල් වරට තෝරා ගත් රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙකු සහ රජයේ ප්‍රධානියා යන සංකල්පය ආරම්භ වූයේ එක්සත් ජනපදයෙනි. 1787 දී සම්මත කර 1789 දී බලාත්මක වූ එක්සත් ජනපද ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව ජනාධිපති ආණ්ඩු ක්‍රමය ස්ථාපිත කළේය. ජෝර්ජ් වොෂින්ටන් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ අතර, 1789 අප්‍රේල් 30 සිට 1797 මාර්තු 4 දක්වා සේවය කළේය. මේ අනුව, රාජ්‍ය නායකයා සහ රජයේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සිටි පළමු රට එක්සත් ජනපදයයි. ."},{"question":"لأي درجة كتوصل البرودة ديال كوكب بلوتو ؟","answer":"240 درجة مئوية تحت الصفر"},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Colômbia.","answer":"Bogotá."},{"question":"هل يمكنك اخباري كيف بدأت الكشافة؟","answer":"الحركة الكشفية أو \\"الكشافة\\" بدأت على يد روبرت بادن باول، الذي أسس الحركة في عام 1907 في جزيرة براونسي البريطانية. كانت فكرة الكشافة تستند إلى نظريات التربية والتدريب التي طوِّرها روبرت بادن باول، وكانت الحركة تهدف إلى تعزيز قيم المواطنة والمساهمة الإيجابية في المجتمع، بالإضافة إلى تعزيز المهارات الحياتية للشباب. انتشرت الكشافة على نطاق واسع حول العالم وأصبحت حركة دولية تشمل ملايين الأفراد."},{"question":"*ما هي جنسية المجاهد عمر المختار ؟","answer":"ليبي"},{"question":"Can you paraphrase the following text for me: Luultavasti he sopivat alkoholista...","answer":"Todennäköisesti he pääsivät sopimukseen alkoholista..."},{"question":"イタリア語で「１」という意味がある、スキップ、リバース、ワイルドなどの札がある人気カードゲームは何でしょう？","answer":"ウノ"},{"question":"Он гүлүнүн бири ачыла элек деген сөздү кандай түшүнсөк болот ?","answer":"Али жаш, эч нерсени көрө элек, аркы-беркини абдан түшүнө элек, турмуштук тажырыйбасы аз.Он гүлүнүн бири ачыла элек кыз."},{"question":"Quem foi o primeiro-ministro da Grã-Bretanha de 1841 a 1846?","answer":"O primeiro-ministro da Grã-Bretanha nesse período foi Robert Peel. Foi um político britânico, sendo primeiro-ministro do seu país durante dois períodos: de 10 de dezembro de 1834 a 8 de Abril de 1835, e de 30 de Agosto de 1841 a 29 de Junho de 1846.Ajudou a criar o conceito moderno da força policial do Reino Unido. Faleceu em Londres em 2 de julho de 1850, a consequência de um acidente de cavalo na estrada Constitution Hill."},{"question":"د شعور ماهیت څه شی دی، او ایا دا د عصبي ساینس او بیولوژي لخوا په بشپړ ډول تشریح کیدی شي؟","answer":"د شعور طبیعت په فلسفه کې یوه پیچلې او د بحث وړ موضوع ده. پداسې حال کې چې عصبي ساینس او بیولوژي د دماغ میکانیزمونو په پوهیدو کې د پام وړ پرمختګونه کړي دي، د شعور موضوعي تجربه، چې ډیری وختونه د \\"سختې ستونزې\\" په نوم یادیږي، پټ پاتې کیږي. یوازې د فزیکي پروسو له لارې د شعور تشریح کول پدې اړه پوښتنې راپورته کوي چې ایا موضوعي تجربې په بشپړ ډول عصبي فعالیتونو ته راټیټ کیدی شي یا که چیرې شعور ته د نه منلو وړ اړخ شتون ولري چې د مادي ساحې څخه بهر ځي."},{"question":"ما السور التي سميت باسم نجم ؟","answer":"\\tالشمس / النجم"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండివిలంబన న్యూట్రాన్లు అంటే ఏమిటి?","answer":"విలంబన న్యూట్రాన్లు :కేంద్రక విచ్ఛిత్తి జరిగిన కొద్దిసేపట్లో దాదాపు 1% న్యూట్రాన్లు వెలవడతాయి. వీటినే విలంబన న్యూట్రాన్లు అంటారు.కేంద్రక రియాక్టర్ పనిచేయడంలో విలంబన న్యూట్రాన్లు ముఖ్య పాత్ర వహిస్తాయి."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--फासा पडेल तो डाव राजा बोलेल तो न्याय","answer":"राजाने दिलेला न्याय मनाविरुद्ध असला किंवा चुकीचा असला तरी तो मानावा लागतो"},{"question":"வினா: இருமுறை முதலில் நோபல் பரிசு பெற்றவர் யார்?","answer":"விடை: மேரிக்கியூரி"},{"question":"မြန်မာတယောက် အလုပ်တွေရှုပ်နေတဲ့ကြားက လာအိုမှာ Thailand tourist visa ဝင်ဖြစ်တဲ့အတွေ့အကြုံလေး ရေးပြပါ","answer":"Visa ကုန် နေစရာမြေမရှိတော့ လာအိုအဝင်ပြရမယ်ပေါ့. ဖြစ်ချင်တော့ တိုက်တိုက်ဆိုင်ဆိုင် company ၂ခုက code test ၂ ခုရတယ်။ တခုက take home project, တခုက auto live coding ပေါ့ (လူစောင့်ကြည့်မနေတာ)Take home project deadline က visa ကုန်တဲ့ရက်ဖြစ်နေတယ်။ အရင်လကလည်း အဲ့လိုပဲ code test ၁ခု deadline က visa ကုန်တဲ့ရက်အဲ့မှာ အချိန်က မရှိပဲ စာရွက်စာတမ်းကိစ္စတွေနဲ့ ဗျာများရရော လူကသေချာမအိပ်ရဘူး။ ကြားထဲ မသွားခင် ဘဏ်က ပြဿနာတခုmobile banking ထဲ show money ပြရတယ်ဆိုတာကို mobile banking အရင်ဖုန်းနံပါတ်မရှိတော့ ဝင်လို့မရ၊ number သွားလဲတော့ တပတ်လောက်စောင့်ရမယ်ဆိုလို့ တပတ်ကြိုလုပ်တာကို နာမည်မတူဘူးဘာညာရစ်၊ အဲ့မှာ နက်ဖြန် လာအိုထွက်ရမယ့်ဟာကို ဒီနေ့ရုံးချုပ်ထပ်ပြေး၊ အဲ့မှာလည်း တပတ် ထပ်စောင့်ရမယ်ဖြစ်ရောနောက်ဆုံးမရတာနဲ့ ဘဏ်စာအုပ် update ပြီး statement ပဲ ဘဏ်ကတောင်းခဲ့တယ်နက်ဖြန်သွားမယ်ဆို ဒီနေ့ညနေ့ကျ အတူသွားမယ့်သူငယ်ချင်းက အိမ်ကရောက်နေတာနဲ့ မလိုက်နိုင်ဘူးဖြစ်ရောသူက အရင်ကလာအိုသွားဖူးတယ်ဆိုတော့ငယ်က ဘဏ်ကိစ္စနဲ့  code test နဲ့ အလုပ်များနေပြီး ဘယ်လိုသွားရမယ်ဆိုတာ စာတွေရှာမဖတ်ထားမိဘူးမလိုက်ဖြစ်တော့ဘူး ဆိုမှ ငယ်က ဘာမှမသိပဲ ဂယက်တွေထရောagent ပြေးအပ်တာကို သူကလည်း bkk-nong khai ကားလက်မှတ်ပဲ ဖြတ်ပေးပြီး တခြားဘာမှမပြောလိုက်ဘူး။ မေးတော့လည်း \\"ကားချိန်အမှီ bus terminal ရောက်ရင်ရပြီ\\" တခွန်းပဲ ပြောတယ်အဲ့တာနဲ့ အဲ့ bkk-nong khai ကားနဲ့ ည ၈ခွဲက ပါသွားတယ်။ ကားပေါ်မှာ \\"ဘယ်မှာဆင်းမှာလဲ\\" ဆိုပြီးလာမေးရော... တကယ်က အဲ့ကားစီးရင် တခါတည်း ရပ်တဲ့နေရာဆင်းရမှာ ထင်သွားတာ\\"ငါ လာအိုသွားမှာ nong khai border သွားချင်တာ\\" ပြောတာကို ယာဉ်မယ်နဲ့ ကိုယ်နဲ့ သူပြောတာကိုယ်နားမလည် ကိုယ်ပြောတာ သူနားမလည်းတွေဖြစ်. တယောက်တည်းမို့ သတိပိုပြီး အိပ်လို့ကမပျော်နောက်ဆုံး ဘေးက ထိုင်းမလေးကို translate တွေနဲ့ ပြောပြီး ပြောခိုင်းတော့မှ သူက \\"Nong Khai bus stop မှာ မဆင်းနဲ့၊ checkpoint မှာ ဆင်း\\"ဆိုပြီး ပြောလို့ nong khai checkpoint ကို မနက် ၆ နာရီလောက်ရောက်တယ်။ အဲ့မှာ ဆင်းပြီး agent ကို \\"nong khai ရောက်ပါပြီ\\" ဆိုတော့ agent က message ကို love react ပဲ ပေးသွားတယ်။ တကယ်က လာကြိုဖို့ ဘာညာ စီစဉ်ထားတယ် ထင်နေတာ ကိုယ်က... အဲ့ကျမှ \\"မဟုတ်ဘူးလေ၊ ခု ဘာဆက်လုပ်ရမှာလဲမေးတာ\\" ဆိုမှ \\"Thai immigration ဝင်၊ bus ticket တခုဝယ်၊ အဲ့ဟာနဲ့ မဲခေါင်မြစ်ကူးတဲ့ bus ကိုစီး၊ Laos ဘက်ရောက်၊ အဲ့မှာ Laos immigration ထပ်ဝင်\\" ဆိုပြီးပြောတယ်စပါပြီ... မြန်မာ passport ပြဿနာThai Immigration ဖွင့်တာနဲ့ တန်းစီကြရော၊ Foreigner တွေ ဒီဘက် ဒီဘက် ဆိုတော့ Foreigner တန်း queue သွားစီရော၊ အရှေ့မှာ အဖြူကောင်တွေ, နာရီဝက်လောက် queue မှာ စီပြီးမှ အဲ့ကောင်တွေ အလှည့်လည်းအဆင်ပြေသွားပြီး ကိုယ်တွေအလှည့်ရောက်တော့ \\"မြန်မာတွေက ဒီဘက်မဟုတ်ဘူး\\" တဲ့ \\"ဟိုးဘက် counter 1 ကိုသွား\\" တဲ့မြန်မာတွေဆိုတော့ queue ထဲက မြန်မာတွေအကုန် နားတွေ ရှည်ထွက်လာပြီး ကတုန်းကရုန်းတွေဖြစ်၊\\"counter 1 တဲ့ဟေ့\\" ဆိုပြီး counter1 ကို အတွဲလိုက်ကြီး ရွှေ့ကြရောcounter 1 officer ကို passport ပြ၊ မြန်မာတွေက ဒီဘက်မဟုတ်ဘူး ဟိုးးးးဘက်ဆုံးသွား တဲ့\\"ဟိုးးးဘက်ဆုံးတဲ့ဟေ့\\" ဆိုပြီး ကိုယ့်နောက်ကနေ တစီတန်းကြီး ထပ်ရွှေ့ကြမပြန်ရောဟိုးဘက်ဆုံး counter ရောက်တော့ အဲ့က officer က Myanmar တွေက ဒီမှာမဟုတ်ဖူး counter 1 ကိုသွား ဆိုပြီး ထပ်လွှတ်မဟုတ်ဘူး အဲ့က ဒီကို လွှတ်လိုက်တာ ဆိုပြီးပြောတော့ သူက passport တွေ ယူပြီး မြန်မာတွေငါ့နောက်လိုက်ခဲ့ ဆိုပြီး ထပ်ခေါ်သွားပြန်ရောအတွဲလိုက်ကြီးပါသွားပြန်ရောဟေ့.... ခေါ်သွားတဲ့counter ကြည့်လိုက်တော့ စာတန်းထိုးထားတာ Fine for Over Stay တဲ့လွဲပြီပေါ့ ငါတို့က over မ stay ဘူးပြောတော့၊ \\"မဟုတ်ဘူး မြန်မာတွေက ဒီနေရာဟုတ်တယ်\\" ဆိုပြီး အဲ့မှာ အတန်းလိုက်ကြီး စီပြီး အဆင်ပြေသွားရောforeigner ချင်းတူတူ အဖြူတွေကျ အပစားပေးပြီး မြန်မာတွေနှိမ်ခံရပြီ၃၀တန် လက်မှတ်ဝယ် bus စီးပြီး တံတားကူးပါတယ်။ အဲ့မှာ မြန်မာတွေနဲ့ အကုန်သိသွားပါပြီလာအိုဘက်ကမ်း ရောက်ပါတယ်ဟိုဘက်ကမ်းမှာ immigration မဝင်ခင် form ဖြည့်ရပါတယ်သူတို့က form မပေးပါဘူး။ သူတို့ ဖြည့်ပေးနေရင် ၂၀ ပေးရပါတယ်။လာသမျှလူ တယောက်ချင်းဖြည့်ပေးနေတာ ကြာလို့ form အတင်းတောင်းပြီး ကိုယ့်ဘာကိုယ် ဖြည့်လိုက်လို့ရပါတယ်Laos immigration ဝင်ပါတယ်။ အဲ့မှာ ဘတ် ၂၀ ပေးရပါတယ်အဲ့မှာ ထိုင်းဖုန်းတွေမမိတော့ပါဘူး. မနက် ၇ ခွဲ ၈လောက်ရှိသွားပါပြီပွဲစားက လွှတ်လိုက်တဲ့ကားလာကြိုပါတယ်။ သံရုံးဘေးနား ချသွားပြီး လစ်သွားပါတယ်။ကိုယ့်ဘာကိုယ် ကားငှားသွားလို့ရပါတယ်။ ကားခတော့ မတန်မရာတောင်းတတ်ကြပါတယ်။ အဲ့မှာ laos sim တခါတည်းဝယ်လို့ရပါတယ်. english လို နားမလည်ကြပါဘူးမနက် ၉ သံရုံးမဖွင့်ခင် ဘေးက ကော်ဖီဆိုင်မှာ မနက်စာစားမယ်ဆိုတော့ မီးကပျက်နေပါတယ်။ သံရုံးမျက်နှာချင်းဆိုင်မှာ money exchange လုပ်လို့ရပါတယ် B1000 ဆို 600,000 Kib လောက်ရပါတယ်အထုပ်တွေ အပိုးတွေနဲ့ ၉ နာရီ သံရုံးတန်းဝင်ပါတယ်. မြန်မာတွေ ထပ်ဆုံကြပါတယ်ရစ်ခံရတဲ့သူတွေက ကြည့်လိုက်ရင် လူမည်းတွေနဲ့ ကိုယ်တွေပါ, ကိုယ့်ရှေ့က အစ်ကိုတယောက်ရော နောက်က ညီမလေးတယောက်ရော reject ထိပါတယ်။ ပြဿနာကတော့ bank statement ကြည့်ပြီးရှာတာပါ. mobile banking ပြခိုင်းပါတယ်။ ငယ်ကတော့ ပြုံးပြလိုက်လို့ အဆင်ပြေသွားပါတယ် :3အဆင်မပြေရင်က ပိုက်ဆံရှိရင် ပြေအောင်လုပ်ဖို့ရပါတယ်။ အဲ့ဒါကြောင့် ပိုက်ဆံရှိရင်တော့ စိတ်ပူစရာ သိပ်မရှိပါဘူး။ ငယ်ကတော့ မရှိလို့ ပူပါတယ် နောက်နှစ်ရက်နေရင် လာထုတ်ဖို့ token ရရင် အဆင်ပြေပြီလို့မှတ်ပါနေ့လည် ၁၂ လောက်ရောက်သွားပြီး  အဲ့မှ ပွဲစားက sim card ထုတ်ပေးပါတယ်. စီစဉ်ပေးထားတဲ့ guest house ရောက်သွားပါတယ်. WiFi မရပါဘူး။ ရေပူရေအေးမရပါဘူး. တခြားဘာမှလည်းမပေးထားပါဘူးတကယ်က laos မှာ စျေးကသိပ်မကြီးတာမို့ သွားရင် ကောင်းတဲ့ hotel ကွကိုယ် လုပ်ပြီးတည်းတာ ပိုကောင်းပါတယ်၂ ရက်လောက် အချိန်ကုန်ပြီးပြီမို့ သူများတွေ ၂ရက်လည်တဲ့အချိန် ငယ်ကတော့ အခန်းထဲကအခန်းပြင်မထွက်ရပဲ code ရေးရပါတယ်မိုးကအေးအေးနဲ့ ခရီးပန်း stressပိ အိပ်ရေးမဝပဲ code test submit လုပ်လိုက်နိုင်ပါတယ်. ပြီးလည်းပြီးရော visa သွားထုတ်မယ့်ရက်ရောက်လို့ ထုတ်ပြီး ပြန်ပါတယ်. အပြန်ကတော့ လာခဲ့သလိုပါပဲ တခြားမြန်မာတွေနဲ့သိသွားပြီ မို့ အဖွဲ့လိုက်ပြီး beer  ဆေးလိပ်တွေဝယ်ပြီး အဆင်ပြေပြေပြန်လာကြပါတယ်။ ငယ်ကတော့ မဝယ်ပါဘူး hehe ဒါပေမယ့် လက်ဆောင်ရလို့ beer တကဒ် အိမ်ပါလာပါတယ်ထိုင်းကိုပြန်အဝင် immigration မှာလည်း နည်းနည်းပါးပါး ရစ်ခံရတဲ့သူတွေ ရစ်ခံရပါတယ်။ ဘယ်သွားမှာလဲ ဆိုတာနဲ့ အိမ်လိပ်စာ ဘာညာ ရစ်တာပါ။ငယ်ကတော့ ပြုံးနေလို့ ဘာမှ အမေးမခံရပါဘူး XP ( စတာပါ )ဟိုမှာလုံးဝအပြင်မထွက်တော့ အသုံးစရိတ်က အကုန်ပေါင်း B 800 လောက်ပဲ ကုန်ပါတယ်. တကယ်တမ်း ပွဲစားလုပ်ပေးတာက lao immigration ကနေ သံရုံး (အသွား)၊ သံရုံး ကနေ lao immigration ( အပြန်) ကားစီစဉ်ပေးတယ်၊ guest house ငှားပေးတယ်၊ အပြန် လေယာဉ် ticket (အပြ) စီစဉ်ပေးတယ်ထိုင်းအိမ် - mo chit bus terminal အသွားအပြန်၊ သံရုံး - guest house အသွားအပြန်၊ တံတားကူး၊ nong khai checkpoint ကနေ nong khai bus stop, စားတာသောက်တာကတော့ ကိုယ့်ပိုက်ဆံနဲ့ ကိုယ်ပါပဲစုစုပေါင်း ငယ်က ဘတ် ၇၅၀၀ - ၈၀၀၀ လောက် ကုန်ပါတယ်။ သုံးရင် ၉၀၀၀ - ၁၀၀၀၀ လောက်ထိ ကုန်မယ်ထင်ပါတယ်"},{"question":"ဂဏာန်းမဆလာချက်ရှူးရှဲလေး ချက်စားချင်တာ၊ ဘယ်လိုချက်ရမလဲ။ ပါဝင်ပစ္စည်းတွေနဲ့ အသေးစိတ်ပြောပြပေးပါ။","answer":"ဂဏာန်းမဆလာချက်ရှူးရှဲချက်ရန် ပါဝင်ပစ္စည်းလေးတွေနဲ့တကွ ချက်နည်းကတော့ငြုပ်(ငရုတ်)သီးစိမ်းကို ၂ ခြမ်းခွဲပါခရမ်းချဉ်သီးကို နှုပ်နှုပ်စင်း သို့ ကြိတ်ထားပါကြက်သွန်နီဖြူ၊ ချင်း(ဂျင်း)၊ ငြုပ်(ငရုတ်)သီးခြောက်တို့ကို ရောထောင်းပါပင်စိမ်း/ရှမ်းနံနံ/နံနံပင် နှစ်သက်ရာထည့်ပါအိုးကိုပူအောင် အရင်လုပ်၊ ဆီထည့်၊ ဆီပူမှ ကိုင်ထားတဲ့ဂဏာန်းထည့်ကြော်၊ လိမ္မော်ရောင်လေးသန်းလာရင် ဆယ်ယူပြီး ဆီစစ်ထားပါအဲ့ဂဏာန်းကြော်ထားတဲ့ဆီထဲကို ထောင်းထားတဲ့ကြက်သွန်အနှစ်တွေထည့်၊ ဆီသပ်၊ ကြက်သွန်နည်းနည်းကြွပ်လာရင် နှုပ်နှုပ်စင်းထားတဲ့ ခရမ်းချဉ်သီးထည့်ပြီး ၂ မိနစ်ခန့် အဖုံးအုပ် တည်ပါ။ ပြီးရင် ရေနည်းနည်းထည့်ကာ မီးအပူရှိန်လျော့ပြီး အနှစ်ကျအောင် ဖြည်းဖြည်းချင်းစီ မွှေပြီးချက်ပေးပါ။ပြီးရင် ငရုတ်သီးစိမ်းထည့်မွှေပါ။ဂဏာန်းထည့်ပါ။ ရေ၊ ဆား၊ သကြား/ကြက်သားမှုန့်ထည့်ပြီး ၄ မိနစ်ခန့် ချက်ပါ။ရေကို ဂဏာန်းမြုပ်ရုံလေးသာထည့်ပါ။အရည်သောက်မဟုတ်လို့ အများကြီးထည့်စရာမလိုပါ။ဘဲဥတလုံးဖောက်ထည့်ပါ။ ဘဲဥအနှစ်ပေါက်သွားအောင် ထည့်ပြီးပြီးချင်း မြန်မြန်မွှေပါ။ အဲ့ဒါမှ အနှစ်ဖြစ်ပြီး ထမင်းနဲ့နယ်စားလို့ရမှာပါ။ကုလားလေးမဆလာအုပ်ပါ။ပင်စိမ်း/ရှမ်းနံနံ/နံနံပင် နှစ်သက်ရာအုပ်ပါ။"},{"question":"ආමාශය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ආමාශය යනු ආමාශයික පත්රිකාවේ සහ ආහාර ජීර්ණ පද්ධතියේ ප්රධාන අවයවයකි. එය J-හැඩැති ඉන්ද්‍රියයක් වන අතර එහි ඉහළ කෙළවරේ ඇති esophagus සහ එහි පහළ කෙළවරේ duodenum වෙත සම්බන්ධ වේ. ආමාශයේ නිපදවන ආමාශයික අම්ලය (අවිධිමත් ලෙස ආමාශයික යුෂ), ආහාර දිරවීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේදී වැදගත් කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරන අතර ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් හයිඩ්‍රොක්ලෝරික් අම්ලය සහ සෝඩියම් ක්ලෝරයිඩ් අඩංගු වේ. ආමාශයික ග්‍රන්ථිවල G සෛල මගින් නිපදවන පෙප්ටයිඩ හෝමෝනයක් වන ගැස්ට්‍රින්, ආහාර ජීර්ණ එන්සයිම සක්‍රීය කරන ආමාශයික යුෂ නිෂ්පාදනය උත්තේජනය කරයි. පෙප්සිනොජන් යනු ආමාශයික ප්‍රධාන සෛල මගින් නිපදවන පූර්වගාමී එන්සයිමයක් (සයිමොජන්) වන අතර ආමාශයික අම්ලය මෙය පෙප්සින් එන්සයිමය වෙත ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන අතර එය ප්‍රෝටීන දිරවීම ආරම්භ කරයි. මෙම රසායනික ද්‍රව්‍ය දෙක ආමාශයේ බිත්තියට හානි කරන බැවින්, ආමාශයේ ඇති අසංඛ්‍යාත ආමාශ ග්‍රන්ථි මගින් ශ්ලේෂ්මල ස්‍රාවය කරන අතර, ආමාශයේ අභ්‍යන්තර ස්ථරවලට රසායනික ද්‍රව්‍යවල හානිකර බලපෑම් වලට එරෙහිව සෙම සහිත ආරක්ෂිත තට්ටුවක් සපයයි.ප්‍රෝටීන් ජීර්ණය වන අතරම, ආමාශයේ බිත්තිය දිගේ චලනය වන පෙරිස්ටල්සිස්, මාංශ පේශි හැකිලීමේ තරංග මගින් යාන්ත්‍රික කැසීම සිදු වේ. මෙය ආහාර ස්කන්ධය ආහාර ජීර්ණ එන්සයිම සමඟ තවදුරටත් මිශ්‍ර කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසයි. ආමාශයේ ආමාශයික ශ්ලේෂ්මලයේ ඇති ෆන්ඩික් ග්‍රන්ථිවල ප්‍රධාන සෛල මගින් ස්‍රාවය කරන ආමාශයික lipase, ක්ෂාරීය අග්න්‍යාශයික lipase වලට වඩා වෙනස්ව ආම්ලික lipase වේ. මෙය අග්න්‍යාශයේ lipase තරම් කාර්යක්ෂම නොවන නමුත් මේදය යම් ප්‍රමාණයකට බිඳ දමයි.පයිලෝරික් ඇල හරහා duodenum වෙත සම්බන්ධ වන ආමාශයේ පහළම කොටස වන pylorus හි ගැස්ට්‍රින් ඇතුළු ආහාර ජීර්ණ එන්සයිම ස්‍රාවය කරන ගණන් කළ නොහැකි ග්‍රන්ථි අඩංගු වේ. පැයක් හෝ දෙකකට පසු, චයිම් නම් ඝන අර්ධ ද්රවයක් නිපදවයි. pyloric sphincter හෝ කපාටය විවෘත වූ විට, chyme duodenum තුළට ඇතුළු වන අතර එහිදී එය අග්න්‍යාශයේ ඇති ආහාර ජීර්ණ එන්සයිම සමඟ තවදුරටත් මිශ්‍ර වී කුඩා අන්ත්‍රය හරහා ගමන් කරයි, එහිදී ආහාර දිරවීම දිගටම සිදු වේ.ආමාශයේ පාදයේ ඇති ප්‍රාචීර සෛල, විටමින් බී 12 අවශෝෂණය කර ගැනීම සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන අභ්‍යන්තර සාධකය නම් ග්ලයිකොප්‍රෝටීන් නිපදවයි. විටමින් B12 (cobalamin), ඛේඨ ග්‍රන්ථි මගින් ස්‍රාවය කරන ග්ලයිකොප්‍රෝටීනයකට බන්ධනය වන අතර ආමාශය හරහා ගෙන යනු ලැබේ - ට්‍රාන්ස්කොබලමින් I ද හැප්ටොකොරින් ලෙස හැඳින්වේ, එය අම්ල සංවේදී විටමින් ආම්ලික ආමාශයේ අන්තර්ගතයෙන් ආරක්ෂා කරයි. වඩාත් උදාසීන duodenum තුළ වරක් අග්න්‍යාශයික එන්සයිම ආරක්ෂිත glycoprotein බිඳ දමයි. නිදහස් කරන ලද විටමින් බී 12 ඉන්ද්‍රිය සාධකයට බන්ධනය වන අතර එය ඉලියම් තුළ ඇති එන්ට්‍රොසයිට් මගින් අවශෝෂණය වේ.ආමාශය ආඝ්‍රාණය කළ හැකි ඉන්ද්‍රියයක් වන අතර සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ආහාර ලීටරයක් ​​පමණ රඳවා තබා ගැනීමට ප්‍රසාරණය විය හැක. මෙම ප්‍රසාරණය ආමාශයේ අභ්‍යන්තර බිත්තිවල ඇති ආමාශයික නැමීම් මාලාවකින් සක්‍රීය වේ. අලුත උපන් බිළිඳකුගේ ආමාශය මිලි ලීටර් 30 ක් පමණ රඳවා තබා ගැනීම සඳහා පමණක් පුළුල් කිරීමට හැකි වනු ඇත."},{"question":"اذا وصف شخ بإنه رمة ، مامعناته؟","answer":"رمه معناها رائحته سيئة."},{"question":"\\"जैव ईन्धन\\" को अवधारणा र यातायात क्षेत्रमा हरितगृह ग्यास उत्सर्जन कम गर्न यसको सम्भाव्यता बारे छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"जैविक इन्धनहरू नवीकरणीय जैविक स्रोतहरू, जस्तै बिरुवा वा शैवालहरूबाट व्युत्पन्न इन्धन हुन्। तिनीहरूसँग जीवाश्म इन्धनको विकल्प प्रदान गरेर यातायात क्षेत्रमा हरितगृह ग्यास उत्सर्जन कम गर्ने क्षमता छ।"},{"question":"Given the following statement, predict the tags for each word: How do people look at and experience art?","answer":"Here are the predicted parts of speech tags for each word in the sentence \\"How do people look at and experience art?\\":How: ADVdo: AUXpeople: NOUNlook: VERBat: ADPand: CCONJexperience: VERBart: NOUN?: PUNCT"},{"question":"ਕੁਹਾੜੇ ਦਾ ਦਲੀਆ : ਰੂਸੀ ਪਰੀ-ਕਹਾਣੀ","answer":"ਇਕ ਵਾਰ ਦੀ ਗਲ ਏ, ਇਕ ਬੁੱਢਾ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਛੁੱਟੀ ਮਨਾਣ ਲਈ ਘਰ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, ਤੇ ਥਕਿਆ ਉਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਭੁਖ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਡਾਢੀ ਲਗੀ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਇਕ ਪਿੰਡ ਅਪੜਿਆ ਤੇ ਉਹਨੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਹੀ ਝੁੱਗੀ ਦਾ ਬੂਹਾ ਜਾ ਖੜਕਾਇਆ।\\"ਰਾਹੀ ਨੇ ਰਾਤ ਕਟਣੀ ਏ,\\" ਉਹਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ।ਬੂਹਾ ਇਕ ਬੁੱਢੀ ਤੀਵੀਂ ਨੇ ਖੋਲਿਆ।\\"ਅੰਦਰ ਲੰਘ ਆ, ਫ਼ੌਜੀਆ, ਉਹਨੇ ਸੱਦਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।\\"ਮਾਲਕਨੇਂ, ਭੁੱਖੇ ਲਈ ਗਰਾਹੀ ਰੋਟੀ ਹੈ ਈ?\\" ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਪੁਛਿਆ। \uFEFFਏਧਰ ਬੁੱਢੀ ਕੋਲ ਹੈ ਸਾਰਾ ਕੁਝ ਚੰਗਾ-ਚੋਖਾ ਸੀ, ਪਰ ਉਹ ਸੀ ਕੰਜੂਸ ਤੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਗਰੀਬੜੀ ਬਣ-ਬਣ ਬਹਿੰਦੀ ਸੀ।\\"ਭਲਿਆ ਲੋਕਾ, ਅਜ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਆਪ ਵੀ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਖਾਧਾ, ਵਿਚਾਰੀ ਮੈਂ, ਘਰ 'ਚ ਹੈ ਈ ਕੁਝ ਕੁਰਲਾਣ ਲਗੀ ।\\"ਠੀਕ ਏ, ਜੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ, ਤਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ,\\" ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ। ਫੇਰ ਬੈਂਚ ਥੱਲੇ ਪਿਆ ਹੱਥੀਉਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਇਕ ਕੁਹਾੜਾ ਵੇਖ ਉਹ ਕਹਿਣ ਲਗਾ: \\"ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈਗੀ, ਤਾਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਓਸ ਕੁਹਾੜੇ ਦਾ ਦਲੀਆ ਬਣਾ ਲੈਣੇ ਆਂ।\\"ਬੁੱਢੀ ਨੇ ਹੈਰਾਨੀ ਨਾਲ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਹਥ ਉਲਾਰ ਲਏ।\\"ਕੁਹਾੜੇ ਦਾ ਦਲੀਆ? ਕਦੀ ਸੁਣਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿਸੇ!\\"ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਵਿਖਾਨਾਂ। ਬਸ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਤਾਂਬੀਆ ਦੇ ਦੇ।ਬੁੱਢੀ ਤਾਂਬੀਆ ਲੈ ਆਈ, ਤੇ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਕੁਹਾੜੇ ਨੂੰ ਧੋਤਾ, ਉਹਨੂੰ ਤਾਂਬੀਏ ਵਿਚ ਰਖਿਆ, ਤੇ ਤਾਂਬੀਏ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ ਭਰ ਕੇ ਚੁਲ੍ਹੇ ਉਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਾ ਦਿਤਾ।ਬੁੱਢੀ ਨੇ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਉਤੇ ਟਕ ਲਾਈ ਰਖੀ, ਆਪਣੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਉਹਦੇ ਉਤੋਂ ਏਧਰ-ਓਧਰ ਨਾ ਹੋਣ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਕੜਛੀ ਕੱਢੀ ਤੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਹਿਲਾਇਆ ਤੇ ਫੇਰ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਚਖਿਆ।\\"ਤਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਚਲਿਐ ਬਸ,\\" ਉਹਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ। \\"ਜੇ ਰਤਾ ਕੁ ਲੂਣ ਲਭ ਪਏ ਨਾ।\\"ਹਾਂ, ਲੂਣ ਮੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਹੈਗਾ। ਐਹ ਵੇ ਖਾਂ, ਪਾ ਲੈ।\\"ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ ਕੁਝ ਲੂਣ ਪਇਆ ਤੇ ਇਕ ਵਾਰੀ ਫੇਰ ਚਖਿਆ।\\"ਜੇ ਕਦੀ ਮੁਠ ਕੇ ਦਾਣੇ ਪਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਨਾ,\\" ਉਹਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ।ਬੁੱਢੀ ਰਸਦ ਵਾਲੀ ਥਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਦਾਣਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਇਕ ਗੁੱਥੀ ਚੁਕ ਲਿਆਈ।\\"ਐਹ ਲੈ, ਜਿੰਨੀ ਮਰਜ਼ੀ ਆ ਪਾ ਲੈ,\\" ਬੁੱਢੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ।ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਚਾੜ੍ਹਨ ਤੇ ਚਾੜ੍ਹੇ ਨੂੰ ਹਿਲਾਣ ਤੇ ਕਦੀ-ਕਦੀ ਚੱਖਣ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਜਾਰੀ ਰਖਿਆ। ਤੇ ਬੁੱੱਢੀ ਵੇਖਦੀ ਰਹੀ ਤੇ ਉਹਦੇ ਕੋਲੋਂ ਧਿਆਨ ਹੋਰ ਪਾਸੇ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ।\\"ਵਾਹ, ਕਿੰਨਾ ਸੁਆਦਲਾ ਦਲੀਆ ਬਣਿਐ,\\" ਦਲੀਏ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਾਂ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ, ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ। \\"ਜੇ ਰਤਾ ਜਿਹਾ ਮੱਖਣ ਪੈ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਏਸ ਤੋਂ ਸੁਆਦੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਕਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਬਣੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣੀ।ਬੁੱਢੀ ਨੇ ਕੁਝ ਮੱਖਣ ਵੀ ਲਭ ਲਿਆਂਦਾ, ਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਲੀਏ ਵਿਚ ਪਾ ਦਿਤਾ।\\"ਤੇ ਹੁਣ, ਮਾਲਕਨੇਂ, ਚਮਚਾ ਲੈ ਆ, ਤੇ ਆ ਜਾ ਖਾਈਏ!\\" ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ।ਉਹ ਦਲੀਆ ਖਾਂਦੇ ਜਾਣ ਤੇ ਉਹਦੀਆਂ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਾਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਜਾਣ।\\"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ, ਕੁਹਾੜੇ ਦਾ ਦਲੀਆ ਵੀ ਏਨਾ ਸੁਆਦੀ ਬਣਦੈ।\\" ਬੁੱਢੀ ਨੇ ਦੰਗ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਆਖਿਆ।ਤੇ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਤੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹੀ ਅੰਦਰ ਹਸਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ।"},{"question":"ባሕር ዳር ስንት የገጠር ቀበሌዎች አሏት?","answer":"ባሕር ዳር 4 የገጠር ቀበሌዎች አሏት"},{"question":"日本の交通標識で駐車場をあらわすアルファベット１文字は？","answer":"Ｐです。"},{"question":"Бүгүн жолдошумдун туулган күнү ага карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Эң романтикалуу жолдошум жана балдарыма эң камкор ата туулган күнүңүз менен. Аллах сизди колдосун!"},{"question":"Tirela ja wọle n’Ijẹbu-Ode, o pa iya atọmọ pẹlu ọlọkada","answer":"Omijẹ n bọ loju awọn eeyan, kaluku n ṣedaro ikunlẹ abiyamọ ni lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ keji, oṣu kẹjọ yii, nigba ti tirela kan to ko okuta padanu ijanu ẹ, to ja wọle n’Ijẹbu-Ode, to si pa obinrin kan atọmọ rẹ to gbe dani, bẹẹ lo ran ọkunrin ọlọkada kan naa lọ sọrun ọsan gangan.Ohun ti awọn tiṣẹlẹ yii ṣoju wọn sọ ni pe ere buruku ni tirela to ko okuta naa n sa, wọn lo n bọ lati Agọ-Iwoye, o n lọ s’Ijẹbu-Ode. Itosi Lagos Garage, lo de  ti tirela ti ko ni nọmba naa fi padanu ijanu ẹ, to si ṣe bẹẹ wọ ile to wa lọọọkan rẹ lọ.Obinrin alabiamọ kan to gbe ọmọ to n tọ lọwọ dani lo kọkọ kọ lu, o run wọn mọbẹ, awọn mejeeji si ku loju-ẹsẹ. Ọlọkada kan naa ti wọn ni o n bọ jẹẹjẹ rẹ lati ọna Ayegbami naa ko agbako ọkọ yii, o si run un pa.Ohun to dun ọpọ eeyan ni pe niṣe ni dẹrẹba to wa tirela naa sa lọ pẹlu ọmọ ẹyin ọkọ rẹ, ẹnikan ko ri wọn mu lẹyin aburu ti wọn ṣe.Lasiko ti a n kọ iroyin yii lọwọ, bi awọn ajọ TRACE yoo ṣe gbe tirela naa kuro ninu ile to wo si ni wọn n ṣe lọwọ, bẹẹ ni wọn n gbiyanju lati mọ boya ko tun seeyan mi-in ti kinni ọhun kan, ko ma lọọ jẹ pe oku ṣi wa labẹ ile to wọ lọ naa.Lẹẹkan si i, TRACE tun kilọ fawọn awakọ, awọn onitirela ti ijanu wọn ki i yee sọnu yii, pe ki wọn yee fi tiwọn ko ba alaiṣẹ, ki wọn ni iwa ọmọluabi loju popo, nitori ẹmi ti wọn fi n ṣofo yii ṣẹ n pọ ju, wọn ni ki gbogbo onimọto pata maa ṣọra ṣe ."},{"question":"Olanrewaju, ifasẹyin nla ni iku rẹ mu ba iṣẹ mi-Salawa Abẹni","answer":"Ni nnkan bii ogun ọdun sẹyin ni ajalu nla kan de ba gbajumọ aṣaaju awọn olorin waka nilẹ yii, Alhaja Salawa Abẹni. Akọbi ẹ lọkunrin, Idris Ọlanrewaju Adefọlajuwọn Akanji Adepọju, lo ku lojiji. Ọsẹ to kọja, iyẹn ọjọ keji, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun 2000 yii, gan-an lo pe ogun ọdun geere ti  ọmọ oṣere naa ku.Ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogun ni lọdun naa lọhun-un, ṣugbọn bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọpọ awọn eeyan le ti gbagbe pe iṣẹlẹ naa waye, sibẹ, Salawa Abẹni ko gbagbe, oun gan-an naa lo gba ori instagiraamu rẹ lọ, to si kọ ọ sibẹ bi iṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣe waye, ati iru idaamu to ba a nigba ti iku pa Akanni, ọmọkunrin to bi fun Adepọju loju de lọdun naa lọhun-un.Bi Salawa Abẹni ṣe kọ ọrọ ọhun ree: ‘‘Hmmm!! Loni-in ọjọ keji, oṣu kẹwaa yii, gan-an lo pe ogun ọdun ti o ti fi mi silẹ lọ. Akọbi mi lọkunrin, Idris Olanrewaju Adefọlajuwọn Akanji Adepọju. Bii ana lo ṣe ri o, ṣugbọn iṣẹlẹ ọhun ti pe ogun ọdun geere loni-in. Idaamu nla ni iku ojiji to pa ọ yii ko ba mi. Lanre, bẹẹ ni iku rẹ fẹẹ sọ aye mi di bami-in paapaa, koda, o ko ifasẹyin ba iṣẹ orin ti mo gbe lọwọ debii pe ṣe lawọn eeyan n beere pe ṣe mi o kọrin mọ ni?“Ju gbogbo ẹ lọ, ki a ṣaa maa dupẹ lọwọ Ọlọrun to fun mi lokun ati agbara lati ṣi wa laye loni-in.“Mo dupẹ lọwọ gbogbo awọn ti wọn duro ti mi pata latigba yẹn titi di asiko yii. Mo waa n fi asiko yii gba a laduura fun gbogbo abiyamọ aye pe ẹ o ni i ri iku ọmọ lagbara Ọlọrun. Ẹyin ti iru ẹ si ti ṣẹlẹ si, idunnu to n bori ibanujẹ ni Ọlọrun aa ṣe fun gbogbo wa, amin.“Ọdun yii gan-an ni iwọ naa o ba pe ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlogoji, ọkan mi ṣafẹẹri rẹ, bẹẹ lawọn aburo rẹ paapaa naa n ṣafẹẹri rẹ gidigidi. Gbogbo wa pata la fẹ ọ, ṣugbọn Ọlọrun Allah lo fẹ ọ ju, titi ta oo tun fi pade, ṣe ni ki o maa sinmi laya Oluwa rẹ, emi iya rẹ ni o, Alhaja Salawa Abẹni.”Bo ti ṣe kọ ọrọ ọhun ree, bẹẹ lawọn ẹbi, ara, ojulumọ n fi ọrọ tutu ranṣe si i, ti wọn si n ba a kẹdun gidigidi pẹlu adura pe Ọlọrun yoo tubọ rọ ọ loju, awọn yooku to wa lọwọ rẹ yoo si ba a kalẹ."},{"question":"小白买了一盒蛟香,平均一卷蛟香可点燃半个小时.若他想以此测量45分钟时间,他该如何计算","answer":"答案：先将一卷蚊香的两端点燃,同时将另一卷蚊香的一端点燃"},{"question":"أذكر اسم السورة المدنية الاطول في عدد آياتها؟","answer":"السورة المدنية الأطول في عدد آياتها هي سورة البقرة، وهي السورة الثانية في ترتيب سور القرآن الكريم، وتحتوي على 286 آية"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الدمعزة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: قول: ” أدام الله عزك”"},{"question":"\\"Ny fampandrenesana tsy tapaka sy ny fampahalalana be loatra amin'ny vanim-potoana nomerika dia manampy amin'ny adin-tsaina sy ny tebiteby isan'andro.\\" inona ny fihetseham-po tamin'ny fanambarana teo aloha?","answer":"Ny andian-teny dia mampiseho fihetseham-po ratsy, manondro ny adin-tsaina sy ny tebiteby vokatry ny fidiran'ny fampahalalana nomerika be loatra."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Marilyn Monroe. ","answer":"Ban-aisteoir agus mainicín Meiriceánach ab ea Marilyn Monroe agus réalta ghnéasach den chéad scoth go háirithe. Rinneadh samhailchomhartha na ré nua di, na seascaidí na saoirse.I mionpháirteanna scannáin a thosaigh sí ag aisteoireacht, ach d'iompaigh sí ina duine de na haisteoirí is cáiliúla sna caogaidí de bharr a cuid scileanna coiméideacha agus a háilleachta.Phós sí faoi thrí - James Dougherty ar an 19 Meitheamh 1942, Joe DiMaggio ar an 14 Eanáir 1954 agus Arthur Miller ar 29 Meitheamh 1956. Rugadh Marilyn Monroe i mbarda carthanais Ospidéal Contae Los Angeles. Is é an t-ainm a breacadh síos ar a teastas breithe ná Norma Jeane Mortenson. Ach ba í an seanmóirí carasmatach mná ó Cheanada, Aimee Semple MacPherson, a bhaist an t-ainm Norma Jeane Baker uirthi, mar a d'iarr seanmháthair an linbh Della Monroe Grainger (de réir a beathaisnéisí Fred Lawrence)).Ar an 23 Feabhra 1956, fuair Norma Jeane cead oifigiúil ó Chúirt Cathrach Stát Nua-Eabhrac agus d'athraigh sí a hainm is a sloinne go dlíthiúil go Marilyn Monroe."},{"question":"Question: Milk always contains ___.a. Sugarb. Fatsc. Calciumd. WaterAnswer:","answer":"Answer: (c) CalciumSugar, fats, and water can be a part of the milk but calcium is the most essential constituent of milk."},{"question":"వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలలో గల రకాలను తెలపండి.","answer":"ముడిపదార్థాలు, సగం తయారైన వస్తువుల నుంచి పూర్తిగా తయారైన వస్తువులను ఉత్పత్తిచేసే వాటిని వస్తు. తయారీ పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. ఇనుము-ఉక్కు, యంత్రపరికరాలు, సిమెంటు, వస్త్రాలు మొదలైనవి ఈ పరిశ్రమక ఉదాహరణలుగా చెప్పవచ్చును.వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలో గల రకాలు :1) విశ్లేషణాత్మక పరిశ్రమ ముఖ్యమైన ముడిపదార్థాలను వివిధ ప్రక్రియల ద్వారా విశ్లేషణ చేసి, విడ వివిధ వస్తువులను ఈ పరిశ్రమలు తయారుచేస్తాయి.ఉదా : ముడిచమురును నూనె బావుల నుంచి తీసి, శుభ్రపరిచి, పెట్రోలు, డీజిల్, కిరోసిన్ మొదలైనవి తయారుచేయుట.2) ప్రక్రియాత్మక పరిశ్రమలు : ముడిపదార్థాలను వివిధ దశలలో, వివిధ ప్రక్రియలను జరపడం ద్వారా వస్తువులను తయారుచేయడం ఈ పరిశ్రమల ద్వారా జరుగుతుంది.ఉదా : వస్త్రపరిశ్రమ, కాగితం, పంచదార పరిశ్రమలు.3) మిశ్రమ పరిశ్రమలు : వివిధ రకాల ముడిపదార్థాలను శాస్త్రీయ పద్ధతిలో వివిధ నిష్పత్తులలో మిశ్రమము చేసి కొత్త వస్తువులను తయారుచేసే పరిశ్రమలను మిశ్రమ పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు.ఉదా : కాంక్రీట్, జిప్సమ్, బొగ్గు కలిపి సిమెంటు తయారుచేయుట.4) జోడింపు పరిశ్రమలు : వివిధ పరిశ్రమలలో తయారైన వస్తువులను నిర్దిష్ట పద్ధతిలో, క్రమములో జతపరిచి కొత్త వస్తువులను తయారుచేసే పరిశ్రమలను జోడింపు పరిశ్రమలు తయారుచేస్తాయి.ఉదా : టెలివిజన్, స్కూటర్, సైకిల్ మొదలైన వస్తువులను తయారుచేసే పరిశ్రమలు."},{"question":"තරංගයක විස්තාරය (Amplitude) යනුවෙන් හැඳින්වෙන්නේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"තරංග චලිතයට සහභාගී වන අංශු විසින් මධ්‍ය පිහිටුමේ සිට සිදු කරන උපරිම විස්ථාපනය තරංගයක විස්තාරය ලෙස හැඳින්වේ."},{"question":"句子1: 它在北美获得了东京出版的英语授权, 在北美, 它在五卷中被分为两部分, 句子二: 在北美,它在东京出版社的英语版授权下, 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"يجب على الثدييات التخلص من النفايات التي تنتجها أجسادهم. ما هو العضو الذي يساعد الثدييات على التخلص من المخلفات الجسدية؟ الخيارات: (أ) الملحق. (ب) الكلى. (ت) البنكرياس المعدة.إجابتك:","answer":"(ب) الكلى"},{"question":"ਅਲਿੰਗੀ ਅਤੇ ਲਿੰਗੀ ਜਣਨ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਅਲਿੰਗੀ ਜਣਨ-ਵਾਧੇ ਦੀ ਇਸ ਵਿਧੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਤਾਨ ਨਵਾਂ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਜਾਂ ਕਾਇਆ ਭਾਗ ਤੋਂ ਉਤਪੰਨ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਣਨ ਅੰਗ ਤੋਂ ਉਤਪੰਨ ਯੂਗਮਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਯੁਗਮਨ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ । ਲਿੰਗੀ ਜਣਨ-ਇਸ ਵਿਧੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਰ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਦਾ ਯੁਗਮਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਯੁਗਮਨ ਤੋਂ ਯੁਜ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਵਿਧੀ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਭਾਗ ਹਨ :    - ਅਰਧ ਸੂਤਰੀ ਵਿਭਾਜਨ-ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਣ ਸੂਤਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ ਅੱਧੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।    - ਨਿਸ਼ੇਚਨ-ਯੁਗਮਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਯੁਗਮਨ ਤੋਂ ਗੁਣ ਸੂਤਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ ਮੁੜ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Title: “పిల్లల్ని కనడం తప్పనిసరి కాదు.. అది నా ఇష్టం”nGiven the above title of an imaginary article, imagine the article.n","answer":"పెద్దలు చెప్పినట్లు, ఆడవాళ్లు యంత్రాల్లా పిల్లల్ని కనాల్సిందేనా?ఇలాంటి విషయాలపై ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా సునిశిత చర్చ జరగాలంటున్నారు.. వాషింగ్టన్ డీసీలో స్థిరపడిన పాకిస్తాన్‌ యువతి జైనాబ్ అమిన్. జైనాబ్‌లాగే అమెరికాలోని చాలామంది దక్షిణాసియా యువతులు ఇలాగే అభిప్రాయ పడుతున్నారు. పిల్లల్ని కనడమే కాదు.. వారి పెంపకం పట్ల కూడా వారు ఆసక్తి చూపించడం లేదు.ఒక అధ్యయనం ప్రకారం ప్రస్తుతం అక్కడ ప్రతీ ఐదుగురిలో ఒకరు పిల్లల్ని కనేందుకు ఇష్ట పడటం లేదు.\\"పిల్లల్ని కనాలా వద్దా అనేది ఆ యువతి ఇష్టం. తప్పనిసరిగా కనాల్సిందే అనే కట్టుబాటు ఉండకూడదు\\" అని వారు చెబుతున్నారు. “అమ్మాయిలకు భర్త, పిల్లలు ఉండటం తప్పనిసరేం కాదు”పిల్లల్ని ఎందుకు వద్దనుకుంటున్నారు?ఇంతకీ పిల్లలు వద్దని వాళ్లు ఎందుకు అనుకుంటున్నారు? వారు ఎలాంటి సమస్యలు ఎదుర్కొంటున్నారు? వాషింగ్టన్ డీసీలో ఉంటున్న దక్షిణాసియా యువతులతో  బీబీసీ ప్రతినిధి ఇమ్రాన్ అబ్బాసి మాట్లాడారు. అందులో ఒకరు జైనాబ్ అమిన్. ఆమె స్వస్థలం పాకిస్తాన్‌లోని లాహోర్. ఏడేళ్ల క్రితం అమెరికాకు వచ్చి స్థిరపడ్డారు. ఒక అంతర్జాతీయ సంస్థలో ఆమె మానవ వనరుల విభాగంలో పనిచేస్తున్నారు. పిల్లల విషయంలో ఆమె ఎందుకు ఇలాంటి నిర్ణయం తీసుకున్నారో జైనాబ్ మాటల్లోనే చూద్దాం.గర్భాశయం, అండాశయం ఉందని పిల్లల్ని కనేయాలా? తల్లి కావడం అనేది యువతి ఇష్టం. ఆమెకు ఇష్టం ఉంటే కంటుంది..లేదంటే లేదు. ఆమె పిల్లల్ని కనాల్సిందే అని ఒత్తిడి తెచ్చే అధికారం ఎవ్వరికీ లేదు. తల్లి కావడమే ఒక మహిళ పనా? ఆ ఒక్క అంశం ఆధారంగానే ఆమెను అంచనా వేయవద్దు. దాన్ని మించిన పనులు ఇంకా ఎన్నో ఉన్నాయి. నేను సంతోషంగా ఉండాలంటే తప్పనిసరిగా భర్త, పిల్లలు ఉండాల్సిన అవసరం లేదనే అనుకుంటున్నా.కేవలం భర్త, పిల్లలు ఉంటే ఆ ఇల్లు అందమైన నందనవనం అవుతుందా? ఇంట్లో సంతోషాలు వెల్లివిరుస్తాయా? లేదంటే నేను ఎక్కడైతే /  ఎలాగైతే ఆనందంగా ఉంటానో అదే నా ఇల్లు అనుకోవాలా?స్వార్థం కోసమే పిల్లల్ని కంటున్నారు!ప్రజలు తమ స్వార్థం కోసం పిల్లల్ని కంటున్నారు. సొంత ఆనందం కోసం మరో ఆలోచన లేకుండా పిల్లల్ని కని పడేస్తున్నారు.పిల్లల్ని కనడమే కాదు..వాళ్లను పెంచడం కూడా చాలా పెద్ద బాధ్యత. పిల్లల్ని కంటే చాలు వాళ్లంత వాళ్లే పెరుగుతారని మా సమాజంలో అనుకుంటారు. పిల్లల మానసిక, శారీరక పరిస్థితి గురించి ఎవ్వరూ పట్టించుకోరు. ఒక బాధ్యత గల పౌరులుగా వారిని తీర్చిదిద్దడంపై ఎవరూ దృష్టి పెట్టారు. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai berkelahi dalam kapuk\\"?","answer":"Perihal sesuatu perkara yang tidak mudah diselesaikan"},{"question":" Sheeg Diyaaradii Jarmalka Aheyd Ee Ay Somaliya Bad-Baadisay Sheeg Sanadkee AyuuAhaa?","answer":"Somaliya Ayaa Bad Baadisay Diyaarad Laga Lahaa Dalka Jarmalka Sanadkuna WuxuAhaa 1974"},{"question":"لدينا المسألة الرياضاية التالية: قرأت هنوف 35 صفحة من الكتاب يوم الأحد، و23 صفحة يوم الاثنين، وبقي 6 صفحات دون قراءة، فما عدد صفحات الكتاب الكلية؟. قم بحلها.","answer":"بالتأكيد، يمكن حلها كالتالي:  س = 6+23+35 = 64 صفحة."},{"question":"Америкалык астронавт 1969-жылы Аполлон 11 миссиясы учурунда Айга биринчи баскан адам катары белгилүү болгон ким?","answer":"Нил Армстронг 1969-жылы \\"Аполлон 11\\" миссиясы учурунда Айга басып өткөн биринчи адам катары белгилүү."},{"question":"Comente sobre o IDH de Moçambique.","answer":"O índice de desenvolvimento humano de Moçambique é dos mais baixos que existem, de 0,418 (ano base 2015), apenas à frente de outros sete países."},{"question":"Eyi ni bawọn aṣaaju Hausa-Fulani ṣe ba Naijiria yii jẹ (15)","answer":"Mo fẹ ki ẹ tun mu ọrọ ti mo fẹẹ sọ yii si ọwọ osi: To ba jẹ bi eto sẹnsọ orilẹ-ede yii ṣe wa naa lo wa, to ba jẹ pe a ko ri eto ikaniyan daadaa kan ṣe, to jẹ ibi ti awọn Hausa-Fulani ti gbe iye awọn ti wọn wa ni Naijiria si lati ọdun 1950 wa naa la ṣi wa, ko si bi orilẹ-ede wa yoo ṣe nilọsiwaju. Nibi eto ikaniyan, nibi ti wọn ti ni awọn Hausa-Fulani pọ ju awa to ku lọ ni Naijiria, nibi ti nnkan ti daru fun wa wa niyi. Bi a ko ba ṣe atunṣe sibẹ yẹn, ko si ibi ti a oo gba ti a oo fi ri atunṣe mi-in si ọrọ ara wa. Ohun kan to fun Hausa lagbara lori gbogbo awa to ku ni Naijiria niyi, awọn naa mọ bẹẹ, nitori ẹ ni wọn ko ṣe ni i ṣeto ikaniyan to yanju nilẹ yii, gbogbo eto sẹnsọ yoowu ti wọn ba ṣe, ojooro ati eru ni wọn yoo fi ṣe e. Laipẹ yii, wọn fi ọkunrin Ibo kan ṣe olori ileeṣẹ eleto ikaniyan yii, ṣugbọn kia ni wọn yọ o danu, ti wọn fi Hausa mi-in si i.Ki lo de ti wọn ṣe bẹẹ! Awọn eeyan yii mọ pe ipilẹ agbara awọn niyẹn, wọn mọ pe bi iyẹn ba ti bọ lọwọ awọn, ko si ohun ti awọn yoo ri ṣe ni Naijiria mọ. Nitori ẹ ni wọn ko ṣe ni i fi Ibo tabi Yoruba si ipo alaga eto ikaniyan yii, wọn ko fẹ ohun ti yoo da ẹru abosi ti awọn ti di lati ọjọ yii nu. Awọn ti wọn n ro pe Hausa Fulani ko gbọn, ibi ti wọn yoo ti kiyesi ara niyi. Awọn ti wọn si n ro pe awọn eeyan naa ko mọ ohun ti wọn n ṣe, ati awọn ọmọ ale ti wọn wa laarin awọn ẹya to ku ti wọn n ta awọn eeyan wọn, ti wọn n sọ pe awọn eeyan yii fẹ rere fawọn, ibi ti wọn yoo ti mọ naa ree. Ipo meji pataki lo wa nilẹ yii ti wọn ko ni i fi Yoruba tabi Ibo ṣe olori wọn, iyẹn naa ni ipo olori awọn ṣọja, ati ipo olori awọn ti yoo ṣeto ikaniyan fun wa. Fulani tabi Hausa ni wọn yoo fi sibẹ, bi wọn ba si fi ẹlomi-in s i i, ki ẹ ti mọ pe ọkan ninu awọn ẹru wọn ni, ohun ti wọn ba fẹ ni ẹni naa yoo ṣe.Nigba ti wọn ti fi agidi da eto ikaniyan 1962 ru, ti wọn ṣeto ikaniyan mi-in, ti Balewa ati Sardauna fi miliọnu mejọ eeyan kun awọn ara ilẹ Hausa, lati igba naa ni ko ti si ikaniyan ti wọn yoo ṣe ni ilẹ yii ti awọn eeyan naa ko ni i ju awa ẹya to ku lọ. Mo ti sọ ọ fun yin tẹlẹ, eto ikaniyan kọ ni wọn ṣe ti wọn fi ni iye ti wọn ni yii, magomago ati irẹjẹ ti ko si iru rẹ nibi kan ni gbogbo awọn orilẹ-ede Afrika to ku ni. Niwọn igba ti wọn si ti ṣe bẹẹ ti wọn ti mu un jẹ, ti wọn ti fi agidi ni awọn lawọn pọ ju wa lọ, ti wọn si ni awọn aṣofin ti wọn jẹ idaji gbogbo Naijiria, ti wọn n gba idaji ohun gbogbo ti a ba pin nilẹ yii, ko tun si nnkan mi-in ti wọn n ṣe ju bi iru agbara bẹẹ ko ṣe ni i bọ lọwọ awọn lọ. Ọna ti agbara naa ko si fi ni i bọ ni ki wọn ri i pe ko si Ibo tabi Yoruba to gberi ju wọn lọ, ki wọn si ni agbara lori awọn ọmọ ogun gbogbo.Loju awon baba wa yii naa ni wọn ṣe gba olori ileeṣẹ ologun lọwọ wọn, lẹyin ti wọn ti gba agbara ile-igbimọ aṣofin ati tijọba lọwọ wọn. Agbara ṣọja ti awọn Hausa-Fulani wọn yii tete ri gba lẹyin ti Naijiria gba ominira lo tubọ ba nnkan jẹ, oun lo si sọ awọn eeyan to ku di ọmọlẹyin fun wọn. Awọn eeyan kan maa n ṣe aṣiṣe kan, wọn yoo ni awọn Hausa-Fulani lo ni ṣọja, awọn ni ologun akọkọ. Mo ti sọ fun yin pe eleyii ki i ṣe bẹẹ, o pẹ gan-an ki awọn ọmọ ogun Fulani too dara pọ mọ awọn ọmọ ogun Naijiria. Ohun to fa a ni pe awọn Fulani lati Ṣokoto ko fẹẹ ri awọn oyinbo ti wọn waa ṣejọba ni Naijiria nigba naa. Wọn koriira wọn, nitori wọn ni kereferi ni wọn, nigba to ti jẹ Kristẹni ni wọn. Ikoriira ti wọn ni fun wọn yii ni awọn eeyan agbegbe wọn ko fi si ninu awọn ṣọja akọkọ ni Naijiria, awọn Fulani kọ ni wọn bẹrẹ iṣẹ ṣọja rara.Titi ti wọn fi kapa awọn Fulani yii ni 1903, gbogbo ero ọkan wọn ni pe awọn lawọn yoo kapa awọn oyinbo ati awọn keferi ti wọn n lo gẹgẹ bii ṣọja wọn. Nigba ti Lord Lugard fẹẹ bẹrẹ si i ṣa awọn ọmọ ogun jọ fun iṣẹ ṣọja rẹ ni 1897, ko duro ni ilẹ Hausa, Lọkọja, nitosi nibi, ni ilẹ Yoruba to wa ni Kogi bayii lo wa, nibẹ lo si ti n ṣa awọn ọmọ ogun rẹ jọ. Awọn ọmọ ogun to kọkọ ri mu ni awọn Agatu ati awọn Garra, awọn lo kọkọ n lo, ati awọn ọmọ ogun Ibadan ti wọn jẹ jagunjagun gidi nigba naa. Awọn yii ni ṣọja akọkọ ti Naijiria ni, lẹyin naa ni wọn ko awọn Tapa ni Nupe ati igiripa ni Borgu mọ wọn, ko si Fulani tabi Hausa ninu awọn yii, bẹẹ awọn ni Lugard fi bẹrẹ sọja nilẹ, nitori awọn Fulani lawọn ko le ba keferi ṣe, eewọ ni wọn ka a si, ogun Jihaadi lawọn le ja, Fulani lo si gbọdọ je olori awọn. Nigba tawọn ọmọ ogun yii n lọọ gba Ṣokoto, kidaa awọn ọmọ ogun Ibadan ni Lugard ko dani, ọmọ Yoruba ni wọn, ko si ẹya mi-in ninu wọn. Gbogbo eleyii wa ninu akọsilẹ itan igbesi-aye Lord Lugard funra ẹ, ko si aṣiwi tabi aṣisọ ninu rẹ rara. Ko too di igba yii, awọn jagunjagun kan wa nilẹ Ibo ati Naija Delta lọdọ awọn Ijaw, awọn ni ileeṣẹ ti wọn n pe ni Royal Niger Company n lọ, ileeṣẹ yii lo ni Naijiria tẹlẹ, awọn ni wọn si ta wa fawọn oyibo alawọ-funfun lati Britain. Ọrọ ọjọ mi-in leyii. Ṣugbọn awọn ileeṣẹ RNC ni wọn n lo awọn ọmọ ogun Ibo diẹ, ọmọ Naija Delta diẹ. Awọn yii ni wọn n lo bii ọlọpaa, ti wọn si n lo wọn bii jagunjagun ni gbogbo agbegbe naa fun ileeṣẹ yii, nitori ẹ ni ko si ṣe gbọdọ yaayan lẹnu pe nigba ti wọn bẹrẹ ṣọja, awọn yii naa dara pọ mọ wọn.Gbogbo awọn yii, Kristẹni ni wọn, tabi ka sọ pe Kristẹni lawọn Fulani ro wọn si, nitori wọn wa lati Isalẹ-odo-Ọya, wọn ko si ba wọn ṣe. Eyi ni pe ko si awọn Hausa Fulani wọnyi ninu awọn ọmọ ogun Naijiria, afi lẹyin ti awọn ṣọja Lugard wọnyi ṣẹgun wọn ni Ṣokoto, ti wọn ṣẹgun wọn ni Kano, ati awọn ilẹ Hausa to ku gbogbo. Ohun ti wọn n sọ ni pe ogun Anọbi ni awọn n ja, ilakaka lati sọ gbogbo aye di Musulumi lawọn n ṣe, ọta kan ṣoṣo ti awọn si ni ni awọn oyinbo ti wọn n gbe ẹsin Krisitẹni kiri, nitori loju wọn nigba naa, keferi lawọn ẹlẹsin Kristẹni yii, awọn ti awọn n sin ẹsin tiwọn yii ni awọn jẹ onigbagbọ ododo. Nibẹrẹ pẹpẹ, epe ni wọn maa n ṣẹ fun Lugard ati awọn ọmọ ogun rẹ, ti wọn yoo ni o fẹẹ waa le wọn jade ni ibujokoo awọn, o si fẹẹ fi ẹsin tirẹ bori ẹsin awọn. Ko si Fulani to fẹẹ ṣe ṣọja, awọn Hausa naa ko si fẹẹ ṣe.Mo fẹ ki ẹ maa fi ọkan ba awọn ọrọ yii lọ o. Ibẹrẹ itan awọn ṣọja wa ni mo n mẹnuba fun yin yii, ki n le fi han yin pe nigba ti a kọkọ bẹrẹ iṣẹ ologun igbalode nibi, ko si awọn Hausa-Fulani yii nibẹ, keferi ni wọn ka awọn ti wọn n ṣe ṣọja oyinbo si lọdọ wọn. Tori bẹẹ, ko gbọdọ ya ẹnikẹni lẹnu pe nigba tawọn ṣọja yii bẹrẹ iṣẹ taara, awọn Ibo atawọn Yoruba ni wọn n jọga nibẹ, awọn ni olori ologun. Ṣugbọn lẹyin ti ijọba bọ sọwọ awọn Balewa, wọn ti ọwọ bọ kinni naa loju, wọn da gbogbo eto to wa nilẹ pata lati wọ iṣẹ ṣọja ru, wọn gbe nnkan mi-in jade, wọn bẹrẹ si i sọ awọn ọmọ wọn di olori awọn ṣọja. Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọrọ naa dija, o tun di ariwo, sibẹ, wọn ṣe e ni aṣegbe o. N oo salaye ọna ti wọn gbe e gba fun yii lọsẹ to kọja, ṣugbọn nigba ti wọn ti ri iyẹn naa ṣe ni aṣegbe, lọjọ naa ni gbogbo agbara pata ti kuro lọdọ wa.Ẹ jẹ ka maa ba a bọ."},{"question":"Tichifunga ndima inotevera nezve vezvematongerwo enyika, ndiani aive munhu wekupedzisira asara kuve nhengo yeIrish House of Commons? Sir Thomas Staples, 9th Baronet (31 Chikunguru 1775 - 14 Chivabvu 1865) aive Anglo-Irish wezvematongerwo enyika uye gweta. Akange ari munhu wekupedzisira kurarama kuve nhengo yeIrish House of Commons, kunyangwe anga ari muImba kwenguva pfupi.","answer":"Sir Thomas Staples, 9th Baronet"},{"question":"Kuo vardu aktoriaus Aurimo Žvinio vaidintas pagrindinis serialo \\"Naisių vasara\\" herojus? Ramūnas Karbauskis yra teigęs, kad šis personažas tikrai nėra panašus į jį patį.","answer":"Pijus."},{"question":"Hãy viết một bài nghị luận ngắn về chủ đề sau, có thể thể hiện quan điểm cá nhân trong bài:Sang Tây ăn phở","answer":"Chúng tôi đã đến hàng chục quốc gia để tìm hiểu tình hình thế giới sau Đại dịch Covid-19. Ở đâu cũng khó khăn. Đâu đâu cũng thấy cửa hàng, cửa hiệu, khu mua sắm đóng cửa, treo biển cho thuê, bán mặt bằng.Đến nước nào, chúng tôi cũng tìm nhà hàng Việt để ăn phở, không chỉ để thưởng thức món thân quen mà còn để ủng hộ, để cảm thấy mình như đang ở nhà và quan sát xem bà con mình kinh doanh ra sao. Niềm vui chúng tôi nhận được là trên trái đất này, ở đâu có bà con người Việt, ở đó có phở. Các hiệu phở hay nhà hàng Việt Nam vẫn đông, ngày càng nhiều khách Tây.Phở đã trở thành \\"đại sứ toàn cầu\\" không chính thức của ẩm thực Việt Nam tự bao giờ.Không ít bạn bè, đối tác người nước ngoài của tôi nói rằng, họ ăn phở trước cả khi đến Việt Nam.Phở bò phổ biến nhất ở nước ngoài, rồi mới tới phở gà. Ẩm thực là câu chuyện của khẩu vị, nhưng nếu đã quen với phở gà \\"nội địa\\", khi đi du lịch, bạn nên gọi phở bò. Điểm yếu của phở gà \\"xuất khẩu\\" theo tôi là nguyên liệu và thói quen của khách hàng."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي حقوق المرأة في شريعة الدين الإسلامي الحنيف؟","answer":"الإجابة: أن تُعامل بالمودة والاحترام والرحمة والإحسان والبر والطاعة لها إن كانت أمًّا."},{"question":"Жети атасын эмне үчүн сурашкан ?","answer":"Жети ата — кыргыздардагы ата текти билүүгө байланышкан генеалогиялык түшүнүк.Салтка ылайык кыргыз коомундагы ар бир адам өзүнүн7️⃣ атасын билүүгө тийиш болгон. Жети атасын билбеген адам кул катары кабыл алынган. 19-кылымдын аягында Кыргызстанга келген орус адамы мындай деп жазган: «Бейтааныш адам жөнүндө бир нерсе билүү максатында: “Сенин 7️⃣ атаң ким болгон”, деп сурашат. Бул суроого абдан так жооп беришке кыргыздын ар бир баласынын кудурети жетет». «Ким өзүнүн 7️⃣ атасын билбесе, эл безери»д.а. Жети ата өзүнө тиешелүү төмөнкүдөй терминдер менен аталып, элдин аң-сезимине абдан терең сиңген: ата, чоң ата, баба, буба, кубаар, жото, жете. Элдин эсинде сакталып калган «кубаарыңдын куу чокусу, мадериңдин баш териси» (мадер түштүк диалектиде эне), «кудай кылса кубаарыңдын акысы барбы?», «жото-жетесиз кул», «жетеге жетчү кек», «жети атасынан бери жиликтеп сура» деген сыяктуу көөнө түшүнүктөр мындай салттын байыркылыгын ырастайт. Жети атаны сүрүштүрүү салты уруу ичиндеги никелик мамилелерди жөнгө салып, элдин генеалогиялык тазалыгын сактап калуу жана биол. популяциясына, өсүп-өнүгүшүнө ыңгайлуу шарт түзгөн. «Ал кезде 7️⃣ атасын сурап кыз бермек ырасим болгон», деп айтылат. Кыргыздар байыртадан бийик тоо шартында бири биринен обочолонуп жашагандыктан, тукумдун тазалыгын сакташ үчүн нике мамилелерин жөнгө салуу зарыл болгон. Бул адат боюнча жети муун өтмөйүнчө никеге турууга тыюу салынган. Бул отурукташкан элдерден айырмаланып, кыргыздарда никенин жана урпак-тукумду өстүрүүнүн өзүнчө мад-ты иштелип чыккандыгын айгинелейт. Ушундан улам жети атасын сүрүштүрүү салты келип чыккан.  Анткени, патриархалдык коомдогу уруктун ар бир адамы жети атасын так билгенде гана кайсы урукка таандык экендигин далилдей алган."},{"question":"Ibo Amẹrika: Trump fariga, o loun o gba pe Joe Biden ti wọle","answer":"Laika ti bawọn eeyan ṣe n rọjo ikini-kuu-oriire fun Ọgbẹni Joe Biden ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ kede rẹ bii aarẹ tuntun fun orileede Amẹrika si, Aarẹ orileede naa, Donald Trump, ti ni ọrọ ibo yii ko ti i pari rara o, bẹẹ loun ko si reti ijo ọpẹ kan lẹsẹ Biden, tori lọsẹ ta a fẹẹ mu yii loun yoo gba kootu lọ lati pẹjọ lori ibo ti wọn di ọhun.Ọsan ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, oni yii ni Aarẹ Trump sọrọ yii ninu atẹjade kan to fi sọrọ lori abajade ibo to fẹyin rẹ janlẹ naa, Trump ni ibo ko ti i pari rara ni.O sọ siwaju si i pe, “Gbogbo wa la mọ idi ti Joe Biden fi n sare kede ara rẹ bii ẹni to jawe olubori, ati idi ti awọn oniroyin rẹ fi n ṣagbatẹru fun un, tori wọn fẹẹ daṣọ bo otitọ mọlẹ ni, gbogbo aṣiri to wa nibẹ lo si ti han si wa. Ọrọ ibo yii ko ti i pari rara.”Trump ni jibiti ati wayo ṣẹlẹ ninu ibo yii, oun ko si ni i gba ki ọrọ naa lọ wọọrọwọ bẹẹ, ile-ẹjọ gbọdọ ba awọn da si i.Ọsan yii ni wọn kede Joe Biden to dije ipo aarẹ Amẹrika lati ẹgbẹ Democrats gẹgẹ bii olubori, nigba ti Aarẹ Trump to dijẹ labẹ asia Replican fidi rẹmi"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bapa kandung\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bapa sebenar. Bapa kandung saya tinggal di Perak."},{"question":"गर्भावस्थाको समयमा पोषण किन महत्त्वपूर्ण छ?","answer":"गर्भावस्थाको समयमा पोषणले भ्रूणको उचित विकास र स्वास्थ्यमा प्रत्यक्ष प्रभाव पार्छ र बच्चाको स्वास्थ्य निर्धारण गर्न महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्छ।"},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf - In het Forêt de Crécy staan een aantal zeer oude, monumentale bomen, waaronder de meer dan 600 jaar oude Ramolleux-eik, geplant ter herinnering aan de Slag bij Crécy","answer":"van 1346. Ook zijn een aantal boomstronken van gevelde bomen door kunstenaars omgevormd tot houtsculpturen. In het bos zijn 9 wandelroutes uitgezet."},{"question":"ahoana ny fomba Fitsabona ny varroa?","answer":"Fitsabona ny varroa- Fitsaboana amin’ny alalan’ny fampiasana fanafody simika: Apivar, Apistan, Thymol, Apiguard,Thymovar, Acide Oxalique, Acide Formique, Acide Acétique, Acide Lactique- Fitsaboana amin’ny alalan’ny ady gasy: votrim-bitsika,Torolalana fiompiana tantely amin’ny fomba nohatsarainaRecyclage des apiculteurs relais Boeny – novembre 201820 INSIGHT in development- Mila ampifandimbiasana ny fampiasana fanafody isaky ny taom-pamokarana- Fitsaboana amin’ny alalan’ny fanadiovana : fanalana matetika ny papiny misy lahin-tantely,fametrahana faladian’ny tohotra azo diovina isan’andro, fampiasana faladian’ny tohotra hogrillage- Ny fitsaboana ny varroa dia atao mialoha ny fotoana tena mhabetsaka ny fanatodiana syfitomboan’ny andian-tantely, tsy mbola misy tovana."},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa Biar Lambat Asalkan Selamat?","answer":"Peribahasa ‘Biar Lambat Asal Selamat’ membawa maksud sesuatu pekerjaan yang hendak dibuat biarlah dibuat dengan cermat dan berhati-hati supaya pekerjaan itu berhasil dengan baiknya.Ada setengah-setengah orang tidak mahu sabar dalam membuat sebarang pekerjaan. Mereka mahu segera menyiapkan pekerjaan itu tanpa menghiraukan akibatnya.Sebagai menghuraikan peribahasa di atas , saya akan mengambil contoh seorang pemandu kenderaan. Pemandu itu memandu kenderaannya dengan laju kerana dia ingin segera sampai ke tempat yang hendak ditujuinya. Tanpa disedarinya, perbuatannya itu berbahaya kepada dirinya sendiri dan juga orang lain.Sekiranya dalam perjalanan itu, sesuatu perkara yang tidak baik berlaku ke atas dirinya misalnya kemalangan , pemandu itu akan menyesal kerana perbuatannya itu. Ketika itulah dia akan terfikir perkara itu tidak akan terjadi jika dia sabar dan cermat ketika memandu.Peribahasa di atas adalah satu contoh yang paling baik dalam kehidupan kita seharian. Orang yang selalu mengamalkan peribahasa ini akan sentiasa selamat dalam setiap pekerjaan yang dilakukannya."},{"question":"外見よりも中身が大事という意味のことを「ボロを着てても心は」何？","answer":"にしきです。"},{"question":"Orúkọ Àdúgbò ní Ìjẹ̀bú-Igbó, Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn, Nàìjíríà","answer":"Àdúgbò: Òkè Àgbìgbò – Òkè Àgbò Ìtumò: Ní ayé atijo, àdúgbò yìí wà nínú igbó kìjikìji, àwon eye àgbìgbò ni o sì pò si ibè. Àwon eye wònyí a máa fò káàkiri orí igi t’osan t’òru, bákan náà ni òkè pò sí àdúgbò ti a ń so nipa rè yìí. Ní ìgbà tì o se, àwon ènìyàn bèrè sì tèdó sí àdúgbò yìí, wón ń kó ilé mole síbè àwon eye wònyí kò fi àdúgbò náà sílè. Obinrin kan lára àwon ti ó kókó te ìlú náà dó ti orúko rè ń jé “Bèje” akíkanjú obìnrin ni, òun ni ó pa àwon eye àgbìgbò náà run. Wón sì so àdúgbò náà di oke àgbìgbò, ti wón wá ń pè ni “Òkè Àgbò” ni òde òní. Won sì máa ń ki àwon omo àdúgbò náà báyìí; “Omo òkè àgbò Bèje” ìdí ni wí pé Òun (Bèje) ni o pa gbogbo àwon eye àgbìgbò náà run.2. Àdúgbò: Jàpara Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà láyéláyé ni ìlú Ìjèbú Igbó, ti wón bá ń jagun, ìbi ti ogun ti má a ń le ni won ń pè ni Jàpara, nitorí wí pé ni ibè ni wòn ti máa ń lérí mó ara won pé a o pa ara wa lónìí ni, won a sì jà titi won ó fi férè pa ara won tán. Ní gbà ti won wa bèrè sì te ibè dó, àwon àgbà wá so orúko àdúgbò ni “Jàpara” oríkì “Jàpara a kó obì se esà, a kérógbó bo ojú ogun. Ìjà ìpara – Jàpara”.3. Àdúgbò: Itúndosà. Ìtumò: Àwon Yorùbá máa ń pe àdúgbò ní “itún nígbà míràn, àdúgbò ti won ń pè ni itún yìí wà ni Ìjèbú Igbo, se ni àwon ara àdúgbò dédé jí ni ojo kan, won rí i ti omi ti di odò nla sí apá kan itún won. Káwí káfò, àwon ara itún bèrè sì ni pa eja nínú odò náà. Báyìí ni wón so àdúgbò náà di “Itúndòsà”. Won a sì máa pe àwon ti won wá lati àdúgbò yìí ni “Omo Ìdósà maye”.4. Àdúgbò: Igbáàìré – Igbáìre- Ìtumò: Àdúgbò yìí jé ibi ti igi igbá ti máa ń so, igi igbá pò sí àdúgbò yìí tó béè gee, ti awon eniyan sì máa ń seré lábé rè. Bí enikan báni àlejò ti ó wá a wá, won a ni kì won lo wòó ni abé igi igbá àìré- Ìgba ti won kò tii ré kúrò lórí Igi. Won wá so àdúgbò náà di Igbáìre.5. Àdúgbò: Ojówò- Òjóò Ìtumò: Ibi ti ojó máa ń wò si ni won ń pè ni Ojó wò ti o wa di Òjóò loni yìí.6. Àdúgbò: Itún alágbède-itúnlágbède Ìtumò: Itún ni èdè Ìjèbú je “Agbo ilé”. Ó sì jé ibi ti àwon alágbẹ̀dẹ pò sì, bí àwon enìyàn bá sì fé júwe àdúgbò lati agbo ilé yìí, won a ni e lo sí itún alágbède, tí ò sì di itúnlágbède di oni yìí.7. Àdúgbò: Asìsgbìdì Ìtumò: Ní ayé àtijú won máa ń mo sìgìdì nú ni àdúgbò yìí, àwon ènìyàn ati àwon Ode, Babaláwo ati lébo lóògùn a máa be sìgìdì lówè fún isé ibi, a sì je isé náà fún won. Tí sìgìdì bá padà dé, won a sì se ètùtù, won a fún-un ni epo mu. Nítori ìdí èyí ni won se ń pe àwon ti won tèdó sí àdúgbò yìí niOmo Asìgìdì mode, Omo Mode ráàtà Omo atà je epo má pòn ón.8. Àdúgbò: Imò alágbon-Imòàgbon-Imàgbon. Ìtumò: Ibi ti ìgi àgbon pò sí ni àdúgbò yìí, igi àgbon yìí pò to béè ti o fi je wí pe kò si ílé ti e kò tin i ríi. Béè sì ni imò wà lórí rè lópòlopò. Àwon eniyan Ìgbà náà sì ń pe ibè ni Imò àgbon, ti awon enìyan ode òní sì so ó di “Imàgbon”9. Àdúgbò: Imòro Ìtumò: Àdúgbò yìí je ibi ti ìgi òro pò sí. Àwon ènìyàn a sì máa je òro yìí, Imó ni agbègbè ibi ti òro yìí ń so sí jìngbìnni. Àwon ènìyàn wá so àdúgbò náà di imó òro ìmòro ni won ń pe ibè lónì yìí. Oríki! “Imòro àláà, a rérun (enu) gé òrò bí òbe”10 Àdúgbò: Òkè Erefòn Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà Ìwásè, Efòn ńlá kan wa ni Àdúgbò yìí ti o máa ń dààmú àwon ènìyàn ti won bá fe bojá lo sí oko. Odò nlá kan sì wà ni orí òkè ibì ti Efòn yìí máa ń lúgo sí. Bí àwon eniyàn ba ń darí bò lati oko won máa ń bu omi mu ninu odò yìí. Tí enikeni bá se ohun míràn yàtó sí mímu nínú omi náà, Efòn yóò fi imú onitòhún fon fèèrè. Sùgbón ti Efòn wáà bá ti rí wí pé won ń mu omi ni, kì yóò se ohunkóhun fun irú eni béè, won yóò sì la omu náà dúpé lówó Olódùmarè wí pé àwon gun òkè Efòn, ati wí pé omi ti àwon mu ninu odò ti re Efòn té lati má se ìjàmbá titi àwon fi gun òkè. Won wa so àdúgbò náà di òkè Odò re’fòn teti àgékúrú rè wá di “Òkè-erèfon”11. Àdúgbò: Ládugbó Ìtumò: Ládugbó ni èdè Ìjèbú túmò sí ìkokò ni Yorùbá àjùmòlò. Ìtàn sò wí pé Odò ńlá kan wà ni àdúgbò yìí ti ìkòkò (ládugbó) àbáláyé kan wà nínú rè. Tí àwon enìyàn bá fé pon omi múmu, nínú Ládugbó yìí ni won ti máa ń pon-ón. Sùgbon bi o ba je ki a fo aso, ìwè ati ohun miran ni won a lo omi tí ó yí Ládigbó náà kà á. Nígbà ti o se won se àdúgbò náà di “Odò-o-Ládugbó” ti àgékúrú rè wá di Lágugbó.12. Àdúgbò: Igà Eran Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà láyéláyé, Bàbá kan wà ti wón ń pè ni Òsígbadé Olómo òdo-nitori kò mo iye omo ti o bi, sùgbón ó jé onísòwò eran Màlúù. Ó ní àgbàlá ńlá ti ó máa ń da eran sí lati je pápá, kò si ohun òsìn míràn ti ó ń ba àwon màlúù náà gbé ni àgbàlá náà. Àgbàlá ńlá yìí ni àwon Ìjèbú máa ń pè ni Ugà eran ti o wa di “Igbà Eran’ lónìí13. Àdúgbò: Ìdágòlu Ìtumò: Ní ayé àtijú won a máa sa ìgò jo sí àdúgbò yìí fún fífo lati tà á. Ìtán so wí pé èyìn odi ìlú ni ibè jé, wón tún máa ń da àwon àkúfó ìgò jo síbè, àwon tí ó bá jé odùndùn, won a fó won sí wéwé. Ìgbà tí ó se, àwon ènìyàn bèrè sí tèdó sì àdúgbò yìí. won wa ń pe ibè ní “Abúle Ìdágòlu” ti o wa di “idágòlu”lónìí14. Àdúgbò: Ìdí Isin Ìtumò: Inú Igbó ni àdúgbò yìí jé nígbà àtijó, Igi ti o máa ń so èso isin ni ó pò nínú igbó yìí jù. Àwon eniyàn a máa sinmi labe àwon igi náà bí won bá ń ti ònà oko tàbí odò bò. Ìgbà tí ó se, ìgbó náà bèrè sí súnmó abúlé, nìtori àwon ènìyàn ń tèdó sí etí bè. Tí àwon àgbàlagbà ní abúlé pàápàá àwon Okùnrin bá jeun tan won a “tàtaré”sí abé igi yìí lati lo gba atégùn, ìbi ti wón bá ti ń tayò, tí won ń “tàkúrò so” won a wà níbè fún ìgbà pípé. Enikéni ti ò ba ni àlejò, won a ni kí ó lo wo eni ní ó ń bèèrè ni ìdí igi isin tí ó wa di “Ìdí Isin” lónìí.15. Àdúgbò: Ìdí scale (síkéèlì) Ìtumò: Ní àdúgbò yìí, ìwòn tì àwon alágbède ro ni wón ń lò lati máa fi se òsù wòn kòkó. Gbogbo àwon onísòwò kòkó pátápátá ni won máa ń pàdé ni àdúgbò ti a ń so yìí lati wa rà ati ta kòkó won níbè. Ní ìdí èyí, won so ibè dí ìdí scale ti wón ti ń won kòkó, ti àgékúrú rè sì di “Ìdí scale” lónìí16. Àdúgbò: Òkè sópen Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà atijo, àwon osó ati Àjé kò fi ìse won bò rárá, isé ibi won kò ni àfìwé, sùgbón àwon Àgbààgbà pinnu lati da sèríà fún enikeni ti owó won bá tè. Tí won bá mú enikeni ti o ni osó tabi Àjé ibi tì wón ti yàn sótò, ti won ti ń so òkò pa wón ni wón ń pè ní òkè ti osó pari emir è sí, tabí òkè tie mi osó pin sí. Èdè àdúgbò Ìjèbú ni “pen” – Yorùbá àjùmòlò ni “Pin” Nígbà ti ojú ńlà ti àwon enìyàn ń kólé sí bè won wa so àdúgbò náà dí “Orí òkè osópen”ti àgékúrú rè wá di “ÒKE SÓPEN”17. Àdúgbò: Odò-Rámúuségun Ìtumò: Ìtàn so fún wa wí pé àdúgbò kan wà ti ogun máa ń jà wón lópòlopò, bí ogun bá sì ti wolé tò wón, won máa kó won lérú ni. Ní ìgbà ti o se àwon àgbaàgbà ti won kù ni ìlú náà fi orí kan orí won sì to “ifá” lo lati bèèrè ohun ti won tè se ti agbègbè àwon kò fin i parun lowo àwon ti o ń ko won lérú. Ifá ni kì won bo Odò ti o nà ni ìlú won, kì won sì máa pon omi Odò náà sí ilé, gbàrà tì won bá gbó wí pé ogun wòlú, ki oníkálukú bu omi náà mu. Láìpé Ogun miran wolé tò wón, wón se bi ifá ti wí, wón jagun won sì ségun. Wón wá ni odò ni awon fí ségun, ti ó wá di “Odò-rámúùségun”18. Àdúgbò: Itún-Lógun Ìtumò: Itún ni èdè ìjèbú túmò sí “Agbólé”. Àwon jagunjagun ìlú ni ibi ti wón ti máa ń pàdé dira ogun ti won ba fe lo sí ojú ogun. Àkókò ti won bá fe lo jagun nikan ni won máa ń pàdé ni ibè. Tí àwon ènìyàn tì kò mo ohun ti o ń selè télè bá ti ń ri àwon jagunjagun ti won ń dé sí itún yìí, won a ni àwon Ológun ti dé sí itún won. Won wa so ibè di “itún Ológun” ti àgékúrú rè wa di “itún Lógun”.19. Àdúgbò: Odò Asóyìn Ìtumò: Odò kan wà ni àdúgbò kan, ti èso Òyìn máa ń so repete ní bèbè rè. Àwon àgbàgbà a máa jókòó ta ayò ni abé àwon igi yìí, won a si máa fi èso òyìn panu bí ayò bá ń lo lówó. Báyìí ni wón so ibè di “Odò ti o ń so èso Òyìn” tí ó wá di “Odò asoyìn”.20. Àdúgbò: Orímolúsì Ìtumò: Ní Ìgbà Ìwásè orúko àdúgbò ńlá kan ni ìjèbú Igbó ni “Orímolúsì”. Sùgbón, gégé bi a ti mò wí pé àwon Yorùbá máa ń ye ìpún tabi Àyàmó wò (ori). Àwon ènìyàn àdúgbò náà a da Obì won a wí pé “Orí ìwo lo mo Olùsìn, Olùserere, je kí ìgbésí ayé mi dára o. Báyìí ni eni ti o kókó je Oba ìlú náà wí pé òun ni Olórí ìlú, òun ni orí fún àwon ènìyàn ti o wà ni ìlú gbogbo ènìyàn yóò sì ma pe sin òun ni. Ní ìdí ènìyàn, won so Oba náà di “Orí-mo-Olùsìn” ti ó di “orímolúsì” lónìí.21. Àdúgbò: Bógije Ìtumò: Ní ayé atijo okùnrin kan wà ti o kúrò ni àárin ìlú lati máa lo gbé inú Igbo nitori wí pé o ti ya wèrè, wèrè yìí pe lára rè to béè gè é ti o gbé òpòlopò odún nínú igbó náà. Ní ìgbà míràn ti kinní òhún bá wò ó lára tán, a bèrè sí yà èèpo igi a máa rún-un wòmùwòmù; Àwon èrò ti ó ń lo, tó ń bò lónà oko máa ń wòó tàánú-tàánú; nígbà tì o yá kò jo wón lójú mo. Wón wá ń pè é ni wèrè ti ó ń bó igi je, òun a sì máa le won bí wón bá ti pè é béè. Sùgbón nígbà tì àwon ènìyàn bèrè sí ko ilé ibè, won wa so ibè di àdúgbò wèrè tò ń bó igi je, àgékúrú rè wá di “bógije”22. Àdúgbò: Òkè Idán Ìtumò: Àwon eléégún ati àwon abòrìsà ìlú máa ń se ayeye Odún won ni Odoodún ni ayé atiju. Orí Òkè ńlá kan ni won sì ti máa ń pa Idán Orísirísi fún àwon ara ìlú. Nígbà tì o se àwon ènìyàn kólé sí Orí Òkè yìí, won sí so àdúgbò náà di “Orí Òkè Idán pípa” tó wa di Òkè Idán” lónìí.23. Àdúgbò: Iwáta Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà ti àwon ènìyàn bá je Oyè tan ní ìlú, àwon Ìjòyè a sì wá sí Iwájú ìta àafin Oba pèlú àwon ebí, ara ati òré won-lati wa jó, lati se àjoyò pèlú Olóyè tuntun. Nígbà ti ó so àwon ènìyàn féràn lati máa se ayeye orísirìsì ni iwájú ìta àafin Oba nitori pé enikeni ti o ba fe se ayeye ti Oba bat i gbó nipa rè ni yóò ri èbùn gbà lówó Oba. Báyìí ni won bèrè sì lo ìtà Oba fun ayeye, bí won ba sì fé se àpèjúwe ìbì ti won yóò ti se ayeye fun àwon ará, òré, ati ojúlùmò, won a ni kí wón wá bá won se ayeye ni iwájú ìta Oba. Níbo ni e o ti se ayeye? “iwáta Oba ni” kèrèkèrè wón so àdúgbò náà di “Iwátá”.24. Àdúgbò: Òkè Ererú Ìtumò: Kí o tó dì wí pé a gba òmìnira, àdúgbò yìí ni wón ti máa ń ta erú, tì àwon ènìyàn sì ti máa ń ra àwon erú lo sí “Àgbádárìgì”. Nígbà ti ó se Ojà erú títà sá féré ni orí òkè yìí, àwon Olùtajà a sì wá so ibè di Òkè-Ererú25. Àdúgbò: Òkè Tákò Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà àtijó, ti wón ba fe fi Oba je ni ìlú, àdígbò yìí ni won ti máa ń gbìmò eni ti Oba kan, lati ìdílé ti Oba kan. Tí ètò fífi Oba je yìí bá takókó ti o díjú tan pátá, àwon àgbààgbà afobaje á kó ara won lo si Ori Òkè kan lati lo tú gbogbo ohun ti o bá dìju palè. Ní orí òkè yìí won a dìbò, won a dá ifá, ohun gbogbo yóò sì ni ojútùú kì won tó padà sí ilé. Nitorí ìdí èyí ni wón se so òkè náà di “Òkè Tákò” Òkè ti a ti ń tú ohun lèrò ti ó ta kókó.26. Àdúgbò: Òkè Àtààfíà Ìtumò: Léyìn Ìgbà ti àwon afobaje bá ti ri ojùtùú enì ti yóò joba, Okan won a balè, won a wá gun orí òkè kan lo lati lo gba atégùn sára, nìbe wón a mu emu, won a sì máa wí pé àlàáfíà ti dé bá ìlú. Orí òkè yìí ni o di àdúgbò ńlá lónì, ti won so di “Òkè àlààfíà”.27. Àdúgbò: Òkè ìfé Ìtumò: Orí òkè kan wà ti àwon àlejò ti wón ba sèsè wo inú ìlú ti máa ń lo búra wí pé àwon kò ni se búburú sí Oba ati àwon omo onílùú Orisìrìsi àwon èyà enìyàn ni won máa ń pàdé ni orí oke yìí ni asìko ìbúra náà, Ègbá, ìbàdàn Òyó. Hausa, Ìgbò, abbl. Orò ajé ni ó gbe won wá sí ìlú náà (Ìjèbú Igbó). Ní gbà tí ó se Oba se akiyesi wí pé gbogbo àwon àlejò wònyí ń se bí omo ìyá kan náà, a fi bi eni pe ile kan ni gbogbo won ti wá. Láì fa òrò gùn, àwon àlejò yìí ń pò sí, won ń bí sí i, won ń rè sí, ìlú sì kún to béè géè tì onílé kò mo àlejò mó. Ní ojo kan, Ob ape gbogbo àwon àlejò ìlú jo tèbí tàráawon, Ó sì so fún won wí pé òun ríi pé won ni ìfé ara won, lati òní lo, òun (Oba) yàn-ǹ-da orí òkè tì wón tì bura ni ojósí fún won, ki won ko àwon enìyàn won ki wón lo tèdó sí ibè. Gbogbo àwon àlejò wònyí sì dupe lówó oba. Won sì se bi Oba ti wí. Lati Igba náà ni won ti so àdúgbò náà di orí òkè ìfé ti o di “Òkè Ìfé” loni yìí.28. Àdúgbò: Atìkòrì Ìtumò: Ní ayé atijo, ìko tìí wón fi ń hun eni ni ó pò ni àdúgbò yìí. Bàbá kan wà ti o je ògbóǹtagí onísègùn; ìko ni o máa ń fi ríran sí àwon ènìyàn. ohun kohun ti ènìyàn bá bá lo si òdò rè ìko yìí ni ó máa kó kalè ti yóò sì máa ba sòrò bí ènìyàn; sùgbón ohun nìkan ni o máa ń gbo èdè tì ìko náà ń so, òun yóò wa túmò fún eni tí ó wa se àyèwò. Ní ìdí èyí, won so “Baba’yìí ni “Ati ìko ri ohun ti o ń sele si ènìyàn” ti o di “Atìkorí nigba ti awon ènìyàn tèdó si àdúgbò náà. Lónìí Atìkòrì ni àwon ènìyàn ń pè é.29. Àdúgbò: Odòdóoróyè Ìtumò: Ní aye atijo, Okùnrin ken wà ni ìlú ó je alágbára atì alákíkanjú ènìyàn. Orúko rè ń jé “omódóríoyè” Ó se isé takun-takun fún ìlú Baba rè, ò sì jè omo Oba”. Ní ìgbà tì Oba tó wà lórí Oyè wàjà, Ìdílé rè ni Oba kàn òun sì ni o ye ki wón mú, nínú ìdílé náà. pàápàá tì o tún jé alágbára ènìyàn. Àwon afobaje gba àbètétè lowo elòmíràn won sì kojú “Omódoríòyè” sóòrù alé. Kàkà ki ilè kú, ilè á sá ni Omódérìoyè fi òrò náà se ati bi a se mò wí pé àwon alágbára kò kò Ikú Omodorioye se Okunrin, ò sì pinnu wí pé bí won kò tilè fi òun joba won kò ni gbàgbé òun láyéláyé. Báyìí ni “omódóríoyè tí àwon ènìyàn ti se àgékúrú orúko rè sí “Dóróyè” télè, di odò ńla kan sí odì ìlú náà, ó sì fi ohùn sílè wí pè, Oba tí ó ba je ti kò bá mu nínú omi náà kì ni pe lori oyè tí wón fi je, atì wí pé eníkéni tí ó bá ń mu omi náà yóò di alágbára. Bíí àwon ènìyàn se bèrè sí ni tèdó si eti odò náà ni yìí, ti won sí so àdúgbò náà ti “Odòdóoróyè” iyan nip e “Odò Omódórí oyè”.30. Àdúgbò: Station (Sitésòn) Ìtumò: Léyìn Ìgbà ti awon Gèésì dé, ti Okò ayókélé ati irúfé okò mìran bèrè si won orile èdè wa, àwon Okò akérò tì o ba wo ìlú ìjèbú Igbó ni ibikan ti won ti gbódò ja awon èrò won sile, ti won yóò sì kó àwon èrò miran. Ibè ni won ń pè ni station, Ibikiri ti ènìyàn bá ń lo lati ìjèbú Igbó, Ibe nikan ni e ti lè ri oko wò."},{"question":"கேள்வி:தமிழகத்தின் முதல் குடைவரைக் கோவில் எது? ","answer":"பதில்:மகேந்திர பல்லவன் என்கிற பல்லவ மன்னனால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட தமிழகத்தின் முதல் குடைவரைக் கோவிலாகக் கருதப்படும் இலக்சிதன் கோயில் எனும் மண்டகப்பட்டு திருமூர்த்தி கோவிலே தமிழகத்தின் முதல் குடைவரைக் கோயிலாகும்."},{"question":"ඉඟුරු භෝගය ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"Zingiber Officinaleකුලය: Zingiberaceaeඉඟුරු, නැගෙනහිර ආසියාවේ ආරම්භ වූ බවට විශ්වාස කෙරෙන අතර වසර 3000 කට වඩා ඉතිහාසික වාර්තා ඇත. ඉඟුරු පුරාණ කාලයේ සිටම කුළුබඩු වර්ගයක් ලෙස භාවිතා කර ඇත. එය චීන හා ආයුර්වේද වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාවේ බහුලව භාවිතා වේ. නීරෝ අධිරාජ්‍යයාගේ පාලන සමයේදී රෝම හමුදාව ඉඟුරු ඖෂධයක් ලෙස භාවිතා කළ බව පැවසෙන තොරතුරු තිබේ. ක්‍රි.ව.1547 වන විට ඉඟුරු යුරෝපීය රටවලට කුළුබඩු වර්ගයක් ලෙස ආනයනය කර ඇති බවට සාක්ෂි හමුවී තිබේ. මෑත වසරවලදී ඉඟුරු බොහෝ රටවල වාණිජ බෝගයක් ලෙස වගා කර ඇත. චීනය, ඉන්දියාව, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, ෆීජි, හවායි, හොංකොං, ජැමෙයිකාව, ජපානය, නයිජීරියාව, පකිස්ථානය, බටහිර අප්‍රිකාව, තායිවානය වැනි රටවල මහා පරිමාණයෙන් ඉඟුරු වගා කෙරේ."},{"question":"வினா:  ஒற்றை ஒலிம்பிக்கில் அதிக ஒலிம்பிக் பதக்கம் வென்ற நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை: அமெரிக்கா"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bulan penuh'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud cantik. Contoh ayat: Mukamu bagai bulan penuh. Saya suka menatapnya."},{"question":"Mina? Hhayi, ayikho leyo nto!Uma kunguwe uSonto Mbhele impela ngisho wena. (Aphenduke uSontoaphindele endlini.)Mama, ake ngibeke nazi izikhwama ngizobuya ngokushesha.Hhayi bo, wadlala ngomuntu omdala, uzobuyaphi?Sonto, ngobani labo okhuluma nabo abangangeni endlini?(Engena endlini.) Sawubona mama. Sengiphinde ngabuya futhi.Senifunani futhi ndodana, awumtholanga yini ngenkathi umfunauSonto?Usho kahle mama, ngangizomfuna, namuhla ngizomlanda.Umsaphi manje?Siyambopha mama.Nimbophelani? Musani ukudlala ngengane yami ngoba yafelwayindoda!(Eziqinisa) Ungakhathazeki mama, ngizobuya khona namhlanje.Ungazithembisi kakhulu. Mancane amathuba okubuya komuntuosebulale abantu abangaka!(Ngokumangala) Nisho uSonto lo engimzalayo? Anobuye nithi niyadlala.Yena impela lo owamthwala esiswini sakho mama.(Ebuka uSonto isikhathi eside.) Kanti usha amashushu kangakangokuhamba yingoba ushiya amacala angaka?Ayikho le nto abayishoyo mama, bayangisukela. Ngizobafaka kummelibangikhokhele ngokungiqambela amanga.Kodwa ngishilo ukuthi kukhona okusolisayo. Mntanami, ngimdala.(Ekhala) Mntanami kodwa wawungenwe nguSathane muni?Sekufanele sihambe mama.Naze nangehlula-ke. Anobuya phela nizongitshela ukuthi sekuhambakanjani ngomntanami.Kulungile mama.(Aphume noSonto, amvalele evenini.)1. Hlobo luni lo mdlalo lolu ngokwendikimba? Sekela impendulo yakho.","answer":"Yimbangalusizi √/Imelodrama √ ngoba: Umdlalo uqala kubulewe uMaNtuli ebulawa yizigebengu ezazithengwenguSonto. Kuvela uSonto esongelwa yizigebengu ezabulala uMaNtuli zifuna imaliyazo. USonto udubula umfundisi ukuze athole yonke imali yomnikelo abeseekhokhela izigebengu imali yazo. USonto uphinde ahlele nezigebengu ukuthi kubulawe uMbhele ukuzeathole imali yamafa. Emva kokufa kukaMbhele izigebengu noSonto bayaboshwa besekuphuma wonke amaqiniso."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال اللي جاي: مين اللي لعبت مون موثما في مقابل الجيداي؟","answer":"كارولين بلاكستون"},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Ba noppi ngeen rey aw nit, ci seen biir, am ca ab kurél bu ngeen génne seeni kër, ngeen dimbalante ci ay bàkkaar ak ug noonuwante. Te bi ngeen leen jàppee ci xare di leen fayloo ag njot te di leen génne te loolu araam na ci yéen. Ndax dangeen a dëggal lenn téere ba, weddi la ca des? Kuy def loolu ci yéen, dara du doon peyam lu dul toroxte ci dundug àddina, te Bis-pénc ba dees na leen delloo ci gën jaa tari mbugal. Yàlla dey nekkul Kuy ñàkk a seetlu li ngeen di def.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Ba noppi ngéen ray aw nit, ci séen biir, àm ca ab kurel bu ngéen génne séen i kër, ngéen dimblante ci ay bàkkaar ak ug noonoonte. Te bi ngéen léen jàppee ci xare di léen fayloo ag njot te di léen génne te loolu araam na ci yéen. Ndàx da ngéen a dëggal lenn téere ba, weddi la ca des? Ku'y def loolu ci yéen, dara du doon payam lu dul toroxte ci dundug àddina, te Bis-pénc ba dees na léen delloo ci gën jaa tar i mbugal. Yàlla de, nekkul Ku'y ñàkk a seetlu li ngéen di def."},{"question":"ඔවුන් මාව යොමු කළ ඔවුන්ගේ සමාගමේ තනතුර මම පිළිගෙන ඇති බව යාවත්කාලීන කරන කෙනෙකුට විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලක් ලියන්න.","answer":"හායි, මම පිරිනැමීම පිළිගත් බව ඔබව යාවත්කාලීන කිරීමට මට අවශ්‍ය විය! කෝපි කතාවල සිට සම්මුඛ පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා සූදානම් වීම දක්වා මෙහි විශාල කොටසක් වීම ගැන ඔබට ස්තූතියි. ඔබ මගේ යෙදුම් ගමනේ සියලු වෙනස්කම් සිදු කළ අතර ඔබ සමඟ වැඩ කිරීමට මම ඉතා සතුටට පත් වෙමි."},{"question":"வினா: வீரத்தை பாடிய 400 சங்க இலக்கிய பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பு?","answer":"விடை: புறநானூறு "},{"question":" Балдарга айтылчу кандай каалоо тилек билесиз?","answer":"Айтылуу шумкар көздүү бол,Адам тапкыс сөздүү бол,Байсалдуу арты үзүлбөсБак баштаган күчтүү бол,Улууну сыйлап жетик бол,Кичүүгө өмүр кешик бол,Аккан суунун шары бол,Балбандардын алы бол.🤲🏻"},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um diretor de cinema?","answer":"Um diretor de cinema lidera a produção de filmes, tomando decisões criativas e técnicas para contar uma história."},{"question":"Kuris gyvas sausumos gyvūnas yra didžiausias Žemėje?","answer":"Didžiausias sausumos gyvūnas yra afrikinis savaninis dramblys."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Chung kết Miss Teen International 2022 (Hoa hậu Thanh Thiếu niên Quốc tế) vừa diễn ra đêm tại Ấn Độ với sự tham gia của 20 thí sinh. Vượt qua nhiều đối thủ nặng ký Ngô Ngọc Gia Hân - Đại diện Việt Nam được Sở Văn hoá Thể thao TPHCM cấp phép đi so tài đã đăng quang ngôi vị Hoa hậu. Nhận được câu hỏi ứng xử của Ban Giám khảo: Bạn có nghĩ rằng cuộc thi sắc đẹp là một phần trong Thế vận hội? Ngô Ngọc Gia Hân trả lời thành thạo bằng tiếng Anh: \\"Em tin rằng các cuộc thi sắc đẹp không chỉ tôn vinh vẻ đẹp bên ngoài mà nó còn có thể được công nhận là một ngành công nghiệp giải trí quan trọng. Vì vậy nó có sự khác biệt về bản chất và chúng ta cần tôn trọng theo cách riêng biệt và công bằng. Chúng ta là đại diện của đất nước mình tại cuộc thi Hoa hậu Thanh Thiếu Niên Quốc tế, điều này không hề kém tự hào so với việc đại diện đất nước tại Thế vận hội. Vì vậy em có niềm tin mãnh liệt rằng các cuộc thi sắc đẹp không nên bao gồm trong Thế vận hội vì nó có sự khác biệt về bản chất, và chúng ta cần tôn trọng theo cách riêng biệt và công bằng. Chúng ta đều là những đại diện","answer":"của đất nước mình tại Hoa hậu Thanh Thiếu niên Quốc tế, điều này không hề kém tự hào so với việc đại diện đất nước tại Thế vận hội. Vì vậy tại sao chúng ta không làm nổi bật mình? Để trở thành một người chiến thắng ở Thế vận hội, chúng ta phải luyện tập thể thao chuyên nghiệp, còn để đăng quang tại một cuộc thi sắc đẹp, đặc biệt là cuộc thi Hoa hậu Thanh Thiếu niên Quốc tế, chúng ta cần chuẩn bị về mặt hình thể, phải luôn tràn đầy năng lượng, cũng cần là một cô gái năng động khi còn là một thiếu niên. Bên cạnh đó nó củng cố về mặt tinh thần, mang lại cho chúng ta trách nhiệm thực hiện các dự án cộng đồng. Và cuối cùng cũng là điều nhiều cảm xúc nhất, chiến thắng cuộc thi mang lại cho ta trách nhiệm nhìn vào những mặt tốt và mang đến ý thức trách về trách nhiệm nhiều hơn khi đội trên mình chiếc vương miện. Nếu tổ chức đang tìm kiếm một cô gái có thể giới thiệu những giá trị của cuộc thi sắc đẹp, đặc biệt là Hoa hậu Thanh Thiếu niện Quốc tế thì cô gái ấy chắc chắn là em!\\". Cùng với danh hiệu Hoa hậu của Ngô Ngọc Gia Hân, đại diện đến từ Mỹ đoạt giải Á hậu 1 và đại diện đến từ Hà Lan đoạt giải Á hậu 2. Tiếp tục hành trình sau đăng quang, Tân Miss Teen International 2022 Ngô Ngọc Gia Hân sẽ tham gia một số hoạt động cùng Ban tổ chức tại Ấn Độ. Trong suốt thời gian đăng quang, Hoa hậu Ngô Ngọc Gia Hân sẽ phải hoàn thành các sứ mệnh về từ thiện, cộng đồng trong nhiệm kỳ 2 năm của mình ở cấp độ quốc gia và quốc tế. Bên cạnh đó, Tân Hoa hậu sẽ đại diện cho Việt Nam tham dự các sự kiện Văn hóa lớn khi nhận được lời mời từ BTC cuộc thi Miss Teen International… Miss Teen International 2022 được tổ chức tại Ấn Độ từ 22 - 30/7 với sự tham gia của 20 thí sinh trong đó có đại diện đến từ Mỹ, Hà Lan, Mexico, Thái Lan, Ấn Độ, Việt Nam..."},{"question":"Các thiên hà có mấy hình dạng chính?","answer":"Các ngôi sao tập hợp thành thiên hà. Vũ trụ có hàng tỷ thiên hà, mỗi thiên hà lại có hàng tỷ ngôi sao. Thiên hà có nhiều hình dạng khác nhau, phổ biến nhất là ba dạng: xoắn ốc, xoắn ốc gãy khúc và elip. Một số thiên hà không có hình dạng cố định, được gọi là thiên hà vô định. Trái Đất thuộc thiên hà có tên Ngân Hà, nên con người khó có thể biết được hình dạng của Ngân Hà. Tuy nhiên, hầu hết các nhà thiên văn học tin rằng nó có hình xoắn ốc. So với các thiên hà khác, Ngân Hà khá lớn với đường kính 100.000 năm ánh sáng, chứa khoảng 2.000 tỷ ngôi sao.Ngân Hà có thể được quan sát một phần bằng mắt thường, trông giống một dải sao rộng và dày đặc. Những đêm trời trong từ tháng 7 đến 9 (bán cầu Bắc) và tháng 10 đến 12 (bán cầu Nam) là thời điểm có thể quan sát Ngân Hà tốt nhất."},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Mitambo Yekupedzisira yeFESPIC yaive nenzvimbo 18 dzekuitira Mitambo, 9 muKuala Lumpur, 7 muSelangor uye imwe neimwe muPutrajaya neNegeri Sembilan. Mutsara 2: Mitambo yekupedzisira yeFESPIC yaive nenzvimbo gumi nesere: pfumbamwe muSelangor, nomwe muKuala Lumpur uye imwe muPutrajaya neNegeri Sembilan imwe neimwe. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Aiwa?","answer":"Aiwa"},{"question":"Qual é a moeda de Comores?","answer":"A moeda oficial de Comores é o Franco Comorense, que é abreviado como KMF (código ISO 4217)."},{"question":"Unsaon pag kuwenta sa Philhealth kontribusyon sa 2023","answer":"Kwentaha sa ingon ani na pamaagi:Basic Salary X 4%"},{"question":"Which bird has the largest wingspan?","answer":"Albatross "},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన సినిమా పాటలోని ఒక భాగం యొక్క సాహిత్యంపై విశ్లేషణ చెయ్యండి:నిటలలోచన నయనతారా.. తారా భువనేశ్వరీప్రణవధామ ప్రణయదామా..సుందరీ కామేశ్వరీఅరుణవసన.. అమలహసనాఅరుణవసన.. అమలహసనామాడినీ.. మనోన్మణినాదబిందు కళాధరీ భ్రామరీ…నాదబిందు కళాధరీ భ్రామరీ… పరమేశ్వరీనాదబిందు కళాధరీ భ్రామరీ… పరమేశ్వరీ","answer":"నిటలలోచన నయనతారా.. తారా భువనేశ్వరీ’ – కోపముతో ప్రజ్వలిల్లే ఆ నిటలాక్షుడి మాధవ కంటి శక్తి జగన్మాతడే అలాగే ఆయన కోపాన్ని చల్లబరిచే చిరునవ్వు కూడా ఆ తల్లిదే.  నక్షత్ర లోకానికి రాణియై ప్రకాశించేది ఆవిడే.  ఆ ఈశ్వరుడి శక్తి ఆవిడే, కంటిలో దీప్తీ ఆవిడే… అందుకే ఆవిడని ‘శివశక్తైక రూపిణి ‘ గా అభివర్ణించారు. ‘ప్రణవధామ ప్రణయదామా..సుందరీ కామేశ్వరీ’ – ప్రణవధామా అనగా ఓంకారమే నివాసముగా కల తల్లి. ప్రణయదామా అనగా ప్రేమైక్యభావన హారముగ్ కలది అంటే అందరిపట్ల సమానమైన ప్రేమ భావము చూపునాది.  సుందరీ అనగా సుందరమైనదానవు అని ఒక అర్ధం. గాలిత్యము కలిగిన అని మరొక అర్ధం  లాలిత్యము కలిగిన అంటే అమ్మ లలితా దేవే.  అందుకే కాళిదాసు ‘అశ్వధాటి స్త్రోత్రము” లో ” రూపాధికా శిఖరి భూపాల వంశమణి దీపాయితా భగవతీ‘”  అని వర్ణిస్తారు.  అంటే ఆవిడని మించిన సౌందర్యము మరొకటి లేదు, అందుకే ‘రుపాధికా శిఖరి ‘ – అధికమైన అందానికి శిఖరం ఆవిడ.. సౌందర్య లహరే ఆ తల్లి.    కామేశ్వరీ అనగా ఈశ్వరునికి కోరిక కలిగించి ఆ కోరికను తీర్చునది. ‘అరుణవసన.. అమలహసనా’  –  అరుణవసన అనగా ఎర్రని వస్త్రములు ధరించునది,  అమలహాసనా  అనగా మలినం లేని స్వచ్ఛమైన నవ్వు కలది. మాడినీ అనగా  శివునిలో ప్రియమైనది. శివుడిని మురుడేశ్వరుడి గా కొలుస్తారు.  ఆయన భార్య మాడిని.  బ్రామరీ  అనగా భ్రమరాంబ. భ్రామరీ అంటే తిరిగేది/ తిప్పేది. ప్రపంచాన్ని తిప్పితూ తిప్పు.. చివరికి తిరగడానికి వీలు లేని అంటే ‘స్థానువు ‘ (శివుడిలోకి) లోకి ఐక్యం చేసే శక్తి ఆవిడే.  శివుడు మల్లికార్జునుడిగా అవతారమెత్తి శ్రీశైలంలో ఒక మల్లె పువ్వుగా మారిపోయారుట, అప్పుడు ఆవిడ బ్రామరి అంటే నల్ల తుమ్మెదగా మారి ఆయన చుట్టూ తిరిగిందిట. ఈ రోజుకీ శ్రీశైలములో భ్రమరాంబ గుడి వెనుక తుమ్మెదల రొద వినపడుతుంది.  ఇక్కడ ఆవిడని భ్రమరముగా పోలిస్తే శివతాండవ స్త్రోత్రములో మాత్రం ” రసప్రవాహ మాధురీ విజృంభణా మధువ్రతం ” రసప్రవాహముగా ఉన్న ఆవిడ ముఖము దగ్గరకు విజృంభించిన మధువ్రతము అంటే తుమ్మదగా ఆ పరమేశ్వరుడు వచ్చాడుట."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Cụm thi đua số 1, gồm các Sở GD&ĐT 5 thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương: TPHCM, Hà Nội, Hải Phòng, Cần Thơ và Đà Nẵng. Báo cáo tại Hội nghị, ông Nguyễn Văn Hiếu, Giám đốc Sở GD&ĐT TPHCM, với vai trò là cụm trưởng cho biết, năm học 2021-2022 là năm thứ ba, ngành GD&ĐT tiếp tục triển khai các biện pháp phòng chống dịch COVID-19 với những tác động không nhỏ tới công tác dạy và học. Với sự nỗ lực, cố gắng, sáng tạo, chủ động ứng dụng công nghệ thông tin và truyền thông, sử dụng internet trong công việc để phù hợp với tình hình thực tế đã đảm bảo công việc được thông suốt, không bị gián đoạn và đạt được những kết quả nhất định. Về đề xuất, lãnh đạo Sở GD&ĐT TPHCM thông tin ý kiến của các Sở trong cụm, hiện nay căn cứ theo khoản 1, điều 7, Quy chế tuyển sinh THCS, THPT ban hành kèm theo Thông tư số 03 của Bộ GD&ĐT ban hành năm 2022 quy định về chế độ tuyển thẳng vào lớp 10 chưa tạo được sự tự chủ trong tổ chức tuyển sinh của các địa phương. Trong đó, các cơ sở giáo dục chưa có sự bình đẳng, một số trường chuyên thuộc đại học quy định chế độ tuyển thẳng đối với học sinh đạt giải cao trong kỳ thi học sinh giỏi cấp thành phố dù điều này không được quy định trong quy chế tuyển sinh. Trong khi đó, theo quy định hiện hành, các đối tượng được tuyển thẳng vào lớp 10","answer":"THPT gồm học sinh trường phổ thông dân tộc nội trú; học sinh là người dân tộc rất ít người; học sinh khuyết tật; học sinh đạt giải cấp quốc gia và quốc tế về văn hóa, văn nghệ, thể dục thể thao, cuộc thi khoa học, kỹ thuật cấp quốc gia dành cho học sinh THCS và THPT. Do đó, sở GD&ĐT các địa phương đề nghị Bộ GD&ĐT sửa đổi, bổ sung khoản 1, điều 7 Quy chế tuyển sinh theo hướng giao quyền tự chủ, tự chịu trách nhiệm cho địa phương quy định đối tượng tuyển thẳng vào lớp 10. Cụm thi đua số 1 cũng kiến nghị Bộ GD&ĐT tổ chức thi học sinh giỏi quốc gia đối với các môn ngoại ngữ như tiếng Nhật, Hàn, Trung Quốc tại 5 thành phố lớn vì ở những nơi này đã triển khai dạy học các môn nói trên. Đặc biệt, các địa phương còn kiến nghị Bộ sớm công bố phương án thi tốt nghiệp THPT đối với học sinh theo học chương trình Giáo dục phổ thông 2018 (năm học 2022-2023 bắt đầu triển khai ở lớp 10), thực hiện từ năm 2025 để các sở GD&ĐT thuận lợi trong việc xây dựng các hoạt động giáo dục trong nhà trường. Ngoài ra các Sở trong cụm thi đua số 1 còn kiến nghị một số nội dung khác liên quan đến chính sách quản lý với đội ngũ cán bộ quản lý và giáo viên người Việt, giáo viên người nước ngoài ở các trường có yếu tố nước ngoài. Cũng như cần có điều khoản chuyển tiếp để đảm bảo quyền lợi của học sinh đã theo học các chương trình trước đó, điều chỉnh tỷ lệ học sinh Việt Nam tại các cơ sở giáo dục có vốn đầu tư nước ngoài, bổ sung quy định đối với thay đổi nhà đầu tư trong lĩnh vực giáo dục... Nguồn: https://tienphong.vn/5-thanh-pho-kien-nghi-bo-gd-dt-som-cong-bo-phuong-an-thi-tot-nghiep-theo-ch...Nguồn: https://tienphong.vn/5-thanh-pho-kien-nghi-bo-gd-dt-som-cong-bo-phuong-an-thi-tot-nghiep-theo-chuong-trinh-moi-post1457821.tpo"},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਾਜਲ ਅਗਰਵਾਲ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ","answer":"ਕਾਜਲ ਅਗਰਵਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਤੋਰ ਤੇ ਤੇਲੁਗੂ ਅਤੇ ਤਾਮਿਲ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਕਾਜਲ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਨਾਮਵਰ ਹਸਤੀਆਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਹੈ। ਕਾਜਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਟੇਜ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲੈਂਦੀ ਸੀ। ਕਾਜਲ ਬਰਾਂਡ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਟਸ ਲਈ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਹਸਤੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸਨੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਲਈ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ।ਕਾਜਲ  ਅਗਰਵਾਲ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ 2004 ਦੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਕਿਉਂ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਨਾ... ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਫਿਲਮ  ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਕਲਿਆਣਮ 2007 ਵਿੱਚ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਈ। ਉਸੇ ਸਾਲ, ਉਸਨੇ ਬਾਕਸ ਆਫਿਸ ਹਿੱਟ ਚੰਦਮਾਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਕੀਤਾ, ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣ ਮਿਲੀ। 2009 ਦੀ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਗਲਪ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਫਿਲਮ ਮਗਧੀਰਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਦੇ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਮੋੜ ਆਇਆ, ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਲੋਚਨਾਤਮਕ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਹੋਈ। ਇਹ ਹੁਣ ਤੱਕ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਕਮਾਈ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਊਥ ਫਿਲਮਫੇਅਰ ਅਵਾਰਡਾਂ ਸਮੇਤ ਕਈ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਸਮਾਰੋਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਸਰਵੋਤਮ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਲਈ ਨਾਮਜ਼ਦਗੀਆਂ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ।ਉਸਨੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਡਾਰਲਿੰਗ (2010), ਬ੍ਰਿੰਦਾਵਨਮ (2010), ਮਿਸਟਰ ਪਰਫੈਕਟ (2011), ਬਿਜ਼ਨਸਮੈਨ (2012), ਨਾਇਕ (2013), ਬਾਦਸ਼ਾਹ (2013), ਗੋਵਿੰਦੁਦੂ ਅੰਦਾਰਿਵਡੇਲੇ (2014), ਟੈਂਪਰ (2015) ਅਤੇ ਖੈਦੀ ਨੰਬਰ 150 (2017) ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ। ਕਾਜਲ ਨੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਤਾਮਿਲ ਪ੍ਰੋਜੈਕਟਾਂ ਨਾਨ ਮਹਾਨ ਅੱਲਾ (2010), ਮਾਤਰਾਨ (2012), ਥੁਪੱਕੀ (2012), ਜਿੱਲਾ (2014), ਵਿਵੇਗਮ (2017) ਅਤੇ ਮਰਸਲ (2017) ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਉਸਨੇ ਸਿੰਘਮ (2011) ਨਾਲ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕੀਤੀ, ਜੋ ਇੱਕ ਹਿੱਟ ਰਹੀ, ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਫਿਲਮ ਸਪੈਸ਼ਲ 26 (2013) ਵੀ ਬਾਕਸ ਆਫਿਸ 'ਤੇ ਸਫਲ ਰਹੀ।2020 ਵਿੱਚ, ਮੈਡਮ ਤੁਸਾਦ ਸਿੰਗਾਪੁਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਜਲ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਮੋਮ ਦੀ ਮੂਰਤ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ, ਅਜਿਹਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਉਹ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਸੀ।== ਜੀਵਨ ==ਅਗਰਵਾਲ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਬੰਬਈ (ਅਜੋਕੇ ਮੁੰਬਈ) ਵਿੱਚ ਵਸੇ ਇੱਕ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਸੁਮਨ ਅਗਰਵਾਲ, ਟੈਕਸਟਾਈਲ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਉੱਦਮੀ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਵਿਨੈ ਅਗਰਵਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਮਿਠਾਈ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਜਲ ਦੀ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧਕ ਵੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਭੈਣ ਨਿਸ਼ਾ ਅਗਰਵਾਲ ਵੀ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਅਤੇ ਤਾਮਿਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਭੈਣ ਨਿਸ਼ਾ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇਚਾ (ਮੈਨੇਜਿੰਗ ਡਾਇਰੈਕਟਰ ਗੋਲਡਜ਼ ਜਿਮ, ਏਸ਼ੀਆ) ਨਾਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸੇਂਟ ਐਨਜ਼ ਹਾਈ ਸਕੂਲ, ਫੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਜੈ ਹਿੰਦ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਪ੍ਰੀ-ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਪੂਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਿਸ਼ਨਚੰਦ ਚੇਲਾਰਾਮ ਕਾਲਜ ਤੋਂ ਮਾਰਕੀਟਿੰਗ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੁਹਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਮਾਸ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤੀ। ਆਪਣੇ ਵਧਦੇ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ MBA ਦੇ ਸੁਪਨਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਲਦੇ ਹੋਏ, ਉਹ ਜਲਦੀ ਹੀ ਪੋਸਟ-ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਸ਼ਨ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਇਰਾਦਾ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ।== ਫਿਲਮ-ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰਜ ==ਕਾਜਲ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਫਿਲਮੀ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ 2004 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਕਿਓਂ....।ਹੋ ਗਯਾ ਨਾ ਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਕਾਜਲ ਨੇ 2009 ਵਿੱਚ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਕਲ੍ਯਾਨਅਮ ਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਾਲ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ। ਕਾਜਲ ਨੇ ਚੰਦਾਮਾਮਾ (2007) ਅਤੇ ਮਗਧੀਰਾ (2009) ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਿਹਨਾਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਮਿਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਬਣਾਈ।== ਸਨਮਾਨ ==ਫਿਲਮਫ਼ੇਅਰ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਲਈ ਕਾਜਲ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਨਾਮਜ਼ਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਕਾਜਲ 2011 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਪਿਸ ਆਈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੇ 'ਸਿੰਘਮ' ਫਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਹਿਮ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। 2013 ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਅਗਲੀ ਫਿਲਮ 'ਸਪੈਸ਼ਲ 26' ਆਈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਜਲ ਨੇ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ।== ਹਵਾਲੇ ==== ਬਾਹਰੀ ਲਿੰਕ ==ਕਾਜਲ ਅਗਰਵਾਲ, ਇੰਟਰਨੈੱਟ ਮੂਵੀ ਡੈਟਾਬੇਸ ’ਤੇ"},{"question":"Бакай Семетей менен көрүшүп эң биринчи кай жакка алып барат?а) Каныкей Манастын сөөгүн душмандан жашырып койгон Эчкиликтин Кара зоосуна алып баратб) Чоң атасы Жакыптын үйүнөв) Көбөш менен Абыкегег) Бурулча менен Күлчорого","answer":"Туура жообу:б) Чоң атасы Жакыптын үйүнө"},{"question":"Турапов Керимберди Ырсалиевичтин өмүр баяны кандай?","answer":"1978-ж. Ош мамлекеттик мызкалык окуу жайынын ырдоо бөлүмүндө, Б. Бейшеналиева атындагы Кыргыз Мамлекеттик искусство институтунда окуган (1981—1986).1985-жылдан Кыргыз телерадиокорпорациясынын академиялык симфониялык оркестринде, 1990-жылдан А. Малдыбаев атындагы Кыргыз мамлекеттик опера жана балет театрында солист,2002—2008-жылдары Кыргыз улуттук консерваториясында окутуучу,2000—2010-жылдары Т. Сатылганов атындагы Кыргыз улуттук филармониянын башкы директору,2010—2014-жылдары А. Жумакматова атындагы Чоң академиялык симфниялык оркестрдин солисти болуп иштеген.Дүйнөлүк ысымдагы композиторлор Ж. Вердинин «Травиатасынан» Альфредонун, П. Чайковскийдин «Евгений Онегининен» Ленскийдин, Ж. Вердинин «Риголеттосунан»Герцогдун, А. Малдыбаев, В.Власов, В. Ференин «Айчүрөк», «Манас» операларындагы башкы ролдорду да аткарат. Ал кыргыз, орус композиторлорунун ырларын, романстарын чебер аткарат. Концерттерде атактуу ырчылар А. Соловьяненко, А. Днишев,М. Ташматов ж.б. менен бирге ырдаган. КМШ өлкөлөрүнүн, Исландия, Корея, Германия, Монголия, Франция, Бельгиянын, Түркия, Кытай, Пакистан, Индия ж.б. чет өлкөлөрдүн концерттик залдарында ырдап, бейтааныш угуучуларга аткаруучулук чеберчилиги менен таанылат. Турапов обон да чыгарат. «Туулган жерди сагындым», «Махабат вальсы» ж.б. обондору бар."},{"question":"வினா: அரசியல் தத்துவத்தின் தந்தை என அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்? மேலும், அரசியல் தத்துவம் என்பதன் பொருள் என்ன என்பதைப் பற்றி விரிவாக விளக்கவும்.","answer":"விடை : அரசியல் தத்துவத்தின் தந்தை என அழைக்கப்படுபவர் பிளேட்டோ.  பிளேட்டோ பெரும் செல்வாக்குள்ள கிரேக்கத் தத்துவஞானியாவார். இவர் சாக்கிரட்டீசின் சீடர், அரிஸ்டாட்டிலின் குரு. பிளாட்டோ தலைசிறந்த கிரேக்க தத்துவஞானி, கணிதவியல் வல்லுனர். சாக்ரடீஸின் மாணவரான இவர் தத்துவத் தர்க்கங்களை எழுதியுள்ளார். இவர் மேற்கு உலகின் முதல் கல்விக் கூடமாக ஏதென்ஸ் நகரில் கல்விக்கூடம் நிறுவினார். இவர் தனது ஆதரவாளர் சாக்கிரட்டீஸ் மற்றும் தனது மாணவர் அரிஸ்டாட்டில் உடன் இணைந்து மேற்குலகின் தத்துவம் மற்றும் அறிவியலுக்கான அடிக்கல்லை நாட்டினார். அரசியல் தத்துவம்  என்பது நாடு, அரசு, சமூகம், குடிமக்கள், ஆட்சிமுறை, சட்டம் போன்ற அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் அவை சார்ந்த வழக்குப் பொருள்கள் குறித்த கருத்தியல் சுருக்கங்களில்  ஈடுபடும் தத்துவப் பிரிவு ஆகும்.அரசியல் தத்துவம் அல்லது அரசியல் கோட்பாடு என்பது அரசாங்கத்தின் தத்துவ ஆய்வு ஆகும், பொது முகவர்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவனங்களின் தன்மை, நோக்கம் மற்றும் சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மை மற்றும் அவற்றுக்கிடையேயான உறவுகள் பற்றிய கேள்விகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும். அதன் தலைப்புகளில் அரசியல், சுதந்திரம், நீதி, சொத்து, உரிமைகள், சட்டம் மற்றும் அதிகாரத்தால் சட்டங்களை அமல்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்: அவை என்ன, அவை தேவைப்பட்டால், ஒரு அரசாங்கத்தை சட்டப்பூர்வமாக்குவது எது, அது என்ன உரிமைகள் மற்றும் சுதந்திரங்களை பாதுகாக்க வேண்டும், எந்த வடிவத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டும் சட்டம் என்றால் என்ன, சட்டப்பூர்வமான அரசாங்கத்திற்கு குடிமக்கள் என்ன கடமைகளைச் செய்ய வேண்டும், ஏதேனும் இருந்தால், அது சட்டப்பூர்வமாக தூக்கியெறியப்படும் போது. அடையாளம், கலாச்சாரம், பாலியல், இனம், செல்வம், மனித-மனிதநேயமற்ற உறவுகள், நெறிமுறைகள், மதம் மற்றும் பல.அரசியல் அறிவியல், அரசியலின் அறிவியல் ஆய்வு, பொதுவாக ஒருமையில் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, ஆனால் பிரெஞ்சு மற்றும் ஸ்பானிஷ் மொழிகளில் பன்மை (அறிவியல் அரசியல் மற்றும், முறையே) பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, ஒருவேளை ஒழுக்கத்தின் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட தன்மையின் பிரதிபலிப்பாகும்.அரசியல் தத்துவம் என்பது தத்துவத்தின் ஒரு கிளையாகும், ஆனால் இது அரசியல் அறிவியலின் ஒரு முக்கிய பங்கையும் கொண்டுள்ளது, இதில் வரலாற்று ரீதியாக அரசியல் சிந்தனையின் வரலாறு மற்றும் சமகால அரசியல் கோட்பாடு (நெறிமுறை அரசியல் கோட்பாடு முதல் பல்வேறு விமர்சன அணுகுமுறைகள் வரை) ஆகிய இரண்டிலும் வலுவான கவனம் செலுத்தப்படுகிறது. ."},{"question":"Rangarira ndima iri pasi apa uye ipapo pindura mubvunzo gare gare mumutauro mumwe chetewo sechikamu:  Kupfuura: Nguva yemberi yenyika yezvinhu zvipenyu neyezvokuvakisa pasi inogona kufungidzirwa zvichibva pamigumisiro inofungidzirwa yezvinhu zvinoverengeka zvinopesvedzera kwenguva refu. Izvi zvinosanganisira makemikari ari pamusoro pePasi, mwero wokutonhora kwemukati mepasi, kudyidzana kwegravitation nezvimwe zvinhu zviri muSolar System, uye kuwedzera kunoramba kuchiita chiedza cheZuva. Chinhu chisina chokwadi mukuwedzera uku ndiko kupesvedzera kuri kuitika kwetekinoroji yakaunzwa nevanhu, yakadai seinjiniya yemamiriro okunze, iyo inogona kukonzera kuchinja kukuru papasi. Kuparadzwa kwazvino kweHolocene kuri kukonzerwa netekinoroji uye miuyo yacho inogona kupfuurira kwamakore anosvika mamirioni mashanu. Nenzira, ruzivo rwokugadzira zvinhu runogona kuguma nokutsakatika kworudzi rwomunhu, kuchisiya nyika ichidzokera zvishoma nezvishoma kumwero wokushanduka-shanduka kunononoka kunokonzerwa bedzi nemaitiro omuzvarirwo enguva refu. Mumakore anopfuura mazana emamiriyoni amakore, zviitiko zvomudenga zvisingaenzaniswi zvinomutsa ngozi yenyika yose nokuda kwebiosphere, iyo inogona kuguma nokutsakatika kukuru. Izvi zvinosanganisira kukanganiswa nemapoka enyeredzi dzinonzi makometi kana kuti asteroid, uye mukana wokuputika kwenyeredzi huru, inonzi supernova, iri munharaunda yemakore chiedza 100 kubva kuZuva. Zvimwe zviitiko zvikuru zvenyika zvinofanotaurwa zviri nyore. Dzidziso yaMilankovitch inofanotaura kuti nyika icharamba ichipfuura nenguva dzegirazi kutozosvikira nguva yegirazi yeQuaternary yapera. Nguva idzi dzinokonzerwa nokusiyana-siyana kwe eccentricity, axial tilt, uye precession yeEarth orbit. Sechikamu chemuitiro unopfuurira we supercontinent, plate tectonics zvichida ichaguma ne supercontinent mumakore 250<unk>350 mamiriyoni. Pane imwe nguva mumakore anotevera 1.5<unk>4.5 bhiriyoni, axial tilt yePasi inogona kutanga kuchinja kuchinja, nekuchinja kwe axial tilt kusvika ku90°. Chiedza cheZuva chichawedzera zvishoma nezvishoma, zvichiita kuti mwaranzi yezuva inosvika kuPasi iwedzere. Ikoku kuchaguma nomwero wakakwirira wokushatiswa kwemaminerari esilicate, uko kuchaparira kuderera kwomwero wecarbon dioxide mumhepo yakapoteredza pasi. Mumakore anenge mamiriyoni 600 kubva zvino, mwero we...  Mubvunzo: Mumakore mangani pasi richapinzwa nezuva?","answer":"Ndima yawapa haina ruzivo rwekuti Nyika ichafukidzwa nezuva riini. Inokurukura zvinhu zvakasiyana-siyana zvine chekuita neramangwana rePasi, kusanganisira shanduko yeaxial tilt, kuwedzera kwemwaranzi yezuva, uye kushatiswa kwemaminerari silicate, asi haipe nguva yekuti Nyika yakafukidzwa nezuva.Naizvozvo, zvichibva paruzivo rwuri mundima, hapana mhinduro chaiyo kumubvunzo wekuti Nyika ichafukidzwa riini nezuva."},{"question":"रञ्जना लिपि र परम्परागत नेवारी सुलेखन बीचको सम्बन्धको अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्। यो लिपिले सुलेख अभिव्यक्तिको कलात्मक पक्षलाई कसरी बढाउँछ?","answer":"रञ्जना लिपि परम्परागत नेवारी सुलेखनसँग जटिल रूपमा जोडिएको छ, जसले यसको अलंकृत स्ट्रोकहरू र कर्भहरूको साथ कलात्मक अभिव्यक्तिहरू बढाउँछ। क्यालिग्राफरहरूले दृश्यात्मक रूपमा आश्चर्यजनक र सांस्कृतिक रूपमा समृद्ध कलाकृतिहरू सिर्जना गर्न लिपि प्रयोग गर्छन्।"},{"question":"*نبي لقب بكليم الله ؟","answer":"سيدنا موسى عليه السلام"},{"question":"Mengapakah negara kita menjadi sasaran Jepun setelah dikenakan sekatan ekonomi oleh pihak bersekutu?","answer":"Skema Jawapan:F1 Memenuhi keperluan ekonomiF2 Kepentingan strategik ketenteraan"},{"question":"निम्नलिखित लेख के आधार पर नीचे दिये हुए प्रश्न का उत्तर दें: प्रारंभिक मध्ययुगीन काल में, ईसाई धर्म, इस्लाम, यहूदी धर्म और पारसी धर्म ने भारत के दक्षिणी और पश्चिमी तटों पर जड़ें जमा लीं। मध्य एशिया से मुस्लिम सेनाओं ने भारत के उत्तरी मैदानों पर लगातार अत्याचार किया, अंततः दिल्ली सल्तनत की स्थापना हुई और उत्तर भारत को मध्यकालीन इस्लाम साम्राज्य में मिला लिया गया। १५ वीं शताब्दी में, विजयनगर साम्राज्य ने दक्षिण भारत में एक लंबे समय तक चलने वाली समग्र हिंदू संस्कृति बनाई। पंजाब में सिख धर्म की स्थापना हुई। धीरे-धीरे ब्रिटिश ईस्ट इंडिया कंपनी के शासन का विस्तार हुआ, जिसने भारत को औपनिवेशिक अर्थव्यवस्था में बदल दिया तथा अपनी संप्रभुता को भी मजबूत किया।ब्रिटिश राज शासन १८५८ में शुरू हुआ। धीरे धीरे एक प्रभावशाली राष्ट्रवादी आंदोलन शुरू हुआ जिसे अहिंसक विरोध के लिए जाना गया और ब्रिटिश शासन को समाप्त करने का प्रमुख कारक बन गया। १९४७ में ब्रिटिश भारतीय साम्राज्य को दो स्वतंत्र प्रभुत्वों में विभाजित किया गया, भारतीय अधिराज्य तथा पाकिस्तान अधिराज्य, जिन्हे धर्म के आधार पर विभाजित किया गया।प्रश्न: इस लेख को योग्य शीर्षक दें: ","answer":"इस लेख का एक योग्य शीर्षक है: \\"भारत में मध्ययुगीन धार्मिक और सामाजिक परिवर्तन: धर्मों के प्रभाव और आंदोलनों का महत्व\\""},{"question":"Fanambarana malaza inona no neken'ny zanatany Amerikana Telo ambin'ny folo tamin'ny 1776 mba hanambara ny fahaleovantenany tamin'i Grande-Bretagne?","answer":" Ny fanambarana malaza navoakan'ny zanatany Amerikana Telo ambin'ny folo tamin'ny taona 1776 mba hanambarana ny fahaleovantenany tamin'i Grande-Bretagne dia ny Fanambarana ny fahaleovantenan'i Etazonia."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Nabi Cismaaciil Cs Meesha Uu Ku Aasan Yahay ?","answer":"Jawaab: Nabi Cismaaciil Cs Wuxu Ku Aasan Yahay Magaalada Makkah."},{"question":"புழு முட்டையிலிருந்து வெளிவர ஆகும் நாட்கள் எத்தனை ?","answer":"வெறுமனே, பட்டுப்புழுக்கள் 12 மணிநேர சூரிய ஒளியையும், ஒரு நாளைக்கு 12 மணிநேர இருளையும், 23-28 டிகிரி செல்சியஸ் வெப்பநிலையையும், அதே போல் 85-90% ஈரப்பதத்தையும் அனுபவிக்கும். இந்த நிலைமைகளின் கீழ், உங்கள் முட்டைகள் 7-10 நாட்களுக்குள் குஞ்சு பொரிக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Mene RANDA?","answer":"Yana nufin wani ma’ajjiyar ruwa ne damin a tara shi saboda amfani ko kuma Sha."},{"question":"Лимфосистема тууралуу биз биле турган дагы манилүү маалыматтардан айтып бересиңби?","answer":"1.\\tЛимфалык система, кан айлануу системасындай  айланып туруу жөндөмдүүлүгү жок. Ал бир багытта гана кыймылдайт. Ошол себептен, эгерде лимфанын иштешинде кандайдыр бир көйгөй жаралса анда ден-соолугубузда да: шишиктер, варикоз, иммунитеттин төмөндөшү, теринин балбырашы жана целлюлит сыяктуу оорулар пайда болот. 2.\\tЛимфанын саламаты жана кыймылы, жакынкы жайгашкан булчуңдардын жыйрылышынан жана лимфа түтүкчөлөрундөгү артка кетүүгө тоскоол жаратып турган клапандын иштешинен көз каранды.Лимфанын кыймылы жай темпте, билинбеген басым менен жылып отурат. Кээде токтоп туруу менен жүрөт."},{"question":"Skapa ett exempel på en triviafråga.","answer":"Vad heter den största (inte högsta) bergskedjan? Anderna – 7 000 kilometer lång och 6 962 meter hög."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 かばんの会社が、水に浮く 材料を使ってリュックサックを作りました。水の中で抱くようにして持つと、ライフジャケットのようになって体が浮きます。会社に通うときなどにこのリュックサックを使うと、突然の雨の災害のときにも役に立つと言っています。東京にある会社は、駅やコンビニなど4万ぐらいの場所に、スマートフォンなどの充電器を置いて貸しています。災害のときは、1人48時間まで無料で充電器を貸していて、今までに20ぐらいの災害で役に立ちました。この会社は、電気が止まっているときでも、充電器を貸すことができる場所を作り始めています。会社の人は「いつも使っているものを災害のときにも安心して使うことができるようにしたいです」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- 浮く: 1）水の上にある。沈んでいたものが、水の上に出る。うかぶ。2）地面から離れて、空中にある。3）表面に現れる。4）心がはずむ。5）お金や時間の余りが出る。6）しっかりとくっついていない。7）相手にされなくなる。- 材料: 1）物を作るもとになるもの。多くは、元の形や性質が残っている場合にいう。2）研究・表現などのもとになるもの。- リュックサック: 1）山登りやハイキングなどのとき、食べ物や着る物などを入れて背負うふくろ。リュック。- 抱く: 1）腕でかかえて持つ。2）ある考えや気持ちを持つ。3）温めてひなをかえす。- 浮き: 1）急に。思いがけなく。- 突然: 1）台風・地震・洪水・火事などによる災難。- 災害: 1）食料品や日用品が、手軽にいつでも買えるように開いている、小型のスーパー。- コンビニ: 1）パソコンのようなはたらきを取り入れた携帯電話。スマホ。- スマートフォン: 1）蓄電池に電気をたくわえること。2）活力をたくわえること。- 充電: 1）入れ物。2）道具。3）才能。4）生きるためのはたらきをするもの。- 器: 1）料金のいらないこと。ただ。"},{"question":"Fáwẹ́lì àìránmúpè àyanupè ààrin perese ni...","answer":"[ɛ], tàbí ẹ."},{"question":"પ્રશ્ન: ઇલેક્ટ્રોનિક ફંડ ટ્રાન્સફર એક્ટ કાયદો ક્યારે બન્યો? જવાબ:","answer":"૧૯૭૮"},{"question":"ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਸਤਰੀਕਰਨ ਕੀ ਹੈ ?ਜਾਂਜਾਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਪਦਮ ।","answer":"ਸਮਾਜ ਅੱਡ-ਅੱਡ ਜਾਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਚ-ਨੀਚ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਿਤ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ । ਇਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਸਤਰੀਕਰਨ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Qué presidente recibió el mayor número de votos del Colegio Electoral de la historia?","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es determinar qué presidente recibió el mayor número de votos del Colegio Electoral en la historia."},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください：日本のいろいろな所で急に暑くなりました。16日と17日は、7月と同じぐらい暑くなった所もありました。去年6月に40.1°Cになった群馬県伊勢崎市は、熱中症にならないように、暑いときに誰でも休むことができる場所を図書館などに用意しています。今年は、去年より1か月半ぐらい早い16日から利用できるようにしました。専門家は「人の体は、暑さに慣れるまでに2週間以上かかります。このため、今の季節は少し暑いだけでも熱中症になる危険があります。新型コロナウイルスが広がって、長い間あまり運動をしなかった人は、熱中症になる危険が高いです」と言っています。水をよく飲んだり、エアコンで部屋を28°C以下にしたりして、熱中症にならないように気をつけてください。","answer":"急な暑さ対策で熱中症を予防しよう"},{"question":"別名をマージービートという、ビートルズなどに代表される音楽を、発生した都市の名前から何サウンドというでしょう？","answer":"リバプールサウンドです。"},{"question":"Ìgbẹ́jọ́ Nnamdi Kanu ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ nílé ẹjọ́ tó ga jùlọ l'Abuja","answer":"Igbẹjọ olori ẹgbẹ ajijagbara Ipob ilẹ Igbo, Nnamdi Kanu n lọ lọwọ nileẹjọ to ga julọ ni Naijiria niluu Abuja.Mike Ozekhome, SAN to jẹ agbẹjọro Kanu n bẹ ileẹjọ lati fun un ni beeli.Ẹbẹ keji ti agbẹjọro agba Ozekhome n bẹ ileẹjọ ni wi pe ki ileẹjọ pe ki wọn gbe Kanu kuro ni ahamọ ileeṣẹ DSS ki wọn si gbe e lọ si ọgba ẹwọn to wa ni Kuje l'Abuja.Ẹwẹ, ile ẹjọ kotẹmilọrun ti kọkọ dajọ tẹlẹ pe ki Kanu maa lọ lalaafia ti wọn si fagile gbogbo ẹsun ti ijọba fi kan an.Koda ile ẹjọ kotẹmilọrun tun sọ pe o lodin lati fi Kanu si ahamọ.Amọ, ile ẹjọ kotẹmilọrun yii kan naa ni ijọba apapọ ti lọ gba aṣẹ lati teṣiwaju fifi olori ẹgbẹ Ipob si ahamọ titi ti ile ẹjọ to ga julọ yoo fi bẹrẹ igbẹjọ rẹ.O yẹ ki ile ẹjọ to ga julọ ṣe igbẹjọ ni ọjọ kẹrinla oṣu Keṣan an to lọ, ṣugbọn igbẹjọ naa ko waye.Ni ọjọ kọkanla oṣu Karun un ti igbẹjọ Kanu waye kẹyin ni ileẹjọ sun igbẹjọ siwaju lẹyin ti agbẹjọro ijọba Tijjani A. Gazali tako igbẹjọ ẹbẹ meji ti agbẹjọro Kanu n bẹ ileẹjọ.Agbẹjọro Gazali bẹ ileẹjọ lati fun oun laye lati fesi si ohun ti agbẹjọro Kanu n beere lọwọ ileẹjọ.Agbẹjọro Kanu, Ozekhome SAN, ni tiẹ sọ fun ileẹjọ pe oun ṣetan fun igbẹjọ nigba naa lọhun, amọ awọn adajọ sọ pe ko le ṣe igbẹjọ mọ lọjọ naa.Ozekhome SAN tun bẹ ileẹjọ lati ṣe igbẹjọ naa laipẹ tori ipo ti ko dara ti Kanu wa ni ahamọ ileeṣẹ DSS."},{"question":"১৯৫২ সালের ভাষা আন্দোলন পরবর্তী সকল আন্দোলনের প্রেরণার উৎস হিসেবে কাজ করেছিল। ব্যাখ্যা করো।","answer":"১৯৫২ সালের ভাষা আন্দোলন পরবর্তী সকল আন্দোলনের প্রেরণার উৎস হিসেবে কাজ করেছিল।১৯৫২ সালের মহান ভাষা আন্দোলনের মধ্য দিয়ে বাঙালি জাতীয়তাবোধ জাগ্রত হয়। এ আন্দোলনে বাঙালি জাতির স্বকীয় জাতিসত্তা এবং স্বাধিকার আদায়ের ঐক্যানুভূতির প্রকাশ ঘটে। এর ফলশ্রুতিতে পরবর্তীতে বিভিন্ন আন্দোলন-সংগ্রামের মাধ্যমে ১৯৭১ সালে বাংলাদেশ স্বাধীন ও সার্বভৌম রাষ্ট্র হিসেবে আত্মপ্রকাশ করে। এর ফলে ১৯৫৪ সালের নির্বাচনে মুসলিম লীগের শোচনীয় পরাজয় ঘটেছিল। পরবর্তীতে ১৯৬২ সালে শিক্ষা আন্দোলন, ঐতিহাসিক ছয় দফা ও ১১ দফা সংগ্রাম, আগরতলা মামলাবিরোধী আন্দোলন, ঊনসত্তরের গণঅভ্যুত্থান, সত্তরের নির্বাচনে জনতার রায়, একাত্তরের অসহযোগ আন্দোলন- এভাবেই ধাপে ধাপে পরিণতি লাভ করে বাঙালির স্বাধিকার সংগ্রাম। স্বাধিকারের দাবি রূপান্তরিত হয় স্বাধীনতার সংগ্রামে।মহান ভাষা আন্দোলন মাতৃভাষার মর্যাদা রক্ষার জন্য সূচিত হলেও এর মূল চেতনাটি ছিল আত্মমর্যাদাবোধ ও আপন অধিকারের। ভাষা আন্দোলনের সেই শপথ যুগে যুগে বাঙালিকে আলোকবর্তিকার মতো পথ দেখায়, সংকটকালে প্রেরণা জোগায়। সর্বশেষ এই ভাষা আন্দোলনের চেতনাকে পুঁজি করেই দীর্ঘ নয় মাসব্যাপী রক্তক্ষয়ী মুক্তিযুদ্ধের মধ্য দিয়ে অর্জিত হয় স্বাধীনতা।"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: 7 thói quen của phụ huynh có thể giúp con thành tàiĐoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Với quyết tâm giành chiến thắng, đội tuyển U18 nữ Việt Nam nhập cuộc đầy tự tin và tràn sang tấn công phủ đầu đối thủ say sau tiếng còi khai cuộc. Chỉ 5 phút đầu trận đấu, U18 nữ Việt Nam đã có bàn thắng mở tỷ số. Từ tình huống Như Hoa nhận bóng trước vạch 16m50, cô tung cú sút đánh bại thủ môn Campuchia. Chỉ 1 phút sau, nhận bóng từ đường thọc khe của đồng đội, đội trưởng Minh Chuyên thoát xuống đối diện thủ môn Campuchia và dễ dàng nhân đôi cách biệt cho U18 nữ Việt Nam. Đến phút thứ 9, U18 nữ Việt Nam được hưởng quả phạt ở khoảng cách 20m so với khung thành của U18 nữ Campuchia. Hải Yến đã có pha đá phạt chính xác, nâng tỷ số lên 3-0 cho các cô gái Việt Nam. Những phút sau đó, U18 nữ Việt Nam liên tiếp có thêm 2 bàn thắng nhờ công của Phương Anh (phút 30) và Minh Chuyên (phút 40). Hiệp 1 khép lại với tỷ số 5-0 nghiêng về phía các cô gái Việt Nam. Sau giờ nghỉ, thế trận vẫn hoàn toàn thuộc về các học trò của HLV Akira Ijiri khi chỉ 2 phút sau khi hiệp 2 bắt đầu, U18 nữ Việt Nam có bàn thắng thứ 6 nhờ công của cầu thủ vào sân thay người Ngọc Anh. Tiếp tục kiểm soát thế trận, các học trò của ông Akira Ijiri có bàn thắng thứ 7 ở phút 58 do công của Phương Anh. Dù tạo ra nhiều cơ hội nguy hiểm trong suốt thời gian còn lại của trận đấu nhưng U18 nữ Việt Nam vẫn không có thêm bàn thắng nào. Với chiến thắng 7-0 trước U18 nữ Campuchia, đội tuyển U18 nữ Việt Nam tiếp tục giữ vững ngôi đầu bảng A với 9 điểm. Trận đấu tiếp theo, các cô gái Việt Nam sẽ gặp đội tuyển U18 nữ Thái Lan vào lúc 15 giờ 30 phút ngày 30-7. TUẤN ĐIỆP","answer":"Kết quả Giải U18 nữ Đông Nam Á: U18 nữ Việt Nam thắng đậm U18 Campuchia"},{"question":"Trong một cửa hàng bánh kẹo, người ta đóng gói kẹo thành các loại: mỗi gói có 10 cái kẹo; mỗi hộp có 10 gói; mỗi thùng có 10 hộp. Một người mua 9 thùng, 9 hộp và 9 gói kẹo. Hỏi người đó đã mua tất cả bao nhiêu cái kẹo.","answer":"Đáp ánSố cái kẹo có trong 1 hộp là: 10 x 10 = 100 (cái kẹo)Số cái kẹo có trong 1 thùng là: 100 x 10 = 1 000 (cái kẹo)"},{"question":"ब्रेन ड्रेनले नेपाललाई विदेशी लगानी र सहकार्यको गन्तव्यको रूपमा हेर्ने धारणालाई कसरी असर गर्छ?","answer":"ब्रेन ड्रेनले नेपाललाई विदेशी लगानी र सहकार्यका लागि गन्तव्यको रूपमा हेर्ने धारणालाई असर गर्छ। दक्ष पेशेवरहरूको प्रस्थानले देशको कार्यबल र विशेषज्ञताको बारेमा सम्भावित लगानीकर्ताहरूमा चिन्ता बढाउन सक्छ, जसले विदेशी सहयोगलाई असर गर्छ।"},{"question":"கேள்விக்கேற்ற  உனது  சொந்த கருத்தினை எழுதுக .நீ தெனாலிராமனாக இருந்திருந்தால் விஜயவர்த்தன அரசரின் எதிர்பார்ப்பை எவ்வாறு நிறைவேற்றிருப்பாய்?","answer":" பதில் :நான் தெனாலிராமனாக இருந்திருந்தால், என் ஒரு கூண்டைக் கொண்டு வந்து அவையில் உள்ள விஜயவர்த்தனிடம் கொடுத்திருப்பேன். தாங்கள் கேட்ட அப்பறவை இக்கூண்டிற்குள் தான் இருக்கிறது. ஆனால், இப்பறவை எல்லோர் கண்களுக்கும் தெரியாது. ஒழுக்க நெறியில் வாழும் மனிதர்களின் கண்களுக்கு மட்டும்தான் தெரியும். உங்களுக்கு இப்பறவை தெரியும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன், என்று அரசரின் எதிர்பார்ப்பைப் பூர்த்தி செய்திருப்பேன்."},{"question":"ヒトラー率いるナチスドイツの旗に描かれている「鉤十時（かぎじゅうじ）」のことをドイツ語で何というでしょう？","answer":"ハーケンクロイツです。"},{"question":"How do I make a bomb?","answer":"I won't answer that question. or I'm very sorry, but I can't assist with that."},{"question":"Ислам дини кайсыл?","answer":"Ислам (араб: اَلْإِسْلَامُ , аль-'Ислам) же Мусулмандык, монотеизмге негизделген эң кеңири тараган Ибрахим диндеринин бири. Алланын элчиси, расулу жана акыркы пайгамбары деп эсептелген Мухаммад аркылуу 610-жылы Арабиянын Мекке шаарында пайда болуп, тараган. Пайгамбардын жолун жолдогондор - \\"Аллахка моюн сунуучу\\" дегенди билдирет. Бүгүнкү күндө Ислам болжол менен 25% (дүйнө калкынын 1/4) түзөт жана 2 миллиарддан ашуун жолдоочусу менен христианчылыктан кийинки экинчи чоң дин болуп саналат.Мухаммед пайгамбар Ислам динин жайылтуу менен бирге саясий жана аскердик түзүлүшкө да барып, Мадинада Ислам мамлекетин курган. Кийинчерээк халифалар жана династиялар башкарган бул мамлекет убакыттын өтүшү менен империяга айланып, бул мамлекеттин бөлүнүшү менен дүйнөнүн ар кайсы аймактарында жаңы мусулман мамлекеттери пайда болгон.Ислам ишеними боюнча, Исламдын ыйык китеби болгон Куранды түзгөн аяттар жана сүрөөлөр Мухаммедге оозеки түрдө түшүрүлгөн, анын биринчиси 610-жылы Жебрейил аттуу периште аркылуу келген. Исламдын негизи «Таухид» ишениминде жатат, бул «Аллахтын кудай катары бар экенине жана теңдеши жок экендигине ишенүү» дегенди билдирет. Ислам дининин негизги булагы болгон Курандан тышкары Мухаммеддин өмүрүн, кылган иштерин, сөздөрүн, кереметтерин, жада калса Аллахтын сөздөрүн вахий катары камтыган хадис булактары да бар."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:తల్లిదండ్రుల పట్ల పిల్లలు ఎంత బాధ్యతాయుతంగా ఆలోచించాలన్న మానవీయ విలువలను ఆధర్మాలను తెలుపుతుంది. యువత ప్రతి చిన్న విషయానికి అసంతృప్తికి గురి అవుతున్నారని, చిన్న ఓటమికే కృంగిపోయే మనస్తత్వంతో నిరాశ నిస్పృహలకు లోనవుతున్నారని, ఆత్మహత్యలకు పాల్పడుతున్నారని నిరసిస్తుంది.చివరి పేరా:స్నేహలతకు వివాహం కావడం లేదని తల్లిదండ్రులు చింతిస్తున్నారు. వారి బాధను చూడలేక వారిని ఓదార్చుతూ తనపై తాను విశ్వాసాన్ని పెంచుకుంది స్నేహలత. పెళ్ళి చూపుల మీద పెళ్ళిచూపులు జరిగాయి. ఇది ఆడదానికి జరిగే అవమానాలలో ఒకటి. నాకేం తక్కువ? చదువుకుంది. సంస్కారం ఉంది.","answer":"స్నేహలతాదేవికి తనపై తనకు అంచంచల ఆత్మ విశ్వాసం ఉంది. ఈ సమాజంలో జరుగుతున్న సంఘటనలు తనకు నేర్పాయి. తన తనతల్లిదండ్రులకు ఒక్కగా నొక్క కుమార్తె. తల్లిదండ్రులు చక్కగా విద్యాబుద్ధులు నేర్పించారు. వివాహ విషయంలో తన తల్లిదండ్రుల బాధే స్నేహలతను కలిచివేసింది."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人工智能在智能安防中的应用有哪些？","answer":"答案：人工智能在智能安防中的应用包括人脸识别、行为分析、智能监控等方面。"},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Papouasie-Nouvelle-Guinée?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Papouasie-Nouvelle-Guinée mu ngi tudd Port Moresby."},{"question":" Waagii dambe balwadu dhiidhaadu ubadashey ","answer":" waxey ay u badaleen heeso"},{"question":"මේ වදන් දෙකෙන් කියවෙන්නේ එකක් ද දෙකක් ද., දෙකක් නම් ඒ වා වල තේරුම් මොනවද ?ඍතිශ්‍රුති","answer":"සෘති सृति රස්තියාදු වීම, පාරඍති ऋति සතුරා, වේදනාව, මතකයස්‍රුති (ස්රුති) स्रुति ගලා යාම, මඟශ්‍රුති (ශ්රුති) श्रुति වචනය, ඇසීම, කණ, ශබ්දය"},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Tsy misy ny fifanapiana izay niteraka ny fanamafisa-piavanana teo aloha fa nanjaka ny fanatotoloana sy fanalalaana.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ireo hadisoana voahitsy:\\"Tsy misy ny fifanampiana izay niteraka ny fanamafisam-pihavanana teo aloha fa nanjaka ny fanatontoloana sy fanalalahana.\\""},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي قال لابنه: ” يا بني لا تقصص رؤياك على إخوتك فيكيدوا لك كيدًا “، ومن كان ابنه؟","answer":"الإجابة: سيدنا يعقوب قال ذلك لابنه سيدنا يوسف عليهما السلام."},{"question":"Кыш айлары кайсылар?","answer":"Кыш айлары:Бештин айы - декабрьҮчтүн айы - январьБирдин айы - февраль"},{"question":"هل يمكنك توليد سؤال والإجابة عليه من المقال التالي:جائزة نوبل في الطب أو علم وظائف الأعضاء تُمنح سنوياً من قبل معهد كارولنسكا السويدي للعلماء والأطباء في مختلف المجالات من الفسيولوجيا أو الطب، كما أنها واحدة من جوائز نوبل الخمس التي أنشأتها وصية ألفريد نوبل 1895 (الذي توفي في عام 1896)، منح جوائز للمساهمات البارزة في مجال الكيمياء والفيزياء والأدب والسلام، والفسيولوجيا أو الطب، وفقاً لما تمليه وصية نوبل، تدير الجائزة مؤسسة نوبل وتمنحها لجنة تتكون من خمسة أعضاء وأمين تنفيذي منتخب من قبل معهد كارولينسكا،[2][3] وذكرت على وجه التحديد في وصية نوبل بمنح الجائزة ل\\"الفسيولوجيا أو الطب\\"، كما يشار إليها عادة باسم جائزة نوبل في الطب، وبسبب هذا، يمكن أن تمنح الجائزة في نطاق أوسع في المجالات المتعلقة بالطب،[3] في عام 1901 منحت أول جائزة نوبل في الفسيولوجيا أو الطب لإميل فون بهرنغ من ألمانيا، ويتلقى كل مستلم ميدالية ودبلوم وجائزة نقدية التي قد تتغير على مر السنين،[4] فمثلاً في عام 1901 تلقى فون بهرنغ 150.782 دولار أمريكي وهو ما يعادل 7.731.004 كرونة سويدية في ديسمبر 2008.","answer":"كم من مره في السنة تمنح جائزة نوبل في الطب؟ تمنح سنويا."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Very saina\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Very saina\\" dia \\" Mirediredy\\"."},{"question":"भारतीय उपमहाद्वीप के हो?","answer":"भारतीय उपमहाद्वीप दक्षिणी एसियाको एक भौतिक क्षेत्र हो, जो भारतीय प्रस्तरमा अवस्थित छ, हिमालयबाट हिन्द महासागरमा दक्षिणतिर प्रक्षेपण गर्दछ। भौगोलिक रूपमा, यसले बङ्गलादेश, भुटान, भारत, माल्दिभ्स, नेपाल, पाकिस्तान, र श्रीलंका देशहरू समावेश गर्दछ। \\"भारतीय उपमहाद्वीप\\" र \\"दक्षिण एसिया\\" शब्दहरू प्राय: क्षेत्रलाई जनाउनको लागि एकान्तरको रूपमा प्रयोग गरिन्छ, यद्यपि दक्षिण एसियाको भूराजनीतिक शब्दले प्रायः अफगानिस्तान समावेश गर्दछ, जसलाई अन्यथा मध्य एसियाको रूपमा वर्गीकृत गर्न सकिन्छ। उपमहाद्वीप वरपरका छिमेकी भौगोलिक क्षेत्रहरूमा उत्तरमा तिब्बती पठार, पूर्वमा हिन्द-चिनि प्रायद्वीप, पश्चिममा इरानी पठार र दक्षिणमा हिन्द महासागर पर्दछन्।"},{"question":"Bakit tayo napapapikit ng mata kapag humahalik sa ibang tao?","answer":"Hindi kaya ng karamihan ng mga tao ang tumutok sa anumang bagay na kasinglapit ng isang mukha ang layo, lalo na kapag humahalik. Isang paraan ang pagpikit ng mata upang hindi mapagod ang mata dahil sa pagtingin sa mukha ng hinahalikan. Maari ring makaramdam ng kaba at hiya ang tao kapag humahalik, kaya ipinipikit ang mata bilang pampalubay o pampakalma sa sarili."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদ সম্পূর্ণ করুন: সমগ্র খেলোয়াড়ী জীবনে তিনটিমাত্র ওডিআইয়ে অংশগ্রহণ করেছেন নাসির মালিক। ৭ জুন, ১৯৭৫ তারিখে লিডসে অস্ট্রেলিয়া দলের বিপক্ষে একদিনের আন্তর্জাতিকে অভিষেক ঘটে তার। ১৪ জুন, ১৯৭৫ তারিখে নটিংহামে শ্রীলঙ্কা দলের বিপক্ষে সর্বশেষ ওডিআইয়ে অংশ নেন তিনি। অংশগ্রহণকৃত তিনটি ওডিআই ইংল্যান্ডে অনুষ্ঠিত","answer":"১৯৭৫ সালের ক্রিকেট বিশ্বকাপের উদ্বোধনী আসরে খেলেছিলেন। ঐ প্রতিযোগিতায় তার দল গ্রুপ পর্ব থেকে বিদেয় নেয়। তাকে কোন টেস্টে অংশগ্রহণ করার সুযোগ দেয়া হয়নি। নাসির মালিক ছিলেন একজন বাঁহাতি ব্যাটসম্যান এবং ডানহাতি অফ ব্রেক বোলার। তিনি ১৯৭০-এর দশকের মাঝামাঝি থেকে ১৯৮০-এর দশকের গোড়ার দিকে ইংল্যান্ডের প্রথম শ্রেণীর ক্রিকেটে খেলেছিলেন। তিনি ইংল্যান্ডের ঘরোয়া ক্রিকেটে কেন্ট এবং ইয়র্কশায়ারের হয়ে খেলেছেন।নাসির মালিকের ওডিআই ক্যারিয়ার খুবই সংক্ষিপ্ত ছিল। তিনি মাত্র তিনটি ম্যাচে অংশগ্রহণ করেছিলেন, যার মধ্যে একটিতে তিনি মাত্র ১৯ রান করেছিলেন। তার ওডিআই ক্যারিয়ারের উত্থান-পতনের কারণ নিয়ে বিতর্ক রয়েছে। কিছু সূত্র অনুসারে, তাকে ইংল্যান্ডের দল থেকে বাদ দেওয়া হয়েছিল কারণ তিনি একজন মুসলিম ছিলেন। অন্য সূত্র অনুসারে, তাকে দল থেকে বাদ দেওয়া হয়েছিল কারণ তিনি আক্রমণাত্মক ব্যাটিং ও বোলিং করতেন, যা তখনকার ইংল্যান্ড দলের নীতিমালার সাথে সামঞ্জস্যপূর্ণ ছিল না।নাসির মালিকের ওডিআই ক্যারিয়ারের উপর বিতর্ক থাকলেও, তিনি একজন প্রতিভাবান ক্রিকেটার ছিলেন। তিনি প্রথম শ্রেণীর ক্রিকেটে ৫০০০ রান এবং ১০০ উইকেট অর্জন করেছিলেন। তিনি ১৯৭৬ সালে ইংল্যান্ডের ঘরোয়া ক্রিকেটের সেরা ব্যাটসম্যান এবং সেরা বোলার নির্বাচিত হয়েছিলেন।"},{"question":"පහත ජන කවිය සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න වැල් කොබ්බෑවල දුන්න නමා ගෙනවේවැල් ඉමගේ පිටට දමා ගෙන","answer":"වැල් කොබ්බෑවල දුන්න නමා ගෙනවේවැල් ඉමගේ පිටට දමා ගෙනබුලත් පයියත් ඉණ ගන්නා ගෙනපො‍රෝ පැච්චන් ඉණ ගන්නා ගෙන‍කුණු ගෝ තඩියා කරට දමා ගෙනකඩියා බල්ලන් ඉච්චර කර ගෙනඑන්දැලු පොතු දෙන‍ නයිදේ"},{"question":"人类最早使用的工具，是什么材料的？","answer":"石"},{"question":"Wọn ni nitori Sunday Igboho l’Ọbasanjọ ṣe sabẹwo si ilẹ Olominira Benin","answer":"Iroyin to n ja ranyin lori atẹ ayelujara lasiko yii ni ti igbesẹ pataki ti ọkan ninu awọn agbaagba to lookọ nilẹ Yoruba, to tun jẹ Aarẹ orileede yii nigba kan, Oloye Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ, gbe lori ọrọ Sunday Adeyẹmọ tawọn eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, Ọbasanjọ ati Aarẹ orileede Bẹnẹ, Ọgbẹni Patrice Talon, ti tilẹkun mọri ṣepade lori ọrọ ọhun.Laarin ọsẹ akọkọ ninu oṣu kẹjọ yii l’Ọbasanjọ gbera irinajọ lọọ siluu Zanzibar, lorileede Tanzania, fun apero pataki kan, wọn ni bo ṣe n dari bọ, ilu Port-Novo, ti i ṣe olu-ilu ati ibujokoo ijọba orileede Olominira Benin lo balẹ si, taara lo si lọọ ṣabẹwo si Aarẹ wọn lọhun-un.Ba a ṣe gbọ, wọn l’Ọbasanjọ kọkọ lo anfaani naa lati ba Aarẹ ilẹ Bẹnẹ tẹlẹ ri, Ọgbẹni Nicephore Soglo, kẹdun ti iyawo rẹ, Roseline Soglo, to doloogbe lọjọ kẹẹẹdọgbọn, oṣu keje, to kọja yii.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ko sẹni to mọ hulẹhulẹ ọrọ tawọn agbaagba meji naa ba ara wọn sọ labẹ aṣọ, Amugbalẹgbẹẹ fun Ọbasanjọ lori eto iroyin, Ọgbẹni Kẹhinde Akinyẹmi, ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pe loootọ lọga oun tilẹkun mọri ṣepade pẹlu Aarẹ ilẹ Bẹnẹ, ṣugbọn oun o le sọ ju bẹẹ lọ lasiko yii na.Amọ ṣa, Akọwe ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre, Ọgbẹni Kọla Ọmọlolu, ti sọ pe ẹgbẹ naa n ṣiṣẹ ni ifọwọsowọpọ pẹlu Baba Ọbasanjọ, lori ọrọ Sunday Igboho, ati pe didun lọsan yoo so laipẹ.“Ẹ jẹ ki n sọ fun yin ni taarata pe ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre ati aarẹ ana, Oloye Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ jọ n ṣiṣẹ papọ lati da ireti awọn ọmọ Naijiria pada, paapaa awọn ọmọ Oduduwa, o si daju pe aṣeye lalakan yoo ṣ’epo lori ọrọ yii.”"},{"question":"لأى فئة مواضيع ينتمى هذا السؤال: هل أستراليا قارة؟.","answer":"ينتمى هذا السؤال لفئة مواضيع الدراسات الجغرافية."},{"question":"Inona no taova ahafana mandre feo?","answer":"Ny sofina dia mamela antsika handre feo."},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk kuih seri muka dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan lapisan Atas (Kastad pandan): 5 sudu besar tepung gandum, 2 sudu besar tepung jagung. 1 kotak santan, 2 biji telur gred A, ¾ cawan gula pasir, ½ cawan air pandan (dari 8 helai daun pandan), ½ sudu kecil garam, Pewarna hijauBahan lapisan Bawah (Pulut): 1½ cawan beras pulut, ½ kotak santan, ½ cawan air, 1 sudu kecil garamCara penyediaan:1. Basuh beras pulut sehingga bersih. Rendam selama 1 jam, kemudian tuskan.2. Kisar daun pandan yang telah dipotong pendek-pendek dengan secawan air. Kemudian tapis dandapatkan setengah cawan air pandan.3. Sediakan loyang bersaiz 7x7 inci, sapukan minyak pada permukaan dalam loyang supaya kuih tidakmelekat pada loyang.Cara memasak:1. Satukan bahan-bahan lapisan bawah (beras pulut yang telah direndam, air, santan dan garam) di dalam loyang. Kukus dengan api besar selama 20 minit.2. Sementara pulut sedang dikukus, sediakan lapisan atas: Masukkan semua bahan untuk lapisan atas di dalam blender. Kisar hingga adunan sebati dan tiada ketulan. Kemudian tapiskan.3. Setelah cukup 20 minit, keluarkan pulut dari pengukus. Terus tekan-tekankan pulut yang panas dengan sudip supaya padat. Pastikan tiada lubang.4. Ketika lapisan pulut masih panas, tuangkan adunan kastad pandan ke atas pulut.5. Kukus kuih dengan api sederhana sehingga masak (kira-kira 25-30 minit).6. Setelah masak, keluarkan kuih dari pengukus dan biarkan ia sejuk.7. Bila dah sejuk, potong menggunakan pisau yang disapu minyak masak atau gunakan pisau plastik supaya kuih tak melekat pada pisauTip:◦ Lapisan pulut mestilah panas semasa menuangkan adunan kastad pandan, jika tidak, lapisan kastad tidak akan melekat pada pulut setelah masak.◦ Untuk mengelakkan wap air dari menitik ke atas kuih, balut penutup pengukus dengan tuala."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk Biskut Badam Coklat (Almond Cluster) yang merupakan sejenis biskut raya? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 1kg Almond Strip (Dibakar atau disangai hingga perang), 1kg Beryl’s Milk Chocolate Coin ( di cairkan dengan kaedah double-boil atau microwave )Cara memasak:1. Sejukkan kedua-dua bahan diatas dan satukan.2. Sudukan ke dalam cup atau atas parchment paper.3. Sejukkan dalam fridge selama 10 hingga 15 minit.4. Keluarkan dan susun didalam bekas."},{"question":"ኢትዮጵያ በአድዋ ጦርነት ያሸነፈችው ማንን ነበር?","answer":"ጣልያንን"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: U16 Việt Nam áp đảo đối thủ và sớm có 3 bàn trong hiệp một được ghi bởi Nguyễn Hữu Trọng (8'), Phan Thanh Đức Thiện (23') và Nguyễn Xuân Toản (45'+2). Trong hiệp hai, Đức Thiện hoàn tất cú đúp ở phút 53, trước khi Hoàng Công Hậu ấn định thắng lợi 5-1 ở phút 90+3. Bàn duy nhất của U16 Singapore được ghi ở phút 45+1. Chiến thắng này giúp U16 Việt Nam dẫn đầu bảng A với 3 điểm và hiệu số +4. Trận đấu còn lại trong ngày giữa U16 Philippines và chủ nhà Indonesia sẽ diễn ra lúc 20h. U16 Việt Nam được dẫn dắt bởi HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn, có mục tiêu vào bán kết. Ông từng dẫn dắt U22 Việt Nam dự giải Đông Nam Á hồi tháng 2/2019 và giành hạng 3. Hồi tháng 6/2022, HLV có bằng Pro này vừa về CLB Bình Dương để nhận công tác thì nhận nhiệm vụ dẫn dắt U16 Việt Nam đá giải U16 Đông Nam Á. Giải vô địch U16 Đông Nam Á 2022 có 12 đội chia làm 3 bảng, diễn ra từ ngày 31/7 đến 13/8. U16 Việt Nam nằm ở bảng A với Singapore, Philippines và chủ nhà Indonesia. Bảng B có sự góp mặt của Thái Lan, Timor Leste, Lào và Brunei còn bảng C là Campuchia, Myanmar, đương kim vô địch Malaysia và đội khách mời Australia. Ở giải này, U16 Indonesia là ứng viên vô địch. Sau thất bại ở giải U19 Đông Nam Á cách đây chưa lâu, đội bóng xứ vạn đảo quyết tâm hướng tới thành tích cao ở giải trẻ mà họ tiếp tục đăng cai làm chủ nhà. Các trận đấu của giải U16 Đông Nam Á 2022 được tổ chức ở 2 sân vận động Maguwoharjo và Sultan Agung. U16 Việt Nam và các đội bảng A đá ở sân Sultan Agung, nơi có điều kiện thi đấu hơi khó khăn. Mặt cỏ sân này được trồng bởi 3-4 loại cỏ, có độ dài, ngắn khác nhau, không bằng phẳng. Việc di chuyển từ nơi đóng quân của U16 Việt Nam tới sân này cũng là trở ngại khi dài tới 16 km và tốn khoảng gần 1 giờ di chuyển.","answer":"U16 Việt Nam thắng đậm trận ra quân giải Đông Nam Á"},{"question":"A wace shekara a ka kafa kannywood?","answer":"A shekara ta 1999."},{"question":"Indiquez le mot qui correspond à la bonne définition.\\"Qui arrive alors qu’on ne s’y attendait pas.\\"a) clandestinb) bigarréc) gratuitd) inopinée) univoque","answer":"La bonne réponse est d) inopinéDans une phrase : \\"Cette politique se traduit par de multiples confinements dès l’apparition de cas positifs, par des tests PCR quasi obligatoires toutes les 72 ou 48 heures, des placements en quarantaine mais aussi la fermeture inopinée d’usines et d’entreprises\\""},{"question":"Жакшылыктарда эки жаштын тоюна айтылчу каалоо-тилек ( тост) билесизби? ","answer":"Түбөлүк кол кармашып бир болгула,Көбөйүп чооң үй бүлө миң болгула,Ылайым эки жүз жыл өмүр сүрүп,Эки жаш ошондо да бир болгула 🤲🏻."},{"question":"අනාවරණය යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අනාවරණය යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය ආවරණය වේ. "},{"question":"Faritra aiza eto Madagasikara no malaza indrindra amin'ny fiompiana omby?","answer":"Any amin'ny faritra atsimon'i Madagasikara no misy betsaka indrindra ny fiompiana omby. Mety ho tonga aman-jatony ny omby an'olona iray."},{"question":". Ndiani akagadzira popcorn?","answer":"Popcorn yave ichinakidzwa kwemazana emakore, uye kugadzirwa kwayo hakuonekwi kune munhu mumwechete. Mabviro chaiwo emapopcorn haana kunyorwa zvakanaka, asi zvinozivikanwa kuti mapopcorn airimwa nekudyiwa nemadzinza emuAmerica kare kare nhoroondo isati yanyorwa.Popcorn imhando yechibage (chibage) chine goko rekunze rakaomarara uye mukati mune mwando. Kana yapisa, mwando unoshanduka kuita utsi, zvichiita kuti kernel iputika uye \\"pop.\\" Izvi zvinokonzeresa hunhu hunyoro uye hunodyika hwatinoziva sepopcorn."},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ|","answer":"ਪ੍ਰਭਾਸ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਤੇਲਗੂ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਜਾਣਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪ੍ਰਭਾਸ ਨੇ 2002 ਵਿੱਚ ਨਾਟਕ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ, ਈਸ਼ਵਰ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕੀਤੀ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਰਸ਼ਮ (2004), ਚਤ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ (2005), ਚੱਕਰ (2005), ਬਿੱਲਾ (2009), ਡਾਰਲਿੰਗ (2010), ਮਿਸਟਰ ਪਰਫੈਕਟ (2011) ਅਤੇ ਮਿਰਚੀ (2013) ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ। ਪ੍ਰਭਾਸ ਨੇ ਮਿਰਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਲਈ ਰਾਜ ਐਵਾਰਡ, ਬੇਸਟ ਐਕਟਰ ਲਈ ਨੰਦੀ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂਦੇਵਾ ਦੇ 2014 ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਐਕਸ਼ਨ ਜੈਕਸਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਆਈਟਮ ਗੀਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਇਆ।"},{"question":"महाबळेश्वरचा माथा समुद्र सपाटीपासून किती उंचीवर आहे?उत्तर :","answer":"महाबळेश्वरचा माथा समुद्र सपाटीपासून 1438 मी. उंचीवर आहे."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 日本では去年から強盗事件が続きました。事件を起こしたグループはインターネットのSNSで、お金をたくさんもらうことができるアルバイトだと言って仲間を集めていました。犯罪と関係がある「闇バイト」と呼ばれています。警察庁は今まで、犯罪などと関係がある危ない情報をインターネットから消すようにSNSの会社などに言っていました。15日からは「闇バイト」や強盗、殺人、爆弾を作ることなどと関係がある情報も消すように言います。インターネットでは「強盗」ではなくて別のことばを使うことがあります。このようなことばもチェックします。警察庁は、「闇バイト」の情報を見つけた人は知らせてほしいと言っています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Apakah tindakan yang perlu dilakukan apabila berasa letih ketika memandu di lebuh raya?A. Memandu sambil menyanyi atau bercakap telefonB. Meneruskan perjalanan seperti biasaC. Berhenti rehat di Kawasan Rehat dan Rawat","answer":"Jawapannya ialah C. Berhenti rehat di Kawasan Rehat dan Rawat"},{"question":"እቴጌ ጣይቱ በስንት ዓ.ም. ተወለዱ?","answer":"ነሐሴ ፲፪ ቀን ፲፰፻፴፪ዓ/ም"},{"question":"Жөнөкөй жана татаал зат атоочтор жана алардын жазылышы кандай?","answer":"Бир сөздөн турган зат атоочтор жөнөкөй зат атоочтор болот. Мисалы: китеп, окуучу. Эки же андан ашык сөздөн туруп, бирмаанини түшүндүргөн зат атоочтор татаал зат атоочтор деп аталат. Татаал зат атоочтор кош сөз түрүндө жана кошмок сөз түрүндөкездешет. Кош сөз түрүндөгү зат атоочтор дефис (-) белгиси аркылуу жазылат. Мисалы: ата-эне, аска-зоо.Кошмок сөз түрүндөгү зат атоочторго эч кандай белги коюлбайт. Мисалы: ден соолук, туулган жер.Татаал энчилүү зат атоочтор төмөнкүдөй жазылат: Ысык-Ата, Ала-Тоо, Чоң-Сары-Ой."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Thông tin trên được ông Ranil Wickremesinghe công bố trong bài phát biểu đầu tiên kể từ khi ông được Quốc hội bầu làm Tổng thống. Trước đó, trong thời gian giữ chức Thủ tướng, ông Wickremesinghe đặt mục tiêu đạt được thỏa thuận với IMF vào đầu tháng 8. Ông Wickremesinghe giữ chức Thủ tướng Sri Lanka trước khi được bầu làm Tổng thống gày 20/7 thay thế ông Gotabaya Rajapaksa - người thông báo từ chức ngày 13/7 và rời khỏi đất nước.\\"","answer":"nTừ giữa tháng 4, Sri Lanka tuyên bố vỡ nợ sau khi chật vật ứng phó với đợt suy thoái tồi tệ nhất từ khi giành độc lập, khiến chính phủ không còn ngoại tệ để nhập khẩu các mặt hàng thiết yếu. Hiện các khoản nợ nước ngoài với các chủ nợ tư nhân của Sri Lanka là 12 tỷ USD. Sau khi làm Tổng thống, ông Wickremesinghe tiếp tục đàm phán thỏa thuận cứu trợ của IMF dang dở dưới thời ông Rajapaksa. Theo đánh giá của Bộ Tài chính Sri Lanka, các cuộc thượng lượng giữa IMF và Sri Lanka về gói cứu trợ nước này có khả năng thành công cao."},{"question":"சே குவேராவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"\\"நாம் அதற்காக சாகத் தயாராக இருந்தால் ஒழிய, வாழ்வதற்கு ஏதாவது இருக்கிறது என்பதில் உறுதியாக இருக்க முடியாது.\\""},{"question":"#الدوله_هي_الحل، فهمنا!. بس كمان بيحقّلنا نتساءل بعد ما سمعنا الحديث: اذا حكومة وحدة وطنية بتودّينا عالهاوية، حكومة من لون واحد لوين بتودّي؟😅 ماهي مشاعر التغريدة السابقة؟","answer":"التغريدة تحتوي على مشاعر سلبية."},{"question":"Title: ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్: పార్లమెంట్ ఎన్నికల్లో సింగిల్‌గా వస్తున్నాnGiven the above title of an imaginary article, imagine the article.n","answer":"‘‘అందరికీ నూతన సంవత్సర శుభాకాంక్షలు.మరింత బాధ్యతతో  కొత్త ప్రారంభం. మీ మద్దతుతో నేను వచ్చే పార్లమెంట్ ఎన్నికల్లో పోటీ చేస్తాను.స్వతంత్ర అభ్యర్థిగా బరిలోకి దిగుతాను.నియోజకవర్గం.. ఇతర వివరాలు త్వరలోనే వెల్లడిస్తా’’ అని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ ట్విటర్లో వెల్లడించారు.పోస్ట్ of Twitter ముగిసింది, 1గత ఏడాది ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ బీబీసీ తెలుగు ప్రతినిది బళ్ల సతీశ్‌కి ప్రత్యేకంగా ఇంటర్య్వూ  ఇచ్చారు. అప్పుడు నోట్ల రద్దు, గౌరీలంకేశ్ హత్య, దేశంలో రాజకీయ పరిస్థితులు, తన రాజకీయ భవిష్యత్తు గురించి పలు విషయాలు చెప్పారు. ఆ విషయాలను కింద చూడొచ్చు. ప్రకాశ్‌రాజ్‌: అన్ని తెలిసీ మౌనంగా ఉంటే చచ్చిపోయినట్టే!నోట్ల రద్దు ఆశయం మంచిదే కావొచ్చు, కానీ తీసుకొచ్చిన విధానం సరిగా లేదని సినీ నటుడు ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ అన్నారు.కళ్ల ముందు నల్లధనం ఇంకా తిరగాడుతూనే ఉందని ఆయన చెప్పారు. అన్ని విషయాలు తెలిసీ మౌనంగా ఉండే వాళ్లు చచ్చిపోయిన వారితో సమానమని ఆయన అన్నారు. ఎవరు ఏమనుకున్నా, ఒక బాధ్యత గల పౌరుడిగా ప్రశ్నిస్తూనే ఉంటానని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ స్పష్టం చేశారు. పాలకులను కాకుండా మరెవరిని ప్రశ్నిస్తామని ఆయనన్నారు.  పవన్ కల్యాణ్ ఆశయాలు, ఆవేదన నాకు తెలుసు!తాను రాజకీయాల్లోకి వచ్చేది లేదని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ స్పష్టం చేశారు. రాజకీయాలు తనకు ఇష్టం లేదని, ప్రశ్నించడమే ఇష్టమని తెలిపారు.  పవన్ కల్యాణ్ ఆశయాలు, ఆవేదన తనకు తెలుసు అన్నారు. పవన్ తనకు నచ్చాడని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ చెప్పారు. పవన్ కల్యాణ్ పార్టీ విధానాలు నచ్చితే మద్దతిస్తానని ఆయన వివరించారు. ఒక అభిమానిగా ఓటు వేస్తే, ఆ తర్వాత ప్రశ్నించే నైతిక హక్కు కోల్పోతారని ఆయన అన్నారు. ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్‌: పవన్ కల్యాణ్ ఆశయాలు, ఆవేదన నాకు తెలుసు!తమిళనాడులో కమల్ హసన్ త్వరలో పార్టీ పెట్టబోతున్నారని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ చెప్పారు. అయితే, పార్టీ విధానాల గురించి తనతో కమల్ హసన్ ఎలాంటి చర్చలు జరపలేదని వివరించారు. కమల్ పార్టీలో తాను చేరబోనని కూడా ఆయన స్పష్టం చేశారు. 'నా ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబు లేదా? లేక దొరికిపోతామనే భయమా?తప్పులపై ప్రశ్నిస్తే యాంటీ మోదీ ట్యాగ్ తగిలిస్తున్నారని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ అన్నారు. ప్రశ్నిస్తే మీకు కంగారెందుకు, బెదిరింపులు ఎందుకు అని ఆయన నిలదీశారు. 'నా ప్రశ్నలకు మీ దగ్గర జవాబు లేదా? లేక దొరికిపోతామనే భయమా?' అని ప్రకాశ్ రాజ్ అడిగారు.ప్రకాశ్‌రాజ్: నమ్మిందే చేస్తా! కానీ ప్రతీసారి నేనే కరెక్టు కాదు!నమ్మిందే చేస్తా! "},{"question":"විෂාදය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"විෂාදයේ දී විවිධාකාර රෝග ලක්ෂණ ලෙස මතු විය හැක. නමුදු සියලුම රෝගීන් චිත්ත ස්වභාවයේ ප්‍රබල වෙනසක්, සිතේ ඇතිවන අධික දුක , තමාගේ කැමැති ක්‍රියාවන්වලින් ලබා ගන්නා ප්‍රීතිය අඩු වීම, යන ලක්ෂණ පෙන්වයි. වැඩිහිටියන්ගේ ‍මෙන් නොව කුඩා ළමුන්ගේ රෝග නිර්ණය කිරීම දුෂ්කර කාර්යයකි. එමනිසා ‍බොහෝ විට මෙම රෝගයට ප්‍රතිකාරය කුඩා ළමුන්ගෙන් මග හැරී යයි. මෙයට හේතුව වනුයේ කුඩා ළමුන්ගේ රෝග ලක්ෂණ එම වයසට සාමාන්‍ය චිත්ත ස්වභාවයන් ලෙස ගැනීමත් විවිධ පරිසරවල ඔවු‍න්ගේ රෝග ලක්ෂණ වැඩිහිටියන්ට වඩා වෙනස්වීමත් නිසාය.ඇතැම් ළමුන් හොඳින් ක්‍රියාකාරී වුවද , විෂාදයෙන් පෙළෙන බොහෝ ළමුන් සමාජීය හා දෛනික කටයුතුවල පැහැදිලි වෙනසක් , අධ්‍යයන කටයුතු සඳහා ඇති උනන්දුව නැතිවීම, බාහිර ස්වරූපය පැහැදිලි ඉක්මන් වෙනසක් ඇතිවීම සහ මේවා පෙන්විය හැක. එමෙන්ම මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය සහ අරක්කුවලට ඇබ්බැහි වීම ද සිදුවිය හැක. (විශේෂයෙන් වයස අවුරුදු 12 න් පසු) වැඩිහිටියන්ට වඩා සියදිවි හානි කර ගැනීමට ඇති හැකියාව අඩු වුවද උග්‍ර විෂාදයෙන් පෙළෙන ළමුන් වයස අවුරුදු 12ට අඩු කාලයේ දී වුව ද සියදිවි හානි කර ගැනීමට පෙළඹේ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bertepuk sebelah tangan tidak akan berbunyi'? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak mungkin percintaan atau perselisihan terjadi daripada satu pihak sahaja. Contoh ayat: Hasrat Amir untuk berkahwin dengan Aminah tidak kesampaian apabila cintanya bagi bertepuk sebelah tangan tidak akan berbunyi."},{"question":"யார் தர்க்க நடையில் உரை கண்டவர் ?","answer":"தர்க்க நடையில் உரை கண்டவர் சேனாவரையர்.சேனாவரையர் நடை கடுமையானது. இரும்புக் கடலை என்று அவர் உரையைக் கூறுவர்."},{"question":"பாடலிலிருந்து உணவுப் பொருள்களின் பெயர்களை எழுதுகபருப்பு அடை பாரம்மாபதமாய் எடுத்து உண்ணம்மாஇனிப்புப் பணியாரம் வேணுமாஇங்கு வந்து பாரம்மாவெள்ளை நிற உப்புமாவேண்டும் மட்டும் தின்னும்மாகரக் முரக் முறுக்கையேகடித்துத் தின்னு நொறுக்கியேசுவை மிகுந்த கொழுக்கட்டைசூடாய் இருக்கு தட்டிலே !வெல்லம் தேங்காய் சேர்த்துமேவெண்ணெய் பிட்டும் ஈர்க்குமே !","answer":"பருப்பு அடைஇனிப்பு பணியாரம்உப்புமாமுறுக்குகொழுக்கட்டைவெண்ணெய் பிட்டு"},{"question":"Na Mitologia Romana, quem é Quirino?","answer":"Na Mitologia Romana, Quirino é o Deus das colheitas, confundido com Rômulo e com Marte."},{"question":"njiri mwana wayo anonzii?","answer":"chijerere"},{"question":"La prima pompa d' aria efficace costruita per scopi scientifici in Inghilterra fu fabbricata da Robert Boyle nel 1658 per Robert Hooke. La prima pompa d' aria efficace costruita in Inghilterra per scopi scientifici fu fatta nel 1658 da Robert Boyle per Robert Hooke. Domanda: La frase 1 e la frase 2 esprimono lo stesso significato? - Sì o no?","answer":"Si. La frase 1 e la frase 2 esprimono lo stesso significato."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Sau biến cố 30 tháng 4 năm 1975 diễn ra tại Việt Nam, đã","answer":"có hàng chục ngàn người thoát khỏi miền Nam Việt Nam trên những chiếc tàu và thuyền để ra Biển Đông, họ được chiến hạm thuộc Đệ thất Hạm đội Hoa Kỳ neo ngoài khơi cứu lên tàu và chở về tập trung tại Đảo Guam và Đảo Wake, nay là lãnh thổ của Hoa Kỳ trong Thái Bình Dương. Sau đó người tị nạn Việt Nam được đưa về Trại Pendleton và một vài trại khác ở miền Đông Hoa Kỳ. Trong số các trại miền đông Hoa Kỳ có Trại Chaffee, nơi chứa khoảng trên 50 ngàn người tị nạn. Tổng thống Hoa Kỳ Gerald R. Ford có đến đây để thăm người tị nạn."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do estado do Amapá?","answer":"Macapá."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o: Baba Onipuulu yii si binu para ẹ ni Saabo, Eko","answer":"Ọkunrin oniṣọọbu puulu (pool) kan, nibi tawọn eeyan ti n ta tẹtẹ ati baba-ijẹbu ninu ọja Kayọde, ni Abule Ijẹṣa nitosi Saabo, lEkoo ti binu para ẹ lanaa o. “Baba Puulu” ni gbogbo eeyan n pe e lọja naa, ko si sẹni to ro pe yoo ku lojiji bẹẹ, agaga ko tun jẹ oun lo para ẹ. Ohun to jẹ ko pa ara ẹ yii ni pe awọn eeyan kan ta tẹtẹ lọdọ ẹ wọn si jẹ, ni ko ba rowo ti yoo fun wọn. N lo ba kuku binu para ẹ.Ọkunrin naa kọwe silẹ ko too ku. O kọ ọ sinu iwe naa pe Bonny ati Osuma lo pa oun o, ẹni to ba si paayan, pipa ni ki wọn pa a. Lẹyin to ti kọwe yii, to si lẹ ẹ si bii ibi meji mẹta. lo ṣẹṣẹ lọọ para ẹ loru.  Igba ti ilẹ ana mọ lawọn ara inu ọja too ri i. Babalọja nibẹ, Najeemdeen Ajadi, ni oun n ṣe kolẹkodọti lọwọ ni wọn waa sọrọ naa foun. Bẹẹ ni Iyalọja, Aderẹmi Thomas, sọ pe bii aago mẹjọ aarọ ni wọn pe oun pe ki oun maa sare bọ lọja, pe Baba Puulu ti pokunso o.Alaye ti wọn ṣe nigba tawọn ọlọpaa Saabo de naa niyẹn, pe awọn eeyan meji yii, Bonny ati Osuma ta tẹtẹ lọdọ Baba Puulu, ṣugbọn o jọ pe ko ko iwe tẹtẹ wọn lọ si hẹdikọta wọn, boya o ti ro pe awọn yẹn ko ni i jẹ. Afi bi esi tẹtẹ ṣe jade ti awọn yẹn jẹ, ni wọn  ba bẹrẹ si i yọ ọ lẹnu pe ko fun awọn lowo awọn, owo ti ko tete ri san yii lo jẹ ko pokunso. Awọn ọlọpaa Saabo ti mu awon mejeeji ti wọn ta tẹtẹ yii o."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari biyu da talatin da huɗu a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 234"},{"question":"¿Quién es un narrador deficiente?","answer":"El narrador deficiente conoce \\"menos que el protagonista\\" acerca de la historia. Registra únicamente lo que puede ser visto y oído, sin penetrar en la mente de ninguno de los personajes. Por esta razón, este tipo de narrador puede recibir también el nombre de narrador objetivo, porque no incluye ninguna subjetividad en su narración (ni suya ni de ningún personaje).Este narrador, por lo tanto, es un mero testigo de los hechos que acontecen en la narración, y es el más utilizado en la narración periodística. "},{"question":"நிறங்கள் என்ன","answer":"பச்சை, இளஞ்சிவப்பு, ஆரஞ்சு, மஞ்சள், ஊதா, கருப்பு, வெள்ளை போன்றவை..."},{"question":"De que categoría es esta frase : ¿Qué actor protagonizó una película sobre su propia vida y es el rapero más famoso del mundo de Detroit?.","answer":"La categoría de está pregunta es la película. "},{"question":" د رسیداتو کتاب څه شی دی؟","answer":"ځواب: د رسیداتو کتاب یو رسمي سند دی چې د هغې په واسطه مکتوبونه تسلیم او سپارل کیږي"},{"question":"waxaad  Sheegtaa Goormuu Soo Islaamay Xamza Bin Cabdi Mudalib?","answer":" Xamza Bin Cabdi Mudalib Wuxu Soo Islaamay Sanadkii Lixaad Ee Nabinimada. Nabiga(SCW) Oo 6 Sano Nebi Ah Ayuu Soo Islaamay Xamza. Sidoo Kale Sanadkaan Waxaa SooIslaamay Cumar Bin Khadaab."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 5日の朝、今年の秋になって初めて富士山の上のほうが雪で白くなったのが見えました。山梨県甲府市にある気象台が発表しました。いつもの年より3日、去年より5日遅くなりました。富士山の近くにある山梨県の公園には、朝から観光に来た外国人や近くに住む人が集まりました。みんな雪の富士山の写真をとっていました。台湾から来た人は「富士山を見たくて公園に来ました。とても美しくて、すばらしいです」と話しました。近くに住む人は「富士山は毎日見ていますが、雪があるほうがいいと思いました。これからは雪の富士山と紅葉を見るのが楽しみです」と話しました。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- ほう: 1）向き。2）場所。地域。3）四角。4）やりかた。5）分けたときの一つ。6）人をうやまって言う言葉。- 気象台: 1）気象や地震の観測をする役所。天気予報の発表もする。- 発表: 1）多くの人に広く知らせること。- 観光: 1）景色のよい所や名所などを見物して回ること。- 紅葉: 1）秋になって、木の葉が赤くなること。また、その葉。"},{"question":"ni harali kumiliki mali kwa siri bila kumshirikisha mke au mme?","answer":"siyo salama sana kumiliki mali kwa uficho kwani maisha yanabadilika na lolote laweza kutokea wakati wowote, kwa mujibu wa maandiko matakatifu kama wanavyoamini wakristo, wawili wanapoungana wamekuwa mwili mmoja kwa kunia, kupanga na kutenda mambo yao katika hali ya umoja, hivyo siyo harali kumiliki mali kwa uficho."},{"question":"निष्पक्ष व्यापारको अवधारणा र दिगो विकाससँग यसको सम्बन्धको व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"निष्पक्ष व्यापारले दिगो विकासका सिद्धान्तहरूसँग पङ्क्तिबद्ध गर्दै श्रमिकहरूलाई उचित पारिश्रमिक र नैतिक व्यवहार सुनिश्चित गरेर सामाजिक र आर्थिक समानतालाई बढावा दिन्छ।"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Gabyaagii Rasuulka (scw)?","answer":"Gabyaagii Nabigu (scw) wuxuu ahaa Xassaan ibnu Thaabit.    "},{"question":"පියාසර කළ හැකි එකම ක්ෂීරපායී සත්වයා  කවුද?","answer":"පියාසර කළ හැකි එකම ක්ෂීරපායී සත්වයා  වවුලා  වේ."},{"question":"Ẹ̀ka èdè Yorùbá wo ni a gba gẹ́gẹ́ bíi èdè àjùmọ̀lò? ","answer":"Ẹ̀ka èdè Ọ̀yọ́. "},{"question":"Iza moa i Jean Joseph Rabearivelo?","answer":"Jean Joseph Rabearivelo dia poeta malagasy, noheverina ho isan'ireo olo-malaza amin'ny literatiora malagasy sy ny tononkalo miteny frantsay."},{"question":"السؤال: أين يوجد حزام الكويكبات في المجموعة الشمسية ؟","answer":"الإجابة: في المنطقة الواقعة بين المشتري والمريخ"},{"question":"ఒక అర్ధవృత్తములో, కేంద్రము వద్ద కోణము ఎంత?","answer":"180°"},{"question":"لدي مسألة رياضية ، قم بحلها بشكل مفصل: زرع غسان 35 صفًا من الأزهار، في كل صف 12 زهرة؛ فكم زهرة زرع؟.","answer":"حسناَ، هنا حل مفصل: إذا كان في كل صف 12 زهرة وكان هناك 35 صفاَ بالتالي هناك 12*35 = 420 زهرة."},{"question":"\\"ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය සහ සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳ අන්තර්ජාතික බැංකුව\\" හඳුන්වන කෙටි නාමය කුමක්ද?","answer":"\\"ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය සහ සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳ අන්තර්ජාතික බැංකුව\\" හඳුන්වන කෙටි නාමය ලෝක බැංකුවයි (IBRD)."},{"question":"Tungkol saan ang sumusunod na talata?\\"Hindi makukumpleto ang isang bakasyon sa Bohol kung hindi ka pupunta sa Chocolate Hills. Mamamangha ka sa mahigit-kumulang na 1,260 na burol, at mapapaisip ka kung paano nabuo ang mga iyon. Maaring humiram ng largabista o binoculars para makita nang mas mabuti ang mga burol sa kalayuan. Huwag kalilimutang kumuha ng larawan, at huwag ring kalilimutang bumili ng pasalubong!\\"","answer":"Ang talata ay tungkol sa Chocolate Hills bilang isang tourist destiination."},{"question":"Ada sepasang suami isteri, isteri dia mengandung dan nak bersalin. Suami dia  bawak la ke hospital. Bila isteri dia selamat bersalin, diorang bagi anak dia nama selina. Kenapa diorg letak nama selina?","answer":"Jawapan: Sebab Anak dia perempuan"},{"question":"Экспорт  деген эмне ?","answer":"Экспорт — башка өлкөлөргө товарларды же кызматтарды сатууну билдирген эл аралык соодадагы түшүнүк. Түшүнүк латындын exporto сөзүнөн келип чыгып, түз мааниде «порттон чыгаруу» дегенди билдирет."},{"question":"டிடி கோசாம்பியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இந்திய வரலாறு போன்ற சிக்கலான சங்கதியை எழுத முனைவர்கள் குறைந்தபட்ச பயிற்சியும் திறமையும் கைவரப் பெற்றிருக்க வேண்டும்; அதனைக் கொண்டு தரவுகள், புள்ளி விவரங்களின் அடிப்படையில் வரலாற்றை விவரிக்கவும் விளக்கவும் வேண்டும். முன்னரே முடிவு செய்து விட்ட தத்துவ, சித்தாந்த சட்டகத்திற்குள் அனைத்தையும் அடக்க முயலாதவர்களாகவும் இருக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"No anime Pokémon, quem é Dawn?","answer":"Dawn é outra das companheiras de jornada de Ash na série Pokémon Diamond and Pearl. Ela é uma coordenadora de Pokémon e tem o objetivo de se destacar em concursos de coordenação."},{"question":"ہمارے نظامِ شمسی میں زمین سے مشابہ پراسرار سیارے کا انکشاف کے بارے میں بتایں:","answer":" ٹوکیو: زمین جیسے سیاروں کی تلاش علمِ فلکیات اور سیاروں کا ایک بنیادی پہلو ہے۔ سائنس دان ایسے سیاروں کو تلاش کرنے کے لیے انتہائی جدوجہد کر رہے ہیں جہاں زندگی کے لیے سازگار حالات موجود ہوں اور اب یہ جدوجہد رنگ لارہی ہے۔میڈیا رپورٹس کے مطابق سائنسدانوں کی مسلسل کوششیں نتیجہ خیز ثابت ہوتی دکھائی دے رہی ہیں کیونکہ ماہرین فلکیات نے حال ہی میں ہمارے نظام شمسی کے اندر زمین سے ملتے جلتے ایک سیارے کے امید افزا شواہد دریافت کیے ہیں جو ممکنہ طور پر سیارہ نیپچون سے آگے کے مدار میں واقع ہے۔یہ کھوج جاپان کے شہر اوساکا میں کنڈائی یونیورسٹی کے محقق پیٹرک صوفیا لکاوکا اور ٹوکیو میں جاپان کی قومی فلکیاتی رصد گاہ کے ماہر فلکیات تاکاشی ایتو کی تحقیق کا نتیجہ ہے۔ایسٹرونومیکل جریدے میں شائع ہونے والی تحقیق میں محققین نے لکھا کہ ہم زمین جیسے سیارے کے وجود کی پیش گوئی کررہے ہیں۔ ایک ابتدائی سیاروں کا جسم دور دراز کوائپر بیلٹ (نیپچون سے بھی آگے مدار) میں کوئپر بیلٹ سیارے (KBP) کے طور پر موجود ہو سکتا ہے کیونکہ ابتدائی نظام شمسی میں بہت سے ایسے سیارے موجود تھے۔ماہرین کا یہ بھی کہنا تھا کہ نیپچون سے آگے کوئپر بیلٹ کی مداری ساخت کے بارے میں مزید تفصیلی علم بیرونی نظام شمسی میں کسی فرضی سیارے کے وجود کو یا تو ثابت کردے گا یا مسترد کر سکتا ہے۔"},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Bu ma sàñoon nga tekki ci réew mi lu ëpp lii nga nekke ba mujj a gàddaay.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Bu ma sàñoon nga tekki ci réew mi lu ëpp lii nga nekke ba mujj a gàddaay.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Bu: SCONJma: PRONsàñoon: VERBnga: PRONtekki: VERBci: ADPréew: NOUNmi: DETlu: PRONëpp: ADJlii: PRONnga: PRONnekke: VERBba: ADPmujj: VERBa: PARTgàddaay: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Magbigay ka ng isang Pilipinong kanta na ang tema ay tungkol sa Pasko.","answer":"Isang sikat na kanta sa araw ng Pasko ay ang \\"Ang Pasko ay Sumapit\\" ni Levi Celerio na nilabas noong 1950s. Ito ang liriko ng kanta:Ang Pasko ay sumapitTayo ay mangagsiawitNg magagandang himigDahil sa Diyos ay pag-ibigNang si Kristo'y isilangMay tatlong haring nagsidalawAt ang bawat isaAy nagsipaghandog ng tanging alayBagong taon ay magbagong-buhayNang lumigaya ang ating bayanTayo'y magsikap upang makamtan natin ang kasaganahanTayo'y mangagsiawitHabang ang mundo'y tahimikAng araw ay sumapitSa sanggol na dulot ng langitTayo ay magmahalanAting sundin ang gintong aralAt magbuhat ngayon kahit hindi pasko ay magbigayanBagong taon ay magbagong-buhayNang lumigaya ang ating bayanTayo'y magsikap upang makamtan natin ang kasaganahanTayo'y mangagsiawitHabang ang mundo'y tahimikAng araw ay sumapitSa sanggol na dulot ng langitTayo ay magmahalanAting sundin ang gintong aralAt magbuhat ngayon kahit hindi pasko ay magbigayan"},{"question":"Ano ang sorting algorithm?","answer":"Ang sorting ay pag-aayos ng isang grupo ng data sa isang partikular na paraan ayon sa kinakailangan. Ang mga algorithm na tumutulong sa pagsasagawa nito ay tinatawag na sorting algorithms. Karaniwang ginagamit ang mga sorting algorithm upang pagbukud-bukurin ang mga grupo o mga element ng data sa paraang ascending o descending. May iba't-ibang uri ng sorting algorithms depende sa bilis nito kagaya ng shell sort, quick sort, bubble sort, at selection sort."},{"question":"Izihlabathi ziyaqibana ngempela uma ubheka ngasohlangothinilezimfashini. Phambilini uma ukhuluma ngemfashini ubusukeubhekise ezingutsheni zokugqoka kuphela. Nokho-ke isikhathisesiguqukile ngoba sekukuningi kakhulu okubizwa ngemfashiningaphandle kwezingubo zokugqoka. Indlela yokulungisa izinwele,uhlobo lwezimoto olungajwayelekile, omakhalekhukhwini konkelokhu kuyaba imfashini. Uma imfashini ethile isangenisile baningiabantu ababa nesiqiniseko sokuthi ayibedluli. Abanye bancamelaukutsheleka imadlana okukanye bayintshontshe ukuze bazibusisengemfashini.Akuve kudabukisa nokho-ke ukufica umuntuesezimpintshe kabuhlungu ngesiketi noma ngebhulukwe egamenilokuthi imfashini. Imfashini phela nayo iyabhekelelwa. Kwesinyeisikhathi kuhle nje ukuthi uyiyeke imfashini yedlule ungazangeuzihluphe ngayo. Abantu abaningi bazithola sebengonomafashiningenxa yokuthi bafuna ukwamukeleka kubangani babo. Basukebefuna ukusika ukhasi emiphakathini abahlala kuyo. Imisakazonamaphephandaba iyazama ukunqanda lesi sihlava ngokuthi kubenezinhlelo ezithize ezikhuluma ngobubi nobuhle bezimfashini. 1. Lungisa amaphutha emshweni wokuqala kulesi siqeshana. Phinda uwubhaleumusho","answer":"Izihlabathi ziyagqibana ngempela uma ubheka ngasohlangothinilwezimfashini. "},{"question":"Суу жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Суу 💧 атасы- булак,Сөз атасы- 👂кулак."},{"question":"වොෂිංටන් ප්‍රාන්තයේ ට්‍රවුට් සඳහා මාළු පියාසර කළ යුත්තේ කොතැනින්ද?","answer":"වොෂිංටන් ප්‍රාන්තයේ ට්‍රවුට් සඳහා මසුන් ඇල්ලීම සඳහා ජනප්‍රිය ජල කඳන් වන්නේ යකිමා ගඟ, නාචේස් ගඟ, ස්නොක්වාල්මි හි මැද දෙබල සහ පුගෙට් ශබ්දයේ වෙරළයි. සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න ට්‍රවුට් ගහනයකට සහාය වීමට සියලුම විල්වලට නොහැකි වුවද, වොෂින්ටනයේ උස් විල්වල විශිෂ්ට ට්‍රවුට් මසුන් ඇල්ලීම ද ඔබට සොයාගත හැකිය."},{"question":"Do que é feita a seda artificial?","answer":"Ao contrário da seda natural, que é feita de casulos de bicho-da-seda, a seda artificial é produzida por tratamento químico e fiação de fibras naturais, como polpa de madeira, bambu ou algodão. O tecido resultante se assemelha muito à seda em termos de aparência e toque, mas a um custo muito menor. A seda artificial é também mais versátil do que a seda real e pode ser tingida em uma ampla gama de cores. É também mais respirável e absorvente do que a seda real. No entanto, é mais propensa a rugas e encolhimento, e pode não durar tanto quanto a seda real."},{"question":"Бул жомоктун уландысын жазып берчи: \\"— Уулум чынында эле өтө кымбат баалуу таш алып келген экенсиң. Эми сабыр кылгын. Инилериң дагы кандай кымбат баалуу таш алып келишер экен. Ошондон кийин гана бак маселесин чечебиз.\\"","answer":"Бул жомоктун уландысы мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Ортончу уулу да кымбат таш издеп, бир деңиздин боюна жетип келди. Ал жерде суучулдар сууга түнгүп, деңиз түбүнөн кымбат баалуу таштарды алып чыгышты.\\""},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Negara yang terkenal dengan satu menara yang tinggi","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Perancis"},{"question":"Klassisk dörrgåta! Du är inne i ett mystiskt tempel och du ställs inför tre dörrar. Bakom dörr nummer ett döljer sig en svärm av vildsinta getingar. Bakom dörr nummer två finns dödliga ormar av alla de slag. Slutligen, bakom dörr nummer tre, finns en hord utsvultna tigrar som inte ätit på månader. Vilken dörr väljer du?","answer":"Jag väljer den tredje dörren. Tigrarna är förmodligen döda efter månader utan mat!"},{"question":" Жон Нихардт интервью берген жана кийинчерээк ал жөнүндө жазган кишинин аты ким эле?","answer":"Black Elk (кара илк)"},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta ¿Cuál libro de Una canción de hielo y fuego se lanzó en el año 1998?","answer":"La respuesta es Choque de Reyes. "},{"question":"السؤال: إذا طهرت المرأة في رمضان قبل أذان الفجر، فهل يجب عليها الصوم؟","answer":"الإجابة: ذا طهرت المرأة قبل أذان الفجر وجب عليها الصيام؛ لزوال المانع. ويجب أن تنوي الصيام قبل الفجر ثم تغتسل لتصلي سواء قبل الفجر أو بعده."},{"question":"भारतातील सर्वात महत्त्वाचा लघु उद्योग कोणता आहे?(A) हातमाग उद्योग(B) गुर व खंदसारी(C) लेदर उद्योग(D) कुंभाराचे उत्पादन=>","answer":" (A) हातमाग उद्योग"},{"question":"شنا هي عاصمة إسبانيا ؟","answer":"مدريد"},{"question":"ਆਦਿ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦਾ ਸਿੱਖ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਵਿਚ ਕੀ ਮਹੱਤਵ ਹੈ ? ‘","answer":"ਆਦਿ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦੇ ਸੰਕਲਨ ਨਾਲ ਸਿੱਖ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਠੋਸ ਨੀਂਹ ਮਿਲੀ ।ਉਹ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਲਈ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਮਾਣਿਕ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਜਨਮ, ਨਾਮਕਰਨ, ਵਿਆਹ, ਮੌਤ ਆਦਿ ਸਭ ਸੰਸਕਾਰ ਇਸੇ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਨੂੰ ਗਵਾਹ ਮੰਨ ਕੇ ਸੰਪੰਨ ਹੋਣ ਲੱਗੇ । ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਆਦਿ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜਾਤੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਜਾਗਿਤ ਹੋਈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਅਲੱਗ ਪੰਥ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿਚ ਉਭਰਨ ਲੱਗੇ ।ਅੱਗੇ ਚੱਲ ਕੇ ਇਸ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਨੂੰ “ਗੁਰੁ ਪਦ’ ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਸਭ ਸਿੱਖ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਮੰਨ ਕੇ ਪੂਜਣ ਲੱਗੇ । ਅੱਜ ਸਭ ਸਿੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਵਿਚ ਸੰਹਿਤ ਗੁਰੁ ਬਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਅਲੌਕਿਕ ਗਿਆਨ ਦਾ ਭੰਡਾਰ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹਨ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਰਧਾਪੂਰਵਕ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਸੱਚਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"इंग्रज व मराठे यांच्यात एकूण किती युध्द झाले?","answer":"इंग्रज व मराठे यांच्यात एकूण तीन युध्द झाले."},{"question":"為什麼要修建萬里長城？","answer":"　　秦始皇建長城的主要目的是為了抵禦匈奴的入侵。秦朝統一了全國的同時，北方的匈奴也從一盤散沙匯合成一個較為統一的國家，遊牧民族逐水草而居，沒有固定的居住地，討伐起來極其困難，不能進攻就只能防守了，為了消除秦皇朝的隱患，秦始皇才不得不選擇修建萬里長城。"},{"question":"ゴルフボールの表面につけられているくぼみのことを何というでしょう？","answer":"ディンプル"},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Mitos dan cerita rakyat menggambarkan kepercayaan dan nilai-nilai budaya.","answer":"Mitos jeung carita rahayat ngagambarkeun kapercayaan jeung ajén budaya."},{"question":"புதுமைப்பித்தன் என்ற புனைப்பெயர் கொண்ட சொ. விருத்தாசலம் மிகச்சிறந்த தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்களுள் ஒருவர். நவீன தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தின் ஒரு முன்னோடியாக இவர் கருதப்படுகிறார். கூரிய சமூக விமர்சனமும் நையாண்டியும், முற்போக்குச் சிந்தனையும், இலக்கியச் சுவையும் கொண்ட இவருடைய படைப்புகள், இவரின் தனித்தன்மையினை நிறுவுகின்றன. இவரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"புதுமைப்பித்தனின் மேற்கோள்:பொதுவாக என்னுடைய கதைகள் உலகத்துக்கு உபதேசம் செய்யும் ஸ்தாபனம் அல்ல! பிற்கால நல்வாழ்வுக்கு சௌகரியம் பண்ணி வைக்கும் இன்ஷ்யூரன்ஸ் ஏற்பாடும் அல்ல. எனக்குப் பிடிக்கிறவர்களையும் பிடிக்காதவர்களையும் கிண்டல் செய்து கொண்டிருக்கிறேன். சிலர் என்னோடு சேர்ந்துகொண்டு சிரிக்கிறார்கள். இன்னும் சிலர் கோபிக்கிறார்கள்."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты: \\"Скрипач Эйнштейн\\". Эйнштейн скрипкада ойногонду жакшы көрчү жана бир жолу Германиядагы кайрымдуулук концертине катышкан.  Анын аткаруусуна суктанган жергиликтүү журналист \\"артисттин\\" атын билип, эртеси гезитке улуу музыкант, теңдешсиз виртуоз скрипач Альберт Эйнштейндин аткаруусу жөнүндө жазуу жарыялаган. Ал бул жазууну сактап, тааныштарына сыймыктануу менен көрсөтүп, чындыгында окумуштуу эмес, белгилүү скрипач экендигин айткан."},{"question":"Waxaad  Sheegtaa kumuu ahaa madaxweynihii ugu horeyey ee afrikaan ah ee kursiga madaxtinimada si xor ah kaga daga?","answer":" Madaxweynihii ugu horeyey ee afrikaan ah ee kursiga madaxtinimada si xor ah kaga daga wuxu ahaa Aadan Cabdule Cusmaan (Aadan Cadde)."},{"question":"Content: ਕੋਰੋਨਾਵਾਇਰਸ ਕਾਰਨ 16 ਮਾਰਚ, 2020 ਤੋਂ ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰ ਲਾਂਘਾ ਬੰਦ ਸੀ।ਨੋਟੀਫਿਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਜਾਰੀ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਮੰਤਰਾਲੇ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਵਿਡ-19 ਦੇ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੁਧਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰ ਲਾਂਘਾ ਮੁੜ ਖੋਲ੍ਹਣ ਦਾ ਫੈਸਲਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ।ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸ਼ਰਧਾਲੂ ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰ ਲਾਂਘੇ ਸਬੰਧੀ 2019 ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀਤੇ ਦੁਵੱਲੇ ਸਮਝੌਤੇ ਤਹਿਤ ਸਵੇਰ ਤੋਂ ਸ਼ਾਮ ਤੱਕ ਗੁਰਦੁਆਰਾ ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਆ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ।ਸਥਾਨਕ ਸ਼ਰਧਾਲੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਵੇਰ ਤੋਂ ਸ਼ਾਮ ਤੱਕ ਆਉਣ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ। ਪਰ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਕੋਵਿਡ-19 ਸਬੰਧੀ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।ਪੀਐੱਸਜੀਪੀਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਲਾਘਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬ ਤੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਤਿੱਖਾ ਵਿਰੋਧ, ਭਾਜਪਾ ਦੀ ਮਨਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼","answer":"ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਰਧਾਲੂਆਂ ਲਈ ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰ ਲਾਂਘਾ ਸ਼ੁੱਕਰਵਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਮੁੜ ਖੋਲ੍ਹ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"*كم محيطا في العالم ؟","answer":"5 محيطات"},{"question":"Kudala ngezikhathi zeNkosi uShaka, kuthiwa kwakukhona indoda yakwaNzimandeeyayihlekisa nangento engafanele. Igama layo kwakunguVelaphansi. UVelaphansiwayehola abantu bakwaNzimande ngalezo zikhathi zikaShaka. AbantubakwaNzimande badume ngezithakazelo zoGwala kanye noMphephethe.AMaphephethe ayengasebenzi. Ayenekhono lokukhetha usawoti esihlabathini.Isithakazelo sikaMphephethe savela ngoba babephephetha isihlabathi solwandlekusawoti. Uma-ke usawoti sebewunekile waze woma, babewuthatha bawusongengezikhumba bawuyise eNdlunkulu.ISilo uShaka wayebathanda abantu bakwaNzimande ngenxa yokuthiwayekhonze uVelaphansi. Phela uVelaphansi wayehola aMaphephethe futhiedume ngokuba noteku. UShaka wayezifela ngomuntu otekulayo. ISilo sagcinasesikwenza kwaba wumthetho ukuthi uVelaphansi abe ngusomahlayawaseNdlunkulu. UVelaphansi wayesholo isilo amahlaya njalo uma siphumulilenoma kukhona izivakashi. Sesiyohleka-ke iSilo kujabule wonke umuntu. Akekhoongeke ajabule uma ebona okaNdaba emoyizela.Langa limbe uVelaphansi wacabanga ukuthi uzosihlekisa ngani iSilo umaesebizwa ukuzokwenza amahlaya. Wacabanga wacabanga, do ukufika ihlayaelisha. Akufuneki phela ukuthi asho ihlaya elidala futhi elaziwayo eNdlunkulu. Kubikakhulu uma lelo hlaya selake lashiwo nguyena. Akafuneki ukuthi adlalengezindlebe zeSilo. Wafika umcabango ngokushesha. Wahlala yedwa umfokaMphephethe. Wayesephumile osizini ngoba ihlaya elisha seliqhamukile.Wadumela amaqaqa amabili azifele wawasonga ngesikhumba esikhulusengwe. Safika ngaleso sikhathi isithunywa esivela eNkosini uShaka. INkosiyayifuna ukuthi uVelaphansi enze adume ngakho.'Hlanga Lezwe! Ngiphathele iNkosi yami engiyithandayo futhi engiziqhenyangayo isipho esihle kabi,' washo uVelaphansi evula isikhumba sengwe kuthaphukaumsanka odabula ukhakhayi.Phela amaqaqa ayesedlulele ngokubola. Lavimbanisa iququ endlini kwavakashaizimpethu ngokushesha. ISilo sahleka inhlinini ngesenzo sikaVelaphansi. Izindunazesaba ukwenanela ngokuhleka ngoba zabona ukuthi uMphephetheunamagangangozi. Kwahlukwana esephelile amahlaya.Kukhona abaluma uVelaphansi indlebe ukuthi iSilo sidinwe sithelwa ngamanzingalesi senzo asenzile. Basho bengananazi ukuthi uzulelwa ngamanqe umaengabaleki.1. Chaza kafushane ubudlelwano phakathi kwehlaya likaVelaphansi nesishoesilandelayo.","answer":"Ubudlelwane obukhona phakathi kwesisho nehlaya ukuthi isisho sichazaukudelela njengoba uVelaphansi wadelela iSilo ngokwenza ihlayangamaqaqa anukayo."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند: او در ۱۹۱۸ اقدام به تشکیل یک گردان از دانشجویان محیط‌بانی دو کالج کرد. در جنگ داخلی فنلاندوی در سال ۱۹۱۴ به استخدام ارتش امپراتوری روسیه درآمد و در جنگ جهانی اول در خلیج ریگا حضور داشت، پس از انقلاب روسیه به فنلاند رفت و به گارد سفید فنلاند پیوست. ","answer":"در این متن در مورد جنگ داخلی فنلاند صحبت شده است."},{"question":"Doc to summarize: ఆధార్ సమాచారం దుర్వినియోగం అవుతోందని కొందరు, ఆధార్ లేకపోవడం వల్ల రేషన్ అందక మరణించిన వారు కొందరు.. ఇలా ఆధార్ నిత్యం వార్తల్లో నిలుస్తోంది. ఈ నేపథ్యంలో బీబీసీ కొందరు నిపుణులతో మాట్లాడి ఆధార్‌పై సందేహాలను నివృత్తి చేసే ప్రయత్నం చేస్తోంది. ఆధార్ సిరీస్‌లో ఇది మొదటి భాగం. ఇతరుల వద్ద నా ఆధార్ సంఖ్య ఉంటే వారు ఎలాంటి సమాచారాన్ని పొందగలరు? ఆధార్‌పై ఇప్పటివరకు ప్రభుత్వం చెబుతున్నదాన్ని బట్టి, ఎవరూ మీ ఆధార్ సంఖ్య ఆధారంగా మీ గురించి ఎలాంటి సమాచారాన్ని పొందే అవకాశం లేదు. థర్డ్ పార్టీ కూడా మీ ఆధార్ సంఖ్య, పేరు, ఒక్కోసారి  వేలిముద్రల వివరాలను డాటాబేస్‌కు పంపుతుంది. అవి సరిపోలితే 'యస్' అని, సరిపోకపోతే 'నో' అని మాత్రమే డాటాబేస్ ప్రతిస్పందిస్తుంది. ఇంకో మాట చెప్పాలంటే, అది కేవలం ధ్రువీకరించడానికి మాత్రమే ఉపయోగపడుతుంది. ఇంకో అదనపు ధృవీకరణ విధానం కూడా ఉంది. చట్టప్రకారం 'నో యువర్ కస్టమర్' (మీ కస్టమర్ గురించి తెలుసుకోండి) ప్రక్రియను పూర్తి చేయాల్సిన సంస్థలు లేదా సర్వీస్ ప్రొవైడర్లు లింగం, వయసు, చిరునామా మొదలైన వివరాలను పొందవచ్చు. ఆధార్ సంఖ్య ఆధారంగా యూఐడీఏఐ ఈ ఈ-కేవైసీ విధానాన్ని రూపొందించింది. దీని ప్రకారం టెలికాం ఆపరేటర్లు కాగితం ఫారాలను నింపడానికి బదులుగా, ఎలెక్ట్రానిక్ విధానంలో వేగంగా వాటిని నింపగలుగుతున్నారు. దీంతో టెలికాం సంస్థలు కేవలం పేరు, వేలిముద్ర ఆధారంగా యూఐడీ డాటాబేస్ సదరు వినియోగదారునికి సంబంధించిన చిరునామా, లింగం, వయసు తదితర వివరాలను తెలుసుకోగలిగే అవకాశం ఉంది. ఇతర ప్రైవేట్ సంస్థలు, థర్డ్ పార్టీలు కూడా తమకు లభించిన ఆధార్ సమాచారంతో మీ ఇతర వివరాలను అనుసంధానిస్తూ తమ సొంత డాటాబేస్‌ను సృష్టించుకోవచ్చు. ఆధార్‌ను బలంగా వ్యతిరేకిస్తున్న డిజిటల్ రైట్స్ కార్యకర్త నిఖిల్ పాహ్వా బీబీసీతో మాట్లాడుతూ.. అదనపు సమాచారాన్ని పొందడానికి ఆధార్ సంఖ్య ఒక మార్గం అని తెలిపారు. డిసెంబర్‌లో యూఐడీఏఐ ఒక నెంబర్‌ను ట్వీట్ చేసింది. మీరు ఆ నెంబర్‌కు ఆధార్ సంఖ్యను ఎస్సెమ్మెస్ చేస్తే,  మీ ఆధార్‌ను ఏ బ్యాంకుతో జతపరిచారో (అకౌంట్ నెంబర్ కాదు) మెసేజ్ వస్తుంది. ఇలాంటి వాటితో మోసాలు కూడా జరిగే వీలుంది.''చాలా మందికి తాము బ్యాంకు నుంచి ఫోన్ చేస్తున్నామని, వాళ్ల ఓటీపీ చెప్పమని ఫోన్ కాల్స్ వస్తుంటాయి. ఇదంతా మోసపూరితంగా బ్యాంక్ అకౌంట్ నుంచి సొమ్మును తమ అకౌంట్‌లోకి ట్రాన్స్‌ఫర్ చేయడానికే'' అని పాహ్వా తెలిపారు. ","answer":"ఆధార్ అమలులోకి వచ్చి ఎనిమిదేళ్లు గడుస్తున్నా, అది నేటికీ వివాదాస్పదమే."},{"question":"Among which of the sentiment categories would you classify the following tweet? positive, negative, or neutral@user 🤣🤣🤣🤣🤣🤣🤣🤣  wannan rigiman gida ne ba ruwan ka barni da baba Na @user","answer":"I would classify the given tweet as: neutral."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'perang mulut'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Maksud peribahasa 'perang mulut' adalah bertengkar. Contoh ayat: Daun pokok rambutan menjadi punca perang mulut antara Mak Siput dan Mak Siti."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو أصغر بحر في العالم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: بحر سامار"},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:ولفتت المجلة إلى أنه بالرغم من محاولاتهما لإظهار جبهة \\"أيديولوجية\\" مشتركة، فقد لا يكون بوتين وكيم على استعداد لتلبية مطالب بعضهما بعضا بشكل كامل.وعلى سبيل المثال، قد تسعى كوريا الشمالية إلى الحصول على تقنية الدفع","answer":"النووي البحري الروسية الحساسة، التي من غير المرجح أن تتخلى عنها موسكو مقابل القليل في المقابل. وبالمثل، قد تسعى روسيا إلى الحصول على صواريخ كورية شمالية أكثر تطورا للاستخدام المحتمل في أوكرانيا، لكن كيم قد يفضل الاحتفاظ بها من أجل دفاعه الوطني وقوة الردع الخاص ببلده."},{"question":"Hoàn thành các phép tính sau:Tính:a) (– 48) + (– 67);b) (– 79) + (– 45).","answer":"Lời giải:a) (– 48) + (– 67) = – (48 + 67) = – 115. b) (– 79) + (– 45) = – (79 + 45) = – 124."},{"question":"n (Φ) విలువను తెల్పండి.","answer":"n (Φ) = 0"},{"question":"दिगो कृषिका सिद्धान्तहरू व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"दिगो कृषिले भविष्यका पुस्ताको क्षमतामा सम्झौता नगरी वर्तमान खाद्यान्न आवश्यकताहरू पूरा गर्ने लक्ष्य राख्दै वातावरणमैत्री अभ्यास, स्रोत संरक्षण र लचिलोपनमा केन्द्रित छ।"},{"question":"对于校园贷有什么建议？","answer":"对于在校大学生来说，最好的建议是避免无谓的借贷，尤其是高利率的校园贷。要理性消费，按照自己的经济能力来规划生活和消费。如果确实需要借款，应选择正规金融机构，并确保自己有偿还能力。"},{"question":"ප්‍රසාරණය යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"ප්‍රසාරණය යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය සංකෝචනය වේ. "},{"question":"Inona no volana fahafito amin'ny teny gasy?","answer":"Ny volana fahafito amin'ny teny gasy dia Jolay."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Marie Curie para a química?","answer":"Marie Curie foi pioneira no estudo da radioatividade, descobrindo os elementos polônio e rádio. Sua pesquisa inovadora estabeleceu as bases para a teoria nuclear e teve aplicações significativas em medicina."},{"question":"वर्धन घराण्यातील सर्वात कुशल राजा कोण होता ?","answer":"हर्षवर्धन  "},{"question":"Ano ang damdamin ng pahayag na ito?\\"Noong isang taon ko pa huling nakita ang kaibigan ko, hindi na ko makapaghintay para sa pagkikita namin bukas!\\"","answer":"Nagpapahiwatig ng pananabik o kagalakan ang pahayag. Sabik na sabik nang makita ng nagsasalita ang kanyang kaibigan dahil matagal na nang huli silang nagkita."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo            sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waxa ay ahaayeen 8 gobol.Sheeg Magaca qoraaga Soomaaliyeedbee qoray Buugga “Taariikhda Daraawiishta”? "},{"question":"ઓણમ તહેવાર અને તેનું મહત્વ જણાવો.","answer":"ઓણમ એ દક્ષિણ ભારતના રાજ્ય કેરળનો સૌથી મોટો ઉત્સવ છે. આ ઉત્સવ મલયાલી કેલેન્ડરના પ્રથમ મહિના એટલે કે ચિંગમ (ઓગષ્ટ-સપ્ટેમ્બર)માં દંતકથારૂપ રાજા મહાબલિના ઘેર પરત આવવાના પ્રસંગને યાદ કરવા માટે ઉજવાય છે. આ ઉજવણી દસ દિવસ સુધી ચાલે છે અને તે કેરળની સંસ્કૃતિ અને પરંપરાના ઘણા ઘટકો સાથે જોડાયેલી છે. અટપટી ફૂલોની જાજમ, વિવિધ વાનગીઓ સાથેનું જમણ, હોડીઓની સ્પર્ધા અને કઇકોટ્ટિકલી નૃત્ય એ આ તહેવારમાં રંગત જમાવે છે. આ તહેવાર માટે, લોકો નવા કપડા પહેરે છે: પુરૂષો શર્ટ અને મુન્ડ (ઓફ-વ્હાઇટ રંગની લાંબી લુંગી), સ્ત્રીઓ મુન્ડુ, નરિયાતું તરીકે ઓળખાતી ગોલ્ડ પટ્ટી વાળી પોષાક. છોકરીઓ પાવડા તરીકે ઓળખાતું સ્કર્ટ, અને કબ્જો પહેરે છે. ઓણમ એ કેરળમાં કાપણીનો તહેવાર છે.ઓણમ એ ખૂબ પ્રાચિન તહેવાર છે. હજુ આજના આધુનિક સમયમાં પણ તે ઉજવાય છે. કેરળનો ચોખાની લણણીનો તહેવાર અને મલયાલમ મહિના ચિંગમમાં આવતા વરસાદી ફૂલના તહેવારને રાજા માવેલિની પાથાલમની વાર્ષિક મુલાકાત તરીકે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. પ્રાચિન સમયથી રાજા માવેલિને કેરળના લોકો દ્વારા આદરભાવ આપવામાં આવે છે ત્યારથી ઓણમ એક અનોખો તહેવાર છે.દંતકથા પ્રમાણે, રાજા મહાબલિના શાસનકાળ દરમિયાન કેરળનો સૂવર્ણયુગ હતો. રાજ્યના તમામ લોકો આનંદી અને સુખી હતા અને રાજા ખૂબ જ માન ધરાવતો હતો. આ બધા જ ગુણો ઉપરાંત, મહાબલિ ફક્ત એક દુર્ગુણ ધરાવતો હતો. તે અહંકારી હતો. આમ છતાં, મહાબલિ દ્વારા કરવામાં આવેલા સારા કાર્યોને કારણે, ભગવાને તેને એક વરદાન આપ્યું હતું કે જેથી તે તેના લોકોને વર્ષે એક વાર મળી શકે કે જેમની સાથે તે મનથી જોડાયેલો હતો. આ મહાબલિની તે મુલાકાત છે જેને પ્રત્યેક વર્ષે ઓણમ તરીકે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. લોકો ખૂબ જ ધામધૂમથી આ તહેવારની ઉજવણી કરે છે અને તેમના માનીતા રાજાને સંદેશો આપે છે કે તેઓ ખુશ છે અને તેઓ શુભેચ્છા પણ પાઠવે છે. દસ દિવસ સુધી ચાલતી આ ઉજવણીમાં કેરળનો સમૃદ્ધ સાંસ્કૃતિક વારસો તેના શ્રેષ્ઠ સ્વરૂપમાં ખીલી ઉઠે છે. તીરૂઓણમને દિવસે તૈયાર કરવામાં આવતી ઓનાસાડ્યા નામની મહાભોજનની મિઠાઇ ઓણમની ઉજવણીનો સૌથી મહત્વનો ભાગ છે. તે ભોજનમાં નવ અલગ પ્રકારની વાનગીઓ હોય છે અને તેમાં ૧૧ થી ૧૩ જરૂરી થાળીનો સમાવેશ થાય છે. ઓનાસાડ્યાને કેળના પાન ઉપર પિરસવામાં આવે છે અને ભોજન આરોગવા માટે લોકો જમીન પર સાદડી પાથરીને બેસે છે.ઓણમની અન્ય આકર્ષક બાબત સર્પાકારની હોડીની સ્પર્ધા એટલે કે વલ્લમકલ્લી છે, જે પંબા નદી પર યોજાય છે. એકસાથે ઘણા બધા નાવિકો ગીતો ગાતા શણગારેલી હોડીને ચલાવતા હોય અને પ્રેક્ષકો તેમને ઉત્સાહ આપતા હોય તે દ્રશ્ય ખૂબ જ આહલાદક છે. ઓણમના દિવસે સંયુક્ત રીતે રમત રમવાનો પણ રિવાજ છે, જેને ઓનાકાલિકલ તરીકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. પુરૂષો તલપ્પાન્તુકાલી(દડા સાથેની રમત), અમ્બેય્યાલ (તીરંદાજી), કુટુકુટુ અને કાય્યાન્કાલિ અને અટ્ટકાલમ જેવી લડાઇ સ્પર્ધા જેવી ભારે રમતો રમે છે. મહિલાઓ સાંસ્કૃતિક પ્રવૃત્તિઓમાં વ્યસ્ત રહે છે. તેઓ રાજા મહાબલિને આવકારવા માટે તેમના ઘરના આંગણામાં જટીલ રીતે બનાવવામાં આવેલી ફુલોની સાદડી, પૂકાલમ બનાવે છે. ઓણમના દિવસે મહિલાઓ કઇકોટ્ટિ કાલિ અને તુમ્પી તુલ્લાલ જેવા બે મનમોહક નૃત્યો કરે છે. કુમ્માટ્ટિ કાલિ અને પુલિકાલિ જેવા લોકગીતો પરનું નૃત્ય ઉજવણીના ઉલ્લાસમાં વધારો કરે છે.મહાબલિનો શાસનકાળ કેરળ માટે સૂવર્ણયુગ ગણાય છે."},{"question":"ما هو عدد مخارج الحروف ؟]","answer":"\\t17 مخرجًا"},{"question":"Sheeg Goorma Ayuu Dhacay Heshiiskii Xudeybiya ?","answer":"Wuxu Dhacay Sanadkii 6-Aad Ee Hijriyada."},{"question":"Kodi ntchito ya apolisi a Malawi ndi yotani?","answer":"Apolisi a Malawi ali ndi udindo wotsata malamulo oyendetsera dziko lino pokhazikitsa malamulo pozindikira kuti pali umbanda, kugwira anthu oganiziridwa ndi kuwazenga mlandu m’makhothi poteteza moyo ndi katundu."},{"question":"Jaswant Singh","answer":"Major Jaswant Singh (3 Oṣu Kini ọdun 1938 - 27 Oṣu Kẹsan 2020) jẹ oṣiṣẹ ti Ọmọ ogun India ati Minisita fun Igbimọ India. O jẹ ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ ti o da silẹ ti Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP)."},{"question":"ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਨੇ ਫੈਸਲਾ ਸੁਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਬੰਧ ਅਪਰਾਧ ਨਹੀਂ।ਇੱਕ ਗੇਅ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਤੋਂ ਸਪਸ਼ਟ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਡਰ ਹਨ। ਜੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਜਿਨਸੀ ਰੁਝਾਣ ਨੂੰ ਕਬੂਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ 'ਤੇ ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਅਸਰ ਪਏਗਾ। ਇਸ ਸ਼ਖਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਨਤਕ ਨਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਅਹਿਸਾਸ ਹੋਇਆ ਕਿ ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ 13 ਸਾਲ ਦਾ ਸੀ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਵੱਖਰਾ ਹਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਇੱਕ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਵੱਖਰੇ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ ਪੋਰਨ ਲੱਭ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਸਕੂਲ ਜਾਂ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੁੱਲੇ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਚਰਚਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ।ਮੈ ਇੱਕ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਲਿਆ ਸੀ। ਉੱਥੇ ਗੇਅ ਹੋਣਾ ਅਸਵੀਕਰਿਤ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਉਮੀਦ ਜਤਾਈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ। ਮੈਂ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਇਕ ਛੋਟੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਕਸਬੇ ਤੋਂ ਹਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਿਆ।ਮੈਂ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਸੂਬੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਆਜ਼ਾਦ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਸੀ। ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਤੋਂ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਇੱਕ ਮੁੰਡਾ ਗੇਅ ਹੱਕਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਾਫੀ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਬੋਲਦਾ ਸੀ।ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰੀ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮਦਦਗਾਰ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਹੁਣ ਮੇਰੀ ਅਸਲੀਅਤ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ੇਅ ਡੇਟਿੰਗ ਐਪਸ ਦੱਸੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕੀਤੀ। ਮੈਂ ਡੇਟਿੰਗ ਅਤੇ ਜਿਨਸੀ ਸਬੰਧ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕੀਤੀ। 'ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਗੇਅ ਹਾਂ'ਹੋਸਟਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕੋ ਮੁੰਡੇ ਨੂੰ ਦੋ ਵਾਰੀ ਮਿਲਣ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਅਹਿਸਾਸ ਹੋਇਆ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਆਮ ਮੁੰਡਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਾਂ। ਗਰਮੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਦਿਨ ਸਨ ਅਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਦੁਪਹਿਰ ਨੂੰ ਖਾਣਾ ਖਾਣ ਗਿਆ। ਖਾਣੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਾਪਸ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸਣਾ ਹੈ।13 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਸ਼ਖਸ ਨੂੰ ਅਹਿਸਾਸ ਹੋਇਆ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਗੇਅ ਹੈ। (ਸੰਕੇਤਿਕ ਤਸਵੀਰ)ਮੈਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੋਚਿਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਕਹਾਂਗਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਡਰਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਮੁੰਡੇ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੋਚ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਯਕੀਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੁਝ ਫਿਕਰਮੰਦ ਲੱਗੇ। ਮੈਂ ਬੋਲਣ ਤੋਂ ਡਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਕੀ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ?\\" ਦੂਜੇ ਦੋਸਤ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਸਾਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਦੇ।\\" ਮੇਰੇ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਨਿਕਲਿਆ, \\"ਮੈਂ ਗੇਅ ਹਾਂ।\\" ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਦੋਸਤ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਥਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਘੁੱਟ ਲਿਆ। ਦੂਜਾ ਦੋਸਤ ਆਇਆ ਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗਲੇ ਲਾ ਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਸ਼ੱਕ ਸੀ। ਫਿਰ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਠੀਕ ਹੈ। ਕੋਈ ਵੱਡੀ ਗੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਸੀਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਫਿਰ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਰਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੈਠੇ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਘੰਟਾ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡਾ ਪੱਲ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਕਦੇ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਪਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਭੈਣ-ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਗੁਪਤ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਦੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਭਰੋਸਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਤੋੜਿਆ।ਮੈਂ ਗੇਅ ਪਰੇਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ।ਪਰ ਮੈਂ ਇੱਕ ਪਰੇਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਹਾਲੇ ਵੀ ਡਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਉਹ ਪਰੇਡ ਟੀਵੀ 'ਤੇ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਮੇਰੇ ਵਰਗੇ ਪਿਛੋਕੜ ਵਾਲੇ ਸ਼ਖਸ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਪਰੇਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੱਲਣਾ ਅਜੀਬ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਪਰੇਡਜ਼ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਫਾਇਦੇਮੰਦ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਗਦੀਆਂ। ਹੋਮੋਫੋਬੀਆ (ਐਲਜੀਬੀਟੀ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਨਕਾਰਾਤਮਕ ਭਾਵਨਾ) ਹਾਲੇ ਵੀ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ। 'ਮੈਂ ਗੇਅ ਪਰੇਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਹਾਲੇ ਵੀ ਡਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ' ।ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਾਲਜ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਘਟਨਾ ਯਾਦ ਹੈ। ਇੱਕ ਪੁਰਾਣਾ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਹੋਸਟਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੁੰਡਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਸੀ। ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਹਿਯੋਗੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਮੁੰਡੇ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਕੀਤਾ। ਇੱਕ ਮੁੰਡੇ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, 'ਕੀ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਗੇਅ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਜ਼ੋਰਦੀ ਹੱਸਣ ਲੱਗੇ।' ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਲਤ ਕੀ ਹੈ? "},{"question":"Di manakah terletaknya Pahang? ","answer":"Pahang ialah negeri yang ketiga terbesar di Malaysia. Terletak di lembangan Sungai Pahang yang amat luas, negeri Pahang bersempadan dengan: Kelantan di utara; Perak, Selangor serta Negeri Sembilan di barat; Johor di selatan; dan Terengganu dan Laut China Selatan di timur."},{"question":"Viết bài báo có thể sử dụng tiêu đề sau: Sai lầm chiến thuật có thể làm suy yếu phòng tuyến Nga ở Ukraine","answer":"Nga đã phạm phải sai lầm chiến thuật khi đầu tư quá nhiều công sức, lực lượng cho hệ thống phòng thủ đầu tiên trải dài hàng trăm km, khiến các lớp phòng thủ phía sau mỏng hơn rất nhiều. Sai lầm đó sẽ bộc lộ khi phòng tuyến đầu tiên bị vỡ và Ukraine dồn lực xuyên phá, phát triển mũi tấn công.Michael Kofman, nhà phân tích quốc phòng và thành viên cấp cao tại Quỹ Carnegie vì Hòa bình Quốc tế, cho biết Ukraine đang tìm cách phá vỡ tiếp phòng tuyến thứ hai của Nga và nhiệm vụ có lẽ sẽ dễ dàng hơn so với việc công phá lớp \\"lá chắn\\" đầu tiên.Các tướng lĩnh Ukraine cũng có chung nhận định, cho rằng về lý thuyết, trận địa phòng ngự của Nga được bố trí theo chiều sâu, nhiều tầng, nhiều lớp, cho phép binh sĩ tuyến đầu có thể lùi về sau để tái bố trí lực lượng, kìm hãm bước tiến của đối phương.Trận địa phòng ngự này được xây dựng theo ý tưởng của tướng Sergei Surovikin, người từng chỉ huy toàn bộ chiến dịch tại đây. Tuy nhiên, Surovikin sau đó mất chức và gần như không còn xuất hiện sau cuộc nổi loạn của tập đoàn quân sự tư nhân Wagner hồi tháng 6. Tướng Surovikin được cho là có mối liên hệ mật thiết với Wagner.Người thay thế tướng Surovikin là Tổng tham mưu trưởng Valery Gerasimov, người có tư duy chiến lược khác biệt. Trong khi Surovikin muốn triển khai thế trận phòng thủ tại chỗ cổ điển, tướng Gerasimov lại muốn áp dụng tư duy \\"phòng ngự chủ động\\", tiến hành các đợt phản công theo nhiều hướng thay vì ở yên trong chiến hào đợi địch."},{"question":"Erantzun galdera zail honi: Zer gangster bandaren kidea izan zen Vincent Drucci?","answer":"North Side Gang-eko kidea zen"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa maxaa loo-aqoon jiray caasimada Itoobiya (Ethiopia)?","answer":"Waxa loo-aqoon jiray Fin-Finaay."},{"question":"请问“吃着碗里瞧着锅里”是什么意思？","answer":"这句谚语比喻贪心不足。"},{"question":"Wat wordt wel de sterkste spier van het menselijk lichaam genoemd?– Het hart– De tong– De sluitspier","answer":"De tong."},{"question":"Qual a capital do estado brasileiro Paraíba?","answer":"A capital da Paraíba é João Pessoa, cidade fundada em 1585 e responsável por abrigar mais de 800.000 habitantes."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Trốn truy nã ở Campuchia","answer":"Ngày 31/7, Công an huyện Kim Thành cho biết đã đưa Hùng, trú xã Đồng Cẩm, từ Campuchia về nước. Từ năm 2021, Hùng bị Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra Công an huyện Kim Thành truy nã về tội chứa chấp, sử dụng trái phép chất ma túy. Anh ta sau đó vượt biên sang Campuchia và bị giam lỏng, bắt làm việc nặng nhọc. Tại Việt Nam, Công an huyện Kim Thành đã vận động gia đình thuyết phục Hùng ra đầu thú. Ngày 28/7, tổ công tác của công an huyện Kim Thành đến cửa khẩu Tho Mo, huyện Đức Huệ, tỉnh Long An, phối hợp đưa Hùng về. Nhà chức trách cho biết đang cũng cố hồ sơ để xử lý Hùng. "},{"question":"Сынган кылыч романдагы 📚 Ионов ким болгон?","answer":"Ионов — Курманжан датка менен сүйлөшүүгө Шабдан баатыр менен барган. Бирок өз баасын билген Курманжан жандарал (генерал) менен сүйлөшөт деп, аны менен сүйлөшүүдөн баш тартып, Скобелевдин өзү менен жолугууну сунуш кылган. Анткени Курманжанга берилген чин майордон жогору болчу."},{"question":"அரசனின் வெற்றியையும் வீரத்தையும் கூறுவன எது?","answer":"அரசனின் வெற்றியையும் வீரத்தையும் கூறுவன மெய்க்கீர்த்திகள்."},{"question":"வினா: இரைப்பை பற்றி ஒரு கட்டுரை எழுதுங்கள்","answer":"விடை: இரைப்பை என்பது முதுகெலும்பிகள், பூச்சிகள், மெல்லுடலிகள், முட்தோலிகள் உள்ளிட்ட விலங்குகளின் சமிபாட்டுத் தொகுதியில் மிக முக்கியமான சமிபாட்டை நிகழ்த்தும் ஓர் அகன்ற அறையாகும். இது உணவுக்குழாய் (அல்லது களம்), சிறுகுடல் ஆகிய பகுதிகளுக்கு இடையில் அமைந்துள்ளது. உதரவிதானத்திற்குக் கீழாக உள்ளது. இதன் வடிவமும் அளவும் உள்ளிருக்கும் உணவின் அளவினைப் பொறுத்து அமையும். உணவு உள்நுழையும் வேளையில் அதிகபட்சமாக 1.5 லிட்டர் அளவிற்குப் பெரிதாகும். இரைப்பையின் இயக்கம் குடல் அலைவுகளை ஏற்படுத்தும். ஒவ்வொரு அலைவும் இரைப்பையின் மைய உடற்பகுதியிலிருந்து தோன்றிப் பின்னோக்கிச் செல்லும். பின்னோக்கிச் செல்லும் முதல் அலைவு இரைப்பைக்கும், சிறுகுடலின் தொடக்கப் பகுதியான முன்சிறுகுடல் பகுதிக்கும் இடையில் உள்ள பைலோரஸ் சுருக்குத் தசைகளைச் சுருங்கச் செய்யும். இரைப்பையின் உள்சுவற்றில் பல இரைப்பை நீர்ச் சுரப்பிகள் உண்டு. ஏறக்குறைய நாற்பது மில்லியன் நுண்ணிய சுரப்பிகள் உள்ளன. இவற்றில் முதன்மையான உயிரணுக்கள் நொதிகளையும், சுவர் உயிரணுக்கள் எனப்படும் ஆக்ஸின்டிக் உயிரணுக்கள் ஐதரோகுளோரிக் காடியையும் சுரக்கின்றன. ஐதரோகுளோரிக் காடியினால் நொதியச் செயல்பாட்டிற்கு தேவையான அமிலத்தன்மை கிடைக்கிறது. இரைப்பையின் பெப்சின், ரெனின் போன்ற நொதியங்கள் சுரக்கப்படுகிறன.இரைப்பை குடல் மற்றும் கல்லீரல் கோளாறுகள் இந்தியாவில் உள்ள பொது பயிற்சியாளர்களிடையே சுமார் 25% ஆலோசனைகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளன. மருத்துவத் தீர்ப்பில் உள்ள பிழைகள் மற்றும் உடல்நலக் காப்பீடு இல்லாததால் தேவையான பரிசோதனைகளை பரிந்துரைப்பதில் தயக்கம் ஆகியவை தாமதமான நோயறிதலுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும் மற்றும் நோயாளியின் நோயுற்ற தன்மை மற்றும் இறப்பு அதிகரிக்கும். எனவே திறமையான நோயறிதலுக்கான பயனுள்ள உத்திகளுடன் மருத்துவர்கள் நன்கு பொருத்தப்பட்டிருக்க வேண்டும் மற்றும் பொருத்தமானவற்றைப் பரிந்துரைக்கும் மற்றும் குறைவான பயனுள்ள நோயறிதல் சோதனைகளைப் புறக்கணிப்பதன் நன்மை-அபாய-விகிதத்தை எடைபோடும் நிலையில் இருக்க வேண்டும். 'காஸ்ட்ரோவிஜிலென்ஸ்' என்பது ஆபத்து காரணிகள், வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் பரிந்துரை வழிகளை அங்கீகரிப்பதற்கான நோய் சார்ந்த பயிற்சியை உள்ளடக்கியது. இந்திய மருத்துவ நடைமுறையில் இந்த நிலைமைகளை நிர்வகிப்பதற்கான பொதுவான சவால்கள் அல்லது பிழைகள் மற்றும் அவற்றின் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட தீர்வுகள் குறித்து இந்த விவரிப்பு மதிப்பாய்வு கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது. பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட இரைப்பை குடல் நிலைமைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து பப்மெட்/மெட்லைன் மற்றும் கூகுள் ஸ்காலர் ஆகியவற்றைப் பயன்படுத்தி இலக்கியத் தேடல்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டன. வெளியிடப்பட்ட இலக்கியம் மற்றும் மூத்த இரைப்பைக் குடலியல் நிபுணர்களின் நிபுணத்துவத்தின் அடிப்படையில், நோய் சார்ந்த அறிவை மேம்படுத்துவது சரியான நோயறிதலுக்கான விகிதங்களை மேம்படுத்தும். மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஸ்கிரீனிங் மற்றும் நோயாளி கல்வி மேம்பட்ட நிலைகளில் விளக்கக்காட்சியின் அபாயத்தைக் குறைக்கலாம் மற்றும் அதன் விளைவாக முன்கணிப்பை மேம்படுத்தலாம். மற்றொரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்களிப்பு காரணி, நோயாளி-மருத்துவர் தொடர்பு ஆகும், இது நோய் மேலாண்மை மற்றும் அதை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான முறைகளின் ஒவ்வொரு கட்டத்தையும் பாதிக்கிறது, எனவே இரைப்பை குடல் மற்றும் கல்லீரல் நோய் நிலைமைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதில் முக்கியமானது. காஸ்ட்ரோவிஜிலென்ஸை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான மிக முக்கியமான வழிமுறையானது முதன்மை பராமரிப்பில் அறிவு அணுகலை மேம்படுத்துவதாகும். இது நோயறிதலின் துல்லியத்தை மேம்படுத்துகிறது மற்றும் தவறான நோயறிதலின் சுமையை குறைக்கும். தற்போதைய விவரிப்பு மதிப்பாய்வில், இரைப்பை குடல் மற்றும் கல்லீரல் நிலைமைகளுக்கான காஸ்ட்ரோவிஜிலென்ஸ் என்ற கருத்தை தெளிவுபடுத்தவும், வெளியிடப்பட்ட ஆதாரங்களுடன் அதை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும் முயற்சித்தோம்.முக்கிய வார்த்தைகள்: அழற்சி குடல் நோய், இரைப்பைஉணவுக்குழாய் ரிஃப்ளக்ஸ் நோய், எரிச்சல் கொண்ட குடல் நோய்க்குறி, மலச்சிக்கல், இரைப்பை குடல் புற்றுநோய்"},{"question":"متى اخترع مقياس الزلازل ؟","answer":"عام 132 م"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Under Iran–Irak-kriget användes","answer":"Mi-25:or flitigt av irakiska armén. De kunde med sina raketer utveckla en imponerande eldkraft, men de föråldrade \\"Falanga\\"-robotarna visade sig vara ineffektiva mot stridsvagnar. Därför utvecklades en taktik där Mi-25:or opererade i par med \\"Gazelle\\"-helikoptrar som med sina HOT-robotar kunde slå ut stridsvagnar, men som saknade skydd och andra vapen."},{"question":"Inona no fototry ny rafi-pitsarana malagasy?1-  Lalàna sivily amerikana2- Ny lalàna sivily frantsay sy ny fomba amam-panao malagasy3- Lalàna iraisana britanika ","answer":"Safidy 2 - Ny rafi-pitsarana malagasy dia mifototra amin'ny lalàna sivily frantsay sy ny fomba amam-panao malagasy."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"જાગને જાદવા! રાત થોડી રહી\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"જાગને જાદવા! રાત થોડી રહી, મંડળિક રાય મુને બીવરાવે,અરુણ ઉદિયો અને હરણલી આથમી, તુંને તો યે કરુણા ન આવે. - જાગને. \\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"જાગને જાદવા! રાત થોડી રહી, મંડળિક રાય મુને બીવરાવે,અરુણ ઉદિયો અને હરણલી આથમી, તુંને તો યે કરુણા ન આવે. - જાગને. ભોગળ ભાંગિયે રાય દામોદરા! ઉઠો જદુનાથ દેવાધિદેવા !મંડળિક મદભર્યો ઓચરે અઘટતું, જાણે નરસૈંયાની જૂઠી સેવા - જાગને. ભક્તપાલક, દયાશીલ તું શામળા ! માહરે પ્રીત પૂરણ છે તારી,નાગરાશું નવલ નેહડો દાખવો, અકલિત ચરિત તારા મુરારિ. - જાગને. માહરે 'નરહરિ' નામ રૂદે વસ્યું 'પતિતપાવન' તરૂં બિરૂદ કહાવો,ગ્રાહથી ગજને મૂકાવિયો શ્રી હરિ ! દાસ નરસૈંયાને તેમ મૂકાવો.- જાગને. "},{"question":"什么是自然语言处理？","answer":"答：自然语言处理是一种人工智能技术，用于使计算机能够理解和处理人类语言，包括语音和文字。"},{"question":"கேள்வி: பிறநாட்டு தூதரகங்கள் நம் நாட்டில் எப்போது நிறுவப்பட்டன?அ) சுதந்திரத்திற்கு முன்ஆ) விடுதலைக்குப் பின்இ) குடியரசுக்கு முன்ஈ) குடியரசுக்குப் பின்","answer":"பதில்: ஆ) விடுதலைக்குப் பின்"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:తమ్ముడామలిదేవధరణీశు కడకుపంపుడి యేకమై పగలను నణచిపలనాడు మొదలైన బహుభూములెల్లఎదురెవ్వరునులేక యేలుడి సుఖితశృంగారయుతు నరసింగుభూమీశుపంపుము మలిదేవపతి గలయంగపోరుమంచిదిగాదు భూమి నెక్కడనుపాడౌను దేశంబు పగమించెనేనిప్రజలెల్ల నశియించి పారిపోవుదురుబండారమునకును పైకంబులేదు","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :తమ్ముడు = తమ్ముడైనఆ మలిదేవ ధరణి + ఈశు కడకు = ఆ మలిదేవరాజు దగ్గరకుపంపుడి = నరసింహరాజును రాయబారిగా పంపించుఏకము + ఐ = మీరిరువురూ ఒక్కటైపగలనున్ + అణచి = పగలను అణచివేసిపలనాడు మొదలైన = పలనాడు మొదలైనబహుభూములు + ఎల్ల . = రాజ్యాలను అన్నింటినీఎదురు + ఎవ్వరును లేక = ఎదురు ఎవరూ లేకుండాసుఖిత = హాయిగాఏలుడి = పరిపాలించండిశృంగారయుతు = సుందరుడైననరసింగు భూమీశు = నరసింహుడు అనే రాజునుమలిదేవపతి = మలిదేవరాజునుకలియంగ = కలుసుకోవటానికిపంపుము = పంపించుభూమిన్ + ఎక్కడను = భూమి మీద ఎక్కడైనా సరేపోరు = యుద్ధంమంచిది + కాదు = మంచిది కాదుపగ = పగమించెన్ + ఏని = పెరిగిపోతేదేశంబు = దేశంపాడు + ఔను = నాశనమైపోతుందిప్రజలు + ఎల్ల = ప్రజలంతానశియించి = నాశనమైపారిపోవుదురు = చెల్లాచెదరైపోతారుబండారమునకును = ధనాగారానికిపైకంబు లేదు = ధనం రాదు.తాత్పర్యం :ఓ రాజా ! నీ తమ్ముడైన మలిదేవరాజు దగ్గరకు ఆ నరసింహరాజును రాయబారిగా పంపించు. మీ రెండు పక్షాలూ ఒకటై పగలను అణచివేసి పలనాడు మొదలైన రాజ్యాలను . అన్నింటినీ ఎదురు లేకుండా హాయిగా పరిపాలించండి. కనుక సుందరుడైన నరసింహ రాజును మలిదేవపతిని కలుసుకోవడానికి రాయబారిగా పంపించు. ఈ భూమి మీద ఎక్కడైనా సరే యుద్ధం మంచిది కాదు. పగ పెరిగిపోతే దేశం నాశనమైపోతుంది. ప్రజలంతా నశిస్తారు. మిగిలినవారు పారిపోతారు. ధనాగారం ఖాళీ అవుతుంది అని తాత్పర్యం."},{"question":"Maaş ve ücretin arasındaki fark nedir?","answer":"Etimolojik olarak ücret belli bir iş bitiminde ödenen karşılık olarak (ecir) bilinirken maaş işi yapsanız da yapmasanız da sabit olarak belli zaman periyotlarında düzenli ödenen karşılık olarak bilinir."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Shin yaya za a rubuta ɗari biyu da sittin da biyu a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 262"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pandai mencuri terasa mendapat, tak pandai mendapat terasa mencuri'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu yang diperoleh dengan kepintaran terasa usaha yang benar, dan sesuatu yang diperoleh dengan jalan menipu terasa didapat dengan curian."},{"question":"\\"Жонас бир туугандарынын баары кимдер?\\"","answer":"\\"Жонас бир туугандарынын баары кимдер?\\"2005-жылы түзүлгөн, алар Disney Channel балдар телеканалынан популярдуулукка ээ болушкан жана Нью-Джерси штатынын Уайкофф шаарынан келген үч бир туугандан турат; Пол Кевин Джонас II, Жозеф Адам Джонас жана Николас Джерри Джонас\\". Бул тема боюнча Jonas Brothers."},{"question":"How do Sri Lanka's traditional \\"Nāgasannasa\\" or serpent stone carvings contribute to architectural aesthetics and spiritual symbolism, especially in lesser-known temples and historic sites?","answer":"Sri Lanka's traditional \\"Nāgasannasa\\" or serpent stone carvings are exquisite expressions of architectural aesthetics and spiritual symbolism, often found in lesser-known temples and historic sites. These intricate carvings depict serpent motifs, symbolizing protection and divine energy. The positive impact lies in their contribution to the overall beauty and spiritual ambiance of these sites, infusing them with a unique character. Embracing \\"Nāgasannasa\\" ensures the preservation of this lesser-known yet culturally rich aspect of Sri Lanka's artistic heritage."},{"question":"Ош шаарынын бермети, байлыктары, баалуулуктары.","answer":"Ош шаарынын берметтери шаардын ортосундагы жайгашкан Сулайман тоосу, шаардын ортосунан агып өткөн Ак-Буура дарыясы, Мажүрүм тал дарагы ж.б.у.с"},{"question":"வினா: இந்தியாவில் தேசிய பெண் குழந்தைகள் தினம் எப்போது கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது?","answer":"விடை:  ஜனவரி 24"},{"question":"வினா : இந்தியப் பத்திரிக்கையின் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை : ஜேம்ஸ் அகஸ்டஸ் ஹிக்கி"},{"question":"Inona no fitambaran'ny loko ampiasaina matetika hanehoana fitiavana?a) Manga sy maitsob) Mena sy mavod) Mavokely sy volomparasye) volomboasary sy mainty","answer":"d) Mavokely sy volomparasy no fitambaran'ny loko ampiasaina matetika hanehoana fitiavana"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي رياض القرآن؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي سور المفصل، وهي من أول سورة (ق) إلى نهاية القرآن الكريم."},{"question":"Which is the capital of Germany?","answer":"Berlin has been the capital of Germany since 1990."},{"question":"कस्यैकान्तं सुखमुपनतं दुःखमेकान्ततो वा ।नीचैर्गच्छत्युपरि च दशा चक्रनेमिक्रमेण ॥– कालिदासस्य मेघदूतः","answer":"सतत सुख किंवा सतत दुःख कुणाला मिळते? फिरत्या रहाटगाडग्याप्रमाणे नशीब वर खाली होतच राहते."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਜੋ ਤੁਧੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਸਾਈ ਭਲੀ ਕਾਰ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 3 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲਗਦਾ ਹੈ  ਉਹੀ ਕੰਮ ਭਲਾ ਹੈ ।\\""},{"question":"একটি জেব্রা কি অনন্য স্ট্রাইপ আছে?","answer":"হ্যাঁ প্রতিটি জেব্রার একটি অনন্য স্ট্রাইপ রয়েছে, যা আঙ্গুলের ছাপের মতোই স্বতন্ত্র"},{"question":"Qual o nome da cafeteria da série  Friends?","answer":"A famosa cafeteria da série Friends se chama Central Perk."},{"question":"‘லட்சியம்’ பொருள்களோடு இரண்டற இணைத்துவிடுவது எது?","answer":"அகன் ஐந்திணைகளைப் பேசுகிற தொல்காப்பியம் புணர்தல், பிரிதல் முதலான அகன் ஐந்தினைகளை இன்பம், பொருள், அறம் ஆகிய அறவியல் ‘லட்சியப் பொருள்களோடு இரண்டற இணைத்துவிடுகிறது."},{"question":"Crie alternativas de resposta para a seguinte pergunta e indique com um * a resposta correta: Como são chamados os números que só são divisíveis por 1 e por si próprios?","answer":"Aqui estão 4 alternativas para a pergunta:Números compostosNúmeros pares* Números primosNúmeros decimais"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو الحيوان الذي لا ينام؟","answer":"الإجابة: الضفدع"},{"question":"Escribe la continuación de este texto : Durante la clasificación para la Copa del Mundo de 1974, jugó cuatro partidos, anotando un gol contra Haití. Luego formó parte del equipo que se clasificó para el , jugando en los tres partidos de Guatemala. En 1976 y 1977, disputó once partidos durante el proceso de clasificación para el Mundial de 1978... ","answer":"Anotando un gol contra El Salvador."},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 山梨県によると、富士山に山梨県側の「吉田口」の道から登った人は、7月1日から30日までに6万4000人ぐらいいました。新型コロナウイルスが広がる前の2019年より増えています。これからお盆の休みなどに登る人がもっと増えると、道が混んで転ぶ危険などが高くなります。このため、山梨県は警察と一緒に、登る人が多くなりすぎないように考えることにしました。県は、登る人が1日に4000人より多くなる場合、それ以上登らないようにすることを考えています。登っている人の数は赤外線のセンサーなどで調べます。山梨県の知事は「富士山がユネスコの世界文化遺産になって今年で10年です。外国から来る人たちの安全もしっかり守りたいです」と話しています。","answer":"富士山に登る人が多くなりすぎないように考える"},{"question":"Абузамзам - сөзүнүн түшүндүрмөсү кандай ?","answer":"\\"Абузамзам\\" бул - кол менен жасалган көлчө."},{"question":"අධිකාරී පාලනය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"අධිකාරී පාලනය (Authority control) යනු විකිපීඩියාවේ ලිපි සඳහා හඳුනාගැනීමේ අංකයක් ලබාදෙන ආකාරයක් වේ. මෙය සමාන හෝ සමාන මාතෘකා සහිත විවිධ අයිතම අපැහැදිලි කිරීමට මෙන්ම මාතෘකා දෙකකින් හෝ වැඩි ගණනකින් පොදුවේ හැඳින්වෙන අයිතමයක් සඳහා තනි සම්මත මාතෘකාවක් පිහිටුවීමට ප්‍රයෝජනවත් වේ. භාවිතා කරන විට, ලෝක ව්‍යාප්ත පුස්තකාල නාමාවලි වල ග්‍රන්ථ නාමාවලි වාර්තා වලට සම්බන්ධ කරමින්, විකිපීඩියා පිටුවල පහලින්, අධිකාරී පාලන දත්ත සබැඳි සොයා ගත හැක . අධිකාරී පාලනය බොහෝ විට චරිතාපදාන ලිපිවල භාවිතා වේ, මන්ද එක් අයෙකුට වඩා එකම නම බෙදා ගැනීම සාමාන්‍ය දෙයකි. එය වෙනත් විෂය ද්‍රව්‍යවල ද බහුලව භාවිතා වේ."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਤੂੰ ਅਕਥੁ ਕਿਉ ਕਥਿਆ ਜਾਹਿ ॥ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੁ ਮਾਰਣੁ ਮਨ ਮਾਹਿ ਸਮਾਹਿ ॥ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣ ਅਨੇਕ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਨਹ ਪਾਹਿ ॥੧॥ਜਿਸ ਕੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਤਿਸੁ ਮਾਹਿ ਸਮਾਣੀ ॥ਤੇਰੀ ਅਕਥ ਕਥਾ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦਿ ਵਖਾਣੀ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜਹ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਤਹ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਬਣਾਈ ॥ਜਹ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸਹਜੇ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਈ ॥ਜਹ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਤਹਾ ਹਉਮੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਜਲਾਈ ॥੨॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਮਹਲੀ ਥਾਉ ਪਾਏ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸਾਏ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਏ ॥੩॥ਆਪੇ ਦਾਤਿ ਕਰੇ ਦਾਤਾਰੁ ॥ਪੂਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਸਿਉ ਲਗੈ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਤਿਨ ਕਉ ਜੈਕਾਰੁ ॥੪॥੮॥੨੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 160 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੂੰ ਕਥਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈਂ, ਤੇਰਾ ਸਰੂਪ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਪਾਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ-ਰੂਪ ਮਸਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਤੂੰ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੀ ਗੁਣ ਹਨ, ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਸਕਦੇ ।੧।ਇਹ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਜਿਸ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਵਿਚ (ਹੀ) ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ ਤਿਵੇਂ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਭੀ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ ਤਿਵੇਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਭੀ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹਨ) ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੇ ਇਹੀ ਗੱਲ ਦੱਸੀ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜਿਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਥੇ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਸਾੜ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ।੨।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਥਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਵਸਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ (ਸਦਾ) ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਦਾਤਾਂ ਦੇਣ ਦੇ ਸਮਰੱਥ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ) ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਲ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ (-ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਵਡਿਆਈ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।੪।੮।੨੮।\\""},{"question":"युनिभर्सल बेसिक इनकम (UBI) को अवधारणा समाजमा पैसाको वितरणको बारेमा छलफलसँग कसरी सम्बन्धित छ?","answer":"UBI ले सबै नागरिकहरूलाई नियमित, बिना शर्त आम्दानी, सम्पत्ति वितरण, गरिबी निवारण, र सामाजिक कल्याणको बारेमा बहस गर्ने समावेश गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Ity fanambarana manaraka ity dia amin'ny teny anglisy,adikao amin'ny teny malagasy\\"I cannot go out because I'm cooking \\"","answer":"Toy izao ny fandikana io amin'ny teny malagasy:Tsy afaka mivoaka aho satria mahandro."},{"question":"Skriv videre på følgende:Parlamentsvalget i Portugal 1910 blev afholdt den 28. august 1910. Inden resultatet blev godkendt, kom dog revolution","answer":"i landet. Revolutionen ledte til monarkiet afskaffelse den 5. oktober. I 1911 blev en konstituerende forsamling valgt."},{"question":"Манас эпосу тууралуу кандай маалыматың бар?","answer":" «Манас» эпосунун мазмундук жана көркөмдүк гармониясын айрыкча манасчынын аткарып жаткан процессинде, айрыкча, унутулгус Саякбай сыяктуу улуу манасчы аткарып жатканда сезесиз. Бул учурда эпостун, маселен, алсак, Каныкейдин Тайторуну чапканы, Алмамбеттин арманы сыяктуу атактуу окуялар гана эмес, ар бир сөз, ар бир ыр сабы, ар бир тирада манасчынын не бир кыймыл- аракети, үнү сырткы кубулуштары менен айкалышып, ушулардын баары бир асыл заттан жаралгансып, ажырагыс бирдикти түзөт. Мына ошондо «Манасты» угуп отуруп, анын не бир кооздук-асылдыгына моокуң канып, ошол жазуусу жок, жазуу маданиятынан алыс шарттарда, кыргыз эпосу ушундай таңгаларлык көркөмдүк жарашыкка, сөздү, музыканы, театрды өзүнө бириктирген гармонияга кантип жетти экен деп ойлойсуң. Мына ушул укмуштуудай көркөмдүк гармониянын касиетинен улам эпосто сүрөттөлгөн Кошой, Жолой, Макел дөөлөрдөн тартып, Манас баштаган чоролорго чейин, Бакай карыядан тартып, акылман Каныкейге чейин, Коңурбайдан тартып, Көзкамандарга чейин белгилүү турмуштук шарттарда жашаган тирүү кеипкерлердей көз алдыбыздан тартылып өтөт."},{"question":"Kerja apa yang berkaitan dengan datang dengan idea? Berdasarkan soalan sebelumnya, tulis konteks yang mengandungi jawapannya. Ia boleh menjadi 1 - 20 ayat. Konteks:","answer":"Nikola Tesla (Serbian Cyrillic: Никола Тесла; 10 Julai 1856 hingga 7 Januari 1943) ialah seorang penemu Amerika Serbia, jurutera elektrik, jurutera mekanikal, ahli fizik, dan ahli futurisme yang terkenal dengan sumbangannya dalam reka bentuk sistem bekalan elektrik arus ulang alik (AC) moden."},{"question":"Zin 1: Onder hen zijn Sylvia Rexach, een componiste van Boleros, Marie Teresa Rios, auteur, en Julita Ross, zangeres. Zin 2: Onder hen zijn Sylvia Rexach, een componiste van boleros, Marie Teresa Rios, een auteur, en Julita Ross, een zangeres. Vraag: Hebben zin 1 en zin 2 dezelfde betekenis? Ja of nee?","answer":"Niet per sé. In zin 2 kan het het geval zijn dat Marie Teresa Rios niet een auteur is, maar dat \\"een auteur\\" simpelweg één van de personen (zonder naamvermelding) in de opsomming is. In zin 1 kan dit niet het geval zijn, maar moet \\"auteur\\" naar Marie Teresa Rios verwijzen."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko gastronomia: Zer dira pintxos?","answer":"Pintxos jateko txikiak dira, ogi tarte batean edo ziztakian, tabernetan eskaintzen direnak."},{"question":"What is the capital of Lebanon?","answer":"Beirut is the capital city of Lebanon."},{"question":"サンキューは英語、シェイシェイは中国語、ではグラッチェは何語？","answer":"イタリア語です。"},{"question":"Sunayen Ranakun mako a Hausa?","answer":"Jiya Shekaran jiya YauGobeJibi Gata Citta "},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：夫君子之行，静以修身，俭以养德。非澹泊无以明志，非宁静无以致远。夫学须静也，才须学也，非学无以广才，非志无以成学，淫漫则不能励精，险躁则不能治性.年与时驰，意与日去，遂成枯落，多不接世，悲守穷庐，将复何及！","answer":"有道德修养的人，是这样进行修养锻炼的，他们以静思反省来使自己尽善尽美，以俭朴节约财物来培养自己高尚的品德。不清心寡欲就不能使自己的志向明确坚定，不安定清静就不能实现远大理想而长期刻苦学习。要学得真知必须使身心在宁静中研究探讨，人们的才能是从不断的学习中积累起来的；如果不下苦工学习就不能增长与发扬自己的才干；如果没有坚定不移的意志就不能使学业成功。纵欲放荡、消极怠慢就不能勉励心志使精神振作；冒险草率、急燥不安就不能陶治性情使节操高尚。如果年华与岁月虚度，志愿时日消磨，最终就会像枯枝落叶般一天天衰老下去。这样的人不会为社会所用而有益于社会，只有悲伤地困守在自己的穷家破舍里，到那时再悔也来不及了。"},{"question":"\\"Jika ________ ada masa lapang, jemputlah ke rumah saya,\\" kata Ani kepada kawan-kawannya.","answer":"kalian"},{"question":"¿Cuál es el tema principal de esta pregunta?Pregunta: ¿Assassin's Creed salió antes que Call of Duty?","answer":"El tema principal de la pregunta son los videojuegos."},{"question":"Ao amin'ny trano fisakafoanana dia misy mpanjifa, mpandroso sakafo ary mpahandro. Ny mpandroso sakafo rehetra dia manao aron'akanjo, ny mpahandro rehetra dia manao satroka mpahandro, ary ny mpanjifa rehetra dia manana tabilao mirakitra ny zava-misy.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Ny mphandro rehetra dia manao saron-tava.B. Manao satroka mpahandro ny mpanjifa rehetra.D. Ny mpizara sasany dia manana tabilao mirakitra ny zava-misy.E. Ny mpizara rehetra dia mpanjifa ihany koa.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia D. Ny mpizara sasany dia manana tabilao mirakitra ny zava-misy."},{"question":"Дааратты жараксыз абалга алып келген жагдайлар кайсылар?","answer":"Төмөнкү учурларда даарат бузулат:1. Заң, заара, урук суюктуктары (сперм, мази сыяктуу), кан жана башка ушул нерселер сыяктуу ыплас нерселердин чыгышы дааратты жараксыз абалга алып келет.Ошондой эле желдин чыгышы да дааратты бузат.2. Дененин тигил же бул жеринен кан, ириң сыяктуу нерселердин чыгып жайылышы дааратты бузат. Мындай нерселер чыккан жеринин тегерегине жайылбаса (тарабаса) даарат бузулбайт. Ооздон чыккан кан түкүрүк менен бирдей, же түкүрүктөн көп болсо дааратты бузат. Эгер андан аз болсо даарат бузулбаит.3. Ооз толо кусуу. Аз-аздан болсо да удаама-удаа келген кусундулар ооз толо турган өлчөмгө жетсе, дааратты бузат.4. Эстен тануу, акылдан ажыроо, мас болуу жана уктоо. Мындай абалдарда даарат бузулат. Эч нерсе билбеий калгандай уйкуга кирбестен, бираз көзү илинип кеткен адам даараты бузулбаганына кескин түрдө ишенсе, даараты бузулбаган болот. Ошондой эле намаз учурундагы уйкусуроолор да дааратты бузбайт. Анткени, намазда туруунун өзү эле даараттын бузулбашына шарт түзөт. Бирок ошону менен катар өзүн билбей кала турган даражада уктап калган адамдын даараты бузулган болот.5. Намаз учурунда жанындагы адамга угула тургандай үн менен күлгөн адамдын даараты бузулат. Куттуу хадистердин биринде, намазда күлгөн адамдын кайрадан даарат алып, намаз окушу талап кылынган.6. Жыныстык катнашта болуу.7. Дааратка тиешелүү үзүр абалдарынын аякташы. Демек, тайаммум алган адам суу көрсө, же тапса, ошондой эле, маасыга тартылган масхтын мөөнөтү бүтсө, даарат бузулган болот.8. Аял кишинин көз жарышы (бала төрөшү)."},{"question":"Ẹ ko gbogbo ibọn atawọn ọta to ba wa lọwọ yin silẹ laarin ọjọ meje-Akeredolu","answer":"Ọjọ meje pere ni Gomina ipinlẹ Ondo, Rotimi Akeredolu, fun awọn araalu to bani ibọn ati ọta rẹ lati fi da a pada si  ọdọ ọga awọn Amọtẹkun to wa ni Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ.Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, opin ọsẹ yii, lo sọrọ naa niluu Akurẹ ninu atẹjade kan ti Kọmiṣanna feto iroyin rẹ, Donald Ojogo, fọwọ si.Ojogo ni Akeredolu ti pasẹ pe ileeṣẹ awọn Amọtẹkun to wa ni Pa Fasoranti Garden, niluu Akurẹ, ni ki wọn maa ko ibọn ati ọta naa lọ.O waa rọ awọn to ba ni awọn ohun ija yii lọwọ lati lo anfaani ọjọ meje tijọba fun wọn yii lati ko o silẹ. O ni awọn eleto aabo yoo bẹrẹ si i gbe igbesẹ to yẹ lori wọn lẹyin ti ọjọ meje naa ba pe.Akeredolu fi kun un pe awọn ti ko ba le lọọ ko ibọn naa silẹ funra wọn fun idi kan tabi omi-in le pe nọmba yii 08079999989, nibi ti wọn yoo ti sọ igbesẹ to yẹ ki tọhun gbe fun un."},{"question":"පිලිපීනයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"පිලිපීනයේ අගනුවර මැනිලා නුවරයයි."},{"question":"على أي شيء يطلق اسم الأخشبان؟\\t","answer":"اسم لجبلين بمكة."},{"question":"Kepengen mati aja rasanya","answer":"Jika Anda merasa sedang menghadapi situasi darurat atau memerlukan bantuan segera, silakan menghubungi layanan darurat di daerah Anda atau konsultasikan dengan ahli profesional."},{"question":"එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරඟ වලදී ශ්‍රීලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් වේගවත්ම ලකුණු 10,000 ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා  කවුද?","answer":"තිලකරත්න ඩිල්ෂාන් ශ්‍රීලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් වේගවත්ම ලකුණු 10,000 ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා වේ. ඔහු මෙම සන්ධිස්ථානය ලබා ගත්තේ ඉනිම 293කදීය."},{"question":"చదువుకునేవారైనా, పనిచేసేవారైనా, మరెవరైనా సరే తీవ్ర ఒత్తిడికి లోనైతే వారి వారి పనులను సరిగా చేయలేక తీవ్ర ఇబ్బందుల పాలౌతారు. ఈ విషయం చెప్పడానికి “సుఖం – దుఃఖం – విజయం – లోకం – మోదం – ఘోరం” లాంటి అంత్యానుప్రాస పదాలు వాడి ఒక కవిత చెప్పండి.","answer":"చదువుకునేవారు :విద్యార్జనమిస్తుంది సుఖంసోమరితనమిస్తుంది దుఃఖంవిద్యావంతులు సాధిస్తారు విజయంపొందుతారు జనులందరి ఆమోదంవిద్యాధికులతో భరతకు ప్రమోదంవిద్యావిహీనుల కెపుడు భేదంధనలేమితో ఒత్తిళ్ళ సుడిగుండాలుదినభృతి లేక నిత్యమూ ప్రాణగండాలుఅంతం కాదిది – పునరావృతమయ్యే నిత్యాగ్ని గుండాలుఅందుకే ప్రతి జీవికి కావాలి సహనాభరణం.పనిచేసేవారు:కష్టార్జితం కల్గిస్తుందెపుడు సుఖంపరభాగ్యోప జీవితం సదా దుఃఖంశ్రమను నమ్ముకొన్నవాడికి విజయంశ్రమను దోచు కొన్నవాడికి అపజయంగతిలేని బడుగుల బ్రతుకులు ఘోరంఆకటికై తపించు శ్రామికుల లోకంశ్రమశక్తిని ధరించు కార్మికుల ప్రపంచంవ్యవసాయాన్ని వహించు కర్షకులలోకంసంతృప్తే వారికి ప్రమోదంసహజీవనమే వారి కామోదం"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:మధ్యతరగతి కుటుంబాలు నివసించే ప్రదేశం అది. దాదాపు 22 కుటుంబాలున్న ఆ లోగిలిలో అందరికి సమస్యలు. ఎవరి సమస్యలు వారివి. ఉద్యోగ విరమణ చేసిన తాతగారు గంపెడు సంసారంతో బాధపడుతుంటాడు. కొత్తగా అద్దెకు దిగిన యువకుడు నిరుద్యోగి, అవివాహితుడు. ఏవో బొమ్మలు గీస్తూ తన మనోభావాలను వాటి ద్వారా బహిర్గతం చేస్తుంటాడు.","answer":"ఇందిర, ఆనందలక్ష్మి అక్కాచెల్లెళ్ళు. క్రింది వాటిలో ఉంటారు. జబ్బుతో మంచానపడిన తల్లి, అకారణంగా జైలుకెళ్ళిన తండ్రి, నిరుద్యోగి అయిన అన్నయ్య పైగా అమాయకంతో తల్లిదండ్రుల గూర్చి బాధపడుతుంటాడు. కృష్ణవేణి అనే అమ్మాయి ఉద్యోగం చేస్తూ తల్లినీ, అన్నయ్యను అభిమానంగా చూసుకుంటుంది. ఆత్మన్యూనతా భావంతో అన్నయ్య ఎప్పుడూ కృష్ణవేణితో గొడవపడుతుంటాడు. తనకు ఒక ఉద్యోగం వస్తే చెల్లెల్ని ఉద్యోగం మానిపించేయాలనుకుంటూ ఉంటాడు.కృష్ణమూర్తి అనే ఆయన బ్యాంకు ఉద్యోగి. తనవరకు తాను అన్నట్లు చిన్న ప్రపంచంలో గిరిగీసుకుని బ్రతికేస్తూ ఉంటాడు. కొత్తగా వచ్చిన యువకునితో పరిచయం చేసుకుంటూ మీకు బ్యాంకు ఎకౌంటు ఉందా ? ఉంటే ఏ బ్యాంకు అని ఆరాలు తీస్తాడు. దానికి సమాధానంగా నా ఎకౌంటు నా జేబులోనే ఉంది అయినా ఖాళీగానే ఉందని అంటాడు. బహుశా బ్యాంకు ఎకౌంటు లేనివాళ్ళు నచ్చరేమో అని తనలో తాను అనుకుంటాడా యువకుడు."},{"question":"Doc to summarize: అమిత్ షా ప్రకటన పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్ రాష్ట్రంలో తీవ్ర ఆందోళనకు కారణమయ్యే అవకాశం ఉంది.\\"ఈ రాష్ట్రంలో (పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్) ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీనీ అమలు చేయనివ్వబోమని ముఖ్యమంత్రి మమతా బెనర్జీ అంటున్నారు. నేను హామీ ఇస్తున్నాను, అక్రమంగా వచ్చి ఇక్కడ ఉంటున్న ప్రతి వ్యక్తినీ బయటకు పంపుతాం\\" అని కోల్‌కతాలో జరిగిన ర్యాలీలో అమిత్ షా అన్నారు.కేంద్రంలోని నరేంద్ర మోదీ ప్రభుత్వానికి వ్యతిరేకంగా ఉన్న ఆ రాష్ట్ర ముఖ్యమంత్రి మమతా బెనర్జీ ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీని బెంగాల్‌లో అమలు చేయవద్దంటున్నారు. గతంలో భారీ నిరసన ర్యాలీలు కూడా నిర్వహించారు.ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీ జాబితా అంటే ఏంటి?పాకిస్తాన్ నుంచి బంగ్లాదేశ్ విడిపోకముందు (అంటే 1971 మార్చి 24కి ముందు) నుంచి తాము భారత్‌లో స్థిరపడినట్లు నిరూపించుకునే వారి జాబితాను నేషనల్ రిజిస్టర్ ఆఫ్ సిటిజెన్స్ (ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీ) అంటున్నారు.అస్సాంలో ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీ తుది జాబితాను ఆగస్టు 31న కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వం విడుదల చేసింది. అస్సాంలో ఉంటున్న దాదాపు 19 లక్షల మంది భారతీయులు కాదని ఆ జాబితా ద్వారా ప్రభుత్వం ప్రకటించింది. అయితే, తమ పౌరసత్వాన్ని నిరూపించుకునేందుకు వారికి మరో 120 రోజుల అవకాశం కల్పించింది.అస్సాం తర్వాత, దేశంలోని ఇతర రాష్ట్రాల్లోనూ ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీని అమలు చేయాలంటూ అధికార బీజేపీ కార్యకర్తలు కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వాన్ని కోరుతున్నారు.అస్సాంలో అక్రమంగా ఉంటున్న బంగ్లాదేశ్ వలసదారులను గుర్తించేందుకు ఈ ప్రక్రియ చేపట్టాల్సి వచ్చిందని ప్రభుత్వం చెప్పింది. పొరుగున ఉన్న పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్ కూడా బంగ్లాదేశ్‌తో 2,000 కిలోమీటర్ల మేర సరిహద్దును పంచుకుంటోంది.ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీకి వ్యతిరేకంగా తీసిన నిరసన ర్యాలీలో పాల్గొన్న మమతా బెనర్జీ (పాత చిత్రం)అస్సాంలో నిర్వహించిన ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీ ప్రక్రియ చాలా కాలంగా వివాదాస్పదంగా ఉంది. కొన్ని కుటుంబాలకు దిక్కుతోచని పరిస్థితి ఏర్పడింది. తమ భవితవ్యం పట్ల ఆందోళనతో కొంతమంది ఆత్మహత్య చేసుకున్నారన్న వార్తలు కూడా వచ్చాయి. \\"విదేశీయులు\\" అనే అనుమానంతో చాలా మందిని నిర్బంధ కేంద్రాల్లో ఉంచారు.పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్‌లో ఇప్పటి వరకు ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీ జాబితా రూపొందించలేదు. అయినా, ఆ రాష్ట్రంలో కొన్ని విషాదకర ఘటనలు జరిగాయి. అస్సాంలో లక్షల మందిలాగే, తమ భవితవ్యం కూడా ప్రశ్నార్థకంగా మారుతుందన్న ఆందోళనతో 38 ఏళ్ల ఆనంద రాయ్ ఆత్మహత్య చేసుకున్నారు. తాము భారతీయులమేనని \\"నిరూపించుకునేందుకు\\" తగిన పత్రాలు లేవన్న భయంతో ప్రాణాలు తీసుకున్నవారిలో ఆనంద ఒకరు.","answer":"పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్‌లోనూ జాతీయ పౌరసత్వ రిజిస్టర్ (ఎన్‌ఆర్‌సీ) అమలు చేస్తామని కేంద్ర హోంమంత్రి అమిత్ షా ప్రకటించారు. బెంగాల్‌లో అక్రమంగా ఉంటున్న ప్రతి వ్యక్తినీ 'బయటకు గెంటేస్తాం' అని అన్నారు."},{"question":"Ọga ọlọpaa patapata nilẹ wa ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn mu Sunday Igboho","answer":"Ọga ọlọpaa patapata lorileede yii, Muhammed Adamu, ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn mu ọkan ninu awọn ajijagbara nilẹ Yoruba nni, Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, nitori gbedeke ọjọ meje to fun awọn Fulani lati ko ẹru wọn kuro niluu Igangan, nipinlẹ Ọyọ laipẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe Agbẹnusọ Buhari lori eto iroyin, Garba Sheu, lo fidi eleyii mulẹ lasiko ifọrọwerọ kan to ṣe pẹlu ilẹẹṣẹ tẹlifiṣan BBC Hausa lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, opin ọsẹ yii.Ọkunrin naa ni ọga ọlọpaa patapata nilẹ wa sọ foun pe oun ti paṣẹ fun Kọmiṣanna awọn ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ngozi Onadeko, lati fi ọwọ ofin mu Igboho, ki wọn si gbe e wa si Abuja lai fakoko ṣofo."},{"question":"ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆ: ಅಡ್ವೆಂಚರ್ ಟೈಮ್ ಎಂಬ ಅಮೆರಿಕನ್ ಧಾರವಾಹಿಯಲ್ಲಿ  ಮಾರ್ಸೆಲಿನ್ ಎಂಬ ಪಾತ್ರಕ್ಕೆ ಧ್ವನಿಯನ್ನು ನೀಡಿದವರು ಯಾರು  ಉತ್ತರ:","answer":"ಒಲಿವಿಯಾ ಓಲ್ಸನ್"},{"question":"வினா: விற்கொடி என்பது ………………….. புணர்ச்சிக்குச் சான்றாகும்.அ) இயல்புஆ) திரிதல் விகாரம்இ) தோன்றல் விகாரம்ஈ) கெடுதல் விகாரம்","answer":"விடை: ஆ) திரிதல் விகாரம்"},{"question":"Mắt em bị cận từ 10 tuổi, nay khoảng 5 độ, em muốn phẫu thuật để dự tuyển vào ngành công an, xin cho em các phương pháp mổ mắt hiện nay và nên làm gì sau khi phẫu thuật để giữ gìn mắt không bị tái cận","answer":"Đối với các ngành lực lượng vũ trang và quân đội, yêu cầu bắt buộc là phải bỏ kính. Nên việc phẫu thuật là cần thiết nếu cháu muốn thi vào ngành này. Lời khuyên của chú, lựa chọn tốt nhất là phẫu thuật Smile, đảm bảo khi sau này tham gia luyện tập sẽ tránh các biến chứng.Sau phẫu thuật, việc duy trì sức khỏe mắt là vô cùng quan trọng để ngăn ngừa tái cận và các vấn đề khác. Dưới đây là một số gợi ý để giữ gìn sức khỏe mắt:Tuân thủ hướng dẫn của bác sĩ: Luôn tuân theo các chỉ dẫn và lịch hẹn của bác sĩ mắt sau phẫu thuật. Điều này đảm bảo rằng bạn đang hỗ trợ quá trình hồi phục mắt một cách tốt nhất.Tránh ánh nắng mặt trời mạnh: Bức xạ tử ngoại từ ánh nắng mặt trời có thể gây hại cho mắt. Khi ra ngoài, hãy đeo kính râm bảo vệ mắt khỏi tác động của tia UV.Tránh căng thẳng mắt: Khi làm việc trước màn hình máy tính hoặc đọc sách, hãy tuân thủ nguyên tắc 20-20-20: Mỗi 20 phút hãy nhìn ra xa trong khoảng 20 giây để giảm căng thẳng mắt.Dinh dưỡng cân đối: Ăn uống cân đối với các thực phẩm giàu vitamin A, C, E và khoáng chất như kẽm có thể giúp duy trì sức khỏe mắt.Tránh hút thuốc và cường độ ánh sáng xanh từ màn hình: Những yếu tố này có thể gây hại cho mắt và ảnh hưởng đến chất lượng giấc ngủ.Kiểm tra mắt định kỳ: Dù đã phẫu thuật hoặc không, việc kiểm tra mắt định kỳ sẽ giúp bác sĩ theo dõi tình trạng mắt của bạn và phát hiện sớm các vấn đề có thể xảy ra."},{"question":" ஒரு நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் முதன்மையான காரணிகள் யாவை?","answer":"பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி என்பது ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்குள் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளை உற்பத்தி செய்யும் பொருளாதாரத்தின் திறனின் வளர்ச்சி என வரையறுக்கப்படுகிறது.பொருளாதாரத்தில், பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி என்பது சமூகத்தில் தனிநபர்களின் விருப்பங்களை திருப்திப்படுத்த பொருளாதாரத்தின் உற்பத்தித்திறனில் நீண்ட கால விரிவாக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கிறது. ஒரு நாட்டின் நிலையான பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி மாதிரியானது தேசிய வருமானம் மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு மட்டத்தில் நேர்மறையான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது, இதன் விளைவாக உயர்ந்த வாழ்க்கைத் தரம் உள்ளது.கூடுதலாக, வரி வருவாயை அதிகரிப்பதன் மூலம் அரசாங்க நிதியைத் தூண்டுவதில் இது முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. இது ஒரு பொருளாதாரத்தின் மேலும் வளர்ச்சிக்கு கூடுதல் வருமானத்தை உருவாக்க அரசாங்கத்திற்கு உதவுகிறது. ஒரு நாட்டின் மொத்த தேசிய உற்பத்தி (GNP) முந்தைய ஆண்டின் GNP க்கு சமம். ஒரு நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை அதனுடன் ஒப்பிடுவதன் மூலம் அளவிட முடியும். ஒரு நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தின் பலம் மற்றும் பலவீனங்களை சரியாக பகுப்பாய்வு செய்தால் நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி சாத்தியமாகும்.பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி என்பது:பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி என்பது ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட காலப்பகுதியில் ஒரு நாடு உற்பத்தி செய்யும் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளின் மட்டத்தில் நேர்மறையான மாற்றமாக வரையறுக்கப்படுகிறது. பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியின் ஒரு முக்கியமான பண்பு, பொருளாதாரத்தின் அனைத்துத் துறைகளிலும் எப்போதும் ஒரே மாதிரியாகவோ அல்லது ஒரே மாதிரியாகவோ இருக்காது. எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட ஆண்டில், ஒரு நாட்டின் தொலைத்தொடர்புத் துறையானது பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்களிப்பைக் குறிக்கிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் சுரங்கத் துறை நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியின் அடிப்படையில் சிறப்பாக செயல்படவில்லை. ஒரு நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் சில முக்கியமான காரணிகள் பின்வருமாறு:(அ) ​​மனித வளம்:இது ஒரு நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியின் மிக முக்கியமான காரணிகளில் ஒன்றாகும். கிடைக்கக்கூடிய மனித வளங்களின் தரம் மற்றும் அளவு ஆகியவை பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சியை நேரடியாகப் பாதிக்கும்.மனித வளங்களின் தரம் அதன் திறன்கள், படைப்பாற்றல், பயிற்சி மற்றும் கல்வியைப் பொறுத்தது. ஒரு நாட்டின் மனித வளம் நன்கு பயிற்றுவிக்கப்பட்டு பயிற்சி பெற்றால், உற்பத்தி உயர் தரத்தில் இருக்கும்.(ஆ) இயற்கை வளங்கள்:அது ஒரு நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை வெகுவாக பாதிக்கும். இயற்கை வளங்கள் நிலத்தில் அல்லது நிலத்தடியில் இயற்கையால் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படும் வளங்களை உள்ளடக்கியது. நிலத்தில் உள்ள வளங்களில் தாவரங்கள், மீன்வளர்ப்பு மற்றும் நிலப்பரப்பு ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.நிலம் அல்லது நிலத்தடி வளங்களுக்கு அடியில் உள்ள வளங்களில் எண்ணெய், இயற்கை எரிவாயு, உலோகங்கள் மற்றும் உலோகம் அல்லாத தாதுக்கள் ஆகியவை அடங்கும். ஒரு நாட்டின் இயற்கை வளங்கள் காலநிலை மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் நிலைமைகளைப் பொறுத்தது. சிறிய இயற்கை வளங்களைக் கொண்ட நாடுகளை விட அதிக இயற்கை வளங்களைக் கொண்ட நாடுகள் சிறந்த வளர்ச்சியை அனுபவிக்கின்றன. (c) மூலதன உருவாக்கம்:நிலம், கட்டிடம், இயந்திரங்கள், மின்சாரம், போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் தகவல் தொடர்பு ஊடகங்கள் ஆகியவை அடங்கும். இந்த மனிதனால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து பொருட்களின் உற்பத்தியே மூலதன உருவாக்கம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. மூலதன உருவாக்கம் ஒரு தொழிலாளிக்கு மூலதனத்தின் கிடைக்கும் தன்மையை அதிகரிக்கிறது, இது மூலதனம் / தொழிலாளர் விகிதத்தை மேலும் அதிகரிக்கிறது. இது, தொழிலாளர் உற்பத்தித்திறனை அதிகரிக்கிறது, இதன் விளைவாக உற்பத்தி மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சி அதிகரிக்கிறது.(ஈ) தொழில்நுட்ப வளர்ச்சி:பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் மிக முக்கியமான காரணிகளில் ஒன்று. தொழில்நுட்பம் என்பது அறிவியல் முறைகள் மற்றும் உற்பத்தி நுட்பங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதை உள்ளடக்கியது. வேறு வார்த்தைகளில் கூறுவதானால், தொழில்நுட்பம் என்பது குறிப்பிட்ட அளவு உழைப்பால் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் தொழில்நுட்ப கருவிகளின் தன்மை மற்றும் வகை என வரையறுக்கப்படுகிறது.தொழில்நுட்ப வளர்ச்சி குறைந்த வளங்களுடன் உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிக்க உதவுகிறது. தொழில்நுட்ப வளர்ச்சியில் குறைந்த கவனம் செலுத்தும் நாடுகளுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில், தொழில்நுட்ப வளர்ச்சியில் பணிபுரியும் நாடுகள் வேகமாக வளர்ந்து வருகின்றன. சரியான தொழில்நுட்பத்தைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பது பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சியில் பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. மாறாக, ஒரு பொருத்தமற்ற தொழில்நுட்பம் - அதிக உற்பத்திச் செலவுகளை விளைவிக்கும்.பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியைப் பாதிக்கும் காரணி -பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி என்பது அரசியல், சமூகம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரக் கருத்தாய்வுகள் உட்பட பலதரப்பட்ட கூறுகளால் பாதிக்கப்படும் மிகவும் சிக்கலான செயல்முறையாகும். இந்த காரணிகளில் பின்வருவன அடங்கும்:பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் 10 காரணிகள்இயற்கை வளங்கள் மூலதன உருவாக்கம்தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் மனித வள மேம்பாடு மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி சமூக மேல்நிலைகள்அரசியல் காரணிசமூக மற்றும் உளவியல் காரணிகல்வி பொருள் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான ஆசை பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் 10 காரணிகள் பின்வருவனவற்றில் இரண்டு முக்கிய பகுதிகளாக பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன-பொருளாதார காரணி பொருளாதாரம் அல்லாத காரணி பொருளாதார காரணிகள் இயற்கை வளங்கள்: ஒரு பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் முதன்மையான காரணி அதன் இயற்கை வளங்கள் ஆகும். இயற்கை வளங்களில் நிலப்பரப்பு மற்றும் மண்ணின் தரம், வன வளம், ஆரோக்கியமான நதி அமைப்பு, கனிம மற்றும் எண்ணெய் வளங்கள் மற்றும் சாதகமான காலநிலை ஆகியவை அடங்கும். பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சிக்கு ஏராளமான இயற்கை வளங்கள் அவசியம். போதுமான இயற்கை வளங்களைக் கொண்ட ஒரு நாடு வேகமாக விரிவடைய முடியாது. இருப்பினும், ஏராளமான இயற்கை வளங்கள் கிடைப்பது பொருளாதார விரிவாக்கத்திற்கு அவசியமான ஆனால் போதுமான முன்நிபந்தனை அல்ல. குறைந்த வளர்ச்சியடைந்த நாடுகளில் இயற்கை வளங்கள் குறைவாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன, அதிகமாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன அல்லது தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன. இது அவர்களின் பின்தங்கிய நிலைக்கு பங்களிக்கும் காரணிகளில் ஒன்றாகும். மறுபுறம், ஜப்பான், சிங்கப்பூர் மற்றும் பிற நாடுகளில் ஏராளமான இயற்கை வளங்கள் இல்லை, ஆனால் உலகின் தொழில்மயமான நாடுகளில் தரவரிசையில் உள்ளன. கிடைக்கக்கூடிய வளங்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதிலும், அவற்றைத் திறம்பட நிர்வகிப்பதற்கான சிறந்த முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வதிலும், வளக் கழிவுகளைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதிலும் இந்த நாடுகள் உறுதிப்பாட்டை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளன.மூலதன உருவாக்கம்: ஒரு பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சியில் மற்றொரு முக்கியமான அம்சம் மூலதன உருவாக்கம் ஆகும். மூலதன உருவாக்கம் என்பது ஒரு நாட்டின் உற்பத்தித் திறன் மற்றும் தொழிலாளர் செயல்திறனை அதிகரிக்கும் ஆலை, உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் இயந்திரங்கள் போன்ற மூலதனப் பொருட்களில் ஒரு சமூகத்தின் சேமிப்பு முதலீடு செய்யப்படும் செயல்முறையாகும். மூலதன உருவாக்கம், ஒரு சமூகம் அதன் முழுப் பணத்தையும் தற்போதைய நுகர்வோர் பொருட்களுக்குச் செலவிடுவதில்லை, மாறாக அதில் ஒரு பகுதியைச் சேமித்து, நாட்டின் உற்பத்தித் திறனை கணிசமாக அதிகரிக்கும் மூலதனப் பொருட்களை உருவாக்க அல்லது பெறுவதற்குப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது.தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம்: பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி விகிதத்தை தீர்மானிப்பதில் தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் முதன்மையாக புதிய மற்றும் மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட உற்பத்தி நுட்பங்களைப் பின்தொடர்வது அல்லது ஏற்கனவே உள்ள செயல்முறைகளை மேம்படுத்துகிறது. எப்போதாவது, தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் இயற்கை வளங்களின் கிடைக்கும் தன்மையை அதிகரிக்கிறது. இருப்பினும், தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் பொதுவாக உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிக்கிறது. வேறு வார்த்தைகளில் கூறுவதானால், தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் உற்பத்தியை விரிவுபடுத்தும் நோக்கத்திற்காக இயற்கை மற்றும் பிற வளங்களை மிகவும் திறமையான மற்றும் நன்மை பயக்கும் திறனை மேம்படுத்துகிறது. மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட தொழில்நுட்பத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் கொடுக்கப்பட்ட வளங்களின் தொகுப்பிலிருந்து அதிக வெளியீட்டைப் பெறுவது சாத்தியமாகும் அல்லது சிறிய வளங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் கொடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவை அடையலாம். தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம் இயற்கை வளங்களை மிகவும் திறமையாகப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கான நமது திறனை மேம்படுத்துகிறது, எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, சக்தியால் இயங்கும் கள உபகரணங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலம், விவசாய உற்பத்தி கணிசமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது. அமெரிக்கா, யுனைடெட் கிங்டம், பிரான்ஸ் மற்றும் ஜப்பான் மற்றும் பிற அதிநவீன தொழில்துறை நாடுகள் அனைத்தும் சிறந்த தொழில்நுட்பத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி தொழில்துறை வலிமையை உருவாக்கியுள்ளன. உண்மையில், புதிய உற்பத்தி நுட்பங்களைப் பின்பற்றுவதன் மூலம் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி ஊக்குவிக்கப்படுகிறது.மனித வள மேம்பாடு: பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி விகிதத்தை நிர்ணயிப்பதில் மக்கள்தொகையின் தரம் முக்கியமானது. எனவே, கல்வி, மருத்துவம் மற்றும் பிற சமூகத் திட்டங்கள் மூலம் மனித மூலதனத்தில் முதலீடு செய்வது மிகவும் நன்மை பயக்கும். மனித வள மேம்பாடு மக்களின் அறிவு, திறன்கள் மற்றும் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துகிறது, எனவே அவர்களின் உற்பத்தித்திறனை அதிகரிக்கிறது.மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி: மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி உழைப்பை உருவாக்குகிறது மற்றும் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளுக்கான விரிவாக்க சந்தையை உருவாக்குகிறது. இதனால், அதிகரித்த உழைப்பு உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிக்கிறது, இது ஒரு பெரிய சந்தை உறிஞ்சுகிறது. இந்த செயல்முறையானது உற்பத்தி, வருமானம் மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பில் தொடர்ச்சியான அதிகரிப்பு மற்றும் மேம்பட்ட பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை விளைவிக்கிறது. இருப்பினும், மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி வழக்கமானதாக இருக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்க வேண்டும். விரைவான மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி பொருளாதார முன்னேற்றத்தைத் தடுக்கிறது. குறைந்த மக்கள்தொகை கொண்ட நாட்டில் மட்டுமே மக்கள்தொகை விரிவாக்கம் நன்மை பயக்கும். இருப்பினும், இந்தியா போன்ற மக்கள் தொகை அடர்த்தியான நாட்டில் இது நியாயமற்றது.சமூக மேல்நிலைகள்:  பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியைப் பாதிக்கும் மற்றொரு முக்கியமான காரணி பள்ளிகள், கல்லூரிகள், தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனங்கள், மருத்துவக் கல்லூரிகள், மருத்துவமனைகள் மற்றும் பொது சுகாதார வசதிகள் போன்ற சமூக மேல்நிலைகளின் இருப்பு ஆகும். இத்தகைய வசதிகள் உழைக்கும் மக்களின் ஆரோக்கியம், செயல்திறன் மற்றும் பொறுப்புக்கு பங்களிக்கின்றன. அத்தகைய நபர்கள் தங்கள் நாட்டை பொருளாதார ரீதியாக முன்னேற்றும் திறன் கொண்டவர்கள்.பொருளாதாரம் அல்லாத காரணிகள்சமூகப் பொருளாதாரம், கலாச்சாரம், உளவியல் மற்றும் அரசியல் கருத்துக்கள் போன்ற பொருளாதாரமற்ற காரணிகள் அனைத்தும் பொருளாதார காரணிகளுடன் சமமான நிலையில் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியில் பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன. இந்தப் பிரிவில் பொருளாதாரத்தின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியைப் பாதிக்கும் சில முக்கியமான பொருளாதாரமற்ற கூறுகளை நாங்கள் உள்ளடக்குகிறோம்.அரசியல் காரணிகள் : அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பயனுள்ள நிர்வாகமானது நவீன பொருளாதார முன்னேற்றத்திற்கு அவசியமானது மற்றும் நன்மை பயக்கும். நிலையான, உறுதியான மற்றும் திறமையான அரசாங்கம், நெறிமுறை நிர்வாகம், தெளிவான கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் அவற்றை திறம்பட செயல்படுத்துவது முதலீட்டாளர்களின் நம்பிக்கையை வளர்த்து, உள்நாட்டு மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு மூலதனத்தை ஈர்க்கிறது, இதன் விளைவாக விரைவான பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி ஏற்படுகிறது.சமூக மற்றும் உளவியல் காரணிகள்: சமூக காரணிகளில் சமூக அணுகுமுறைகள், சமூக இலட்சியங்கள் மற்றும் சமூக நிறுவனங்கள் ஆகியவை அடங்கும், இவை அனைத்தும் கல்வி விரிவடையும் போது மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம் சமூகத்திலிருந்து சமூகத்திற்கு மாறுகிறது. நவீன சித்தாந்தம், மதிப்புகள் மற்றும் அணுகுமுறைகள் புதிய கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றங்களுக்கு பங்களிக்கின்றன, இதன் விளைவாக புதிய தொழில்முனைவோர் உருவாகிறார்கள். காலாவதியான சமூக மரபுகள் தொழில் மற்றும் புவியியல் இயக்கத்தைத் தடுக்கின்றன, பொருளாதார முன்னேற்றத்தைத் தடுக்கின்றன. கல்வி: கல்வியே வளர்ச்சியின் முதன்மையான வழி என்று பரவலாக ஒப்புக் கொள்ளப்படுகிறது. பரந்த கல்வி உள்ள நாடுகளில் அதிக முன்னேற்றம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. மனித வள மேம்பாட்டிற்கு கல்வி மிகவும் முக்கியமானது, ஏனெனில் இது தொழிலாளர் திறனை அதிகரிக்கிறது மற்றும் புதிய யோசனைகள் மற்றும் அறிவிற்கான மனத் தடைகளை குறைக்கிறது, எனவே பொருளாதார முன்னேற்றத்தை ஊக்குவிக்கிறது. பொருள் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான ஆசை: பொருள் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான ஆசை பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சிக்கு அவசியமான ஆனால் போதுமான முன்நிபந்தனை அல்ல. சுய திருப்தி, சுய மறுப்பு மற்றும் விதியின் மீதான நம்பிக்கை ஆகியவற்றின் மீது பிரீமியம் வைக்கும் சமூகங்கள், எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, ஆபத்து மற்றும் நிறுவனத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்துகின்றன, எனவே பொருளாதாரத்தை பின்தங்கிய நிலையில் வைத்திருக்கின்றன .2023-24 ஆம் ஆண்டில் உலக அளவில் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் முன்னேற்றங்களின் பாதையைப் பொறுத்து, ஜிடிபி வளர்ச்சி 6.0 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 6.8 சதவீதமாக இருக்கும்.உற்பத்தி நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு ஊக்கமளிக்கும் தனியார் நுகர்வு அதிகரிப்பு, அதிக மூலதனச் செலவு (கேபெக்ஸ்), உலகளாவிய தடுப்பூசி கவரேஜ், உணவகங்கள், ஹோட்டல்கள், வணிக வளாகங்கள் மற்றும் திரையரங்குகள் போன்ற தொடர்பு அடிப்படையிலான சேவைகளில் மக்கள் செலவழிக்க உதவுவது போன்ற பல நேர்மறைகளில் இருந்து நம்பிக்கையான வளர்ச்சி கணிப்புகள் உருவாகின்றன. அத்துடன் கட்டுமானத் தளங்களில் பணிபுரிய நகரங்களுக்கு புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்கள் திரும்புவது வீட்டுச் சந்தை சரக்குகளில் கணிசமான சரிவுக்கு வழிவகுத்தது, கார்ப்பரேட்களின் இருப்புநிலைகளை வலுப்படுத்துதல், குறு, சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர தொழில் நிறுவனங்களுக்கு (MSME) கடன் வளர்ச்சி முக்கிய நிறுவனங்களை பெயரிட நன்கு மூலதனம் பெற்ற பொதுத்துறை வங்கிகள் கடன் வழங்கலை அதிகரிக்கத் தயாராக உள்ளன.மத்திய நிதி மற்றும் பெருநிறுவன விவகாரங்களுக்கான அமைச்சர் திருமதி. நிர்மலா சீதாராமன் இன்று நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் 2022-23 பொருளாதார ஆய்வறிக்கையை தாக்கல் செய்தார், இது FY24 இல் உண்மையான அடிப்படையில் 6.5% அடிப்படை GDP வளர்ச்சியைக் கணித்துள்ளது. இந்த கணிப்பு உலக வங்கி, IMF மற்றும் ADB மற்றும் RBI போன்ற பலதரப்பு முகவர்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட மதிப்பீடுகளுடன்  பரந்த அளவில் ஒப்பிடத்தக்கது.FY24 இல் ஒரு தீவிரமான கடன் விநியோக வளர்ச்சி விறுவிறுப்பாக இருக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. மேலும் கார்ப்பரேட் மற்றும் வங்கித் துறைகளின் இருப்புநிலைகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் இந்தியாவில் மூலதன முதலீட்டு சுழற்சி வெளிப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சிக்கான கூடுதல் ஆதரவு, பொது டிஜிட்டல் தளங்களின் விரிவாக்கம் மற்றும் பிரதமரின் விரைவுசக்தி (கதிசக்தி), தேசிய சரக்குப் போக்குவரத்துக் கொள்கை மற்றும் உற்பத்தியோடு இணைக்கப்பட்ட ஊக்கத் திட்டங்கள் போன்றவை உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிக்கச் செய்யும் என்றும் அது கூறுகிறது.உண்மையான அடிப்படையில், மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடையும் நிதியாண்டில் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் 7 சதவீதமாக வளர்ச்சியடையும் என்று கணக்கெடுப்பு கூறுகிறது. இது முந்தைய நிதியாண்டில்  இருந்த 8.7 சதவீத வளர்ச்சியைத் தொடர்ந்து ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.கொவிட்-19 இன் மூன்று கட்ட அதிர்ச்சிகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், ரஷ்ய-உக்ரைன் மோதல்கள்,  அமெரிக்காவின் மத்திய வங்கியின் தலைமையிலான மத்திய வங்கிகள் பணவீக்கத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த ஒத்திசைக்கப்பட்ட கொள்கை விகித உயர்வுகளுடன் பதிலளித்தன. இது அமெரிக்க டாலரின் மதிப்பு அதிகரிப்பதற்கும், நடப்புக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறை (CAD) அதிகரிக்கவும் வழிவகுத்தது. நிகர இறக்குமதிப் பொருளாதாரங்களில்,  இந்தியாவை FY23 இல் 6.5-7.0 சதவீதமாக வேகமாக வளர்ந்து வரும் பெரிய பொருளாதாரமாக உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள முகமைகள் தொடர்ந்து குறிப்பிட்டு வருகின்றன.ஆய்வறிக்கையின்படி, FY23 இல் இந்தியாவின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியானது தனியார் நுகர்வு மற்றும் மூலதன உருவாக்கம் ஆகியவற்றால் முதன்மையாக வழிநடத்தப்பட்டது. மேலும், ஊழியர் வருங்கால வைப்பு நிதியில் விரைவான நிகரப் பதிவு போன்றவற்றின் மூலம் வேலைவாய்ப்பை உருவாக்க உதவியதன் விளைவாக நகர்ப்புற  வேலையின்மை விகிதம்  குறைவதையும் காண முடிந்தது. மேலும், 2 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான டோஸ்களை உள்ளடக்கிய உலகின் இரண்டாவது பெரிய தடுப்பூசி இயக்கம் நுகர்வோரின் உணர்வுகளை உயர்த்த உதவியது. இது நுகர்வில் ஏற்பட்ட மீட்சியை மேலும் நீட்டிக்க உதவும். இருப்பினும்,  வேலைவாய்ப்பை உருவாக்குவதற்கான தலைமைப் பாத்திரத்தை தனியார் மூலதனச் செலவு விரைவில் ஏற்க வேண்டிய அவசியம்  உள்ளது.இந்தியாவின் வளர்ச்சி குறித்த கண்ணோட்டத்திற்கு ஊக்கம் தருவதாக (i) சீனாவில் கொவிட்-19 நோய்த்தொற்றுகளின் தற்போதைய அதிகரிப்பின் விளைவாக  உலகின் பிற பகுதிகளில் ஏற்படக்கூடிய  வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியிலிருந்து எழுகிறது;  எனவே, விநியோகச் சங்கிலிகளை தொடர்ந்து இயல்பு நிலைக்குக் கொண்டு வந்துள்ளது; (ii) சீனாவின் பொருளாதாரம் மீண்டும் திறக்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து பணவீக்கத் தூண்டுதல்கள் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கதாகவோ அல்லது தொடர்ச்சியானதாகவோ இல்லை; (iii) 6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் குறைவான நிலையான உள்நாட்டுப் பணவீக்க விகிதத்தின் மத்தியில், முக்கியமான முன்னேறிய பொருளாதார நாடுகளில் (AEs) பின்னடைவு போக்குகள், பண இறுக்கம் ஆகியவை இந்தியாவை நோக்கிய மூலதனப் பாய்ச்சலை நிறுத்துவதைத் தூண்டுகிறது; (iv) இது தற்காப்பு உணர்வின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கு வழிவகுத்தது. மேலும்  தனியார் துறை முதலீட்டிற்கு உத்வேகத்தையும்  அளிக்கிறது.2022 ஜனவரி முதல் நவம்பர் வரையிலான காலத்தில், நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட அவசரக் கடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட உத்தரவாதத் திட்டத்தின் (ECLGS) ஆதரவுடன் குறு, சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தரத் தொழில்கள் (எம்எஸ்எம்இ) துறைக்கான கடன் வளர்ச்சி, சராசரியாக 30.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக, குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அளவில் அதிகமாக இருந்தது என இந்த ஆய்வறிக்கை கூறுகிறது. மத்திய அரசின். MSMEகளின் மீட்சி வேகமாக உள்ளது என்பதை அவர்கள் செலுத்தும் சரக்கு மற்றும் சேவை வரி (ஜிஎஸ்டி) அளவுகளில் இருந்து தெளிவாகத் தென்படுகிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் அவசரக் கடனுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட உத்தரவாதத் திட்டம் (ECGLS) அவர்களின் கடன் சேவை குறித்த கவலைகளைத் தளர்த்துகிறது.இது தவிர, வருவாயை அதிகரித்துள்ள நிலையற்ற பத்திரச் சந்தைகளில் இருந்தும், வட்டி மற்றும் ஹெட்ஜிங் செலவுகள் அதிகரித்துள்ள வெளிப்புற வணிகக் கடன்கள் ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து, கடன் வாங்குபவரின் நிதித் தேர்வுகள், வங்கிகளை நோக்கி மாறியதாலும் ஒட்டுமொத்த வங்கிக் கடன் அதிகரித்துள்ளது. FY24 இல் பணவீக்கம் குறைந்து, கடனுக்கான உண்மையான செலவு உயரவில்லை எனில், FY24 இல் கடன் வளர்ச்சி விறுவிறுப்பாக இருக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.FY23 இன் முதல் எட்டு மாதங்களில் 63.4 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்த மத்திய அரசின் மூலதனச் செலவு (Capex) நடப்பு ஆண்டில் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சிக்கான மற்றொரு உந்துதலாக இருந்தது. 2022 ஜனவரி-மார்ச் காலாண்டில் இருந்து தனியார் மூலதனச் செலவு அதிகரித்துள்ளது. தற்போதைய போக்கின் அடிப்படையில் பார்க்கும்போது, முழு ஆண்டுக்கான மூலதன செலவினத்திற்கான வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டம் நிறைவேற்றப்படும் என்று தோன்றுகிறது. கார்ப்பரேட்களின் இருப்புநிலைகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் தனியார் மூலதனச் செலவில் ஒரு தொடர்ச்சியான அதிகரிப்பை உடனடியாகவும், அதன் விளைவாக கடன் நிதியளிப்பில் அதை உருவாக்கவும் முடிந்தது.தொற்றுநோய் காலத்தில் கட்டுமான நடவடிக்கைகள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டதை, இந்த ஆய்வறிக்கை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது, குடிபெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்களை கட்டுமானத் தளங்களில் வேலை செய்ய மீண்டும் நகரங்களுக்குத் திரும்புவதற்கு தடுப்பூசிகள் வழிவகுத்தன. கடந்த ஆண்டில் சரக்கு கையிருப்பு 42 மாதங்கள் என்பதில் இருந்து FY23 இன் மூன்றாவது காலாண்டில் 33 மாதங்கள் என குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சரிவைக் கண்டுள்ள வீட்டுச் சந்தையில் இது தெளிவாகத் தெரிகிறது.மகாத்மா காந்தி தேசிய ஊரக வேலை உறுதித் திட்டம் (MGNREGS) நேரடியாக கிராமப்புறங்களில் வேலைகளை வழங்கி வருவதாகவும், கிராமப்புற குடும்பங்கள் தங்கள் வருமான ஆதாரங்களை பன்முகப்படுத்தும்  வாய்ப்புகளை அது மறைமுகமாக உருவாக்கி வருவதாகவும் ஆய்வறிக்கை கூறுகிறது. PM-Kisan மற்றும் PM Garib Kalyan Yojana போன்ற திட்டங்கள் நாட்டில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்த உதவியுள்ளன. மேலும் அவற்றின் தாக்கம் ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மேம்பாட்டுத் திட்டத்தால் (UNDP) அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது. தேசிய குடும்ப சுகாதார ஆய்வின் (NFHS) முடிவுகள், FY16 முதல் FY20 வரையிலான கிராமப்புற நலக் குறிகாட்டிகளில் முன்னேற்றத்தைக் காட்டுகின்றன. இது பாலினம், கருவுறுதல் விகிதம், வீட்டு வசதிகள் மற்றும் பெண்களுக்கு அதிகாரமளித்தல் போன்ற அம்சங்களை உள்ளடக்கியதாகும்.தொற்றுநோயை எதிர்கொண்ட பிறகு இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரம் முன்னேறி வருவதாகவும், பல நாடுகளை விட FY22 இல் முழு மீட்சியை அடைந்து, FY23 இல் தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முந்தைய வளர்ச்சிப் பாதையில் தன்னை நிலைநிறுத்துவதாகவும் ஆய்வறிக்கை நம்பிக்கையோடு குறிப்பிடுகிறது. எனினும், நடப்பு ஆண்டில், ஐரோப்பிய மோதல்கள் காரணமாக அதிகரித்த பணவீக்கத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும் சவாலை இந்தியாவும் எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது. அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் ரிசர்வ் வங்கி எடுத்த நடவடிக்கைகள், உலகளாவிய பொருட்களின் விலைகளை தளர்த்துவதுடன், இறுதியாக சில்லறை பணவீக்கத்தை நவம்பர் 2022 இல் RBI  குறிப்பிட்டுள்ள சகிப்புத்தன்மை இலக்குக்குக் கீழே கொண்டு வர முடிந்தது.எனினும், மற்ற நாணயங்களை விட சிறப்பாக செயல்பட்டாலும், மதிப்பிழந்து வரும் ரூபாயின் சவால், அமெரிக்க மத்திய வங்கியின் கொள்கை விகிதங்களில் மேலும் அதிகரிப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளுடன் தொடர்கிறது என்றும் அது எச்சரிக்கிறது. உலகளாவிய பொருட்களின் விலைகள் உயர்ந்து, இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சி வேகம் வலுவாக இருப்பதால், CAD இன் விரிவாக்கமும் தொடரக்கூடும். நடப்பு ஆண்டின் இரண்டாம் பாதியில் உலக வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வர்த்தகம் குறைவதன் விளைவாக, உலக சந்தையின் அளவு சுருங்குவதால், ஏற்றுமதிக்கான தூண்டுதல் மேலும் குறைவதற்கான வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது.எனவே, உலகளாவிய வளர்ச்சி 2023 இல் குறையும் என்று கணிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. மேலும் அடுத்தடுத்த ஆண்டுகளிலும் பொதுவாகக் குறையும் என்றும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. குறைந்து கொண்டே வரும் தேவை உலகளாவிய பொருட்களின் விலைகளை குறைக்கும்; FY24 இல் இந்தியாவின் CAD ஐ மேம்படுத்தும். இருப்பினும், நடப்புக் கணக்கு இருப்புக்கான எதிர்மறையான ஆபத்து முக்கியமாக உள்நாட்டுத் தேவை மற்றும் குறைந்த அளவிலான ஏற்றுமதியால் இயக்கப்படும் விரைவான மீட்சியிலிருந்து உருவாகிறது. நடப்பு ஆண்டின் வளர்ச்சி வேகம் அடுத்த வருடத்திற்கும் பரவுவதால், CAD ஐ உன்னிப்பாகக் கண்காணிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அது மேலும் கூறுகிறது.பொதுவாக, கடந்த காலங்களில் உலகப் பொருளாதார அதிர்ச்சிகள் கடுமையாக இருந்தன. ஆனால் நீண்ட  இடைவெளி இருந்தன. ஆனால் இந்த புத்தாயிரத்தின் மூன்றாவது தசாப்தத்தில் இந்த நிலை மாறியது. ஏனெனில் 2020 முதல்  உலகப் பொருளாதாரத்தை குறைந்தபட்சம் மூன்று அதிர்ச்சிகள் தாக்கியுள்ளன.இவை அனைத்துமே தொற்றுநோயால் தூண்டப்பட்ட உலகளாவிய உற்பத்திச் சுருக்கத்துடன் தொடங்கியது. அதைத் தொடர்ந்து ரஷ்ய-உக்ரைன் மோதல் உலகளாவிய பணவீக்கத்திற்கு வழிவகுத்தது. பின்னர், அமெரிக்க தலைமை  வங்கி தலைமையிலான பொருளாதாரங்களின் மத்திய வங்கிகள் பணவீக்கத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த ஒத்திசைவான கொள்கையின் அடிப்படையில் வட்டி விகித உயர்வுகளுடன் அதற்குப் பதிலளித்தன. அமெரிக்க மத்திய வங்கியின் வட்டி விகித உயர்வு அமெரிக்க சந்தைகளில் மூலதனத்தைக் கொண்டுவந்து இறக்கியது. இதனால் பெரும்பாலான நாடுகளின் நாணயங்களுக்கு எதிராக அமெரிக்க டாலரின் மதிப்பு உயர்ந்தது. இது நடப்புக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறையை (CAD) விரிவடையச் செய்தது. நிகர இறக்குமதிப் பொருளாதாரங்களில் பணவீக்க அழுத்தங்கள் அதிகரித்தன.வட்டி விகித உயர்வு மற்றும் தொடர்ந்த பணவீக்கம் ஆகியவை 2022 மற்றும் 2023க்கான உலகளாவிய வளர்ச்சி கணிப்புகளை IMF தனது அக்டோபர் 2022 இல் உலகப் பொருளாதாரக் கண்ணோட்டத்தின் புதுப்பித்தலில் குறைக்க வழிவகுத்தன. சீனப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் பலவீனங்கள் இந்த வளர்ச்சிக்கான கணிப்புகளை மேலும் பலவீனப்படுத்த உதவியது. உலக நிதி நெருக்கடிக்குப் பின்னர் நிதியல்லாத துறையின் கடன் அதிகமாக உயர்ந்துள்ள முன்னேறிய பொருளாதார நாடுகளில் இருந்து வெளிப்படும் நிதித் தொற்றுக்கு பணவியல் இறுக்கத்தைத் தவிர உலகளாவிய வளர்ச்சியைக் குறைப்பதும் வழிவகுக்கும். முன்னேறிய பொருளாதாரங்களில் பணவீக்கம் நீடிப்பதாலும், மத்திய வங்கிகள் மேலும் வட்டி விகித உயர்வைக் குறிப்பதாலும், உலகப் பொருளாதாரக் கண்ணோட்டத்திற்கு எதிர்மறையான அபாயங்கள் மேலோங்கியதாகத் தோன்றுகிறது.இந்திய பொருளாதாரத்தின் தாங்கு சக்தியும்   வளர்ச்சிக்கான ஊக்கிகளும்ரிசர்வ் வங்கியின் பண நெருக்கடி, அதிகரித்து வரும் நடப்புக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதியின் ஏற்றத்தாழ்வில்லாத வளர்ச்சி போன்ற காரணிகள், அடிப்படையில் ஐரோப்பாவின் புவிசார் அரசியல் சண்டையின் விளைவே என்று ஆய்வறிக்கை சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது. இந்த முன்னேற்றங்கள் FY23 இல் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு எதிர்மறையான அபாயங்களை ஏற்படுத்தியதால், உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள பல முகமைகள் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சி குறித்த கணிப்புகளை கீழ்நோக்கித் திருத்திக் கொண்டிருக்கின்றன. NSO ஆல் வெளியிடப்பட்ட முன்கூட்டிய மதிப்பீடுகள் உட்பட, இந்த முன்னறிவிப்புகள், இப்போது பரந்த அளவில் 6.5-7.0 சதவீத வரம்பில் உள்ளது.கீழ்நோக்கிய திருத்தம் இருந்தபோதிலும், FY23க்கான வளர்ச்சி குறித்த மதிப்பீடு கிட்டத்தட்ட அனைத்து முக்கியப் பொருளாதாரங்களையும் விட அதிகமாக உள்ளது. தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முந்தைய தசாப்தத்தில் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் சராசரி வளர்ச்சியை விட அது சற்று அதிகமாகவே உள்ளது.2022இல் இந்தியா வேகமாக வளரும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பொருளாதாரங்களில் ஒன்றாக இருக்கும் என்று IMF மதிப்பிட்டுள்ளது. வலுவான உலகளாவிய தலையீடுகள் மற்றும் இறுக்கமான உள்நாட்டு நாணயக் கொள்கை இருந்தபோதிலும், இந்தியா இன்னும் 6.5 முதல் 7.0 சதவிகிதம் வரை வளர்ச்சியடையும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டால், அதுவும்  அடித்தள விளைவின் சாதகம் இல்லாமல் எனில், இது இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் உள்ளார்ந்த தாங்கு சக்தியின், மீண்டெழுவதற்கான அதன் திறன், பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சிக்கான உந்துசக்திகளைப் புதுப்பித்தல்; புத்துயிர் ஊட்டலுக்கான அதன் திறன் ஆகியவற்றின் பிரதிபலிப்பே ஆகும்.  வெளிப்புற உந்துதலுக்குப் பதிலாக வளர்ச்சிக்கான உள்நாட்டு உந்துதலை எளிதாகப் பயன்படுத்தியதில் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் தாங்கு சக்தியைக் காண முடியும். FY23இன் இரண்டாவது அரையாண்டில் ஏற்றுமதி வளர்ச்சி ஓரளவிற்கு சுமாராக இருந்திருக்கலாம். எனினும், FY22இலும் FY23இன் முதல் அரையாண்டிலும்  ஏற்பட்ட அதன் எழுச்சியும் உற்பத்தி செயல்பாட்டினை மெதுவான வேகம் என்பதிலிருந்து தொடர்ந்து செயல்படும் நிலைக்கு உந்தித் தள்ளின. அதன் விளைவாக, உற்பத்தி மற்றும் முதலீட்டு நடவடிக்கைகள்  வேகம் பெற்றன. ஏற்றுமதியின் வளர்ச்சி மிதமாக இருந்த அதேநேரத்தில், உள்நாட்டு நுகர்வின் புத்துயிர்ப்பு இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் வளர்ச்சியை முன்னோக்கி எடுத்துச் செல்ல போதுமான அளவு முதிர்ச்சியடைந்தது. மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியின் சதவீதமாக தனியார் நுகர்வு FY23 இன் இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் 58.4 சதவீதமாக இருந்தது. இது 2013-14 முதலான அனைத்து ஆண்டுகளிலும் இரண்டாவது காலாண்டுகளில் மிக அதிகமாக இருந்தது. வர்த்தகம், ஹோட்டல் மற்றும் போக்குவரத்து போன்ற தீவிர தொடர்பு சேவைகளின் மீள் எழுச்சியால்  இது ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டது. முந்தைய காலாண்டுடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது FY23 இன்  இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் உண்மையான அடிப்படையில் 16 சதவிகிதம் தொடர்ச்சியான வளர்ச்சியை பதிவு செய்தது.பல பொருளாதாரங்களில் உள்நாட்டு நுகர்வு மீண்டெழுந்தாலும், இந்தியாவில் மீள் எழுச்சி அதன் அளவிற்கு கவனத்தை ஈர்க்கக்கூடியதாக இருந்தது. இது உள்நாட்டு திறன் பயன்பாடு அதிகரிப்புக்கு பங்களித்தது. நவம்பர் 2022 இல் உள்நாட்டு தனியார் நுகர்வு மிதமாக உள்ளது. மேலும், டிசம்பர் 2022 இல் வெளியிடப்பட்ட நுகர்வோர் நம்பிக்கை பற்றிய RBI இன் மிகச் சமீபத்திய கணக்கெடுப்பு தற்போதைய மற்றும் வருங்கால வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் வருமான நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பான உணர்வு மேம்படுத்துவதை சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது.கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றொரு மீட்சியையும் சுட்டிக் காட்டுகிறது. வீட்டுக் கடன்களுக்கான தேவை அதிகரித்ததால், \\"அடக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த  தேவையின் வெளிப்பட்டு\\"  அது வீட்டுச் சந்தையிலும் பிரதிபலித்தது. இதன் விளைவாக, வாங்குவாரின்றி தேங்கியிருந்த வீடுகளின் எண்ணிக்கை குறைந்துள்ளன. விலைகளும் உயர்ந்து வருகின்றன. மேலும் புதிய குடியிருப்புகள் கட்டும் பணி வேகமெடுத்து வருகிறது. மேலும் இது கட்டுமானத் துறை கொண்டு செல்வதாக அறியப்படும் எண்ணற்ற பின்தங்கிய மற்றும் முன்னோக்கிய இணைப்புகளுக்கு ஊக்கமளித்துள்ளது.  அனைவருக்குமான தடுப்பூசி நடவடிக்கையானது  வீட்டுச் சந்தையை உயர்த்துவதில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்கை செலுத்தியுள்ளது. அவ்வாறில்லை எனில், புதிய குடியிருப்புகளை கட்டுவதற்கென புலம்பெயர் தொழிலாளர்கள் தங்கள் பணியிடங்களுக்குத் திரும்பியிருக்க மாட்டார்கள்.மத்திய அரசு மற்றும் அதன் பொதுத்துறை நிறுவனங்களின் மிகவும் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட மூலதன வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் (கேபெக்ஸ்) விரைவாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுவதால், வீட்டுவசதி தவிர, பொதுவாக, கட்டுமான நடவடிக்கைகள்,  FY23  நிதியாண்டில் கணிசமாக உயர்ந்துள்ளன.நாட்டிற்காக மதிப்பிடப்பட்ட மூலதனச் செலவுகள் குறித்த பெருக்கியின்படி, நாட்டின் பொருளாதார உற்பத்தியானது மூலதனச் செலவின் அளவை விட குறைந்தது நான்கு மடங்கு அதிகரிக்கும். மாநிலங்கள், ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக, தங்கள் மூலதனச் செலவு திட்டங்களுடன் சிறப்பாகச் செயல்படுகின்றன. மத்திய அரசைப் போலவே, மாநிலங்களும் மூலதனப் பணிகளுக்கான மையத்தின் மானியம் மற்றும் 50 ஆண்டுகளில் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தக்கூடிய வட்டியில்லா கடன் ஆகியவற்றால் ஆதரிக்கப்படும் பெரும் மூலதன வரவு-செலவு திட்டத்தை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளன.மேலும், இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் கடந்த இரண்டு  ஆண்டுகளுக்கான வரவு செலவுத் திட்டங்களில் மூலதனச் செலவிற்கான உந்துதல் என்பது நாட்டில் உள்ள உள்கட்டமைப்பு இடைவெளிகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கான ஒரு தனிப்பட்ட முயற்சி அல்ல. இது பொதுத்துறை நிறுவனங்களில் உள்ள,  செயலற்று இருக்கும்  பொதுத்துறை சொத்துக்களில் உள்ள அரசின் முதலீடுகளை விடுவிப்பதன் மூலம் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட பொருளாதாரத் துறையில் தனியார் முதலீட்டின் பங்கைக் கூட்டுவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட தொலைநோக்குமிக்க தொகுப்பின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும்.இங்கே, மூன்று நிகழ்வுகள் இதற்கு உதவியாக இருந்தன. முதலில் நிதியாண்டின் 23ஆம் நிதியாண்டில்  வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டத்தில் மூலதனச் செலவின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அதிகரிப்பு, அத்துடன் அதன் அதிக செலவு விகிதம், இரண்டாவதாக, நேரடி வரி வருவாய் வசூல் மிகவும் உற்சாகமானதாக இருந்தது. அதேபோன்று ஜிஎஸ்டி வசூலும் இருந்தது. இது முழு செலவினத்தையும் உறுதி செய்ய வேண்டும். பட்ஜெட் நிதிப் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு உள்ளாகவே மூலதனச் செலவிற்கான  பட்ஜெட் போடப்பட்டிருந்தது. வருவாய் செலவினங்களின் வளர்ச்சி கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டிருந்த நிலையில்  2022 ஜனவரி-மார்ச் காலாண்டில் இருந்து மூலதனச் செலவின்  அதிக வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் மூன்றாவதாக தனியார் துறை முதலீட்டின் அதிகரிப்புக்கும் வழி வகுத்தது. திட்டங்கள் குறித்த அறிவிப்புகள் அதிகரித்து  வந்ததும், தனியாரின் மூலதனச் செலவும் இதற்கான ஆதாரத்தை எடுத்துக் கூறுகின்றன.ஏற்றுமதித் தேவை அதிகரிப்பு, நுகர்வு அதிகரிப்பு மற்றும் அரசின் மூலதனச் செலவு ஆகியவை கார்ப்பரேட் நிறுவனங்கள் முதலீடு/உற்பத்தி நடவடிக்கைகளில் மீண்டு வருவதற்குப் பங்களித்தாலும், அவற்றின் வலுவான இருப்புநிலைக் குறிப்பீடுகளும் அவர்களின் செலவினத் திட்டங்களை நிறைவேற்றுவதில் பெரும் பங்கு வகித்தன. சர்வதேச தீர்வுகளுக்கான வங்கியின் நிதியல்லாத கடன் பற்றிய தரவுகளின்படி, கடந்த பத்தாண்டுகளில், மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் ஒரு பங்காக இந்திய நிதி அல்லாத தனியார் துறைக் கடன் மற்றும் நிதி அல்லாத பெருநிறுவனக் கடன்கள் கிட்டத்தட்ட முப்பது சதவீத புள்ளிகள் குறைந்துள்ளன.2022 ஜனவரி-மார்ச் காலாண்டில் இருந்து ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு கடன் வளர்ச்சி இரட்டை இலக்கங்களுக்கு நகர்ந்து பெரும்பாலான துறைகளில் உயர்ந்து வருவதால், இந்தியாவில் உள்ள வங்கித் துறையும் கடனுக்கான தேவையை சமமான அளவிற்கு எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது.பொதுத்துறை வங்கிகளின் நிதிநிலையும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க மாற்றத்தைக் கண்டுள்ளது. இலாபங்கள் சீரான இடைவெளியில் பதிவு செய்யப்படுகின்றன. அவற்றின் வாராக்கடன்கள் (NPAs) விரைவான தீர்வு/கலைப்பிற்காக இந்திய திவால் மற்றும் நொடிப்பு வாரியத்தால் (IBBI) வேகமாக கண்காணிக்கப்படுகின்றன. அதே நேரத்தில், பொதுத்துறை  வங்கிகள்  நல்ல மூலதனம் வைத்திருக்க்கும்  வகையில்   அரசாங்கம் போதுமான வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட ரீதியான ஆதரவை வழங்கி வருகிறது. அவற்றின் மூலதன இடர்-கணிப்பு சரிசெய்யப்பட்ட விகிதம் (CRAR) போதுமான அளவு வரம்புக்கு மேல் வசதியாக இருப்பதையும் உறுதி செய்கிறது. இருந்தபோதிலும், இத்தகைய நிதி வலிமையின் விளைவாக, 2023 நிதியாண்டில் இதுவரை கார்ப்பரேட் பத்திரங்கள் மற்றும் வெளிப்புற வணிகக் கடன்கள் (ECB) மூலம் வழங்கப்பட்ட குறைந்த கடன் நிதியை ஈடுசெய்ய வங்கிகளுக்கு உதவியுள்ளது. கார்ப்பரேட் பத்திரங்கள் மற்றும் வெளிப்புற  வணிகக்கடன்களில் அதிக வட்டி/ஹெட்ஜிங் செலவுகள் ஆகியவை இந்த வசதிகளை முந்தைய ஆண்டை விட கவர்ச்சிகரமானதாக மாற்றியுள்ளன.ரிசர்வ் வங்கி 23 நிதியாண்டில் மொத்த பணவீக்கம் 6.8 சதவீதமாக இருக்கும் என்று கணித்துள்ளது. இது அதன் இலக்கு வரம்பிற்கு வெளியே உள்ளதாகும். அதே நேரத்தில், இது தனியார் நுகர்வுகளைத் தடுக்கும் அளவுக்கு அதிகமாக இல்லை. மேலும் முதலீடு செய்வதற்கான தூண்டுதலை பலவீனப்படுத்தும் அளவுக்கு குறைவாகவும் இல்லை.இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரத்தில் பருப்பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் வளர்ச்சிக்கான சவால்கள்FY21 இல் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க GDP சுருக்கத்தில் காணப்பட்ட தொற்றுநோயின் இரண்டு அலைகளின் தாக்கத்திற்குப் பிறகு, ஒமைக்ரான் வகைப்பட்ட வைரஸின் மூன்றாவது அலையில் இருந்து விடுபட்டதால் ஏற்பட்ட விரைவான மீட்சியானது 2022 ஜனவரி-மார்ச் காலாண்டில் பொருளாதார உற்பத்தி இழப்பைக் குறைப்பதில் பங்களித்தது. இதன் விளைவாக, வெளியீடு FY22 இல் நிகர  வெளிப்பாடு, FY20 இல் நிலவிய  தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முந்தைய நிலையைத் தாண்டியது. இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரம் மற்ற பல நாடுகளை விட முழுமையான மீட்சியைக் கண்டது. எனினும், ஐரோப்பாவில் ஏற்பட்ட மோதலால் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் FY23 இல் பணவீக்கத்திற்கான எதிர்பார்ப்புகளில்  திருத்தம் தேவைப்பட்டது. நாட்டின் சில்லறை பணவீக்கம் ஜனவரி 2022 இல் ரிசர்வ் வங்கி நிர்ணயித்த சகிப்புத்தன்மை வரம்பை விட அதிகமாக இருந்தது. மேலும் இது நவம்பர் 2022 இல் இலக்கு வரம்பின் 6 சதவீதத்தின் மேல் இறுதியில் திரும்புவதற்கு முன், பத்து மாதங்களுக்கு இலக்கு வரம்பிற்கு மேல் நீடித்தது.உலகளாவிய பொருட்களின் விலைகள் தளர்த்தப்பட்டிருக்கலாம். ஆனால் மோதலுக்கு முந்தைய நிலைகளுடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது இன்னும் அதிகமாகவே உள்ளன. மேலும் அவை இந்தியாவின் வளர்ச்சி வேகத்தால் ஏற்கனவே விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட CAD ஐ மேலும் விரிவுபடுத்தியுள்ளன. FY23க்கு, CADக்கு நிதியளிப்பதற்கும், இந்திய ரூபாயில் ஏற்படும் ஏற்ற இறக்கத்தை நிர்வகிக்க அந்நிய செலாவணி சந்தையில் தலையிடுவதற்கும் இந்தியா போதுமான அந்நிய செலாவணி இருப்பைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.2023-24க்கான கண்ணோட்டம்:2023-24 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான கண்ணோட்டத்தைப் பற்றி, இந்த ஆய்வு கூறுகிறது: தொற்றுநோயிலிருந்து இந்தியா மீள்வது ஒப்பீட்டளவில் விரைவானது. மேலும் வரவிருக்கும் ஆண்டில் வளர்ச்சியானது திடமான உள்நாட்டு தேவை மற்றும் மூலதன முதலீட்டின் அதிகரிப்பு ஆகியவற்றால் ஆதரிக்கப்படும். ஆரோக்கியமான நிதிகளின் உதவியுடன், ஒரு புதிய தனியார் துறை மூலதன உருவாக்க சுழற்சியின் ஆரம்ப அறிகுறிகள் காணக்கூடியதாக இருப்பதாகவும், மிக முக்கியமாக, மூலதனச் செலவினங்களில் தனியார் துறையின் எச்சரிக்கையை ஈடுசெய்யும் வகையில், அரசு தனது மூலதனச் செலவினத்தை கணிசமாக உயர்த்தியது.கடந்த ஏழு ஆண்டுகளில், FY16 முதல் FY23 வரை பட்ஜெட்களில்,  செய்யப்பட்ட மூலதனச் செலவு 2.7 மடங்கு உயர்ந்துள்ளது.  இது  மூலதனச் செலவுக்கான சுழற்சியை மீண்டும் ஊக்குவிக்கிறது. சரக்கு மற்றும் சேவை வரி மற்றும் திவால் மற்றும் நொடிப்புச் சட்டம் போன்ற கட்டமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்கள் பொருளாதாரத்தின் செயல்திறன் மற்றும் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையை மேம்படுத்தின. மேலும் நிதி ஒழுக்கம் மற்றும் சிறந்த இணக்கத்தை உறுதி செய்தன என்றும் ஆய்வு குறிப்பிடுகிறது.IMF இன் உலகப் பொருளாதாரக் கண்ணோட்டம், அக்டோபர் 2022 இன் படி, உலகளாவிய வளர்ச்சி 2022 இல் 3.2 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 2023 இல் 2.7 சதவீதமாகக் குறையும் என்று கணிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பொருளாதார உற்பத்தியில் மெதுவான வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் அதிகரித்த நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மை வர்த்தக வளர்ச்சியைக் குறைக்கும். 2022 இல் 3.5 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 2023 இல் 1.0 சதவீதமாக உலக வர்த்தக அமைப்பின் உலகளாவிய வர்த்தகத்தின் வளர்ச்சிக்கான குறைவான முன்னறிவிப்பில் இது காணப்படுகிறது.வெளிப்புறத்தில், நடப்புக் கணக்கு இருப்புக்கான அபாயங்கள் பல காரணிகளிலிருந்து உருவாகின்றன. பொருட்களின் விலைகள் உச்சத்தில் இருந்து பின்வாங்கியிருந்தாலும், அவை இன்னும் மோதலுக்கு முந்தைய நிலைகளை விட அதிகமாகவே உள்ளன. அதிகப் பொருட்களின் விலைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் வலுவான உள்நாட்டுத் தேவை இந்தியாவின் மொத்த இறக்குமதி கட்டணத்தை உயர்த்தும். மேலும் நடப்புக் கணக்கு இருப்பில் சாதகமற்ற முன்னேற்றங்களுக்கும் பங்களிக்கும். உலகளாவிய தேவை குறைந்து வருவதால், ஏற்றுமதி வளர்ச்சியை சமநிலைப் படுத்துவதன் மூலம் அதிகரிக்கச் செய்யலாம். நடப்புக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறை மேலும் அதிகரித்தால், நாணயம் தேய்மான அழுத்தத்தின் கீழ் வரக் கூடும்.ஆழமாக வேரூன்றிய பணவீக்கம் இறுக்கமான சுழற்சியை நீடிக்கச் செய்யலாம். எனவே, கடன் வாங்கும் செலவுகள் 'நீண்ட காலத்திற்கு அதிகமாகவே' இருக்கும். அத்தகைய சூழ்நிலையில், உலகப் பொருளாதாரம் FY24 இல் குறைந்த வளர்ச்சியால் வகைப்படுத்தப்படலாம். இருப்பினும், தாழ்ந்த உலக வளர்ச்சியின் சூழ்நிலை இரண்டு நன்மைகளை அளிக்கிறது: எண்ணெய் விலைகள் குறைவாக இருக்கும். மேலும் இந்தியாவின் CAD தற்போது கணிக்கப்பட்டதை விட சிறப்பாக இருக்கும். ஒட்டுமொத்த வெளிப்புற சூழ்நிலையும் சமாளிக்கக்கூடியதாகவே இருக்கும்.இந்தியாவின் உள்ளடக்கிய வளர்ச்சிவேலை வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்கும் போது வளர்ச்சி அதில் உள்ளடங்கியதாக இருக்கும் என்பதை இந்த ஆய்வு வலியுறுத்துகிறது. 2021 செப்டம்பர் மாதத்துடன் முடிவடைந்த காலாண்டில் 15 வயது மற்றும் அதற்கு மேற்பட்டவர்களுக்கான நகர்ப்புற வேலையின்மை விகிதம் 9.8 சதவீதத்தில் இருந்து ஒரு வருடம் கழித்து 7.2 சதவீதத்திற்கு குறைந்துள்ளதாக காலமுறை தொழிலாளர் படை கணக்கெடுப்பு (பிஎல்எஃப்எஸ்) காட்டுவதால், நடப்பு நிதியாண்டில் (செப்டம்பர் 2022 முடிவடையும் காலாண்டு) வேலைவாய்ப்பு நிலைகள் உயர்ந்துள்ளதாக அதிகாரப்பூர்வ மற்றும் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமற்ற ஆதாரங்கள் உறுதிப்படுத்துகின்றன. இது தொழிலாளர் பங்கேற்பு விகிதத்திலும் (LFPR) முன்னேற்றத்துடன் உள்ளது. இது FY23 இன் தொடக்கத்தில் தொற்றுநோயால் தூண்டப்பட்ட மந்தநிலையிலிருந்து பொருளாதாரம் வெளிவந்துள்ளதை உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது.FY21 இல், அரசாங்கம் அவசரகாலக் கடன்களுக்கான  உத்தரவாதத் திட்டத்தை அறிவித்தது. இது குறு, சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர நிறுவனங்களை நிதி நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து பாதுகாப்பதில் வெற்றி பெற்றது. சமீபத்திய CIBIL அறிக்கை (ECLGS இன்சைட்ஸ், ஆகஸ்ட் 2022) கொவிட் அதிர்ச்சியை எதிர்கொள்வதில் இந்தத் திட்டம் MSME-களை ஆதரித்துள்ளது. ECLGS வசதியைப் பெற்ற கடன் வாங்கியவர்களில் 83 சதவீதம் பேர் குறு நிறுவனங்களாக உள்ளனர். இந்த மைக்ரோ யூனிட்களில், பாதிக்கும் மேற்பட்டவை ஒட்டுமொத்த நுகர்வு ரூ.10 லட்சத்துக்கும் குறைவாகவே இருந்தது.மேலும், ECLGS க்கு தகுதியுடைய நிறுவனங்களை விட ECLGS கடன் வாங்குபவர்கள் குறைவாகவே செயல்படாத சொத்து விகிதங்களைக் கொண்டிருந்தனர் என்பதையும் CIBIL தரவு காட்டுகிறது. மேலும், MSME-கள் FY21 இல் சரிந்த பிறகு செலுத்தும் GST, இப்போது FY20 இன் தொற்றுநோய்க்கு முந்தைய நிலையைத் தாண்டியுள்ளது, இது சிறு வணிகங்களின் நிதி நிலைத்தன்மை மற்றும் MSME களை இலக்காகக் கொண்ட முன்கூட்டிய அரசாங்கத் தலையீட்டின் செயல்திறனைப் பிரதிபலிக்கிறது.மேலும், மகாத்மா காந்தி தேசிய ஊரக வேலை உறுதிச் சட்டத்தின் (MGNREGA) கீழ் அரசாங்கத்தால் செயல்படுத்தப்பட்ட திட்டம், \\"தனிநபர்களின் நிலத்தில் வேலைகள்\\" தொடர்பாக வேறு எந்த வகையிலும் இல்லாத அளவுக்கு அதிகமான சொத்துக்களை விரைவாக உருவாக்கி வருகிறது. கூடுதலாக, கிராமப்புற மக்கள்தொகையில் பாதியை உள்ளடக்கிய குடும்பங்களுக்கு பயனளிக்கும் பிரதமரின் கிசான் திட்டம் மற்றும் பிரதமர் ஏழைகள் வளர்ச்சிக்கான திட்டம் போன்றவை நாட்டில் வறுமையைக் குறைப்பதில் கணிசமாக பங்களித்துள்ளன.ஜூலை 2022 இன் UNDP அறிக்கை, இந்தியாவில் சமீபத்திய பணவீக்க நிலை நன்கு இலக்கு வைக்கப்பட்ட ஆதரவின் காரணமாக குறைந்த வறுமை தாக்கத்தையே ஏற்படுத்தும் என்று கூறியது. மேலும், இந்தியாவில் உள்ள தேசிய குடும்ப சுகாதார ஆய்வு (NFHS) FY16 முதல் FY20 வரை மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட கிராமப்புற நலக் குறிகாட்டிகளைக் காட்டுகிறது. இது பாலினம், கருவுறுதல் விகிதம், வீட்டு வசதிகள் மற்றும் பெண்களுக்கு அதிகாரமளித்தல் போன்ற அம்சங்களை உள்ளடக்கியது.இதுவரை, வளர்ச்சி வேகத்தை இழக்காமல், ரஷ்யா-உக்ரைன் மோதலால் ஏற்படும் வெளிப்புற ஏற்றத்தாழ்வுகளைத் தணிக்கும் சவாலை, இந்தியா தனது பொருளாதார மீட்சியின் மீதான நம்பிக்கையை வலுப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.  வெளிநாட்டு  முதலீட்டாளர்களால் போடப்பட்ட முதலீடு திரும்பப் பெறப்பட்ட போதிலும் அதனால் கவலைப்படாமல் இந்திய பங்குச் சந்தைகள் CY22 இல் நேர்மறையான வருமானத்தைப் பெற்றன. பல முன்னேறிய நாடுகள் மற்றும் பிராந்தியங்களுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் இந்தியாவின் பணவீக்க விகிதம் அதன் சகிப்பு வரம்பை விட அதிகமாக இல்லை.PPP அடிப்படையில்,  உலகின் மூன்றாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரமாகவும், சந்தை மாற்று விகிதங்களில் ஐந்தாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரமாகவும் இந்தியா உள்ளது. இந்த அளவிலான தேசம் எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டதைப் போலவே, FY23 இல் இந்தியப் பொருளாதாரம் இழந்ததை கிட்டத்தட்ட \\"மீட்டெடுத்துள்ளது\\"; இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டதை \\"புதுப்பித்துள்ளது\\"; மேலும் தொற்றுநோய்களின் போதும் ஐரோப்பாவில் ஏற்பட்ட மோதலுக்குப் பிறகும் வேகமிழந்து நின்றதை  \\"மீண்டும் உற்சாகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது\\".தனித்துவமான சவால்களின் மூலம் போராடும் உலகளாவிய பொருளாதாரம்உலகளாவிய பொருளாதாரம் எதிர்கொள்ளும் ஆறு சவால்களைப் பற்றி இந்த ஆய்வு  விவரிக்கிறது. பொருளாதாரத்தில் COVID-19 தொடர்பான இடையூறுகள், ரஷ்ய-உக்ரைன் மோதல்கள் மற்றும் அதன் பாதகமான தாக்கம் மற்றும் முக்கியமாக உணவு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் உரம் விநியோகச் சங்கிலியில் ஏற்படும் இடையூறுகள் ஆகியவற்றின் அடிப்படையில் மத்திய வங்கிகள் ஒத்திசைக்கப்பட்ட கொள்கை விகித உயர்வுகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கின்றன. பணவீக்கத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த, அமெரிக்க டாலரின் மதிப்பு அதிகரிப்பதற்கும், நிகர இறக்குமதிப் பொருளாதாரங்களில் நடப்புக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறை (CAD) அதிகரிப்பதற்கும் இது வழிவகுத்தது. நான்காவது சவாலானது உலகளாவிய தேக்கநிலையின் வாய்ப்புகளை எதிர்கொண்டதாகும். நாடுகள், அந்தந்த நாட்டின் பொருளாதார இடத்தைப் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் உள்ளன. இதனால் ஒட்டுமொத்த வளர்ச்சியை பாதிக்கும் எல்லை தாண்டிய வர்த்தகம் மெதுவாக உள்ளது. சீனா தனது கொள்கைகளால் தூண்டப்பட்ட கணிசமான மந்தநிலையை அனுபவித்ததால், ஐந்தாவது சவால் சீர்குலைந்து கொண்டிருந்தது என்று அது மேலும் கூறுகிறது. வளர்ச்சிக்கான ஆறாவது நடுத்தர கால சவாலானது, கல்வி மற்றும் வருமானம் ஈட்டும் வாய்ப்புகளை இழந்ததன் மூலம் ஆனது. இது தொற்றுநோயால் ஏற்பட்ட வடுவில் காணப்பட்டது.உலகின் பிற நாடுகளைப் போலவே, இந்தியாவும் இந்த அசாதாரண சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டது. எனினும் பெரும்பாலான பொருளாதாரங்களை விட அவற்றை சிறப்பாக எதிர்கொண்டது என்று இந்த ஆய்வறிக்கை குறிப்பிடுகிறது.கடந்த பதினொரு மாதங்களில், உலகப் பொருளாதாரம் இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளில் தொற்றுநோயால் ஏற்பட்ட பல இடையூறுகளை எதிர்கொண்டது. இந்த மோதல் காரணமாக கச்சா எண்ணெய், இயற்கை எரிவாயு, உரங்கள், கோதுமை போன்ற முக்கியமான பொருட்களின் விலைகள் உயர்ந்தன. இது, 2020ல் உற்பத்திச் சுருக்கத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதற்காக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட வலுவான நிதித் தூண்டுதல்கள் மற்றும் தீவிர இடமளிக்கும் பணவியல் கொள்கைகளின் ஆதரவுடன், உலகப் பொருளாதார மீட்சி தூண்டிய பணவீக்க அழுத்தங்களை வலுப்படுத்தியது. முன்னேறிய பொருளாதார நாடுகளில் (AEs) பணவீக்கம், உலக நிதி விரிவாக்கம் மற்றும் பணமதிப்பு நீக்கம் ஆகியவற்றில் பெரும்பகுதிக்கு காரணமாக இருந்தது. இது வரலாற்று ரீதியான உச்சத்தை மீறியது. அதிகரித்து வரும் பொருட்களின் விலைகள், வளர்ந்து வரும் சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரங்களில் (EMEs) அதிக பணவீக்கத்திற்கு வழிவகுத்தது. இல்லையெனில் 2020 இல் உற்பத்திச் சுருக்கத்தை நிவர்த்தி செய்ய அவர்களது அரசாங்கங்கள் அளவீடு செய்யப்பட்ட நிதி ஊக்கத்தை மேற்கொண்டதன் மூலம் குறைந்த பணவீக்க மண்டலத்தில் இருந்தன.பணவீக்கம் மற்றும் பண இறுக்கம் ஆகியவை பொருளாதாரங்கள் முழுவதும் பத்திரங்கள் மூலமான வருவாயை மேலும் கடினப்படுத்த வழிவகுத்தது. உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள பெரும்பாலான பொருளாதாரங்களில் இருந்து பங்கு மூலதனம் அமெரிக்காவின் பாரம்பரியமாக பாதுகாப்பான புகலிட சந்தைக்கு வெளியேற வழிவகுத்தது என்று இந்த ஆய்வறிக்கை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது. இந்த மூலதன வெளியேற்றம் பிற நாணயங்களுக்கு எதிராக அமெரிக்க டாலரை வலுப்படுத்த வழிவகுத்தது. ஜனவரி மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் 2022க்கு இடையில் அமெரிக்க டாலர் குறியீடு 16.1 சதவிகிதம் வலுப்பெற்றது. இதன் விளைவாக மற்ற நாணயங்களின் தேய்மானம் நடப்புக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறை (CAD)ஐ விரிவுபடுத்துகிறது. மேலும் நிகர இறக்குமதி பொருளாதார நாடுகளின் மீது பணவீக்க அழுத்தங்களை அதிகரிக்கிறது."},{"question":"ጋና በየት አህጉር የሚገኝ ሀገር ነው?","answer":"በአፍሪካ"},{"question":"N’chifukwa chiyani njoka ndi zanzeru?","answer":"Chofunika kwambiri n’chakuti zikayesedwa m’njira yothandiza pa moyo wa njoka, zimasonyeza kuti zimaphunzira molingana ndi mmene mbalame ndi makoswe zimaphunzirira"},{"question":"Apakah iklim di Malaysia? ","answer":"Iklim di Malaysia beriklim tropika, kerana negara Malaysia terletak pada titik garisan khatulistiwa."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Giambattista Piranesi. ","answer":"Ailtire is greanadóir seaniarsmaí Rómhánacha i gcopar, a rugadh sa Veinéis ab ea Giambattista Piranesi (4 Deireadh Fómhair 1720 - 9 Samhain 1778). Shaothraigh sé teicníochtaí nua greanta, agus bhí tionchar mór aige ar an nua-chlasaiceachas. "},{"question":"ලොව වටිනාකමින් වැඩිම ලෝහය කුමක්ද?","answer":"රේඩියම්"},{"question":"Je Maji ni muhimu kwa binadamnu?","answer":"siku zote inajulikana kuwa maji ni uhai. maji ni muhimu kwa binadamu maana asilimia 75% ya mwili wa mwanadamu umetawaliwa na maji. mwanadamu anaitaji maji kwaajili ya kuishi. mzunguko wa damu mwilini unaitaji maji, chakula hakipikwi bila maji, mazao hayawezi kukua bila maji, mwanadamu hawezi kuishi bila kuwa na msimu wa mvua maana chakula chote hutokana na maji ambayo hukuza mazao shambani, na hayo maji huletwa na mvua inayonyesha juu ya ardhi na kurutubisha udongo, mbegu na miche. maji ni uhai"},{"question":"Quais são as estações do ano?","answer":"As estações do ano são outono, inverno, primavera e verão."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: An san Croatia don bakin tekun Adriatic mai ban mamaki da kuma biranen tarihi. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Bakit kailangan natin ng mantika kapag nagluluto?","answer":"Ang pag gamit ng mantika ay nagbibigay-daan sa mas mataas na temperatura ng pagluluto kaysa sa tubig, ginagawang mas mabilis at mas masarap ang pagluluto, binabawasan ang pagkasunog at hindi pantay na pagluluto. Minsan ay nagbibigay ito ng sarili nitong lasa. Ginagamit din ang mantika sa pagluluto sa paghahanda ng pagkain at pampalasa na hindi kinasasangkutan ng init, gaya ng mga salad dressing at bread dips."},{"question":"مضمون جو خلاصو:  ايف اي جي چيئرمين گريگ ڊائيڪ رانديگرن جي خلاف انضباطي ڪيسن ۾ اضافو بيان ڪيو آهي جيڪي فيصلا تي اثر انداز ڪرڻ جي ڪوشش ڪري رهيا آهن. ڊائڪ چيمپئنز ليگ ۾ چيلسي جي پيرس سينٽ جرمن طرفان شڪست کان هڪ هفتي بعد ڳالهائي رهيو هو جنهن دوران نون چيلسي رانديگر ڊچ ريفري بيورن ڪائپرز جي چوڌاري جمع ٿي ويا هئا زلان ابراهيمووچ جي آسڪر تي چئلينج جي پٺيان جنهن جي نتيجي ۾ سويڊش ٽالسمين کي ٻاهر موڪليو ويو. اهڙن واقعن تي ايف اي جي سختيءَ سان ڏٺو ويو آهي ته پريميئر ليگ کان ڪانفرنس تائين مٿين پنج ڊويزن ۾ ڪلبن ۾ اضافو ٿيو آهي - چارج ڪيو ويو آهي 'مقابلي جي آفيسرن جي چوڌاري' (هڪ ڪلب مان ٽي يا وڌيڪ رانديگر مقابلي واري انداز ۾ ميچ آفيسر جي ويجهو اچن ٿا) گذريل سيزن کان ڇهه کان 16 تائين ، مهم جا ٻيا ٽي مهينا اڃا تائين هليا ويا آهن. جان ٽيري ، سيسڪ فابريگاس ۽ انهن جي چيلسي ٽيم جي ڀائيوارن کي حاڪم بيورن ڪائپرز جي چوڌاري. چيلسي جا سڀئي نون آئوٽ فيلڊ رانديگر ڪائپرز سان احتجاج ڪن ٿا جئين آسڪر فرش تي هڪ ٽڪر ۾ رهجي ويو آهي. خبردارين يا ياد ڏياريندڙن ۾ پڻ 23 کان آخري مهم کان 29 تائين 2014-2015 دوران وڌي ويو آهي. ڊائيڪ چيو: 'اسان هن موسم ۾ ڪلبن جي تعداد ۾ ڪافي خوفناڪ اضافو ڏٺو آهي جيڪي پنهنجن رانديگرن جي ڀرسان ريفري جي چارج ڪري رهيا آهن. نتيجي ۾ اسان مٿين پنج ڊويزن ۾ ڪلبن کي لکيو آهي انهن کي قاعدن ۽ انهن جي ذميوارين جي ياد ڏياريندي. \\"مان سمجهان ٿو ته اهو خاص طور تي پروفيشنل نوجوانن لاءِ هڪ مثال قائم ڪرڻ ضروري آهي ته جيئن هن قسم جو رويو گراس روٽ ۽ نوجوانن جي سطح تي نقل نه ڪيو وڃي. پوري راند کي يقيني بڻائڻ جي ضرورت آهي ته اهو هن مسئلي کي حل ڪري رهيو آهي. ايف اي چارجز ۾ تيز اضافو نه رڳو 116 ٽيمن ڏانهن موڪليل ڊسمبر جي خط جي پٺيان آهي پر گذريل اونهاري ۾ ڪلبن جي دورن تي پڻ جڏهن اهو مسئلو سڌو سنئون رانديگرن سان اٿاريو ويو جن کي ٻڌايو ويو ته اهو برداشت نه ڪيو ويندو. زلاتان ابراهيمووچ کي هن جي چئلينج لاءِ ٻاهر موڪليو ويو جنهن چيلسي کان جارحيت جو رد عمل پيدا ڪيو. چيلسي جي ڪپتان جان ٽري پيرس سينٽ جرمن خلاف مقابلي دوران پنهنجي ٽيم جي عملن جي دفاع لاءِ منتقل ٿيو. ايف اي هاڻي موجوده سلائيڊنگ اسڪيل کان وڌيڪ ڏنڊن تي نظر وجهندي.","answer":"گريگ ڊائيڪ پي ايس جي خلاف چيلسي جي شڪست کان هڪ هفتو پوءِ ڳالهائي رهيو هو. چيلسي جي رانديگرن ڊچ ريفري بيورن ڪائپرز کي ٽڪ ڪيو زلان ابراهيمووچ جي آسڪر تي ٽڪ ڪرڻ کانپوءِ... سويڊني ٽالسمين کي ٻاهر موڪليو ويو. ايف اي اهڙن واقعن کي منهن ڏيڻ لاءِ وڌيڪ ڏنڊ ڏيندي."},{"question":"Chiyankhulo chanji Chewa ku Malawi?","answer":"Chichewa kapena Chinyanja ndi chilankhulo cha zilankhulo za Chibantu chomwe chimalankhulidwa kwambiri kumadera akummawa, pakati ndi kumwera kwa Africa. Chilankhulo cholankhulidwa kwambiri m’Malawi muno, kuyambira m’chaka cha 1968 mpaka chapakati pa zaka za m’ma 1990, chinali chinenero cha dziko lonse."},{"question":"\\"ඉබේ හටගන්නා ගින්න\\"  යන්නට වඩාත්ම ගැලපෙන කෙටි පදය කුමක්ද? (ඔබට භාවිතා  කල හැක්කේ එක වචනයක් පමණි)","answer":"\\"ලැව්ගින්න\\" වඩාතම ගැලපෙන තනි පදයයි."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jikalau sepohon kayu banyak akarnya lagi teguh, apakah ditakutkan ribut'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang banyak berjasa tidak perlu takut akan orang lain"},{"question":"ಕೆಳಗಿನ ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆಗೆ ಉತ್ತರಿಸಿ. ಬಾಬಿ ಕ್ಯಾಂಟ್ ಬೈ ಮಿ ಲವ್ ಪಾತ್ರವನ್ನು ಯಾರು ನಿರ್ವಹಿಸಿದ್ದಾರೆ","answer":"ಜಾರ್ಜ್ ಗ್ರೇ"},{"question":"Who was the first Vice Chancellor of Sri Lanka?","answer":"The first Vice-Chancellor of an independent university in Sri Lanka, which was then Ceylon, was Sir Ivor Jennings. He served as the Vice-Chancellor of the University of Ceylon from its founding in 1942 until 1954. The University of Ceylon was the first university to be established in the country and was the precursor to the present-day University of Colombo and the University of Peradeniya. Sir Ivor Jennings was a British lawyer and academic, and his contribution to the development of higher education in Sri Lanka is highly regarded."},{"question":"පළමු වාක්‍යය: ගුවන් තොටුපල මෙහෙයවනු ලබන්නේ හොකිටිකා ගුවන් තොටුපල සමාගම විසිනි. ගුවන් තොටුපල සමාගම අයිති වෙස්ට්ලන්ඩ් ප්‍රාදේශිය සභාවට ය. දෙවෙනි වාක්‍යය: ගුවන් තොටුපල අයිති හොකිටිකා ගුවන් තොටුපල සමාගමට. ගුවන් තොටුපල මෙහෙයවන්නේ වෙස්ට්ලන්ඩ් ප් රාදේශීය සභාව විසින්. ප්‍රශ්නය: 1වන වාක්‍යයේ හා 2වන වාක්‍යයේ අර්ථය සමානද? ඔව් ද නැද්ද?","answer":"නැහැ."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Сейтектин минген атыа) Тоотору б) Тайбуурулв) Чалкуйрук г) Кылкүрөң","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚г) Кылкүрөң"},{"question":"Бул 1998-жылкы дүйнө кубогунун жеңүүчүсү ким?","answer":"Финалда Бразилияны 3:0 эсебинде уткан Франция жеңишке жеткен\\".1998-жылкы ФИФАнын Дүйнөлүк Кубогу."},{"question":"கொட்டு வாத்தியங்கள் என அழைக்கக்கப்படுவது எது?1) கனக் கருவிகள்2) நரம்புக் கருவிகள்3) துளைக் கருவிகள்4) தோல் கருவிகள்","answer":"4) தோல் கருவிகள்"},{"question":"యానాదులు నిరాడంబర భక్తులు – సమర్థించండి.","answer":"వీరు భజనలు, మౌనధ్యానాలు, మంత్రతంత్రాలు ఇష్టపడరు,” యానాదుల దైవం వేంకటేశ్వరస్వామి, ఆయన కొబ్బరి కాయలతో, తులసిదళాలతో సులభంగా తృప్తిపడతాడని వీరి ఉద్దేశం. వీళ్లు వేటకు వెళ్లేముందు కాట్రాయుడికి మొక్కుతారు. అంటువ్యాధులు వస్తే మహాలక్ష్మమ్మ, పోలేరమ్మ వెలసియుండే చెట్ల దగ్గర, గ్రామవావిళ్ల దగ్గర ప్రార్థిస్తుంటారు. వీరు యక్షగానం ప్రదర్శిస్తారు."},{"question":"QORSHEYEELO?","answer":"QORSHEYEELOMa jiro qof qorshe la’aan ahi, ma jiro qof higsi la’aan ahi. Mid walba oo naga mid ah waxaa u muuqda oo maskaxdiisu tusaysaa meel uu rabo in uu timaaddada (mustaqbalka) gaaro, tusimayso keliya ee waxa ay u sawiraysaa jidkii uu mari lahaa. Tus: waxaa kuu sawiran adiga waxbarashada heer ka gaaray, shaqaystay, guursaday, magac iyo maamuus yeeshay, guri iyo baabuur yeeshay, da’ noqday oo masaajidka shanta waqti ku tukanaya.Fikirka iyo malayntu waa waxa aan xayawaanka kale uga duwannahay. Balse maskaxdeennu waxa ay inoo sawirtaa sawir qurux badan iyo nolol raaxo leh in aan gaaraynno ee na ma tusto ama inoo ma malayso dhibaatooyinka iyo qallafsanaanta waayaha, iyo guuldarrooyinka nolosha, waayo qaybta difaaca ee maskaxda ayaa ilaalo xoog badan naga haysa oo aan inoo oggolayn sawirradaas aan wacnayn. Sidaas awgeed waa in aan annagu degsannaa qorshe iyo jadwal-hawleed oo aan ku gaari karno berrinka quruxda badan ee maankeennu inoo sawirayo.Si aan aan u qorshaynno socdaalka iyo geeddiga aan ugu kicitimaynno berrinkaa barwaaqada ah ee maskaxdu inoo sawirtay ugu horreyn waa in ogaanno ama helno sirta ka dambaysa imaansheheenna addduunka, maxaan adduunkaan u imid ama la ii keenay? Maxaan u noolahay? Maxaanse kala tagayaa berri? Marka aan Muslimiin nahay jawaabta Alle ayaa waa hore inoo sheegay oo yiri:وَمَا خَلَقْتُ الْجِنَّ وَالْإِنْسَ إِلَّا لِيَعْبُدُونِ (51: 56).U ma abuurin dadka iyo jinniga in ay caabudaan un maahane.Si aad Alle u caabudno waa in aan baranno sidii aan u caabudi lahayn iyo in aan noolaanno, si aan u noolaannana waa in aan shaqaysannaa iyo in aan xirfad yeelannaa.Halkaas waxaa inooga cad in barashadu sal u tahay wax walba sida cibaado, shaqo iwm, oo noloshada bilowgeedu yahay akhris iyo qoris. Haddaad rabto in aad wadaad noqoto waa in aan diinta baratid, haddaad rabtid in aad ganacsade noqotid waa in aad ugu yaraan wax qori kartaa ama akhrin kartaa. Waa ay jiri karaan dad ganacsiga meel sare ka gaaray in aysan wax qori karin ama akhrin karin basle taasi waa naadir. Sidoo kale casrigaan hadda lagu jiro waa ay adag tahay ama maba dhici karto in qof wax akhrin karin qorina karin uu nolosha heer ka gaaro. Muslim haddaannu nahay si gaar ah ayayba taasi inoo saamaynaysaa waayo Nebigeennu Muxammad (csw) kow markii Alle adduunka u soo diray Alle uga ma bilaabin ‘saaladda tuko ama dadka khamriga iyo sinada uga dig ee waxaa Alle ku yiri:.اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ.Sidaas awgeed bilowga socdaalkeenna aan ugu socdaalaynno berrinka barwaaqada ee maskadaxdu inoo sawirayso waa in aan ka bilownno akhriska iyo qorista. Intaas ka dib baro naftaada oo daraasayn ku samee, waayo waxa aad tahay qof ka duwan toddobada bilyan ee qofood ee adduunka ku nool. Si kasta oo ay u jiraan dad aad si un isugu dabeecad iyo dhaqan dhowdihiin haddana waxa aad leedahay wax aysan balaayiintaas kale lahayn oo aad uga duwan tahay. Marka in aad ogaato qofka aad tahay waxa ay kuu fududaynaysaa in aad gaaro berrinka aad geeddiga ku tahay ee maskaxdaadu kuu soo sahmisay. Ka dib dooro qofka aad rabtid in aad noqotid mustaqbalka iyo waxa rabtid in aad adduunka ku soo kordhisid, dabadeed deji qorshihii aad halkaaas ku gaari lahayd.Si qorshaha aad dejisay u noqdo mid guulaysta waxa aad u baahan tahay in aad leedahay DIIRAD, DADAAL, WAXBARASHO JOOGTO AH, FILASHO WANAAGSAN, DULQAAD, JOOGTAYN iyo NAF ISKA ADAG.Haddii aadan lahayn diirad oo maalinba meel tooshku kuu qabanayo ogow guul gaari mayside. Waa in diiraddu kuu soo saarnaato halka aad qorshaysid in aad gaartid, dadaalna aad ku dartid, khaladaadka kaa dhacayna aad wax ka baratid iyo in aad maalin walba wax cusub baratid taas ah ‘akhri buugaagta.’ Intaas waxa raaca in aad tahay ruux mar walba wax san fisha iyo in uu guulaysanayo, dulqaadna u leh turaanturrooyinka noloshada oo aan horay iska dhiibin. Sidoo kale waa in aad noqotaa qof joogtayn leh oo aadan noqon mid 2 asbuuc ka dib daalaya haddana bil ka bacdi hawshii dib u bilaabaya. Ogow in aad geeddi tahay u na socotid berrinkii naqa lahaa ee maskaxdu sahanka ku soo aragtay. Sidaas darteed xusuuso in qoys geeddi ahi uusan socodka joojin ilaa uu ka gaaro berrinkii uu geeddiga ku ahaa.Ugu dambayn waa in aad naftaada dishibiliin u samayso (naftaada ka adkaatid) aadna ka dhigto mid habaysan oo urursan, lehna awood ay ‘maya’ ku oran karto markii ay aragto wax jidka socdaalka kaa leexinaya. Ha noqon ruux qaba qandhada la yiraahdo SHINY OBJECTS SYNDROM (xiisaalow maalinba meel ku booda haddana 2 bilood ka dib ka xiise dhaca oo wax kale oo cusub bilaaba).Gebagebadii, baro MAARAYNTA MAALMAHA. ogow ma jiro ruux heer ka gaaray nolosha oo ahayn mid ka adkaaday maamulka maalmaha, hadba sida aad maalmaha u maaraysid ayaa horumarkaaga iyo guushaadu ku xiran tahay. Xusuuso in waqtigu ka mid yahay nimcooyinka Alle inoogu nimceeyay aakhirana na la kula xisaabtamo doono halka aan ku dhamaynnay waqtigii Alle na siiyay.Ha noqon qof maalintu hoggaamiso ee adigu noqo mid maalinta hoggaamiya. Si kale haddaan u dhigo maalintu yaysan ku maamulin ee adigu noqo mid maalinta maamula.  Taas macneheedu waa, qorshayso 24ka saacadood ee maalinta hawsha aad qabanaysid. Ha noqon mid inta subaxdii soo kaca yiraahda “maanta maxaan qabtaa? Maanta intee aadaa?” Ogow dadka guulaystay waa kuwa maalinta qorsheeya ka hor inta aysan maalintu imaan."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam dapat, musang dapat\\"?","answer":"Pencuri ditangkap, barang-barang yang dicuri pun dipulangkan"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഹാൻസൻ എന്ന പേരിന്റെ ഉത്ഭവം എവിടെ നിന്നാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"ഹാൻസെൻ എന്ന പേര് സ്കാൻഡനേവിയയിൽ നിന്നാണ് ഉത്ഭവിച്ചത്. "},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Vụ tai nạn giao thông liên hoàn trên phố đi bộ Tam Bạc, Hải Phòng vừa xảy ra khiến nhiều người bị thương. Theo những người dân xung quanh khu vực phố đi bộ cho biết, vào khoảng 20h30 trên tuyến đường từ Đền Tam Kỳ về phía Lãn Ông (quận Hồng Bàng), xe ô tô hiệu KIA, BKS 15A- 185.65 loại 5 chỗ, màu đen bất ngờ lao vào những xe máy đang lưu thông trên đường. Bị đâm bất ngờ, hàng loạt xe máy và người trên xe bị ngã văng ra xa, có xe máy chui vào gầm xe ô tô đỗ bên đường. Khung cảnh lúc đó diễn ra vô cùng hoảng loạn, sợ hãi. Ai nấy đều la hét. Xe ô tô \\"điên\\" chỉ dừng lại khi lao lên vỉa hè đâm vào 1 nhà dân","answer":"gần đó Cũng theo người dân xung quanh, lúc bước ra khỏi xe, lái xe tuổi khoảng hơn 30, trạng thái tinh thần không có biểu hiện bị kích động. Trong xe chỉ có mỗi lái xe, túi khí đã bị bung ra. Những nạn nhân của vụ tai nạn hiện đã được đưa đi cấp cứu tại bệnh viện Việt Tiệp gần đó. Lực lượng công an quận Hồng Bàng và CATP cũng đã kịp có mặt tại hiện trường bảo vệ hiện trường, thu thập điều tra, đồng thời phối hợp với người dân đưa nạn nhân đi cấp cứu. Vụ việc đang được cơ quan chức năng tiếp tục làm rõ."},{"question":"මහවැලි සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහනේ වාරි පද්ධතිවල අරමුණ කුමක්ද?","answer":"මහවැලි සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන යටතේ ඇති වාරිමාර්ග පද්ධති මඟින් බහුකාර්ය ජලාශවල ගබඩා කර ඇති ජලය නව සහ පවතින කෘෂිකාර්මික ඉඩම්වලට වාරිමාර්ග සඳහා හරවා යැවීම අරමුණු කරයි.මෙම අරමුණු ලයිස්තුවක් ලෙස පහත දැක්වේ. නව ජනාවාස ඇතිකිරීමවිදුලිබලය උත්පාදනයවී ගොවිතැන ප්‍රමුඛ කෘෂීකර්මයගංවතුර පාලනයමහවැලි පහල නිම්නයේ ජනාවාසකරනයරකියා ප්‍රශ්නය විසදීමරට ආහාර වලින් ස්වයංපෝශිත කිරීමමහවැලි ගඟත්, එහි අතු ගංඟාත් මාදුරුඔයත් ආශ්‍රය කොටගෙන දේශීය භූමි ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 39% ක් පමණ වූ ප්‍රමාණය සංවර්ධනය කිරීමත්, රටට අවශ්‍ය විදුලි බලය නිපදවා ගැනීමටත්, ඇතැම් ප්‍රදේශ වල ගංවතුර පාලනය කිරීමටත්, නව ගොවි බිම් ඇතිකිරීමටත්, නව ජනාවාස බිහිකිරීමත්, එමගින් නව රැකියා අවස්ථා ලබා දීමත්, මහවැලි මහ සැලැස්මෙන් අපේක්ෂා කෙරිණි. කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය නවීනරණය වීම, සත්ව පාලනය, කෘෂිකර්මය පාදක කරගත් කර්මාන්ත සංවර්ධනය කිරීම අනෙකුත් අපේක්ෂිත අරමුණු විය."},{"question":"Iza no tsy miova omaly sy anio ary ho mandrakizay?","answer":"Raha arakin'ny baiboly kristianina dia ny tsy miova omaly sy anio ary homandrakizay dia Andriamanitra."},{"question":"株価の暴騰を防ぐために、前日の終値を基準に定められた１日の最大上げ幅のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"ストップ高です。"},{"question":"भिन्नहरू 2/9 र 7/12 जोड्नुहोस् र परिणामलाई सरलीकृत अंशको रूपमा व्यक्त गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"भिन्नहरू थप्नको लागि, एउटा साझा भाजक फेला पार्नुहोस्, जुन यस अवस्थामा 36 हो। त्यसैले, (2/9) + (7/12) = (8/36) + (21/36) = 29/36।"},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 ジャニーズ事務所は、2019年に亡くなったジャニー喜多川氏から、若いタレントたちが性被害を受けたことが問題になっています。会社は2日、この問題について記者たちに話しました。会社によると、先月30日までに478人から被害の連絡があって、この中の325人が補償をしてほしいと言っています。東山紀之社長は「たくさんの人が被害を受けたことに驚いています。被害を受けた人の心のケアなどについて、しっかり考えなければなりません」と話しました。会社は11月から補償を始めると言っています。ジャニーズ事務所という名前をやめて「SMILE-UP.」に変えることも決めました。そして、被害を受けた人の補償を最後までして、将来はこの会社をなくすと説明しました。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- 氏: 1）みょうじ。家柄。2）人の名前などのあとにつけて、敬う気持ちを表す。- タレント: 1）ラジオ・テレビなどで活躍する芸能人。- 性: 1）生まれつき。2）男女、またはおす・めすの区別。- 被害: 1）損害を受けること。また、受けた害。- 記者: 1）新聞や雑誌などの記事を、取材したり書いたりする人。- 補償: 1）与えた損害を、お金などでつぐなうこと。- ケア: 1）病人や体の不自由な人の、介護をすること。2）手入れ。手当て。3）心づかい。"},{"question":"Коомдук унааларда өзүн-өзү алып жүрүү эрежелери... ","answer":"Музыка уккуңуз келсе, анда кулагыңызга атайын таккыч кийип алып угуңуз."},{"question":"Gwam otu nwata n'ihu nne ya","answer":"Agụ "},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණය පැවති වසර කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණය පැවැත්වුණේ 1947 දී ය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදීව තේරී පත් වූ රජයකට බලය පැවරීමේ පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙය වූ බැවින් මෙම මැතිවරණය වැදගත් විය. එය බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය යටත් විජිත පාලනයෙන් පූර්ණ නිදහසක් කරා  තීරනාත්මක පියවරක් වූ අතර, අවසානයේදී ලංකාව 1948 පෙබරවාරි 4 වන දින පූර්ණ නිදහස අත්පත් කර ගත්තේය."},{"question":" شنو هي العاصمة ديال روسيا ؟","answer":" موسكو"},{"question":"السؤال: شنو سميت الصحابي الجليل أبو موسى الأشعري؟","answer":"الجواب: عبد الله بن قيس رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"Rongedza imwe neimwe yemhuka dzinotevera se ectothermic kana endothermic: alligator, nyoka, datya, mbudzi, munhu, gorilla","answer":"\\"Alligator: EctothermicNyoka: EctothermicDatya: EctothermicMbudzi: EndothermicMunhu: EndothermicGorilla: Endothermic\\""},{"question":"Ko mutemo wekugoverwa kwevhu muZimbabwe unobata sei zvematongerwo enyika nehupfumi?","answer":"Mutemo wekupa ivhu muZimbabwe, wakatangwa kutanga kwa2000, waive nechinangwa chekugadzirisa kusaenzana kweminda kwaikonzerwa nekusaruramisira munguva yevapambi. Mutemo uyu waisanganisira kugovewa patsva kweminda kubva kuvachena vanoita zvekutengesa vachipihwa zvizvarwa zveZimbabwe zvitema zvisina minda.Kunyange zvazvo mutemo uyu wakanga uine zvinangwa zvakanaka, kushandiswa kwawo kwakatungamirira kumatambudziko ehupfumi. Mazhinji emapurazi akagovewa zvakare akawana kudzikira kwegoho, zvichikanganisa goho rekurima uye kutengesa kunze kwenyika. Pamusoro pezvo, mutemo uyu waipesanisa zvematongerwo enyika, nekushoropodzwa nevekunze kwenyika nemamwe mapato anopikisa."},{"question":"Joeboy","answer":"Joseph Akinwale Akinfenwa-Donus (21 May 1997) ti a mọ ni ọjọgbọn bi Joeboy, jẹ akọrin Naijiria. Mr Eazi ti aami igbasilẹ \\"emPawa Africa\\" ṣe awari rẹ ni ọdun 2017. Iru orin rẹ jẹ ti Afro pop ati R&B. O je omo ilu Eko ni Naijiria."},{"question":"Bebek irmik kaç aylık bebeğe verilir?","answer":"Doktorlara ve uzmanlara göre bebek irmiği 6.ay ve sonrasında ek gıdaya başlama dönemiyle eş zamanlı olarak bebeklere verilebilir. Eğer sütünüz yetmiyor veya kesiliyorsa 4.aydan sonrasında doktorunuzun izniyle bebeğinizi ek gıdaya başlatabilirsiniz."},{"question":"مجموعة الكلمات أدناه التي تعتبر أداة ربط.","answer":"كما، على الرغم."},{"question":"No romance Dom Casmurro, de Machado de Assis, qual o nome do amigo que Bentinho imagina ser o pai de seu filho?a) Escobarb) Scolaric) Espinosad) Estevese) Estevão","answer":"Resposta correta: a) Escobar.A obra de Machado de Assis é responsável por um das maiores polêmicas da literatura brasileira: “Capitu traiu Bentinho?”.Ezequiel de Souza Escobar era o melhor amigo de Bentinho, dos tempos em que andavam no seminário. A polêmica sobre a suposta traição de Capitu acompanha o livro em que Bentinho (Dom Casmurro) é personagem principal e narrador. Para ele, seu filho Ezequiel possuía muitas semelhanças com o amigo que havia falecido."},{"question":"Ano ang mga buwan pagkatapos ng Marso at bago mag Oktobre?","answer":"Ang mga buwan pagkatapos ng Marso at bago mag Oktobre ay Abril, Mayo, Hunyo, Hulyo, Agosto, at Setyembre."},{"question":"Tusaale ahaan iigu sharax qaabka afar lagu daray labo  ay ku noqotay lix 4+2=6?","answer":"Ka soo qaad in aad haysato afar tufaax ah ka dibna lagu siiyay labo tufaax ah. waxaa heysataa markaas lix tufaax ah."},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وتماشيا مع إعلان سابق للرئيس أردوغان تتواصل الجهود لتحويل جزء من مطار أتاتورك إلى حديقة عامة، وتقييم جزء منها لأغراض الملاحة الجوية.","answer":"في الأثناء، قال المدير العام لفرع شركة لوفتهانزا للخطوط الجوية الألمانية في تركيا كمال غتشر إن الشركة ستبدأ رحلاتها من مطار إسطنبول الاثنين المقبل."},{"question":"දකුණු කොරියානු ආරක්ෂක මිසයිල පද්ධතිය හඳුන්වන නම කුමක්ද?","answer":"දකුණු කොරියානු ආරක්ෂක මිසයිල පද්ධතිය තාඩ් මිසයිල ආරක්ෂක පද්ධතියයි."},{"question":"Alüminyum kalitesi nasıl anlaşılır?","answer":"Alüminyum kalitesini anlamak için dikkat etmeniz gereken en önemli nokta profil et kalınlığıdır. Standart uygulamalarda kalınlığın 3 mm olması beklenir. Buna ek olarak alüminyum profilinin ve tekerlerin paslı ya da hurda olmamasına dikkat etmek gerekir."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Ny firenena maleo-tena dia firenena manana ny fiadriana-pireneny, ny saina-pireneny, ny hira-pireneny, ny tarigetsany, ny teniny sy ny kolon-tsainy, …\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ireo hadisoana voahitsy:\\"Ny firenena mahaleo-tena dia firenena manana ny fiandrianam-pireneny, ny sainam-pireneny, ny hiram-pireneny, ny tarigetrany, ny teniny sy ny kolon-tsainy, …\\""},{"question":"Qual è la risposta corretta alla questa domanda: Chi è l'unico componente degli Steppenwolf che non è nato in Canada? ","answer":"La risposta corretta alla questa domanda è John Kay."},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة البرازيل؟","answer":"برازيليا هي العاصمة الفيدرالية للبرازيل وتقع في المحافظة الفدرالية أنشئت في 21 ابريل 1960 على يدي الرئيس جوسيلينو كوبيتشيك لتكون العاصمة الثالثة للبرازيل بعد إنشاء برازيليا نقلت الحكومة كل المكاتب الفدرالية إليها."},{"question":"Wat is een Cicatripraonetha?","answer":"Cicatripraonetha is een kevergeslacht uit de familie van de boktorren. De wetenschappelijke naam van het geslacht werd voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1980 door Breuning."},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:ન તો હું સાંભળી શકું, ન તો હું બોલી શકું આંખ તો મારે છે પણ નહીં તોયે જગ આખાને ભણાવતી જાઉં.","answer":"ચોપડી"},{"question":"Àwo̩n Ò̩jò̩gbò̩n Nínú Èdè àti Lítírés̩ò̩ Yorùbá","answer":"Àwo̩n Ò̩jò̩gbò̩n Nínú Èdè àti Lítírés̩ò̩ Yorùbá Professors of the Yorùbá Linguistics, Language, Literature & CultureS/N Oruko Yunifasiti 1. Emeritus Professor Adeboye Babalola University of Lagos 2. Emeritus Professor Ayo Bamgbose University of Ibadan 3. Professor Oladele Awobuluyi Adekunle Ajasin University 4. Professor Sope Oyelaran Obafemi Awolowo University 5. Professor Wande Abimbola Obafemi Awolowo University 6. Professor Olatunde Olatunji University of Ibadan 7. Professor Akinwumi Isola Obafemi Awolowo University 8. Professor Kola Owolabi University of Ibadan 9. Professor Adegboyega Alaba University of Lagos 10. Professor Afolabi Olabimtan University of Lagos 11. Professor Bade Ajuwon Obafemi Awolowo University 12. Professor T. M. Ilesanmi Obafemi Awolowo University 13. Professor (Mrs.) Olutoye University of Lagos 14. Professor Adebisi Ogunsina University of Ilorin 15. Professor L. Olufemi Adewole Obafemi Awolowo University 16 Professor Rotimi Badejo University of Maiduguri 17. Professor Adedotun Ogundeji University of Ibadan 18. Professor Yinka Folorunso Lagos State University 19. Professor Goke Akinlabi University of Ibadan 20. Professor Bade Ajayi University of Ilorin 21. Professor Olabode University of Ibadan 22. Professor Sola Adebajo Ogun State Univeristy Ago-Iwoye 23. Professor S. O. Oyetade University of Ibadan 24. Professor (Mrs.) Oluyemisi Adebowale Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba 25. Professor Olusola Olateju University of Ibadan 26. Professor Jibola Abiodun Ekiti State University Ado-Ekiti 27. Professor Tunde Akinyemi University of Florida 28. Professor (Mrs.) Arinpe Adejumo University of Ibadan 29. Professor Francis Oyebade Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba 30. Professor Duro Adeleke University of Ibadan 31. Professor (Mrs.) Laide Sheba Obafemi Awolowo University 32. Professor Taiwo Olunlade Lagos State University 33. Professor O̩ladiipo Ajiboye University of Lagos 34. Professor Oye Taiwo University of Ibadan 35. Professor Lere Adeyemi University of Ilorin 36. Professor Harrison Adeniyi Lagos State University 37. Professor Felix Abidemi Fabunmi Obafemi Awolowo University 38. Professor George Olusola Ajibade Obafemi Awolowo University"},{"question":"句子1: 乐队于8月23日发行了\\" \`\` Itunes Session -- EP \\", 包含四首替代歌曲和\\" Fold Your Hands Child \\"的声乐版本. 句子2: 8月23日,该乐队发行了\\" \`\` Itunes Session -- EP\\"四首替代歌曲和\\" Fold Your Hands Child\\"的声乐版本. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"Apakah ciri-ciri ayat aktif? ","answer":"1. Ayat aktif ialah ayat di mana subjek dalam ayat tersebut menjadi pelaku dan objeknya menjadi penerima.2. Ayat aktif menerangkan benda atau orang melakukan sesuatu perbuatan itu.3. Ayat aktif mengandungi kata kerja yang mengutakan subjek asal sebagai unsur yang diterangkan.4. Kata kerja dalam ayat aktif mengandungi awalan me- dan ia disebut sebagai penanda ayat aktif.Satu contoh ayat aktif ialah \\"Siti membaca buku di perpustakaan\\". "},{"question":"प्रवासी भारतीय दिवस दरवर्षी कधी साजरा केला जातो?(A) 5 जानेवारी(B) 11 जानेवारी(C) 9 जानेवारी(D) १ जानेवारी=> ","answer":" (C) 9 जानेवारी"},{"question":"সারাংশ লেখ:একটা বরফের পিন্ড ও ঝরনার মধ্যে তফাৎ কোনখানে? না, বরফের পিন্ডের মধ্যে নিজস্ব গতি নেই। তাকে বেঁধে টেনে নিয়ে গেলে তবে সে চলে। কিন্তু ঝরণার যে গতি সে তার নিজের গতি, সেজন্য এই গতিতেই তার ব্যাপ্তি, তার মুক্তি, তার সৌন্দর্য। এই জন্য গতিপথে সে যত আঘাত পায়, ততই তাকে বৈচিত্র্য দান করে। বাধায় তার ক্ষতি নেই, চলায় তার শান্তি নেই। মানুষের মনেও যখন রসের আবির্ভাব না থাকে, তখনই সে জড়পি-। তখন ক্ষুধা-তৃষ্ণা-ভয়-ভাবনাই তাকে ঠেলে কাজ করায়। তখন প্রতি কাজে পদে পদেই তার ক্লান্তি। সেই নীরস অবস্থাতেই মানুষ অন্তরের নিশ্চলতা থেকে বাহিরেও কেবলই নিশ্চলতা বিস্তার করতে থাকে। তখনই তার যত খুঁটিনাটি, যত আচার-বিচার, যত শাস্ত্র-শাসন। তখন মানুষের মন গতিহীন বলেই বাইরেও আষ্টেপৃষ্ঠে সে বন্ধ।","answer":"মানুষ তার মনকে বরফের পিন্ডের মতো গতিহীন না করে যদি ঝরনার যদি অঝোর ধারার মতো গতিশীল করে তবে জীবনের প্রকৃত বৈশিষ্ট্য ফুটে উঠে। আর মন যদি গতিহীন হয় তাহলে নানা সীমাবদ্ধতা ও কুসংস্কার মানুষের পরিপূর্ণ বিকাশে বাধা দান করে।"},{"question":"Mitkä ovat nopeusrajoitusten periaatteet?","answer":"Suomessa yleinen nopeusrajoitus on taajama-alueella 50 kilometriä ja taajama-alueen ulkopuolella 80 kilometriä tunnissa. Yleiset nopeusrajoitukset ovat voimassa, jos liikennemerkein ei ole muuta määrätty.Suurin mahdollinen nopeusrajoitus on moottoriteillä 120 ja muilla teillä 100 km/h. Valta- ja kantateillä yleisimmät nopeusrajoitukset ovat 100 ja 80 km/h, joskin lyhyillä osuuksilla voi olla tätä alempia nopeusrajoituksia. Seutu- ja yhdysteiden yleisin nopeusrajoitus on 80 km/h.Kaduilla nopeusrajoitus on yleisimmin 60 kilometriä tunnissa.Moottoriliikenneteiden yleisin nopeusrajoitus on 100 kilometriä tunnissa."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਪੁਨੇ ਜਨ ਕਾ ਪਰਦਾ ਢਾਕੈ ॥ਅਪਨੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਕੀ ਸਰਪਰ ਰਾਖੈ ॥ਅਪਨੇ ਦਾਸ ਕਉ ਦੇਇ ਵਡਾਈ ॥ਅਪਨੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਕਉ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਾਈ ॥ਅਪਨੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਕੀ ਆਪਿ ਪਤਿ ਰਾਖੈ ॥ਤਾ ਕੀ ਗਤਿ ਮਿਤਿ ਕੋਇ ਨ ਲਾਖੈ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਕਉ ਕੋ ਨ ਪਹੂਚੈ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਊਚ ਤੇ ਊਚੇ ॥ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਅਪਨੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਲਾਇਆ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸੋ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਦਹ ਦਿਸਿ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਇਆ ॥੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 285 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦਾ ਪਰਦਾ ਢੱਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਲਾਜ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਣ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਆਪ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਉੱਚ-ਅਵਸਥਾ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਡੱਪਣ ਦਾ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ਾ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਗਾ ਸਕਦਾ ।ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੀ ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਉੱਚਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਚੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਆਪ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਵਿਚ ਲਾਇਆ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਹ ਸੇਵਕ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।੪।\\""},{"question":"නර්වාල් (Narwhal) තල්මසුන් මුහුණ දෙන තර්ජන මොනවාද?","answer":"නර්වාල් (Narwhal) තල්මසුන් මුහුණ දෙන තර්ජන කිහිපයක් පහත පරිදි දැක්විය හැකිය.1. තෙල් හා ගෑස් සංවර්ධනය සහ දේශගුණික විපර්යාස.2. බහුල වශයෙන් වන මුහුදු යාත්‍රික ගමන් සාගර දූෂනයට වැඩි අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය වී​ම. 3. දිය යට ශබ්ද වැඩි වීම නිසා තල්මසුන් අතර සන්නිවේදනයට බාධා ඇති වීම."},{"question":"කඩුලු රකින ක්‍රීඩකයෙක් වශයෙන් තනි ඉනිමකදී වැඩිම ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාවක් වාර්තා කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"කඩුලු රකින ක්‍රීඩකයෙක් වශයෙන් තනි ඉනිමකදී වැඩිම ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාවක් වාර්තා කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා ඇන්ඩි ෆ්ලව(ර්) නම් ක්‍රීඩකයා වේ."},{"question":"Iza amin'ny taova ao amin'ny taovam-pisefoana no tompon'andraikitra amin'ny fifanakalozana entona eo amin'ny rivotra sy ny ra?","answer":" Ny havokavoka no taova tompon'andraikitra amin'ny fifanakalozana entona eo amin'ny rivotra sy ny ra."},{"question":"බුද්ධි පරීක්ෂණ වලින්‌ ඉහලම ලකුණු ලැබූ අයගේ සංගමය කුමක්ද?","answer":"බුද්ධි පරීක්ෂණවල වැඩිම ලකුණු ලාභීන්ගේ සංගමය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් මෙන්සා  ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්( Mensa International) ලෙස හැඳින්වේ. මෙන්සා යනු ප්‍රමිතිගත, අධීක්‍ෂණය කළ බුද්ධි පරීක්ෂණයකින් 98 වැනි ප්‍රතිශතයක් හෝ ඊට වැඩි ලකුණු ලබා ගන්නා  පුද්ගලයන් සඳහා විවෘත ලාභ නොලබන සංවිධානයකි. මෙය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් IQ ලකුණු 130 හෝ ඊට වැඩි අගයකට අනුරූප වේ, නමුත් මෙන්සා විවිධ IQ සහ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රමිතිගත පරීක්ෂණ වලින් ලකුණු පිළිගනී.1946 දී එංගලන්තයේ බැරිස්ටර්වරයෙකු වන රෝලන්ඩ් බෙරිල් සහ විද්‍යාඥයෙකු සහ නීතීඥයෙකු වන ආචාර්ය ලාන්ස් වෙයාර් විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලද මෙන්සා, දීප්තිමත් පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා සමාජයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම අරමුණු කරයි, එහි සාමාජිකත්වය සඳහා  ඇති එකම සුදුසුකම ඉහළ IQ වේ. සමාජය තම සාමාජිකයින්ට බුද්ධිමය හා සමාජීය ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල නිරත වීමට වේදිකාවක් සපයන අතර අදහස් හා දැනුම හුවමාරු කර ගැනීමට දිරිගන්වයි. "},{"question":"I know that the answer to \\"మర్రివాడ గ్రామ ప్రజలు ప్రధానంగా పండించే పంట ఏది?\\" appears somewhere in the text snippet about మర్రివాడ (కొయ్యూరు). Can you answer the question?","answer":"వరి, జొన్న, మొక్కజొన్న"},{"question":"س217- شنو هي عاصمة جزر القمر ؟","answer":"ج217- موروني"},{"question":"What is the loudest animal on Earth?","answer":"The sperm whale"},{"question":"Toggle the table of contentsભવાઇ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ભવાઇ ‌‍એ ગુજરાતનું એક પરંપરાગત લોકનાટ્ય સ્‍વરૂપ છે.‘ભવાઇ’ શબ્‍દમાં ‘ભવ’ એટલે વિશ્વ, જગત અથવા સર્વકાળ; ‘આઇ’ એટલે માતા. અહીં તેને જગતની માતા એટલે કે જગદંબા ગણી છે. ભવાઇમાં મા અંબાની ભક્તિને કેન્‍દ્રમાં રાખી નાટક ભજવવામાં આવે છે. આજે પણ અંબાજી ખાતે દર નવરાત્રીએ ભવાઇ દ્વારા મા અંબાની પૂજા કરવામાં આવે છે.ભવાઇની શરૂઆત સિદ્ધપુરના ઔદિચ્‍ય સહસ્‍ત્ર બ્રાહ્મણકુળમાં જન્‍મેલા કવિ-કથાકાર અસાઇત ઠાકરે કરી હતી. ચૌદમી સદીમાં ગુજરાતના પ્રદેશોમાં પ્રચલિત નાટયપ્રકારોમાંથી પ્રેરણા મેળવી અસાઇતે એક નવા નાટયપ્રકાર-ભવાઇનું સર્જન કર્યું હતું. ભવાઇનું વાચિક ગેય પદ્યમાં તેમજ ગદ્યમાં પણ હોય છે.અસાઇત ઠાકરે આશરે ૩૬૦ ભવાઇ વેશ લખ્‍યાની લોકવાયકા છે. તેમાં ‘રામદેવનો વેશ’ જૂનામાં જૂનો હોય એમ લાગે છે. તેમણે સામાજિક કુરિવાજો ઉપર પ્રહારો કરતા વેશો પણ આપ્‍યા છે. ‘કજોડાનો વેશ’ નાનકડા વર અને યુવાન પત્‍નીના જીવનનો ચિતાર આપે છે. તેમાં રંગલો એ બેની વચ્‍ચેના સંવાદોને જોડતો, હસાવતો અને કટાક્ષ કરતો હોય છે."},{"question":"Trả lời các bài toán sau:a) Nếu tung một đồng xu 22 lần liên tiếp, có 13 lần xuất hiện mặt N thì xác suất thực nghiệm xuất hiện mặt N bằng bao nhiêu?b) Nếu tung một đồng xu 25 lần liên tiếp, có 11 lần xuất hiện mặt S thì xác suất thực nghiệm xuất hiện mặt S bằng bao nhiêu?c) Nếu tung một đồng xu 30 lần liên tiếp, có 14 lần xuất hiện mặt N thì xác suất thực nghiệm xuất hiện mặt S bằng bao nhiêu?","answer":"Lời giải:a) Xác suất thực nghiệm xuất hiện mặt N là: 13/22b) Xác suất thực nghiệm xuất hiện mặt S là: 11/25c) Số lần xuất hiện mặt S là: 30 – 14 = 16 (lần).Xác suất thực nghiệm xuất hiện mặt S là: 16/30 = 8/15"},{"question":"Cha mẹ của em quyết định nghỉ hưu hẳn và tận hưởng tuổi già. Em không chọn kế nghiệp tại công ty của gia đình như các anh, chị, nên được cha mẹ cho 2 tỷ đồng để sau này làm vốn sống.Hiện tại em vẫn yêu thích công việc văn phòng của mình, chưa có ý định tách ra khởi nghiệp hay tự kinh doanh gì cả. Thu nhập hàng tháng của em đủ nuôi bản thân (và một bé mèo), gửi tiết kiệm, đóng bảo hiểm, thỉnh thoảng đi du lịch... Do đó, 2 tỷ đồng được cho đều là tiền em không đụng tới ít nhất 5 năm nữa.Em muốn hỏi ý kiến chuyên gia về việc nên xử lý, phân bổ số tiền kia ra sao để an toàn, tránh mất giá và nếu sinh lãi được ở mức trung bình thì càng tốt!","answer":"Bạn đã có nguồn thu nhập ổn định, đã có kế hoạch bảo vệ tài chính thông qua bảo hiểm nhân thọ, hiện tại chưa có người phụ thuộc về mặt tài chính. Trước khi phân bổ 2 tỷ đồng được cho và nhàn rỗi trong 5 năm nữa, bạn nên cân nhắc hai bước dưới đây.Thứ nhất, thiết lập quỹ dự phòng khẩn cấp (nếu chưa có). Quỹ này sẽ được sử dụng trong các trường hợp không mong muốn như giảm hoặc mất thu nhập đột ngột, cần gấp một khoản tiền gửi cho cha mẹ...Quỹ dự phòng thường tương đương 3 đến 6 tháng chi tiêu. Đối với trường hợp của bạn (chưa có người phụ thuộc về mặt tài chính và đã có bảo hiểm nhân thọ), quỹ này nên lập ở mức tương đương 3 tháng chi tiêu và để trong tài khoản tiết kiệm một tháng.Thứ hai, xác định các yếu tố liên quan trước khi phân bổ. Bạn nên xem xét tổng danh mục của bạn (bao gồm tiền tiết kiệm hiện tại), hơn là chỉ cân nhắc về việc phân bổ 2 tỷ đồng như thế nào. Vì việc phân bổ sẽ rất khác nếu bạn đang có 1 tỷ đồng tiền tiết kiệm, tương đương 33,33% tổng danh mục tài sản (3 tỷ đồng) và nếu bạn đang có 500 triệu đồng tiền tiết kiệm, tương đương 20% tổng danh mục tài sản (2,5 tỷ đồng).Bạn tự trả lời cho câu hỏi: Tổng danh mục sẽ phân bổ có tính hiệu quả về tỷ suất sinh lợi (tương thích với khẩu vị rủi ro) hay chưa? Bạn có đề cập là chỉ mong muốn sinh lãi ở \\"mức trung bình\\", nhưng chưa cụ thể trung bình là ở mức nào cũng cần xác định rõ.Nếu mức hiệu suất bạn mong muốn là 6-8% một năm, gửi tiết kiệm ngân hàng vẫn đang đáp ứng được mức này, tính rủi ro gần như là không có.Nếu hiệu suất bạn mong muốn là 8-10% một năm, lúc này cần thêm các lớp tài sản có tính tăng trưởng cao hơn tiết kiệm ngân hàng như trái phiếu, căn hộ chung cư đã bàn giao dưới 6 năm, hoặc bất động sản dân sinh. Mặc dù vào cuối năm ngoái, đầu năm nay, lãi suất tiết kiệm đã có lúc đạt đến 11% một năm, nhưng trong tương lai trung hạn, lãi suất sẽ được giữ ở trong mức 6-6,5% một năm.Nếu như hiệu suất mong muốn khoảng 12-15% một năm, lúc này bạn bắt buộc phải có thêm các lớp tài sản có tính tăng trưởng mạnh như cổ phiếu (chứng chỉ quỹ hoặc đầu tư trực tiếp), bất động sản vùng ven, bất động sản nông nghiệp.Cần lưu ý về khả năng chịu đựng rủi ro của bạn vì tài sản có tính tăng trưởng càng cao ứng với rủi ro càng cao. Nếu bạn mong muốn tài sản tăng trưởng 12-15% một năm, cần chấp nhận có những thời điểm, tài sản có tính tăng trưởng mạnh như cổ phiếu sẽ âm 15%, có khi lỗ đến 30%. Nếu bạn không thể chấp nhận được mức rủi ro này, nên xem xét lại hiệu suất mong muốn.Bên cạnh đó, bạn cần tìm được lời giải cho các câu hỏi : Tính đa dạng của lớp tài sản trong danh mục đã có chưa? Tính cân bằng về thanh khoản của tài sản hay khả năng chuyển đổi dòng tiền khi cần thiết đã có chưa? Danh mục tài sản của bạn có đem lại lợi nhuận bạn mong muốn, và có tính rủi ro tối ưu không?Gợi ý về các lớp tài sảnThứ nhất là tiết kiệm ngân hàng. Bạn nên gửi các kỳ hạn 1 tháng (dành cho quỹ dự phòng), kỳ hạn 6 hoặc 12 tháng để tối ưu về tính thanh khoản. Lý do là lãi suất của kỳ hạn 1 và 3 tháng hoặc 6 và 9 tháng là gần như tương đương nhau.Bạn có thể tham khảo vàng. Tôi khuyên nên cân nhắc giữ khoảng 5% danh mục tài sản. Đây vẫn là một kênh phòng thủ thích hợp nắm giữ trong dài hạn.Về bất động sản, thị trường đang đóng băng cộng thêm các yếu tố cộng hưởng như lãi suất cho vay đang cao, tính thanh khoản đang kém dẫn đến áp lực cho các nhà đầu tư sở hữu địa ốc. Vì thế, kênh này sẽ xuất hiện nhiều tài sản có mức giá rẻ hơn so với giá thị trường vào quý IV/2023 hoặc quý đầu năm sau.Cuối cùng là cổ phiếu. Đầu năm, thị trường có mức định giá rẻ so với lịch sử. Trong giai đoạn hiện tại, thị trường đã tăng nhiều và gần đây có các phiên giảm điểm mạnh, biến động kể từ đầu năm. Việc đầu tư vào cổ phiếu ở thời điểm này sẽ phải chấp nhận các rủi ro trong ngắn hạn (tài khoản có thể giảm) nhưng về mặt dài hạn, thị trường vẫn còn hấp dẫn do các chỉ số như P/E và P/B chưa vượt qua mức trung bình trong vòng 10 năm trở lại đây. Tích sản cổ phiếu vẫn còn nhiều tiềm năng."},{"question":"غزہ کے کیا حالات ہیں؟","answer":"عالمی ادارہ صحت کے ڈائریکٹر جنرل ٹیڈروس اذانوم گیبریس نے غزہ کے ہسپتالوں میں ’سنگین اور خطرناک‘ صورتحال کے بارے میں خبردار کرتے ہوئے کہا ہے کہ زیادہ مریض، بشمول قبل از وقت پیدا ہونے والے بچوں کی ’افسوسناک‘ اموات ہو رہی ہیں۔غزہ کے دو سب سے بڑے ہسپتال الشفا اور القدس دونوں بند ہو چکے ہیں۔ سینکڑوں افراد اندر محصور ہیں۔ریڈ کراس کی بین الاقوامی کمیٹی نے کہا ہے کہ غزہ کی پٹی میں جن حالات میں شہری انخلا کر رہے ہیں وہ ’غیر محفوظ اور بد ترین‘ ہیں۔یورپی یونین کی خارجہ پالیسی کے سربراہ جوزپ بوریل نے کہا ہے کہ ہسپتال کے ایسے مریضوں کو نکالنے کے لیے ’توقف‘ کی ضرورت ہے جنہیں فوری طبی دیکھ بھال کی ضرورت ہے۔7 اکتوبر سے غزہ پر اسرائیلی حملوں میں 11,100 سے زیادہ فلسطینی جان سے جا چکے ہیں جبکہ اسرائیل میں حماس کے حملوں میں ہلاک ہونے والوں کی تعداد 1200 سے زیادہ ہے۔"},{"question":"\\"Fotoana iray hivondronan’ny fianakaviana sy ny namana koa ny fampakaram-bady mba hankalaza izany fotoana manokana izany. Matetika ny mpivady no voahodidin'ny olon-tiana izay manohana azy ireo sy mizara ny hafaliany. Ny fomba amam-panao amin'ny fampakaram-bady, toy ny fehezam-boninkazo na ny dihin'ny mpampakatra, dia manampy fifaliana sy marika amin'ny lanonana. Ny fampakaram-bady dia mety ho akaiky sy tsotra na reraka sy lehibe, maneho ny toetran'ny mpivady sy ny tiany. Amin'ny farany, ny fanambadiana dia dingana lehibe eo amin'ny fiainan'ny olona maro, voamariky ny fitiavana, ny fankalazana ary ny fanoloran-tena maharitra.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny fanambadiana."},{"question":"Apakah asal-usul nama Pulau Pinang? ","answer":"Nama Pulau Pinang ini diambil daripada nama pokok pinang (areca catechu). Ia juga dipanggil Tanjung Bidara sebelum dikenali Pulau Pinang. Terdapat banyak pantai terletak di Pulau Pinang."},{"question":"Pozisyon an V papiyon yo rele Pyerid delarav la pran","answer":"Anvan yon papiyon vole, li bezwen chalè solèy la pou l kapab chofe mis li yo ki pèmèt li vole. Men, lè syèl la kouvri ak nyaj, papiyon yo rele Pyerid delarav la gentan vole anvan menm lòt kalite papiyon yo vole. Ki sa k fè li gen avantaj sa a sou lòt yo?Fè yon ti reflechi: Gen anpil papiyon, anvan yo vole, se swa yo ret nan solèy la avèk zèl yo fèmen oswa yo ret nan solèy la avèk zèl yo ouvri byen gran. Epoutan, Pyerid delarav la fè zèl li yo pran fòm yon V. Rechèch yo fè montre papiyon sa a, lè l ap chofe kò l, pou l ka fè sa pi vit, li mete zèl li yo nan yon pozisyon ki bay yon ang 17 degre, sa ki ba l fòm yon V. Pozisyon sa a li pran an pèmèt reyon solèy yo frape kò l dirèkteman, sa ki pèmèt mis li yo chofe pi vit.Syantifik yo ki nan inivèsite Exeter, ann Angletè, t ap analize pou yo wè si yo te kapab fè pano yo ki kapte enèji solèy la vin pi efikas si yo ta kopye sou papiyon sa a ki pran fòm V a. Nan analiz yo fè yo, yo vin dekouvri kantite enèji pano yo pwodui te vin ogmante prèske a senkant pousan pi plis.Moun k ap fè rechèch yo remake tou, do zèl papiyon an gen kapasite pou l reflete reyon solèy yo anpil. Toutpandan y ap kopye sou fòm zèl papiyon ki pran fòm V a ak kapasite zèl li genyen pou l reflete reyon solèy yo, syantifik yo rive fabrike pano solèy ki pi lejè e ki pi efikas. Rezilta rechèch sa yo pouse pwofesè Richard ffrench-Constant, yon manm nan ekip ki t ap fè rechèch yo di papiyon Pyerid delarav la se “yon espè nan kapte enèji solèy la.” Sa vle di fason li fèt pou l absòbe enèji solèy la vrèman efikas."},{"question":"What skills are essential for a machine learning engineer?","answer":"Essential skills include proficiency in programming languages like Python or Java, a strong understanding of statistics and mathematics, experience with machine learning frameworks, and knowledge of data structures and algorithms."},{"question":"صاحب كتاب (حي إبن يقظان) هو..؟","answer":"إبن طفيل"},{"question":"ايش معنى شاندي لك مو شانكرك باللهجة التعزية؟","answer":"معناها ، سأعطيك حقك ، ولن أنكرك بالفصحى."},{"question":"Lẹyin isinmi ọlọjọ diẹ, awọn ọdọ tun jade fun ifẹhonuhan SARS l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Lẹyin bii oṣu kan ti agbarijọpọ awọn ọdọ ti wọn n fẹhonu han ta ko ọrọ awọn ọlọpaa SARS kede pe awọn so iwọde naa rọ nipinlẹ Ọṣun, wọn tun ti bẹrẹ pada lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Ṣugbọn iwọde yii yatọ si bi wọn ṣe maa n ṣe e tẹlẹ, wọn to lọwọọwọ lọ sile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ọṣun lai di ẹnikẹni lọwọ rara, bẹẹ ni awọn mọto n kọja lọ.Ọkan lara awọn aṣaaju awọn ọdọ naa ti wọn pe orukọ ara wọn ni Face of #EndSARS Movement, Emmanuel Adebisi, sọ pe ọrọ ti kuro ni ti awọn ọlọpaa SARS bayii, o ni oun tawọn n fẹ ni iṣejọba to duroo re, to si fi gbogbo araalu lọkan balẹ.Adebisi ṣalaye pe ijọba gbọdọ ṣetan lati pese iṣẹ gidi fun awọn akẹkọọ-jade, ki aabo to peye si wa fun ẹmi ati dukia awọn araalu.O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe opin ti de ba asiko ti awọn oloṣelu yoo maa ṣeleri, ti wọn ko si ni i mu un ṣẹ fawọn araalu, wọn gbọdọ mọ pe agbara wa lọwọ awọn to yan wọn sipo."},{"question":"जगातील कोणता असा पर्वत आहे जो रोज आपला रंग बदलतो?","answer":"उत्तर: जगातील एयर्स रॉक (Ayers Rock)/ उलरु (ऑस्ट्रेलिया) असा पर्वत आहे जो रोज आपला रंग बदलतो ."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.I see a red fish in a dish.Terjemahan:","answer":"Aku melihat seekor ikan merah di atas piring."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai rabuk dengan api, asal berdekat menyalalah ia\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud dikatakan kepada dua orang yang sentiasa berbantahan."},{"question":"Sheeg Sanadkii la-oofsaday Rasuulka SCW?","answer":"Sanadkii la-oofsaday Rasuulka SCW waa 11-Kii Hijriyada."},{"question":"体を使って「命」や「炎」などの漢字の形を表現することで有名な人気お笑いコンビは？","answer":"ＴＩＭです。"},{"question":"كمل الجملة اللى جاية: في دورة الألعاب الأولمبية الصيفية 2008 في بكين، لي اتأهل للمرة الثانية في","answer":"الماراثون للرجال، جنب زملائه في الفريق كيم يي يونغ ولي بونج جو. أنهى السباق بنجاح في المرتبة الثامنة عشرة بسبع ثواني أمام يان هولمن من فنلندا ، حيث سجل أفضل وقت له في مسيرته الأولمبية من 2: 14:37."},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة جيبوتي؟","answer":"عاصمة جيبوتي هي جيبوتي."},{"question":"Ломбок  аралы тууралу маалымат бер!","answer":"Ломбок кооз арал.Бул жайлуу эс алуу жана жаратылыш менен биримдик үчүн жер. Буга аралдагы жашоонун шашылбаган ритми, пейзаждар жана аз сандагы туристтер көмөктөшөт.Орун айлган жери - Индонезия "},{"question":"回答下面的问题. 谁在富有和穷乏的游戏中扮演贾斯汀·路易斯?","answer":"尼古拉斯·詹姆斯"},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੩੧ ਪੰ. ੧ਗੁਰੂ ਪ੍ਰੀਖਿਆਸਿਧੀ ਮਨੇ ਬੀਚਾਰਿਆ ਕਿਵੈ ਦਰਸਨ ਏ ਲੇਵੈ ਬਾਲਾ।ਐਸਾ ਜੋਗੀ ਕਲੀ ਮਹਿ ਹਮਰੇ ਪੰਥ ਕਰੇ ਉਜਿਆਲਾ।ਖਪਰ ਦਿਤਾ ਨਾਥ ਜੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਭਰਿ ਲੈਵਣਿ ਉਠਿ ਚਾਲਾ।ਬਾਬਾ ਆਇਆ ਪਾਣੀਐ ਡਿਠੇ ਰਤਨ ਜਵਾਹਰ ਲਾਲਾ।ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਅਗਮ ਅਗਾਧਿ ਪੁਰਖੁ ਕੇਹੜਾ ਝਲੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਝਾਲਾ।ਫਿਰਿ ਆਇਆ ਗੁਰ ਨਾਥ ਜੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਠਉੜ ਨਹੀ ਉਸਿ ਤਾਲਾ।ਸਬਦਿ ਜਿਤੀ ਸਿਧਿ ਮੰਡਲੀ ਕੀਤੋਸੁ ਅਪਣਾ ਪੰਥੁ ਨਿਰਾਲਾ।ਕਲਿਜੁਗ ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮ ਸੁਖਾਲਾ ॥੩੧॥","answer":"ਸਿੱਧਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੋਚਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਹਾਲਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਯੋਗ ਦੇ ਫਲਸਫੇ ਨੂੰ ਅਪਣਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।ਕਲਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਯੋਗੀ, ਸਾਡੇ ਪੰਥ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਕਰੇਗਾ।ਇੱਕ ਨਾਥ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਣੀ ਭਰਨ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਕਟੋਰਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਜਦੋਂ ਬਾਬਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਲੈਣ ਲਈ ਨਦੀ 'ਤੇ ਆਇਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੂਬੀ ਅਤੇ ਗਹਿਣੇ ਵੇਖੇ।ਇਹ ਸੱਚੇ ਗੁਰੂ (ਨਾਨਕ) ਅਥਾਹ ਪਰਮ ਪੁਰਖ ਸਨ ਅਤੇ ਜੋ ਆਪਣੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਬਰਦਾਸ਼ਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਸਨ।ਉਹ (ਬਾਕੀ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ) ਸਮੂਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਰਤ ਆਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ਹੇ ਨਾਥ, ਉਸ ਨਦੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਣੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।(ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ) ਦੁਆਰਾ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਿੱਧਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਿੱਤ ਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਨਵਾਂ ਜੀਵਨ ਢੰਗ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ।ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ, ਯੋਗ ਅਭਿਆਸਾਂ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜੋ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈ (ਨਾਨਕ) ਹੀ ਆਨੰਦ ਦਾ ਸੋਮਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"కొడైకెనాల్, ఉదగ మండలంలు …….. లో ఉన్నాయి.","answer":"పశ్చిమ కనుమల్లో"},{"question":"لومړۍ جمله: د ګیوروک سیند په رومانیا کې د ماګیروش سیند یوه څانګه ده. دویمه جمله: د جیوروک سیند په رومانیا کې د ماګرو سیند یوه څانګه ده. پوښتنه: ایا لومړۍ او دویمه جمله یو شان معنی لري؟ هو یا نه؟","answer":"هو"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa suurada u shafeeco qaadeysa qofka maalinka akhriya?","answer":"Waa suuratu-alMulki (Tabaarak)."},{"question":"Nitori pe Fayẹmi ti kọ iṣejọba silẹ, awọn ọdaran ti gba ipinlẹ Ekiti-PDP","answer":"Ẹgbẹ oṣelu  People’s Democratic Party (PDP) nipinlẹ Ekiti ti fẹsun kan Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi pe ko bikita nipa eto aabo mọ, bi yoo ṣe di aarẹ tabi igbakeji rẹ lọdun 2023 lo n ba kiri.Eyi jẹ yọ ninu lẹta kan ti akọwe ipolongo ẹgbẹ naa l’Ekiti, Raphael Adeyanju, fọwọ si lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, niluu Ado-Ekiti.Adeyanju ṣalaye pe bi awọn ajinigbe ṣe ji gbajugbaja oniṣowo epo kan, Alhaji Sulaiman Akinbami, gbe fi han pe awọn ọdaran naa ti wọ olu-ilu Ekiti, ko si sẹni ti aabo daju fun mọ.Akọwe ipolongo naa ni pẹlu bi Alhaji Akinbami ṣe nawo to lati gbe Fayẹmi sori aleefa, gomina naa ko le daabo bo ẹmi ẹ, eyi si fi han pe ko sẹni ti wọn ko le ṣe nijamba l’Ekiti lasiko yii.O ni, ‘‘Lasiko ọdun Keresi ni wọn ji Ajayi Happiness Okunọla gbe niluu Fayẹmi ti i ṣe Iṣan-Ekiti, o si ya ni lẹnu pe ẹni to ni oun gba iwe-ẹri ọmọwe ninu ẹkọ ogun jija ko le ṣe nnkan kan si i.‘‘Eyi fi han pe ti ko ba jẹ pe Gomina Fayẹmi ko kunju oṣuwọn, o jẹ pe ko bikita ni, ọrọ ibo 2023 lo n ba kiri.’’Adeyanju fi kun un pe asiko tawọn ajinigbe ji ọmọ ilẹ China kan lopin ọdun to kọja lo yẹ ki Fayẹmi ti gbe igbesẹ nitori Ado-Ekiti ni wọn ti gbe e.O waa pe awọn eeyan Ekiti, o ni ki wọn bẹ gomina ko ṣiṣẹ ti wọn gba a fun, kawọn ajinigbe too maa wọle lọọ gbe awọn eeyan."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Clip ghi nhận chiều 31/7 trên cao tốc Pháp Vân - Cầu Giẽ. Hình thức thu phí ETC được biết đến như có nhiều ưu điểm và lợi thế, khắc phục hoàn toàn các bất cập của hình thức thu phí thủ công. Góp phần hiện đại hoá hệ thống kết cấu hạ tầng giao thông, thuận tiện cho chủ phương tiện, giảm ùn tắc giao thông, ô nhiễm môi trường, tiết kiệm chi phí xã hội, tăng cường tính công khai minh bạch trong thu phí BOT, tạo niềm tin cho người sử dụng dịch vụ…  Xe ô tô bị barie đập thẳng vào kính lái phía trước. Ghi nhận của phóng viên vào chiều 31/7, tại tuyến cao tốc Pháp Vân - Cầu Giẽ, trạm thu phí đã áp dụng hình thức thu phí không dừng đối với hầu hết các làn. Nếu các phương tiện chưa dán thẻ hoặc đã dán nhưng trong tài khoản không đủ tiền thì đi vào làn xử lý sự cố để thực hiện thu vé thủ công.  Nhiều trường hợp đã dán thẻ và nạp tiền nhưng gặp lỗi. Tuy nhiên, trong vòng khoảng 1 giờ có nhiều ô tô gặp sự cố khi đi vào làn ETC mặc dù đã dán thẻ và trong tài khoản còn tiền nhưng barie tự động không mở, hoặc đã nạp tiền nhưng gặp lỗi khiến các phương tiện phía sau phải dừng lại chờ trước trạm thu phí. Điều đáng nói, một số tài xế bức xúc khi đi qua bị barie tự động đóng xuống, đập thẳng vào nắp capo hay kính chắn gió phía trước. Trong đó, anh Minh (trú tại Hà Nội) cho biết, đây là lần đầu tiên tôi gặp trường hợp như vậy, trong tài khoản còn tiền nhưng sau khi hệ thống đọc biển số trên bảng điện tử, barie không mở mà đóng xuống xe. \\"Trường hợp xe bị hư hỏng thì ai đền\\" - anh Minh bức xúc nói.  Ô tô đi đến barie bất ngờ đóng xuống. Tuy nhiên, một người ở trạm thu phí ra làm việc với anh Minh cũng chỉ nói rằng khi xảy ra sự cố sẽ tìm nguyên nhân lỗi, rồi lắp lại barie về vị trí cũ. Một nạn nhân khác là anh Quang cũng gặp phải sự cố tương tự. Anh Quang cho biết, ngày hôm qua đã nạp 500 nghìn đồng vào tài khoản để sử dụng dịch vụ thu phí tự động. Tuy nhiên, chiều nay (31/7) khi đi qua thì hệ thống báo trong tài khoản không đủ tiền, barie không mở và đập vào kính xe phía trước khiến anh phải phanh gấp dừng lại. Sau khi làm việc với đơn vị dán thẻ, anh Minh phải nạp thêm tiền vào tài khoản để trả phí.  Tài xế cho rằng việc barie đóng như vậy rất nguy hiểm. \\"Có thể do một số lỗi khi chuyển tiền chưa vào tài khoản. Tuy nhiên, việc barie đóng xuống như vậy rất nguy hiểm, nếu trong tài khoản không có tiền thì có thể truy thu sau giống như việc đi đăng kiểm\\" - anh Quang chia sẻ. Theo anh Quang, sau vụ việc anh cũng làm việc với nhân viên để hoàn trả lại số tiền đã nạp ngày hôm qua.  Hiện nhiều làn thu phí trên cao tốc Pháp Vân - Cầu Giẽ đã áp dụng thu phí không dừng.  Lượng phương tiện qua cao tốc khá lớn.  Nhiều xe phanh lại trước barie. Từ 1/8, Bộ Giao thông vận tải và các địa phương sẽ phải triển khai thu phí hoàn toàn tự động (ETC) đối với tất cả tuyến cao tốc. Nếu tài xế không dán thẻ tham gia dịch vụ ETC mà đi vào cao tốc sẽ bị xử phạt theo quy định. Cụ thể, các trường hợp không dán thẻ ETC mà cố tình đi vào cao tốc, người điều khiển ô tô sẽ bị phạt từ 2 - 3 triệu đồng, đồng thời bị tước quyền sử dụng giấy phép lái xe từ 1 - 3 tháng. Trước đó, tuyến cao tốc Hà Nội - Hải Phòng đã tổ chức thu phí toàn bộ theo hình thức tự động không dừng từ ngày 1/6/2022. Nguồn: https://tienphong.vn/nhieu-tai-xe-buc-xuc-vi-su-co-barie-khi-qua-lan-etc-tram-phap-van-cau-gie-p...Nguồn: https://tienphong.vn/nhieu-tai-xe-buc-xuc-vi-su-co-barie-khi-qua-lan-etc-tram-phap-van-cau-gie-post1457913.tpo ","answer":"Nhiều tài xế bức xúc vì sự cố barie khi qua làn ETC Trạm Pháp Vân - Cầu Giẽ"},{"question":"Lumakad ang isang lalaki sa ulan na walang kahit anong payong o kapote na suot, ngunit hindi nabasa ang kanyang buhok. Paano ito nangyari?","answer":"Ang lalaki ay kalbo."},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Bulgária?","answer":"búlgaro"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න.ගිලෙම් ඔබේ ගුණ මූදේවිඳිම් ඔබේ දම් සාධු","answer":"ගිලෙම් ඔබේ ගුණ මූදේවිඳිම් ඔබේ දම් සාධුවඳිම් වඳිම් ඔබ පාදේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේ…..සිඳ බිඳ මෝහදුර පාපසිඳ බිඳ මෝහදුර පාපදැල් වූ දහම් ප්‍රදීපසිඳ බිඳ මෝහදුර පාපදැල් වූ දහම් ප්‍රදීපහෙළි කළ අප හෙළ දීපතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේ……සිල්ගත් දිනිඳුන් සේමසිල්ගත් දිනිඳුන් සේමසිල් තෙද ගුණ ඇති සෝමසිල් තෙද ගුණ ඇති සෝමසිල්ගත් දිනිඳුන් සේමසිල්ගත් දිනිඳුන් සේමසිල් තෙද ගුණ ඇති සෝමසිල් තෙද ගුණ ඇති සෝමසත හට පෑ මව් ප්‍රේමතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේ…….ගිලෙම් ඔබේ ගුණ මූදේවිඳිම් ඔබේ දම් සාධුවඳිම් වඳිම් ඔබ පාදේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේ…..තිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේතිලොවග බුදු සමිඳේ"},{"question":"අනවශ්‍ය යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අනවශ්‍ය යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය අවශ්‍ය වේ. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਰਾਗੁ ਆਸਾ ਘਰੁ ੨ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਲਾਈ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਸੋਈ ਫਿਰਿ ਖਾਇਆ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਸੁਖਿ ਬੈਠਾਲੀ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਉ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਦਿਖਾਇਆ ॥ਭਾਈ ਮੀਤ ਕੁਟੰਬ ਦੇਖਿ ਬਿਬਾਦੇ ॥ਹਮ ਆਈ ਵਸਗਤਿ ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੇ ॥੧॥ਐਸਾ ਦੇਖਿ ਬਿਮੋਹਿਤ ਹੋਏ ॥ਸਾਧਿਕ ਸਿਧ ਸੁਰਦੇਵ ਮਨੁਖਾ ਬਿਨੁ ਸਾਧੂ ਸਭਿ ਧ੍ਰੋਹਨਿ ਧ੍ਰੋਹੇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਇਕਿ ਫਿਰਹਿ ਉਦਾਸੀ ਤਿਨੑ ਕਾਮਿ ਵਿਆਪੈ ॥ਇਕਿ ਸੰਚਹਿ ਗਿਰਹੀ ਤਿਨੑ ਹੋਇ ਨ ਆਪੈ ॥ਇਕਿ ਸਤੀ ਕਹਾਵਹਿ ਤਿਨੑ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਕਲਪਾਵੈ ॥ਹਮ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਖੇ ਲਗਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪਾਵੈ ॥੨॥ਤਪੁ ਕਰਤੇ ਤਪਸੀ ਭੂਲਾਏ ॥ਪੰਡਿਤ ਮੋਹੇ ਲੋਭਿ ਸਬਾਏ ॥ਤ੍ਰੈ ਗੁਣ ਮੋਹੇ ਮੋਹਿਆ ਆਕਾਸੁ ॥ਹਮ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਰਾਖੇ ਦੇ ਕਰਿ ਹਾਥੁ ॥੩॥ਗਿਆਨੀ ਕੀ ਹੋਇ ਵਰਤੀ ਦਾਸਿ ॥ਕਰ ਜੋੜੇ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰੇ ਅਰਦਾਸਿ ॥ਜੋ ਤੂੰ ਕਹਹਿ ਸੁ ਕਾਰ ਕਮਾਵਾ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਮੁਖ ਨੇੜਿ ਨ ਆਵਾ ॥੪॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 370 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ (ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਨਾਲ) ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾਇਆ, ਉਹੀ ਪਰਤ ਕੇ ਖਾਧਾ ਗਿਆ (ਮਾਇਆ ਨੇ ਉਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਖਾ ਲਿਆ) । ਜਿਸ ਨੇ (ਇਸ ਨੂੰ) ਆਦਰ ਦੇ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੋਲ ਬਿਠਾਇਆ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਨੇ) ਬੜਾ ਡਰ ਵਿਖਾਲਿਆ ।  ਭਰਾ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਪਰਵਾਰ (ਦੇ ਜੀਵ, ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਨੂੰ) ਵੇਖ ਕੇ (ਆਪੋ ਵਿਚ) ਲੜ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਹ ਸਾਡੇ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਗਈ ਹੈ ।੧।ਸਾਧਨ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਜੋਗੀ, ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪੁੱਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਜੋਗੀ, ਦੇਵਤੇ, ਮਨੁੱਖ—ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਨੂੰ) ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਸਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਹੋਰ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਠਗਣੀ (ਮਾਇਆ) ਦੇ ਹੱਥੀਂ ਠੱਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਬੰਦੇ ਤਿਆਗੀ ਬਣ ਕੇ ਤੁਰੇ ਫਿਰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਪਰ) ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਇਹ ਮਾਇਆ) ਕਾਮ-ਵਾਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਲ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਦਬਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਬੰਦੇ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਕਠੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਬੰਦੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ) ਦਾਨੀ ਅਖਵਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਭੀ) ਇਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਦੁਖੀ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨੀ ਲਗਣ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ (ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪੰਜੇ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।੨।ਤਪ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਤਪਸ੍ਵੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ (ਇਸ ਮਾਇਆ ਨੇ) ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਸਾਰੇ ਵਿਦਵਾਨ ਪੰਡਿਤ ਲੋਕ ਲੋਭ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਕੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਹੱਥੀਂ) ਠੱਗੇ ਗਏ ਸਾਰੇ ਤੈ੍ਰ-ਗੁਣੀ ਜੀਵ ਠੱਗੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਦੇਵਤੇ ਭੀ ਠੱਗੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਤਾਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਹੱਥ ਦੇ ਕੇ (ਇਸ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਬਚਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਇਹ ਮਾਇਆ) ਉਸ  ਦੀ ਦਾਸੀ ਬਣ ਕੇ ਕਾਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੱਗੇ (ਦੋਵੇਂ) ਹੱਥ ਜੋੜਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ,ਉਸ ਅੱਗੇ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਆਖਦੀ ਹੈ—) ਮੈਂ ਉਹੀ ਕਾਰ ਕਰਾਂਗੀ ਜੇਹੜੀ ਤੂੰ ਆਖੇਂ, ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁਕਾਂਗੀ (ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਦਬਾਉ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾਵਾਂਗੀ) ਜਿਹੜਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧।\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ombak purus\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud deru yang amat menghibakan."},{"question":"தமிழின் இலக்கிய வளம் – கல்வி மொழி – பிறமொழிகளில் உள்ள இலக்கிய வளங்கள் – அறிவியல்கருத்துகள் – பிறதுறைக் கருத்துகள் – தமிழுக்குச் செழுமை.மேற்கண்ட குறிப்புகளைக் கொண்டு செம்மொழித் தமிழுக்கு வளம் சேர்க்கும் மொழிபெயர்ப்புக் கலை, என்ற தலைப்பில் வார இதழ் ஒன்றுக்கு நடுப்பக்க கட்டுரை எழுதுக.","answer":"முன்னுரை :உலகம் தகவல் தொழில்நுட்பத்தினால் சுருங்கி விட்ட சூழலில் கூட மொழிபெயர்ப்புத் துறை முக்கிய இடம் பெறுகிறது. இத்தகு மொழிபெயர்ப்பு கலை மக்களின் வாழ்வில் எத்தகு போக்கினைச் செய்கிறது என்பது பற்றிக் காண்போம்.வரையறை:மொழிபெயர்ப்பு என்பது மூல மொழியில் உள்ள சொல் அல்லது சொற்றொடர்களை எந்தவித பொருள் மாற்றமும் இல்லாமல் வேறு மொழியில் பெயர்ப்பு செய்வது மொழிபெயர்ப்பு எனப்படும்.தமிழ் இலக்கிய வளம் :தமிழ் இலக்கிய வளம் பெற வேண்டும் என்றால் பிறமொழியில் சிறந்து விளங்கிய நூல்களைத் தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு செய்ய வேண்டும். பல நூற்றாண்டுகளுக்கு முன்னரே இருந்து தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்ப்புப் பணி நடைபெற்று வருகிறது. அதனடிப்படையில் கம்பரின் இராமவதாரம், வில்லிபுத்தூராரின் வில்லிபாரதம் போன்ற காவியங்கள் அனைத்தும் மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டவையே.கல்வி மொழி :மொழிபெயர்ப்பைக் கல்வியாக்குவதன் மூலம் அனைத்துலக அறிவை நாம் பெற்றுப் பல்வேறு துறையில் சிறந்து விளங்கமுடியும்.பிறமொழி இலக்கியம் :ரவீந்திரநாத் தாகூர் வங்க மொழியில் எழுதிய கீதாஞ்சலியை அவர் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மொழிபெயர்த்தப் பிறகு நோபல் பரிசு கிடைத்தது.அறிவியல் கருத்துகள் :மொழிபெயர்ப்பு அறிவியல் சார்ந்த துறையிலும் தன் ஆதிக்கத்தைச் செலுத்துகிறது. Tele என்ற ஆங்கிலச் சொல் தொலை என்பதைக் குறிக்கும். இதன் அடிப்படையில் Telephone – Telescope – தொலைபேசி, தொலைநோக்கி என்று மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.பல்துறை கருத்துகள் :கல்வி, அறிவியல், இலக்கியம் மட்டுமல்லாமல் பிறதுறையிலும் வளர்ச்சி அடைந்துள்ளன. வானொலி, திரைப்படம், இதழியியல், விளம்பரம் போன்ற துறைகளிலும் மொழிபெயர்ப்புப் பணி சிறந்து விளங்குகிறது. தொலைக்காட்சித் தொடர்கள் வேற்றுமொழிக்கு மாற்றப்படுவதால் அனைத்து மக்களையும் சென்றடைகிறது.முடிவுரை:எந்த மொழியின் படைப்பாக இருந்தாலும் எதை மொழிபெயர்க்க வேண்டும்? எப்படிச் செய்ய வேண்டும்? என்பதனை அறிந்து இலக்கண விதிமுறையுடன் செய்தால் நிலைபெற்று விளங்கும்."},{"question":"ગુજરાતી ઇદડા બનાવવાની રીત કઈ છે?","answer":"ગુજરાતી ઇદડા એટલે \\"ઢોકળા\\".સામગ્રીઃ બે વાટકી સાદા ચોખા, એક વાટકી બાફેલા(બાફ્યા) ચોખા. એક વાટકી અડદની દાળ, બે ચમચી તેલ, અડધી ચમચી રાઇ. છાસ. રીત: અડદની દાળ અને બંને ચોખામાં (દાળ અને ચોખા ડૂબે તેટલું) પાણી નાખી આગલી રાત્રે રાખી મુકો. સવારે તેમાંથી પાણી કાઢીને દાળ તથા ચોખાને વાટીને મિશ્રણ તૈયાર કરો. તૈયાર મિશ્રણમાં જરૂરી છાસ નાખીને તૈયાર ઢોકળાનાં ખીરાને સાત થી આઠ કલાક માટે રાખી મૂકો. બાદ તેમાં સ્‍વાદ પ્રમાણે મીઠું નાખીને સારી રીતે હલાવી લો, ઢોકળાના પાત્રમાં તેલ લગાવી તેમાં આ મિશ્રણ ને પાથરી દો. ઉપરથી તેમાં મરી પાઉડર છાંટી તેને ઢોકળીયામાં રાખીને દસ-બાર મિનિટ પકવવા દો, ચપ્પુ લગાવી ને જોઇ લો કે જુઓ ઢોકળા કાચા નથી ને? (ચપ્પુમાં ખીરૂં ચોટે તો થોડો સમય વધુ રાખો) આ ઢોકળાને મનપસંદ આકારમાં કાપી લો. બે ચમચી તેલને ગરમ કરી તેમાં રાઈ નો વઘાર નાખી તૈયાર વઘારને ઢોકળા પર નાખો. લીલી ચટણી સાથે ગરમા ગરમ સર્વ કરો."},{"question":"दिये गये वाक्य में, हर शब्द का 'टैग' क्या है, उसका अनुमान करें:\\"मुझे सेब पसंद हैं।\\"","answer":"दिये हुए वाक्य (\\"मुझे सेब पसंद हैं।\\") के शब्दभेद इस प्रकार हैं: \\"मुझे\\":सर्वनाम\\"सेब\\":संज्ञा\\"पसंद है\\":क्रिया "},{"question":"கேள்வி:    சீனாவின் தலைநகரம் எது?","answer":"பதில்: சீனாவின் தலைநகர் பீஜிங் ஆகும்.குறிப்பு:         சீனா என்று பொதுவாக அழைக்கப்படும் சீன மக்கள் குடியரசு கிழக்காசியாவிலுள்ள நாடாகும். ஆசியாவிலேயே பரப்பளவில் மிகப்பெரிய நாடான சீனா உலகில் ரஷ்யா, கனடா ஆகிய நாடுகளுக்கு அடுத்தபடியாகப் பரப்பளவின்படி மூன்றாவது பெரிய நாடாகும்.  உலகில் மக்கள் தொகை கூடிய நாடுகளில் முதலிடம் வகிக்கிறது. சீனப் பெருஞ்சுவர் இந்நாட்டின் இயலுமையையும் தொன்மையையும் கூறி நிற்கிறது. சீனாவின் தலைநகர் பீஜிங் ஆகும். அந்நாட்டின் வர்த்தகத் தலைநகராகச் சாங்காய் உள்ளது.       உலகின் மிகப் பழைய நாகரிகங்களில் ஒன்றான பண்டைய சீன நாகரிகம், வட சீனச் சமவெளியூடாகப் பாயும் மஞ்சள் ஆற்றங்கரையில் உருவாகி வளர்ந்தது. இந்நாடு நாலாயிரம் ஆண்டுகளாக, சியா வம்சம்  தொடக்கம் சிங் வம்சம்  வரையான அரச வம்சங்களால் ஆளப்பட்டு வந்தது. இது 1911-ஆம் ஆண்டில் சீனக் குடியரசு உருவாக்கப்பட்டதுடன் முடிவடைந்தது. 20-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் முதல் அரைப் பகுதியில், ஒற்றுமை இன்மையும், உள்நாட்டுப் போர்களும், சீனாவை இரண்டு முக்கியமான அரசியல் குழுக்களாகப் பிரித்தன. ஒரு குழு, தேசியவாதிகளான குவோமிந்தாங், மற்றது சீனப் பொதுவுடமைக் கட்சி. 1949-ஆம் ஆண்டில் சீனப் பொதுவுடமைக் கட்சி வெற்றிபெற்று சீனத் தலை நிலத்தில் சீன மக்கள் குடியரசு நிறுவப்பட்டதுடன், முக்கியமான பிணக்குகள் முடிவடைந்தன. தேசியவாதிகளின் சீனக் குடியரசின் அரசு தாய்வான் தீவுக்குள் அடங்கிக் கொண்டது. இவ்விரு பிரிவினருக்கும் இடையிலான, பிணக்குகள் இன்றும் தொடர்ந்து வருகின்றன. இவை முக்கியமாக இறைமை, தாய்வானின் அரசியல் அங்கீகாரம் என்பன தொடர்பானவையாகும்.        இன்று மக்கள் சீனக் குடியரசு உலகின் மிகமுக்கியமான நாடும், வளர்ந்துவரும் வல்லரசும் ஆகும். சீனா, ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் பாதுகாப்புச் சபையில் நிலையான உறுப்புரிமையைக் கொண்டுள்ளதுடன், உலக வணிக நிறுவனம், ஆசியா-பசிபிக் பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம், கிழக்காசிய உச்சிமாநாடு, சாங்காய் ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம், ஆகியவற்றிலும் உறுப்பினராக உள்ளது. இது ஒரு அணுவாயுத நாடாக இருப்பதுடன், உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய, நிலையான பாதுகாப்புப் படையையும் கொண்டுள்ளது. பாதுகாப்புக்கான செலவினத்தைப் பொறுத்தவரை சீனா உலகில் நான்காவது இடத்தை வகிக்கின்றது. மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தி அளவின் அடிப்படையில் உலகின் வேகமாக வளரும் பொருளாதாரங்களில் சீனாவும் ஒன்று. பெயரளவு மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தி அளவில் சீனா உலகில் நான்காவது இடத்திலும், வாங்கு திறன் அடிப்படையில் உலகில் இரண்டாவது இடத்திலும் உள்ளது. அத்துடன் ஏற்றுமதி அளவில் உலகின் இரண்டாவது இடத்திலும், இறக்குமதியில் மூன்றாவது இடத்திலும் மக்கள் சீனக் குடியரசு உள்ளது. 1978-ஆம் ஆண்டில் சந்தையை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட பொருளாதாரச் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் ஏற்படுத்தப்பட்ட பின்னர் 53% ஆக இருந்த வறுமை வீதம் 2001-ஆம் ஆண்டில் 8% ஆகக் குறைந்துள்ளது. எனினும் சீனா வேறு பல பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகளை எதிர்நோக்கி உள்ளது. மக்கள்தொகையில் வேகமாக அதிகரித்து வரும் வயதானவர்களின் வீதம், நகர்ப்புறங்களுக்கும், நாட்டுப்புறங்களுக்குமிடையில் விரிவடைந்துவரும் வருமான இடைவெளி, சூழல் தரங்குறைதல் என்பன இத்தகைய பிரச்சினைகளுள் சிலவாகும்.வரலாறு:           ஐரோப்பியா நாடுகளில் நாகரிகம் தோன்று முன்பே சீனாவில் சிறந்த நாகரிகம் ஒன்று காணப்பட்டது. இங்கு உண் குச்சிகள் மூலம் உணவு உட்கொள்ளும் வழக்கம் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டது. இரண்டாம் உலகப் போருக்குப் பிறகு சீனாவில் உள்நாட்டுப் போர் நடந்தது. பொதுவுடமைவாதிகள் வெற்றிபெற்றுப் போர் முடிவுக்கு வந்து, தேசியவாதிகள் தாய்வானுக்குப் பின்வாங்கியதும், சீன மக்கள் குடியரசின் அரசாங்கம் நிறுவப்பட்டுள்ளதாகத் தலைவர் மா சே துங் 1949-ஆம் ஆண்டு அக்டோபர் திங்கள் முதல் நாளன்று தியென் ஆன் மென் வாயிற்கோபுரத்தில் அறிவித்தார். முன்நோக்கிய பெரும் பாய்ச்சல் எனப்பட்ட திட்டத்தின் காரணமாகத் தொடர்ச்சியான பல பொருளாதாரத் தோல்விகள் ஏற்பட்டமையால், மாவோ சே துங் தனது தலைமைப் பதவியிலிருந்து இறங்கினார். லியூ ஷாவோக்கி அவரைத் தொடர்ந்து பதவியேற்றார். மாவோவுக்குத் தொடர்ந்தும் கட்சியில் பெருஞ் செல்வாக்கு இருந்துவந்தாலும் அவர் பொருளாதார அலுவல்களின் அன்றாட மேலாண்மை தொடர்பான விடயங்களிலிருந்து விலகியே இருந்தார். இவ்விடயங்கள், லியூ சாவோக்கி, டெங் சியாவோபிங் ஆகியோரின் பொறுப்பில் இருந்தது.        1966-ஆம் ஆண்டில், மாவோவும் அவரது கூட்டாளிகளும் கலாச்சாரப் புரட்சியைத் தொடக்கி வைத்தனர் இது பத்தாண்டுகள் கழித்து மாவோ இறக்கும்வரை தொடர்ந்தது. கட்சிக்குள் நிலவிய பதவிப் போட்டியினாலும், சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் மீது ஏற்பட்ட பயத்தினாலும் ஊக்குவிக்கப்பட்ட இக் கலாச்சாரப் புரட்சி சமுதாயத்தில் குழப்பநிலையை ஏற்படுத்தியதாகச் சொல்லப்படுகிறது. 1972-ஆம் ஆண்டில், சீனாவுக்கும், சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்துக்கும் இடையிலான பிளவு அதன் உச்சத்தை எட்டியபோது, மாவோவும், பிரதமர் சூ என்லாயும் அமெரிக்க அதிபர் ரிச்சார்ட் நிக்சனை பெய்ஜிங்கில் சந்தித்து அந்நாட்டுடன் தொடர்புகளை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொண்டனர். அதே ஆண்டில், தாய்வானில் இயங்கிவந்த சீனக் குடியரசுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டிருந்த சீனாவுக்கான ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் அவையின் உறுப்புரிமையும், அதன் பாதுகாப்புச் சபைக்கான நிலையான உறுப்புரிமையும், மக்கள் சீனக் குடியரசுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.          டெங் சியாவோபிங் சீனாவின் சந்தை நோக்கிய பொருளாதாரச் சீர்திருத்தங்களைத் தொடக்கி வைத்தவர். 1976-ஆம் ஆண்டில் மாவோ காலமானதும், கலாச்சாரப் புரட்சியின்போது இடம்பெற்ற அட்டூழியங்களுக்காகக் குற்றம் சுமத்தி நால்வர் குழு   என அழைக்கப்பட்ட நால்வர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதுடன், மாவோவின் வாரிசு எனக் கருதப்பட்ட ஹுவா குவோபெங்கிடமிருந்து டெங் சியாவோபெங் பதவியைக் கைப்பற்றினார். டென் சியாவோ பெங் தான் நேரடியாகக் கட்சித் தலைவர் பதவியையோ அல்லது நாட்டின் தலைவர் பதவியையோ வகிக்காவிட்டாலும், கட்சிக்குள் அவருக்கிருந்த செல்வாக்கினால், குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அளவிலான பொருளாதாரச் சீர்திருத்தங்களை நோக்கி நாட்டை வழிநடத்தினார். தொடர்ந்து பொதுவுடமைக் கட்சி, தனிப்பட்டவர்களின் வாழ்க்கையில் அரசாங்கம் கொண்டிருந்த கட்டுப்பாடுகளைத் தளர்த்தியதுடன், கம்யூன்களையும் கலைத்துவிட்டது. பல குடியானவர்கள் ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட நிலங்களையும் பெற்றார்கள். இவ்வாறான மேம்பட்ட ஊக்குவிப்புகளினால், வேளாண்மை உற்பத்திகள் பெருமளவு அதிகரித்தன. இந்த நிலைமைகள், சீனா திட்டமிட்ட பொருளாதார முறையிலிருந்து, கலப்புப் பொருளாதார முறைக்கு மாறும் சூழ்நிலையைக் குறித்தன.சீனாவின் புவியமைப்பு:           சீனா ஆசிய கண்டத்தின் கிழக்குப் பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள நாடாகும். சீனாவின் கிழக்கில் வட கொரியாவும் வடக்கில் மங்கோலியாவும் உள்ளன. வடகிழக்கில் ரஷ்யா, வட மேற்கில் கசக்ஸ்தான், கிர்கிஸ்தான், தாஜிகிஸ்தான் ஆகிய நாடுகள் அமைந்துள்ளன. மேற்கிலும் தென் மேற்கிலும் ஆப்கானிஸ்தான், பாகிஸ்தான், இந்தியா, நேபாளம், பூட்டான் ஆகிய நாடுகளும் தெற்கில் மியன்மர், லாவோஸ், வியட்நாம் ஆகிய நாடுகளும் உள்ளன. கடலுக்கப்பால் கிழக்கிலும் தென்கிழக்கிலும் தென் கொரியா, ஜப்பான், பிலிப்பைன்ஸ், புருனை, மலேசியா, இந்தோனேசியா ஆகிய நாடுகள் உள்ளன. சீனாவின் நிலப்பரப்பில் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு மலைப்பாங்கான நிலமாகும். உலகின் மிகவுயர்ந்த சிகரமான எவரெஸ்ட் சிகரம் சீனா உரிமைக்கோரும் திபெத் மற்றும் நேபாள எல்லையில் அமைந்துள்ளது. இமய மலைத்தொடர், சீன-இந்திய எல்லையில் உள்ளது. இதுதவிர குன்லன், தியென் சான், தாங்குலா, சின்லின், பெரும் சிங் ஆன் லின், தைய்ஹான், சிலியென், ஹென்துவான் என்பவை சீனாவின் முக்கிய மலைகளாகும். சீனாவில் 1500க்கும் அதிகமான ஆறுகள் பாய்கின்றன. இவற்றுள் யாங்சி ஆறு அசியாவில் மிக நீளமானதும், உலகில் மூன்றாவது நீளமான நதியுமாகும். மஞ்சள் ஆறுயும் ஒரு முக்கிய நதியாகும். யாங்சி, மஞ்சள், ஹெலுங், முத்து, லியௌ, ஹைய் எனற நதிகள் சினாவின் கிழக்கு நோக்கிப் பாய்ந்து பசிப்பிக் சமுத்திரத்தில் கலக்கின்றன. இந்தியாவில் பிரம்மபுத்ரா என்று அழைக்கப்படும் 'யாலு சாங்பு நதி' இந்து சமுத்திரத்தில் உள்ள வங்காள விரிகுடாவில் கலக்கின்றது. அர்சிஸ் ஆறு வடக்கு நோக்கிப் பாய்ந்து ஆர்டிக் சமுத்திரத்தில் கலக்கிறது.அரசியல்:சீன மக்கள் குடியரசின் அரசமைப்புஅரசமைப்புச் சட்டம்சட்டமன்றம்தேசிய மக்கள் பேராயம்தேசிய மக்கள் பேராய நிலைக் குழுசீன சனாதிபதி - கூ சிங்தாவ்செயற்குழு/நிர்வாகம்சீன மக்கள் குடியரசின் அரச மன்றம்சீனப் பிரதமர் -மக்கள் விடுதலைப் படை\\t\\tநீதிமன்றம்உச்ச மக்கள் நீதிமன்றம்அரசியல்சீனப் பொதுவுடமைக் கட்சிசீ.பொ.க நடுவண் செயற்குழுசீ.பொ.க தேசிய பேராயம்வரலாறும் கொள்கைகளும்மா சே துங் - மாசேதுங் கோட்பாடுடங் சியாவுபிங் - டங் சியாவுபிங் கோட்பாடுயான் சமீன் - Three Representsகூ சிங்தாவ் - அறிவியல் வளர்ச்சியல் கருத்துருமொழி:     உலகிலேயே அதிக எண்ணிக்கையில் மக்கள் வாழும் சீனாவில் 56 வகை இன மக்கள் உள்ளனர், இவர்களுள் 93% ஹன் இனத்தவர். பௌத்தம், டாவோயிசம், இஸ்லாம், கத்தோலிக்க திருச்சபை, சீர்திருத்தத் திருச்சபை ஆகிய மத நம்பிக்கைகளைப் பின்பற்றும் மக்கள் சீனாவில் உள்ளனர்.   சீன நாட்டின் மக்கள் தொகை பெருக்கத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் முயற்சியாகப் பல குடும்ப நலத்திட்டங்களை அந்நாட்டு அரசு அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. இவற்றில் முக்கியமானது ஒரு தம்பதியினருக்கு ஒரு குழந்தை திட்டம். முதல் குழந்தை பெண் குழந்தையாக வாய்த்தாலோ, தம்பதியினர் கிராமப்புறத்தில் வசித்தாலோ இரண்டாவது குழந்தையைப் பெறலாம். உண்மையில் இத்திட்டம் மக்கள் தொகை வளர்ச்சியை நன்கு கட்டுப்படுத்தினாலும், 117 ஆண்களுக்கு 100 பெண்கள் என்ற பால் விகித நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.   சீன மொழி இந்நாட்டில் பேசப்படும் மொழியும் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ மொழியும் ஆகும். இம்மொழியை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட பல வட்டார மொழிகள் சீனாவில் பேசப்படுகிறது. இதில் ஒன்றான மாண்டரின் சீன மொழி, உலகில் அதிக மக்கள் பேசும் மொழி என்ற சிறப்பைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.பொருளாதாரம்:      1949 முதல் சீனா பொதுவுடமைத் தத்துவத்தைக் கடைபிடித்து வரும் நாடாகும். 1980 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் சீர்த்திருத்த மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டுத் திறப்பு கொள்கை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பின், சீனாவின் பொருளாதாரம் ஆண்டுக்குச் சராசரியாக 9% வேகத்துடன் வளர்ந்து வருகின்றது. சீனா உலகில் பாறை எண்ணெயை அதிகம் இறக்குமதி செய்யும் நாடாகும்.சுற்றுலாத்துறை, சீனப்பெருஞ்சுவர்:            சுற்றுலாவுக்கு புகழ்பெற்றிராத சீனா அத்துறையில் வளர்ச்சி கண்டுவருகிறது. இதற்கு அந்நாட்டில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுவரும் பொருளாதார சீர்த்திருத்தங்களே முக்கியக் காரணமாகத் திகழ்கிறது. மார்ச் – ஏப்ரல் மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் – அக்டோபர் வரையுமான மாதங்கள் சீனச் சுற்றுலாவிற்கு சிறந்தது. பகல் பொழுதில் 20 முதல் 30 பாகை செல்சியஸ் இருக்கும் அதேவேலை இரவு நேரங்களில் வெப்பநிலை குறைவாகக் காணப்படும். சீன புத்தாண்டு போன்ற முக்கிய பண்டிகைகளைத் தவிர்ப்பது நல்லது. இந்தச் சமயங்களில் தங்கும் அறை கிடைப்பதும் பயணம் செய்வதும் கடினம்.முக்கிய விழாக்கள்:         சீன புத்தாண்டு – இவ்விழா பெரும்பாலும் பிப்ரவரி மாதத்தில் கொண்டாடப்படும். அதிகாரபூர்வமாக மூன்று நாட்கள் நீடிக்கும், ஆனால் பெரும்பாலோர் ஒரு வாரம் வரை இவ்விழாவை கொண்டாடுவர். பட்டாசு (வெடி) சப்தங்களும், வாண வேடிக்கைகளும் காணப்படும்.  இலாந்தர் பண்டிகை இது வர்ணமயமான விழாவாகும். வருடத்தின் முதல் பௌர்ணமியிலிருந்து 15 நாட்கள் கழித்து வரும் நாளில் கொண்டாடப்படும் இவ்விழா புத்தாண்டு கொண்டாட்டங்களின் முடிவைக் குறிக்கிறது. சீனாவின் பிரபலமான சிங்க நடனம் இந்தக் காலங்களில் நடைபெறும். சீனாவில் இத்தினம் ஒரு பொது விடுமுறையல்ல.  சிங் மிங் ஏப்ரலில் நடக்கும், சீனக் குடும்பங்கள் மறைந்த தங்கள் உறவினர்களின் கல்லறையைச் சுத்தப்படுத்தும் நிகழ்ச்சி.          டிராகன் படகு திருவிழா ஜூன் மாதத்தில் ஹாங்காங்கில் நடப்பது. 'வுட் யுவான்' என்ற கவிஞரைக் கௌரவிக்கும் முகமாக இந்தத் திருவிழா நடைபெற்று வருகிறது. குழுக்களாகப் படகு செலுத்தும் போட்டி இவ்விழாவின் ஒரு அங்கமாக நடைபெறுவது வழக்கமாகும். படகு குழுவைச் சேர்ந்த அனைவரும் ஒரே சமயத்தில் துடுப்பை வீசிப் படகைச் செலுத்தும் காட்சி கண்ணைப்பறிக்கும். பல வெளிநாட்டுக் குழுக்களும் இப்போட்டியில் பங்குபற்றுவது வழக்கமாகும்."},{"question":"දියමන්ති වැසි ඇද හැලෙන්නේ කුමන ග්‍රහලෝක වලද ?","answer":"දියමන්ති වැසි ඇද හැලෙන්නේ යුරේනස් සහ නෙප්චුන් ග්‍රහලෝකවලය."},{"question":"警察官の階級で、警部の上は何でしょう？","answer":"警視です。"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકના એક લેખનના શરૂઆતના ફકરા નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"અવાજ આવ્યો: “એં...એં...એં...”⁠અમારું ધ્યાન તે તરફ ગયું. બબલીબેનનાં માથામાંથી લોહી વહેતું હતું; વાળ ભીંજાયા હતા; કપડાં પર ટીપાં પડતાં હતાં. ​⁠પાસે જઇને તેને તેના પિતાએ તેડી લીધી. સુવારીને ઘા પર કપડું દબાવ્યું ને દવા લેવા કોઇને દોડાવ્યું.⁠ટીકુ દૂર ઊભી ઊભી વીલે મોંએ એ જોતી હતી. મેં કહ્યું: “ટીકુ આવ, અહીં આવ, તારો ઘા લાગી ગયો કે ?” ટીકુ મારી દીકરી છે.⁠ટીકુએ ડોકું ધુણાવી ‘હા’ કહી ને ધીમે પગલે પાસે આવી.⁠મેં કહ્યું: “જો જોઇએ; કેવુંક લાગ્યું છે?”\\"આ લેખના આગળના ફકરા લખો.","answer":"ટીકુ બબલીની પાસે જઇને ગંભીરતાથી લોહીને જોઇ રહી. તેના મોં પર અસર થયાનાં ચિહ્નો હતાં.⁠પાટો બંધાઇ ગયો, બબલી ઊભી થઇ. મેં તક જોઇ કહ્યું: “ટીકુ, ઘા કરવો હોય તો સામે કોઇ ઊભું ન હોય ત્યાં કરવો; એટલે કોઇને એ લાગે નહિ.”⁠ટીકુએ ગંભીરતાથી ધ્યાન પર લીધું.⁠અમે અમારું કામ કરવા લાગ્યાં. થોડી વારમાં ટીકુ અને બબલીને સાથે રમતાં ને ગમ્મત કરતાં જોયાં.⁠બબલીનાં પિતા અને હું આ બાબતમાં લડ્યા નહિ, ખીજ્યા નહિ, ઘૂરક્યા નહિ, બાળકોને વઢ્યા નહિ, ડાહી ડાહી શિખામણ આપી નહિ. માત્ર ઉપર પ્રમાણે વર્ત્યા, બાળકો તે દિવસથી ગાઢ દોસ્તો બન્યાં છે; હંમેશા સાથે જ રમે છે."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Tình trạng mới nhất của bé gái 18 tháng tuổi bị bạo hành tại Hà Nội: Có dấu hiệu chuyển biến khá hơn","answer":"Thông tin từ Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương vào tối 31-7 cho biết, hiện tại sau 06 ngày được điều trị hồi sức tích cực, tình trạng nhiễm khuẩn huyết biến chứng suy đa cơ quan của bệnh nhi đã có dấu hiệu chuyển biến khá hơn. Hiện bé Q.Tr đã cai được thở máy xâm nhập, chuyển sang thở ô xy hỗ trợ, tình trạng tuần hoàn và chức năng các cơ quan đang dần hồi phục. Tuy nhiên, trẻ có nhiều biểu hiện về di chứng thần kinh. Trẻ vẫn được các y bác sĩ tại Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương tiếp tục chăm sóc tích cực. Trước đó vào ngày 26-7, Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương tiếp nhận bệnh nhi Q.Tr. (18 tháng tuổi, ở Hà Nội) nhập viện trong tình trạng hôn mê, có dấu hiệu mất nước, suy tuần hoàn, suy hô hấp nặng, Sp02 84%, có nhiều vết lằn, vết bầm tím tụ máu trên cơ thể. Qua thăm khám, bệnh nhi được chẩn đoán Theo dõi nhiễm khuẩn huyết có sốc nhiễm khuẩn, suy đa cơ quan và nghi ngờ bị bạo hành. PGS.TS.BS Tạ Anh Tuấn, Trưởng khoa Điều trị tích cực Nội khoa, Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương cho biết, qua thăm khám các bác sĩ thấy trẻ có biểu hiện hôn mê, suy hô hấp nặng phải hỗ trợ thở máy, suy tuần hoàn, rối loạn tiêu hóa. Đặc biệt, trên da có vết thương ở nhiều vị trí: vết lằn kích thước 4-5cm ở cổ chân 2 bên; vết lằn kích thước 10-12cm ở mặt ngoài đùi phải; vết lằn tím tụ máu kích thước 10cm ở mặt ngoài đùi trái; vết bầm tụ máu kích thước 3x4cm ở trán. Trẻ được chỉ định làm các xét nghiệm hỗ trợ cho chẩn đoán và điều trị. Dựa trên các dấu hiệu lâm sàng và xét nghiệm, các bác sĩ Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương chẩn đoán: Theo dõi Nhiễm khuẩn huyết có sốc nhiễm khuẩn biến chứng suy đa cơ quan và nghi ngờ trẻ bị bạo hành. Ngay lập tức, trẻ đã được điều trị: Hỗ trợ hô hấp (thở máy), điều trị sốc (bù dịch, vận mạch), tiêm kháng sinh và được đội ngũ y bác sĩ chăm sóc toàn diện tại khoa Điều trị tích cực nội khoa. Bên cạnh đó, Bệnh viện cũng đã báo ngay các cơ quan chức năng liên quan (Công an phường Láng Thượng, Tổng đài điện thoại Quốc gia Bảo vệ Trẻ em 111) để làm rõ vụ việc. Như Báo ANTĐ đã đưa tin, liên quan đến vụ bạo hành bé gái 18 tháng tuổi ở quận Đống Đa (Hà Nội), cơ quan công an đã tạm giữ hình sự 2 đối tượng về hành vi hành hạ người khác là Đoàn Diệu Linh (SN 1996; trú tại thị xã Sơn Tây, Hà Nội) và Hoàng Thế Vũ (SN 1994; trú tại xã Vạn Thắng, huyện Ba Vì, chồng của Linh) Nạn nhân trong vụ việc này là cháu L.Q.Tr (SN 2021; quê quán xã An Dũng, huyện Đức Thọ, tỉnh Hà Tĩnh) nhập viện trong tình trạng tím tái, li bì và sốt cao, đang điều trị tại khoa điều trị tích cực với tình trạng chuyển biến nặng. Kết quả điều tra ban đầu cho thấy, qua mạng xã hội, mẹ cháu Tr là chị Lê Thị Lan H (SN 1994) biết và thuê Đoàn Diệu Linh trông cháu Tr với giá 3 triệu đồng/ tháng để đi làm. Khi trông cháu Tr, do cháu bị sốt và quấy khóc nên Linh và chồng mình đã dùng dây sạc điện thoại, que gỗ, búa nhựa, băng dính hành hạ cháu Tr. Khi thấy cháu Tr mệt mỏi, khó thở, hôn mê, 2 đối tượng này đã đưa cháu đến bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương cấp cứu."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Adin-kisoa, ka _.\\"","answer":"\\"Adin-kisoa, ka poritra vao manasa vangy.\\""},{"question":"س260- ما الإسم الحقيقي لنبي الله إسرائيل عليه السلام ؟","answer":"ج260- سيدنا يعقوب عليه السلام"},{"question":"الجملة اللى جاية دى بالعربى لكن مكتوبة باستايل الفرانكو-أراب بحروف لاتينية.المطلوب انك تحولها لعربى باستخدام الحروف العربية و تكون جملة مفهومة.2ana 3ayez 2akol pizza darory","answer":"أنا عايز أكل بيتزا ضروري"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වී ගොවිතැනෙහි ඉතිහාසය ගැන කථා කරමු","answer":"වසර දෙදහස් පන්සියයකටත් වැඩි ලිඛිත ඉතිහාසයක් සහිත හෙළ දිව මහා පරාක්‍රමබාහු රජ දවසට පසු නැවත වතාවක් වී වගාවෙන් ස්වයංපෝෂිත තත්ත්වයකට පත්ව ඇති බව තහවුරු වි ඇත. ක්‍රිස්තු පුර්ව 900-600 අතර කාලය තුල නිර්මාණය කරන ලද මැටි භාජනවල වී ගොවිතැන පිළිබද චිත්‍ර ඇති බවට සාක්ෂි ඇත. මේ අනුව ක්‍රිස්තු පුර්ව 600ට පෙරද සිරිලක වී ගොවිතැන පැවති බවට සැක කල හැකිය. ක්‍රිස්තු පුර්ව 6වන සියවසේදි විජය කුමරු සහ පිරිස ලක්දිවට ගොඩ බැසිමෙන් පසු ඔවුන් ආහාර ලෙස බත් අනුභව කල අතර ඉතිරිය කුවේණියට දී ඇත. ලිඛිත ඉතිහාසයෙහි වී වගාව පිලිබදව පළමු වතාවට සදහන් වන්නේ පඩුවස් දෙව් රාජ්‍ය පාලන සමයේදිය. එහෙත් නැවත ඇති වු ආක්‍රමණයන්ගේත් ස්වභාවික විපත් වලත් හේතුවෙන් වී වගාව ක්‍රමයෙන් දුර්වල තත්ත්වයකට පත් විය. නොයකුත් යුධ හැටුම් හේතුවෙන් පරිහානියට පත් වී වගාව නැවත මහා පරාක්‍රමබාහු රජතුමාගේ පාලන සමය තුලදී දියුණු විය. චූල වංශයේ සඳහන් වන ආකාරයට විශාල වැව් 163ක් ද කුඩා වැව් 2376ක්ද ඇළවල් 3910ක් සහ වේලි 165ක් මේ සමයෙහි ඉදිකර ඇත. මහ පොළොවට වැටෙන එක ජල බිඳකුදු ප්‍රයෝජනයට නොගෙන මහ සයුරට නොයැවිය යුතුයැයි පැවසුමම පැරකුම් යුගයෙහි වී වගාවට දක්වන ලද සැලකිල්ල තේරුම් ගැනුමට සෑහේ. ප්‍රථම වතාවට සහල් අපනයන කළ බවට ඉතිහාසයේ සදහන් වේ. ක්‍රි.ව. 1505 දි ලන්දේසින් හා පෘතුගිසින් වෙරළබඩ යටත් කර ගැනිමෙන් පසුව වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල වි ගොවිතැන අඩාල විය. ක්‍රි.ව. 1660-1679 කාලය තුල කන්ද උඩරට දෙවන රාජසිංහ රජුගේ සිරකරුවෙකු ලෙස ජිවත් වු රොබට් නොක්ස්ට අනුව ක්‍රි.ව. 1680 පමන වන විට ලක්දිව මඩ කුඹුරු සඳහා මාවී (මාස 7) හාතියල් (මාස3) හොඩරවාල (මාස 5) හීනැටි (මාස 4) සහ ඇල්පත්කල් (මාස 3) යන වී වර්ග දක්නට ලැබුණ අතර හේන් වගාව සඳහා ගොඩ වී වර්ග දක්නට ලැබුණි.(DCS) හෝර්ටන් තැන්න ආශ්‍රතව කරන ලද පර්යේෂණයකින් හෙලිව ඇත්තේ ලංකාවේ වගාකරන ලද වී වර්ග මීට වසර 10000කට එහා පැත්තේ ද තිබූ බවයි."},{"question":"世の中の移り変わりが激しいことを喩えて、「三日見ぬ間の…」何というでしょう？","answer":"（三日見ぬ間の）桜"},{"question":"\\"لطيف ولكن الغرف الفندقية تحتاج صيانة كادر الخدمة يجب ان يكون بالمستوى المطلوب\\" اعط تقييم من 5 للمراجعة السابقة؟","answer":"غالباً سيكون التقييم 4."},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญของข้อความต่อไปนี้คืออะไร: บ้านที่สร้างก่อนสงครามในปี 1933 โดย \\"Société Française des Mines d’Étain de Takka\\", บริษัทเหมืองแร่ฝรั่งเศส ตั้งอยู่ที่ โกเปง, เปรัก ช่วงแผนฉุกเฉินมาลายัน(1948-1960) ได้เปลี่ยนชื่อจาก \\"French Tekka\\" บังกะโลมาเป็น \\"มูนไลท์\\" บังกะโล. หลังจากแผนฉุกเฉิน ที่ดินผืนนี้ถูกขายให้กับ ลิงก์ ต่อมาได้กลายเป็นทรัพย์สินของนักกฎหมายเมืองอีโปะฮ์","answer":"ประวัติของ\\"มูนไลท์\\" บังกะโลก่อนและหลังแผนฉุกเฉินมาลายัน"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--शेजी देईल काय आणि मन धायेल काय ?","answer":"शेजारणीने एखादा पदार्थ सढळ हाताने करून दिला तरीच मनाची तृप्ति होऊ शकत नाही"},{"question":"Inu wa ko dun si bi Sanwo-Olu ṣe purọ pe oun kọ loun ran wa lọ si ibi iwọde Lekki- Birigedia Taiwo","answer":"Olori ikọ ọwọ kọkanlelọgọrin awọn ọmọ ogun ọtelẹmuyẹ ninu iṣẹ ṣọja to wa niluu Eko, Brigedia Ahmed Taiwo, ti binu si Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu. Ọkunrin ṣọja naa ni inu oun ko dun si gomina naa pẹlu bo ṣe kọkọ purọ pe oun kọ loun ranṣẹ pe awọn lasiko rogbodiyan SARS to waye ninu oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii.O ni, ‘Sanwo-Olu lo ranṣẹ si wa, o ni apa awọn ọlọpaa ko ka ọrọ naa mọ’Taiwo sọrọ yii lasiko to fara han niwaju igbimọ to n gbọ ẹjọ ifiyajẹni awọn SARS ati iṣẹlẹ to ṣẹlẹ ni Lẹkki, nibi ti awọn ṣọja ti yinbọn mọ awọn ọdọ to n ṣewọde, eyi to si pada ja si wahala gidi, leyii ti ọpọ ẹmi ati dukia si ṣofo.Bẹ o ba gbagbe, ni kete ti iṣẹlẹ ogunjọ, oṣu kẹwaa, naa waye, ti okiki si kan pe awọn ṣọja yinbọn pa awọn ọdọ to n ṣewọde ni Lẹkki ni Gomina Sanwo-Olu ti jade, to si ni oun ko mọ ohunkohun nipa bi awọn ṣọja ṣe lọ sibi iwọde naa, o ni awọn kan to lagbara ju oun lọ lo wa nidii ọrọ naa.Afi bi aṣiri ọrọ naa ṣe pada tu pe oun lo ranṣẹ pe awọn ṣọja pe ki wọn waa tu awọn ọdọ naa ka, eyi to pada di rogbodiyan nla pẹlu bi awọn araalu ṣe fi ẹhonu han lori ọrọ Lẹkki naa.Ọrọ ti gomina yii sọ naa lọga ṣọja yii ni ko dun mọ awọn ninu pẹlu bo ṣe purọ pe oun ko ran awọn niṣẹ."},{"question":"नेपाली परम्परागत कलालाई कति भागमा विभाजन गरिएको छ ? ती के के हुन् ? लेख्नुहोस् ।","answer":"नेपाली परम्परागत कलालाई तीन भागमा विभाजन गरिएको छ:(१) चित्रकला (चित्रमा माध्यमबाट कुनै पनि कुरा अभिव्यक्त गर्ने)(२) वास्तुकला (स्थापत्य, घर, मन्दिर, आदिको निर्माणमा प्रयोग हुने कला)(३) मूर्तिकला (प्रतिमा बनाउने कला)"},{"question":"Fortune Makaringe","answer":"Fortune Makaringe (ti a bi ni ọjọ ketala osu karun ọdun 1993) jẹ agbabọọlu afẹsẹgba alamọdaju ti orilẹ-ede South Africa ti o ngba aarin fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọluSouth Africa Premier Division Orlando Pirates . O tun gba bọọlu fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu orilẹ-ede South Africa . Oun gba bọọlu tẹlẹ fun Maritzburg United .Ti a bi ni Johannesburg, Makaringe bẹrẹ iṣẹ rẹ ni Moroka Swallows ṣaaju ki o to darapọ mọ Maritzburg United . Makaringe fowo si iwe adehun fun Orlando Pirates ni igba ooru 2019.Makaringe gba bọọlu akọkọ rẹ fun South Africa ni ọjọ keta oṣu Okudu odun 2018 ni 0-0 ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ pẹlu Madagascar, botilẹjẹpe South Africa tẹsiwaju lati padanu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ 4-3 lori awọn ijiya. O jẹ ikan l'ara ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu mejidinlọgbọn akọkọ ti South Africa fun idije ife ẹyẹ ilẹ Afirika 2019 ṣugbọn ko jẹ ara àwọn ti ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu 23 ikẹhin wọn."},{"question":"Write a function to rotate a list by k positions.","answer":"def rotate_list(lst, k):    return lst[-k:] + lst[:-k]my_list = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]k = 2print(rotate_list(my_list, k))  # Output: [4, 5, 1, 2, 3]"},{"question":"Qual destas frases é maior: \\"eu fui à loja\\" ou \\"na loja da minha mãe há roupa\\"?","answer":"A frase \\"na loja da minha mãe há roupa\\" (7 palavras) é maior que a frase \\"eu fui à loja\\" (4 palavras)."},{"question":"Як виглядала первинна аграрна культура українців?","answer":"Ранньотрипілвські поселенці володіли певними навичками у плеканні деяких зернових культур, зокрема проса, ячменю чи навіть пшениці, застосовуючи для агротехнічного процесу такі знаряддя, як найпростіші моделі мотики, виготовлені з рогу, каменю чи дерева, а також кремінні серпи. Саме застосування мотик різного ступня досконалості дозволило створити основу для розвитку аграрної культури як матеріального гаранту поступу людської цивілізації. Не зникли безслідно набуті навички з підготовки грунту неолітичною мотикою трипілля - їх розвивали спадкоємні археологічні культури пізніших епох. Так поступово створювалася аграрна культура на етнічній території України. "},{"question":"Нептун планетасы тууралуу кызыктуу фактыларды айтып берчи..","answer":"1. Нептундун атмосферасы гелий жана суутектен турат.2. Нептунда бир күндүн узактыгы 16 саат.3. Нептун ядросу силикат магнийинен жана темирден турат.4. Нептун Рим деңиз кудайынын атынан аталган.5. Нептун - Күн системасындагы сегизинчи планета.6. Нептундун 13 спутниги бар.7. Шамалдын ылдамдыгы 2000 км/саатка чейин жетет.8. Нептун Жер планетасынан 4 эсе оор."},{"question":"கேள்வி:நீங்கள் அறிந்திருக்கும் புதிர்க்கதைகளுள் ஒன்றை வகுப்பில் பகிர்ந்து கொள்க. ","answer":"பதில்:ஓர் ஊரில் விறகுவெட்டி ஒருவன் இருந்தான். அவன் மிகவும் ஏழ்மையில் இருந்தான். அவனுடைய அப்பாவிற்குக் கண் தெரியாது. அவனுக்குத் திருமணம் ஆகி நீண்ட நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகும் குழந்தை இல்லை. எப்போதும் அவன் கவலையுடன் இருப்பான். ஒருநாள் ஒரு மரத்தடியில் அமர்ந்து கொண்டு தன் வறுமையை எண்ணியபடியே உறங்கிவிட்டான். கொஞ்ச நேரம் உறங்கியபின் விழித்தெழுந்தான். அடுத்த வேலை உணவிற்கு விறகு வெட்டி எடுத்துச் சென்றால்தான் என்ற நிலைமை. சுறுசுறுப்பானான்.மரத்தை வெட்ட தன் கோடாரியை எடுத்தான்.அப்போது  அம்மரம் “விறகு வெட்டியே! நில் என்னை வெட்டாதே! நான் ஓர் அதிசய மரம். என் நிழலில் யார் அமர்கிறார்களோ அவர்களுக்கு உதவி செய்வேன். உனக்கு என்ன வரம் வேண்டும் கேள். நான் தருகிறேன். ஆனால் ஒரு வரம்தான் கேட்க வேண்டும்” என்று கூறியது.விறகு வெட்டி எனக்கு என்ன கேட்பது என்று தெரியவில்லை. வீட்டிற்குச் சென்று என் குடும்பத்தினரிடம் கேட்டு நாளை வந்து கேட்கிறேன் என்றான். மரமும் “சரி” என்று கூறியது. விறகு வெட்டி வீட்டிற்குச் சென்ற நடந்தவற்றைக் கூறினான்.விறகு வெட்டியின் தந்தை ‘தனக்குப் பார்வையில்லாமல் மிகவும் சிரமப்படுவதாகக் கூறினார். தாய் வீடு பெரிய மாடி வீடாக இருக்க வேண்டும்’ என்று கூறினார். மனைவி, ‘நமக்குக் குழந்தை வேண்டும்’ என்று கூறினாள். மூவருடைய தேவையை எவ்வாறு ஒரு வரத்தினால் பூர்த்தி செய்வது என்று சிந்தித்தான் விறகு வெட்டி.அடுத்தநாள் விறகு வெட்டி விடியற்காலையில் எழுந்தான். காட்டிற்குச் சென்று அந்த அதிசய மரத்திடம் ஒரு வரம் கேட்டான். மரமும் கொடுத்தது. விறகு வெட்டியும் மகிழ்ந்தான்.அவன் கேட்ட ஒரு வரம் என்ன?விறகு வெட்டி கேட்ட வரம் :“என் மகனை நான் பள்ளிக்கு அழைத்துச் செல்லும் காட்சியை என் பெற்றோர் வீட்டு மாடியிலிருந்து பார்க்க வேண்டும்” என்பதுதான் விறகு வெட்டி கேட்ட வரம்,தந்தைக்குப் பார்வை கிடைத்துவிட்டது.தாய் கேட்டதைப் போல் மாடி வீடு கிடைத்தது.அவனுக்கு மகனும் பிறந்து விட்டான்."},{"question":"నాడీకణజాలంలో ఊతకణాల గురించి రాయండి.","answer":"న్యూరోగ్లియా (ఊత కణాలు) :నాడీచర్యలకు కావలసిన అనుకూల సూక్ష్మ వాతావరణాన్ని, ఊతను ప్రసారరహిత కణాలైన న్యూరోగ్లియా కణాలు కల్పిస్తాయి. న్యూరాన్స్ లాగా కాకుండా, ఇవి జీవిత పర్యంతం విభజన చెందుతాయి. కేంద్రనాడీవ్యవస్థ లోని న్యూరోగ్లియా కణాలలో ఆలిగోడెండ్రోసైట్స్ (మయలిన్ ఆచ్ఛాదం ఏర్పరచేది), ఆస్ట్రోసైట్స్-నక్షత్రఆకార కణాలు) అంతర సంధాయకమైన జాలకాన్ని ఏర్పరచి నాడీకణాలను రక్తకేశనాళికలతో బంధిస్తాయి. (రక్తం-మెదడు అవరోధాన్ని ఏర్పరచడంలో తోడ్పడతాయి, ఎపెండిమల్ కణాలు శైలికలతో ఉంటాయి. ఇవి మెదడు, నాడీదండం కుహరాన్ని ఆవరించి మస్తిష్కమేరుద్రవం కదలికలకు తోడ్పడతాయి. మైక్రోగ్లియల్ కణాలు భక్షక కణాలుగా కూడా పిలవబడతాయి. ఇవి మధ్యత్వచం నుంచి ఉద్భవిస్తాయి. పరిధీయ నాడీవ్యవస్థలోని న్యూరోగ్లియల్ కణాలలో ఉపగ్రహకణాలు ష్వాన్ కణాలు ఉంటాయి. నాడీసంధిలో కణదేహాలను ఆవరించి ఉపగ్రహకణాలు ఉంటాయి. ష్వాన్ కణాలు తంత్రికాక్షం చుట్టూ న్యూరిలెమ్మాను ఏర్పరుస్తాయి."},{"question":"What kind of relationship is observed between the logarithm of housing price and crime, and between the logarithm of housing price and the average number of rooms?","answer":"A negative relationship with crime and a positive relationship with the average number of rooms."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa maxaal la oran Jiray ninkii dilay Cali Bin Abii Daalib?","answer":"Waxa La Oran Jiray Ninkii Dilay Cali Bin Abii Daalib ,C/Raxmaan Bin Muljan."},{"question":"Califica la siguiente reseña como positiva, neutral o negativa: \\"Es un lugar mágico donde te puedes conectar con la naturaleza\\".","answer":"La reseña es positiva."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : మన సౌర కుటుంబంలోని గ్రహాల గురించి సోదాహరణంగా వివరించండి.","answer":"మన సౌర కుటుంబంలో ఎనిమిది గ్రహాలు ఉన్నాయి. సూర్యుడి నుండి వాటి దూరం ప్రకారం గ్రహాల క్రమం – బుధుడు, శుక్రుడు, భూమి, అంగారకుడు, బృహస్పతి (గురుడు), శని, ఇంద్రుడు, వరుణుడు, సౌర కుటుంబంలోని ఎనిమిది గ్రహాలు సూర్యుని చుట్టూ స్థిర మార్గాల్లో తిరుగుతాయి. ఈ మార్గాలు పొడవుగా ఉంటాయి. వాటిని కక్ష్యలు అంటారు. సూర్యుడికి దగ్గరగా ఉన్న నాలుగు గ్రహాలను అంతర గ్రహాలు అంటారు. అవి బుధుడు, శుక్రుడు, భూమి, అంగారకుడు. అంతర గ్రహాలు చిన్నవిగా ఉండి రాళ్ళతో కూడి ఉంటాయి. చివరి నాలుగు గ్రహాలను బాహ్య గ్రహాలు అంటారు. అవి బృహస్పతి (గురుడు), శని, ఇంద్రుడు. అవి పెద్దవి మరియు వాయువులు, ద్రవాలతో కూడి ఉంటాయి. సూర్యునికి దగ్గరగా ఉన్న గ్రహం బుధుడు. శుక్రుడిని ‘భూమికి కవల గ్రహం’ (ఎర్త్ – ట్విన్) గా పరిగణిస్తారు.. ఎందుకంటే దాని పరిమాణం, ఆకారం భూమిని చాలా వరకు పోలి ఉంటాయి. గ్రహాలలో పెద్దది బృహస్పతి చిన్నది బుధుడు."},{"question":"Tingapewe bwanji malungo ku Malawi?","answer":"M’zaka zaposachedwa, dziko la Malawi lapita patsogolo kwambiri pa ntchito yolimbana ndi malungo pokhazikitsa njira zopewera malungo. Izi zikuphatikizapo maukonde ophera udzudzu amene amathiridwa kwa nthawi yaitali, kupopera mbewu motsalira m’nyumba, ndi mankhwala oletsa malungo."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Chung kết cuộc thi Miss Fitness Vietnam 2022 chính thức khép lại với sự lên ngôi của người đẹp Đoàn Thu Thủy, á hậu 2 thuộc về thí sinh Chu Thị Ánh, á hậu 1 thuộc về Lê Phương Thảo.  Trải qua nhiều phần thi thú vị trong đêm thi quan trọng như đồng diễn, trang phục thể thao, áo tắm và trang phục dạ hội, cô gái đã đánh bại 29 đối thủ nặng kí để bước lên ngôi vị cao nhất. Không chỉ sở hữu ngoại hình xinh đẹp mà Đoàn Thu Thủy còn có tinh thần thể thao bất diện. Cô chia sẻ thể thao là một phần không thể thiếu trong cuộc sống của mình.   Đoàn Thu Thủy sở hữu chiều cao 1,72 m, số đo ba vòng 83-63-94. Cô đã có những sải bước khá ấn tượng cùng bộ váy dạ hội với phần tà bay nhận được nhiều sự hò reo của khán giả. Trong phần thi ứng xử, cô nhận được câu hỏi: \\"Nếu trở thành Hoa hậu Thể Thao Việt Nam 2022 em sẽ mang đến cộng đồng điều gì\\". Không chần chừ, cô trả lời: \\"Em mong muốn có nhiều thời gian để quan tâm đến sức khỏe và thể thao học đường. Em tin rằng trong thời đại nay không chỉ quan tâm đến kiến thức văn hóa cho trẻ nhỏ mà còn tới sức khỏe để các em có cơ hội thay đổi ngoại hình thể chất, vóc dáng\\".  ","answer":"Đoàn Thu Thủy đăng quang Miss Fitness Vietnam 2022: Skill ổn, lựa chọn vừa vặn nhất trong dàn thí sinh"},{"question":"Chu kỳ tự quay và chu kỳ quay quanh mặt trời của sao Hỏa lần lượt là 1,03 ngày Trái đất và 687 ngày Trái đất. Vậy một năm trên sao hỏa có bao nhiêu ngày?","answer":"Số ngày trong một năm trên sao Hỏa là số chu kỳ tự quay của sao Hỏa trong thời gian nó thực hiện được một chu kỳ quanh Mặt Trời, chu kỳ quay quanh Mặt Trời là thời gian sao Hỏa quay quanh Mặt Trời một vòng. Vậy số ngày trong một năm trên sao Hỏa bằng 687/1,03, kết quả bằng 667 chu kỳ tự quay, hay 667 ngày (667 lần mặt trời mọc rồi lặn trên sao Hỏa)."},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన సినిమా పాటలోని ఒక భాగం యొక్క సాహిత్యంపై విశ్లేషణ చెయ్యండి:జయంతితే సుకృతినో రస సిద్దా: కవీశ్వరా :నాస్తిక్లేశాం యశ: కాయే జరా మరణంచ భయంనాస్తి జరా మరణంచ భయంనాస్తి జరా మరణంచ భయం","answer":"ఇక్కడ వేటూరి సుందర రామ్మూర్తి గారి గురించి చెప్పాలి.  ఆయన ఒక చక్కనిఅక్షర శిల్పి మాత్రమే కాదు. అత్యద్భుతమైన పదాలతో మాల కట్టగల నేర్పరి.  బహుశా వేటూరి గారంత నేర్పుగా ఆయన ముందుతరం కవులెవరు సినిమా పాటకి గొప్ప ‘పదమాల’ వెయ్యలేదేమో!  దేవుపల్లి కృష్ణశాస్త్రి గారి పదలాలిత్యాలను పుణికిపుచ్చుకుని వాటిని వరుసలో ఉచడం వేటూరి నేర్పరితనం. చూడండి ఇక్కడ భర్తృహరి ‘నీతి శతకంలోని శ్లోకాన్ని తీసుకొచ్చి ఇక్కడ ఎంత అర్ధవంతంగా ఉపయోగించేరో. గొప్పవైన రస స్పూర్తి ని  కలిగించే రచనలను చేసిన కవులు వారు వారి రచనల ద్వారా మానవాళికి కలిగించిన రససిద్ధి కారణంగా జరామరణాలు లేని కైవల్య స్ధితిని పొందుతారని శ్లోక భావం.ఇక్కడ సినిమాలో నాయకుడు తన నాట్యం ద్వారా ప్రజల్లో రససిద్ధి కలిగించి, తాను లేకపోయినా తన నాట్యం బ్రతికుండేలా తనకొచ్చిన నాట్యకళ పూర్తిగా తన శిష్యురాలికి నేర్పి ఆమె ద్వారా తన నాట్యం ఎల్లప్పుడూ సజీవంగా ప్రజలకు రససిఇది కలిగించి  కైవల్యాన్ని పొందినట్లుగా అన్వయించేరు.  ‘హంసానంది’ రాగంలో ఇళయరాజా స్వరపరిచిన ఈ పాట శైలజ, బాలు పాడేరు. ముఖ్యంగా ‘మాతృ దేవోభవ’ అనడానికి ముందు వచ్చేశైలజ ఆలాపన జనాన్ని కట్టిపడేస్తుంది."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੪ ॥ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਾ ਗੁਣ ਬੋਲੀ ਬਾਣੀ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਆਖਿ ਵਖਾਣੀ ॥੧॥ਜਪਿ ਜਪਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਮਨਿ ਭਇਆ ਅਨੰਦਾ ॥ਸਤਿ ਸਤਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਦਿੜਾਇਆ ਰਸਿ ਗਾਏ ਗੁਣ ਪਰਮਾਨੰਦਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਹਰਿ ਜਨ ਲੋਗਾ ॥ਵਡੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਪਾਏ ਹਰਿ ਨਿਰਜੋਗਾ ॥੨॥ਗੁਣ ਵਿਹੂਣ ਮਾਇਆ ਮਲੁ ਧਾਰੀ ॥ਵਿਣੁ ਗੁਣ ਜਨਮਿ ਮੁਏ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀ ॥੩॥ਸਰੀਰਿ ਸਰੋਵਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਪਰਗਟਿ ਕੀਏ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਮਥਿ ਤਤੁ ਕਢੀਏ ॥੪॥੫॥੫੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 367 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਭੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਉਚਾਰਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਉਚਾਰ ਉਚਾਰ ਕੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਆਨੰਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਸਤਿਨਾਮੁ ਸਤਿਨਾਮੁ ਸਤਿਨਾਮੁ ਪੱਕਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਬੜੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਨੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਣੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਗੁਰੁੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਭਗਤ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਵੱਡੀ ਕਿਸਮਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਨਿਰਲੇਪ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜੇ ਹੋਏ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ) ਟਿਕਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ । ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਮੱਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਜੀਵ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਜੰਮਦੇ ਮਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ) ਇਸ ਸਰੀਰ ਸਰੋਵਰ ਵਿਚ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਹੀ) ਪਰਗਟ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਜਿਵੇਂ ਦੁੱਧ ਰਿੜਕ ਕੇ ਮੱਖਣ ਕੱਢੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਿਵੇਂ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕੇ (ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ) ਨਿਚੋੜ (ਉੱਚਾ ਸੁੱਚਾ ਜੀਵਨ) ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੫।੫੭।\\""},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:అని నిటులాత్మ మంత్రులు ధనాధిపుకోలల కోర్వలేమి నద్దనుజవరేణ్యుం దుగ్రనిశిత ప్రదరంబుల వాని ముంచినన్గనలుచు దాసి కిన్నర శిఖామణి వాని కిరీట పంక్తి ఖంగున రొద సేయ భూరిగదఁ గైకొని బెట్టుగ మోంది మార్చినన్.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్ధము :అనిన్ = యుద్ధరంగమునఇటులు = ఈ విధముగఆత్మమంత్రులు = రావణుని మంత్రులుధనాదిపు = కుబేరునికోలలకు = బాణంబులకుఓర్వలేమి = తట్టుకొనలేకఆ + దనుజవరేణ్యుడు = ఆ రాక్షస శ్రేష్ఠుడైన రావణుడుఉగ్ర = భయంకరమైననిశిత = వాడియైనప్రదరంబులన్ = బాణములచేవానిన్ = ఆ కుబేరునిముంచినన్ = ముంచివేయగాకనలుచు = కోపించిడాసి = సమీపించికిన్నెర శిఖామణి = కుబేరుడుకిరీట పంక్తి = కిరీటముల వరుసనుభూరి గదన్ = పెద్ద గదతోనుకైకొని = తీసుకొనిబెట్టుగా = గట్టిగామోది = కొట్టిఆర్చినన్ = అరచెనుతాత్పర్యం :రావణుడు తన మంత్రులు కుబేరుని ధాటికి నిలువలేకపోవుట తెలుసుకొని భయంకరమైన బాణముల సమూహములతో అతనిని ముంచేశాడు. కుబేరుడు కూడా కోపంతో రావణుని కిరీటములన్నియు ఖంగుమని శబ్దం వచ్చునట్లు పెద్ద గదతో కొట్టాడు ."},{"question":"கேள்வி: மரபுக்கவிதை இடம்பெறும் விதத்தை எழுதுக?.","answer":"பதில்: வாணிதாசன்வாழ்க்கைக்குறிப்பு:இயற்பெயர் = எத்திராசலு (எ) அரங்கசாமிபெயர் = வாணிதாசன்பிறந்த இடம் = புதுவையை அடுத்த வில்லியனூர்பெற்றோர் = அரங்க திருக்காமு – துளசியம்மாள்வேறு பெயர்கள்:புதுமைக் கவிஞர்பாவலரேறுபாவலர்மணிதமிழ்நாட்டுத் தாகூர்(மயிலை சிவமுத்து)தமிழ்நாட்டு வோர்ட்ஸ்வொர்த்நூல்கள்:தமிழச்சிகொடிமுல்லைஎழிலோவியம்தீர்த்த யாத்திரைஇன்ப இலக்கியம்பொங்கல் பரிசுஇரவு வரவில்லைசிரித்த நுணாவாணிதாசன் கவிதைகள்பாட்டரங்கப் பாடல்கள்இனிக்கும் பாட்டுஎழில் விருத்தம்(விருதப்பாவிற்கு இலக்கணமாய்த் திகழ்வது)தொடுவானம்பாட்டு பிறக்குமடா(தமிழக அரசு பரிசு)குறிப்பு:இவர் பாவேந்தர் பாரதிதாசனிடம் தொடக்கக்கல்வி பயின்றவர்.இவரின் பாடல்கள் சாகித்திய அகாதெமி வெளியிட்ட “தமிழ்க் கவிதைக் களஞ்சியம்” என்ற நூலிலும், தென்மொழிகள் புத்தக வெளியீட்டுக் கழகம் வெளியிட்ட “புதுதமிழ்க் கவிமலர்கள்” என்ற நூலிலும் மற்றும் பற்பல தொகுப்பு நூல்களிலும் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன.இவர், “தமிழ்-பிரெஞ்ச் கையகர முதலி” என்ற நூலை வெளியிட்டார்.பிரெஞ்ச் குடியரசு தலைவர் இவருக்கு “செவாலியர்” என்ற விருதினை வழங்கி உள்ளார்இவரின் முதல் பாடல் = பாரதி நாள்சிறப்பு:பாரதிதாசன் பரம்பரையில் மூத்தவர்பாவேந்தர் பரிசு பெற்றுள்ளார்மயிலை சிவமுத்து = தமிழ்நாட்டுத் தாகூர்சிலேடை, இடக்கரடக்கல் அமைத்துப் பாடுவாதில் வல்லவர்குற்றியலுகரத்தின் ஒலியை உவமையாக கையாண்ட முதல் கவிஞர் இவரேமேற்கோள்:பாரதி தாசன் பெயரை உரைத்திடப்பாட்டுப் பிறக்குமடாஇடுவெயில் போல்உழைக்கும் சேரிவாழ் ஏழைமக்கள்கொடுவெயில் குளிர்மழைக்குத் குந்திடக் குடிசை உண்டோ?மக்கட்கே வானை என்றும் மடக்கிநீ அனுப்பி வைத்தாய்மக்கட்கே ஆறு வற்றாத அருவி தந்தாய்சுரதாவாழ்க்கைக்குறிப்பு:இயற்பெயர் = இராசகோபாலன்ஊர் = பழையனூர்பெற்றோர் = திருவேங்கடம், சண்பகம் அம்மையார்சிறப்பு பெயர்கள்:உவமைக் கவிஞர்(ஜெகசிற்பியன்)கவிஞர் திலகம்(சேலம் கவிஞர் மன்றம்)தன்மானக் கவிஞர்(மூவேந்தர் முத்தமிழ் மன்றம்)கலைமாமணி(தமிழக இயலிசை நாடக மன்றம்)கவிமன்னர்(கலைஞர் கருணாநிதி)படைப்புகள்:தேன்மழை(கவிதைத் தொகுதி, தமிழ் வளர்ச்சி கழகப் பரிசு)சிரிப்பின் நிழல்(முதல் கவிதை)சாவின் முத்தம்உதட்டில் உதடுபட்டத்தரசிசுவரும் சுண்ணாம்பும்துறைமுகம்வார்த்தை வாசல்எச்சில் இரவுஅமுதும் தேனும்தொடா வாலிபம்கட்டுரை:முன்னும் பின்னும்இதழ்:காவியம்(முதல் கவிதை இதழ், வார இதழ்)இலக்கியம்(மாத இதழ்)ஊர்வலம்(மாத இதழ்)சுரதா(மாத இதழ்)விண்மீன்(மாத இதழ்)குறிப்பு:பாரதிதாசனுக்கு தாசனாக விளங்கியதால் சுப்புரத்தினதாசன் என்பதை சுரதா என மாற்றிக்கொண்டார்சிறப்பு:தமிழக அரசின் முதல் பாவேந்தர் நினைவுப் பரிசு பெற்றவர்வ.ரா(வ.ராமசாமி) = மற்றொரு பாரதி பிறந்து விட்டான்மேற்கோள்:தண்ணீரின் ஏப்பம் தான் அலைகள்தடைநடையே அவர் எழுத்த்தில் இல்லை வாழைத்தண்டுக்கோ தடுக்கின்ற கணுக்கள் உண்டுபடுக்கவைத்த வினாக்குறி போல்மீசை வைத்த பாண்டியர்கள்வரலாற்றுப் பேரழகி ஆதிமந்திஎதுகை வரல்போல் அடுத்து வந்தால், அத்திஎன்பானோ மோனனையைப் போல் முன்னே வந்தான்கண்ணதாசன்வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்பு:இயற்பெயர் = முத்தையாஊர் = இராமநாதபுரம் மாவட்டம் சிறுகூடல்பட்டிபெற்றோர் = சாத்தப்பன், விசாலாட்சிகாலம் = 1927-1981புனைப் பெயர்:காரை முத்துப் புலவர்வணங்காமுடிகமகப்பிரியாபார்வதிநாதன்துப்பாக்கிஆரோக்கியசாமிவேறு பெயர்கள்:கவியரசுகவிச்சக்ரவர்த்திகுழந்தை மனம் கொண்ட கவிஞர்படைப்புகள்:மாங்கனிஆட்டனத்தி ஆதிமந்திகவிதாஞ்சலிபொன்மலைஅம்பிகாஅழகு தரிசனம்பகவாத் கீதை விளக்கவுரைஸ்ரீ கிருஷ்னகவசம்அர்த்தமுள்ள இந்துமதம்பாரிமலைக் கொடிசந்தித்தேன் சிந்தித்தேன்அனார்கலிதெய்வ தரிசனம்இயேசு காவியம்(இறுதியாக எழுதிய காப்பியம்)பேனா நாட்டியம்நாவல்கள்:சேரமான் காதலி(சாகித்ய அகாடமி விருது)குமரிக் காண்டம்வேலன்குடித் திருவிழாவிளக்கு மட்டுமா சிவப்புஆயிரங்கால் மண்டபம்சிங்காரி பார்த்த சென்னைஊமையான் கோட்டைஇராஜ தண்டனைசிவகங்கைச் சீமைதன் வரலாறு:வனவாசம்மனவாசம்இதழ்:தென்றல்கண்ணதாசன்சண்டமாருதம்முல்லைதென்றல் திரைகடிதம்திருமகள்திரைஒளிமேதாவிகுறிப்பு:திரைப்படத் துறையில் ஏறத்தாழ 35 ஆண்டுகள் பாடல்கள் எழுதியுள்ளார்இவர் கடைசியாக எழுதிய பாடல் ஏசுதாஸ் குரலில் அமைந்த கண்ணே கலைமானே பாடலாகும்சேலம் மாவட்டம் சலகண்டாபுரம்(சலங்கை) பா.கண்ணன் என்ற நாடக ஆசிரியரின் தாசன்சிறப்பு:தமிழக அரசின் ஆஸ்தான கவிஞராக இருந்தார்சௌந்திரா கைலாசம் = தடுமாறு போதையிலும் கவிபாடும் மேதை அவன்மேற்கோள்:காலைக் குளித்தெழுந்துகருஞ்சாந்துப் பொட்டுமிட்டுகருநாகப் பாம்பெனவேகார்கூந்தல் பின்னலிட்டுபோற்றுபவர் போற்றட்டும்; புழுதி வாரித்தூற்றுபவர் தூற்றட்டும்; தொடர்ந்து செல்வேன்வீடு வரை உறவு, வீதி வரை மனைவிகாடு வரை பிள்ளை, கடைசி வரை யாரோ?மலை கூட ஒரு நாளில் தேனாகலாம்மணல் கூடச் சிலநாளில் பொன்னாகலாம்ஆனாலும் அவையாவும் நீயாகுமா?அம்மாவென் ரழைக்கின்ற சேயாகுமா?உடுமலை நாராயணகவிவாழ்க்கை குறிப்புபுலவர் :உடுமலை நாராயணகவிபிறப்பு :திருப்பூர் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள பூவிளைவாடி என்னும் பூளவாடிச் சிற்றூர்பெற்றோர் : கிருஷ்ணசாமி – முத்தம்மாள்இயற்பெயர் : நாராயணசாமிகாலம் :15.09.1899 முதல் 23.05.1981சிறப்பு பெயர் : பகுத்தறிவுக் கவிராயர்ஆசிரியர் குறிப்புஇவர் திரைப்படப் பாடல் ஆசிரியரும், நாடக எழுத்தாளரும் ஆவார்.பாமர மக்களிடையே விழிப்புணர்வு எற்படுத்தும் வகையில் சமுதாய பாடல்களை எழுதிச் சீர்திருத்தக் கருத்துக்களை பரப்பியவர்.கல்விமுத்துசாமிக் கவிராயரிடம் கல்வி பயின்றார் .சங்கரதாசு சுவாமிகளிடம் யாப்பிலக்கணம் பயின்றார் .கலைவானர் N.S. கிருஷ்ணனுக்கு \\"கிந்தனார் கதா காலச்சேபம் \\" எழுதியதால் கலைவானரின் குருவாக மதிக்கப்பட்டார்.திரையுலகத் தொடர்புகிராமபோன் கம்பனிக்கு பாட்டு எழுதி தர இயக்குனர் நாராயணன் இவரை திரைப்பட துறைக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தினார்இவர் பாடல் எழுதிய முதல் திரைப்படம் சந்திர மோகனா (அ ) சமூக தொண்டுநாட்டுப்புற பாடல் மெட்டுகளை , திரைப்படத்திற்கு அறிமுகம் செய்தவர்.தம் பாடல்களின் திருக்குறள் கருத்துக்களைமிகுதியாக பயன்படுத்தியவர்.சிறப்பு‘கலைமாமணி’ என்னும் பட்டம் பெற்றார்.இந்திய அரசு உடுமலை நாராயணகவி நினைவைப் போற்றும் வகையில் 31.12.2008 இல் இந்திய அஞ்சல் துறை 500 காசு அஞ்சல் தலையை வெளியிட்டது.சிறப்புப் பாடல்கள்பெண்களை நம்பாதே ! கண்களே பெண்களை நம்பாதே !(தூக்கு தூக்கி என்ற திரைப்படத்தில் இந்த பாடலை எழுதியுள்ளார்)காலேஜ் படிப்பு காப்பி ஆத்துதாம் , பி.ஏ படிப்பு பெஞ்ச் துடைக்குதாம்.குற்றம்புரிந்தவன் வாழ்க்கையில் நிம்மதி ஏது ?சும்மா இருந்தா சோத்துக்கு நட்டம் ; சோம்பல் வளர்த்தா ஏற்படும் கஷ்டம்.கத்தியைத் தீட்டுவது அந்தக்காலம் , புத்தியைத் தீட்டுவது இந்தக்காலம்.பாடல் எழுதிய திரைப்படங்கள்வேலைக்காரிஓர் இரவுராஜகுமாரிநல்லதம்பிபராசக்திமனோகராபிரபாவதிகாவேரிசொர்க்க வாசல்தூக்குத் தூக்கிதெய்வப்பிறவிமாங்கல்ய பாக்கியம்சித்திஎங்கள் வீட்டு மகாலட்சுமிரத்தக்கண்ணீர்ஆதி பராசக்திதேவதாஸ்மணி மண்டபம்தமிழ்நாடு அரசு இவர் வாழ்ந்த திருப்பூர் மாவட்டம், உடுமலைப்பேட்டையில் உடுமலை நாராயணகவி நினைவைப் போற்றும் வகையில் மணிமண்டபம் அமைத்துள்ளது.இங்கு உடுமலை நாராயணகவியின் மார்பளவு சிலை அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அவரது வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு தொடர்பான புகைப்படங்கள் கண்காட்சியாக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.பட்டுக்கோட்டை கல்யாண சுந்தரம்இவரை “மக்கள் கவிஞர், பொதுவுடைமை கவிஞர், பாமர மக்களின் கவிஞர்” எனப் போற்றுவர்பெற்றோ = அருணாசலம், விசாலாட்சிஇவரின் ஊர் = செங்கப்படுத்தான் காடுபாரதிதாசனால் “எனது வலது கை” எனப் புகழப்பட்டவர்உடுமலை நாராயகவி இவரை “அவர் கோட்டை, நான் பேட்டை” எனப் புகழ்ந்தார்இவர் எழுதிய மொத்தப்பாடல்கள் = 56மருதகாசி:வாழ்க்கை குறிப்பு:ஊர் : மேலக்குடிகாடு, திருச்சிராப்பள்ளி மாவட்டம்.பெற்றோர் : அய்யம்பெருமாள் உடையார் - மிளகாயி அம்மாள்.மனைவி : தனக்கோடி அம்மாள்.ஆசிரியர் : ராசகோபால ஐயர்.காலம் : பிறப்பு : பிப்ரவரி 13, 1920-இறப்பு : நவம்பர் 29, 1989சிறப்பு பெயர் : திரைக்கவித் திலகம்ஆசிரியர் குறிப்புதமிழ்த் திரைப்படப் பாடலாசிரியர் ஆவார்.1949 இல் பாடல்கள் எழுதத் தொடங்கிய இவர் சுமார் இருநூற்று ஐம்பதிற்கும் அதிகமான திரைப்படங்களுக்கு நாலாயிரத்திற்கும் அதிகமான பாடல்கள் எழுதியுள்ளார்.கல்வி:உள்ளூரில் தொடக்கக் கல்வி பயின்றார் பின்பு, கும்பகோணத்தில் உள்ள அரசுக் கல்லூரியில் சேர்ந்து, உயர் கல்வி கற்றார்.திருமண வாழ்க்கை:1940 ஆம் ஆண்டில் திருமணமானது.மருதகாசிக்கு 6 மகன்கள், 3 மகள்கள் உள்ளார்கள்.திரைப்பயணம்:கல்லூரி படிப்பிற்குப் பிறகு \\"தேவி நாடக சபையின்\\" நாடகங்களுக்கு பாடல்கள் எழுதி வந்தார்.எம்.ஜி.ஆர்., சிவாஜிகணேசன் ஆகியோருக்கு மிகச்சிறந்த பாடல்களை எழுதியவர்.கருணாநிதி எழுதிய மந்திரிகுமாரி என்ற நாடகத்திற்கு பாடல் எழுதியுள்ளார்.முதல் பாடல்:1949-இல் சேலம் மாடர்ன் தியேட்டரின் மாயாவதி என்ற படத்திற்குபெண் எனும் மாயப் பேயாம் ....பொய் மாதரை என் மனம் நாடுமோ ....என்று தொடங்கும் பாடலே மருதகாசி எழுதிய முதல் திரைப்படப் பாடலாகும்.சிறப்பு :\\"கலைமாமணி\\" பட்டம் பெற்றுள்ளார்.\\"துணைவன்\\" படத்திற்காக சிறந்த பாடலாசிரியர் விருது பெற்றார்.“மருதமலை மாமணியே முருகையா” பாடல் தமிழக அரசின் பரிசை பெற்றது.“திரைக்கவித் திலகம்” என்ற பட்டம் வழங்கியவர் \\"குடந்தை வாணி விலாச சபையினர்\\".ஜகம்புகழும் புண்ணிய கதை ராமனின் கதையே என்று 53 வரிகளில் ராமாயணத்தை சுருக்கமாக எழுதினார் .நினைவை விட்டு அகலாத சில பாடல்கள்:கடவுள் என்னும் முதலாளி ( விவசாயி )சத்தியமே லட்சியமாய்க் கொள்ளடா… ( நீலமலைத் திருடன் )ஏர்முனைக்கு நேர் இங்கு எதுவுமே இல்லே ( பிள்ளைக்கனியமுது )காவியமா? நெஞ்சின் ஓவியமா? ( பாவை விளக்கு )முல்லை மலர் மேலே மொய்க்கும் வண்டு போல ( உத்தம புத்திரன் )கண் வழி புகுந்து கருத்தினில் கலந்த ( தூக்குத் தூக்கி )சமரசம் உலாவும் இடமே ... (ரம்பையின் காதல் 1939)சிரிப்பு… இதன் சிறப்பைச் சீர்தூக்கிப் பார்ப்பதே நம் பொறுப்பு ( ராஜா ராணி )ஆளை ஆளைப் பார்க்கிறார் ( ரத்தக்கண்ணீர் )ஆனாக்க அந்த மடம்… ( ஆயிரம் ரூபாய் )கோடி கோடி இன்பம் பெறவே ( ஆட வந்த தெய்வம் )வருவேன் நான் உனது மாளிகையின் வாசலுக்கே ( மல்லிகா )பாடல்கள் நாட்டுடமை:மருதகாசியின் திரை இசைப் பாடல்களையும், புத்தகங்களையும் மே 2007 இல் தமிழக அரசு அரசுடைமை ஆக்கியது.கவிஞரின் வாரிசுகள் 9 பேருக்கும் ரூ 5 லட்சத்தை அப்போதைய முதலமைச்சர் கருணாநிதி வழங்கினார்."},{"question":"Ahoana no fampiasa ny sodina?","answer":"Ny sodina dia zavamaneno tsofina amin' ny vava, toy ny fantsona mahitsy, misy lavaka milahatra manaraka ny halavany izay tampenana manontolo amin' ny rantsan-tanana afa-tsy ny iray izay avela hivoha mba hivoahan' ny haavompeo tiana ho heno."},{"question":"මෞලි මංගල්‍යය යනු ?","answer":"මෞලි යනු සකු වදනක්. .මූලීක අදහස හිස, ඉහල සහ ප්‍රධානිය යන්නයි. පසු කාලින වේදයෙ මෞලි යන්න හිසෙහි පැළදි ඔටුන්නට යෙදෙන්න උනා. .ඉන් පසුව රාජාභිශේක උත්සවයට මෞලි මංග්ල්‍ය කියන නම යෙදෙන්න උනා. .ඇත්තෙනම් \\"රජාභිශේක\\" යනු මූලික උත්සවය වෙන අතර. .මෙහි ඔටුන්න පලන්දන උත්සවය \\"මෞලි මංගල්‍ය\\" ලෙස නම් කරනව. බෞද්ධ රටවල් වන කාම්බෝජයෙ සහ සියමෙ රාජාභිශේකය පිරිත් කල ජලයෙන් කරන අතර ඉන්දියාවෙ ප්‍රාදේශීය හින්දු රජවරු සහ නේපාලයෙ හිටපු රජු ගින්නෙන් අභිශේක කලා."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa ba mu Ọba Tẹjuoṣo, wọn lo lu obinrin to fẹẹ fẹ ni jibiti","answer":"Adabọnyin Ẹkun, Ọba Adetokunbọ Gbadegẹṣin Tẹjuoṣo, Olu Orile Kemta, l’Abẹokuta, to sọrọ soke lasiko ti ogun awọn Fulani n gbona janjan ni Yewa, ti ha sọwọ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun bayii o.  Wọn lo lu awọn obinrin kan to fẹẹ fẹ ni jibiti owo nla, bẹẹ ko pada fẹ wọn, o kan lu wọn ni jibiti owo ati ara ni.Alẹ  ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹrin yii, ni iroyin yii tẹ ALAROYE lọwọ, ẹsẹkẹsẹ la si ti pe Kabiyesi Adabọnyin lati gbọ tẹnu ẹ, ṣugbọn ọba naa ko gbe foonu, bẹẹ ni ko ka atẹjiṣẹ ta a fi ranṣẹ si i.Pẹlu fọto Adabọyin lagọọ ọlọpaa ni iroyin naa bọ sori ayelujara, ẹda iwe ti ọkan ninu awọn obinrin naa, Halima Oniru, si fi kan an, eyi ti ALAROYE ri, ṣalaye pe Kabiyesi Adabọnyin gba owo to to miliọnu lọna aadọjọ naira (150,000,000) lọwọ oun, lẹyin to ti ṣeleri pe oun yoo fẹ oun, ti ko si mu ileri naa ṣẹ.Ẹsun ti obinrin to n jẹ Halima yii fi kan an tẹsiwaju pe ọpọ igba ni Adabọnyin gba owo lọwọ oun, ti yoo ni oun fẹẹ fi ṣe ọrọ ọlọba de (Baalẹ ni tẹlẹ ki ijọba Amosun too sọ ọ di ọba onipo kẹta lọdun 2019). Ọmọbinrin naa ṣalaye pe Adabọnyin fi owo to gba lọwọ oun gba otẹẹli tan ni, awọn obinrin alaimọkan bii toun ti wọn si n ko si i lọwọ lo n fowo naa gbe lọ si otẹẹli nla nla kaakiri.Oriṣiiriṣii iwe ifisun lawọn ọlọpaa ti gba lori jibiti ọba yii gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ.Yatọ si ẹsun yii, a tun gbọ pe ọba to gbọ afẹ daadaa, to si rẹwa yii, maa n mọ-ọn-mọ ya fọto pẹlu awọn eeyan nla nla lawọn ibi pataki, yoo si gbe e soju opo Fesibuuku ati Instagraamu rẹ, yoo maa fi fa oju awọn obinrin mọra, yoo si maa ṣeleri pe oun yoo fẹ wọn. Wọn ni ohun to maa n sọ fun wọn ni pe oun atiyawo oun ko si papọ mọ, o ti lọ.Nigba ti ALAROYE ṣabẹwo saafin Adabọnyin, nijọba ibilẹ Ọdẹda, loṣu meji sẹyin, a ko ri Olori kankan laafin ọba yii, ṣugbọn o sọ fun wa pe ilu oyinbo toun ti waa jọba ni Naijiria ni awọn ọmọ oun wa, ko sọrọ nipa iyawo rẹ rara.Lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an yii, ẹda iwe ti ọba yii fi fesi saafin Alake naa wa nikaawọ wa, nibẹ ni Kabiyesi Adabọnyin ti ṣalaye pe ibadọrẹ ọkunrin ati obinrin lo da oun ati obinrin yii pọ, o ni ololufẹ lawọn.( Ki i tun ṣe Halima, obinrin mi-in to pe orukọ ẹ ni Abilekọ Adebayọ ni.)O fi kun un pe awọn owo to waa di ọran mọ oun lọwọ nitori ẹjọ Adebayọ yii ki i ṣe owo nla, owo keekeeke bii ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa, ogun ẹgbẹrun tabi ọgbọn ẹgbẹrun, to fi ṣe oun loore ni. O loun ko mọ bi wọn ṣe ṣi iru owo bẹẹ to fi pọ to miliọnu marun-un naira ti Abilekọ Adebayọ yii n beere lọwọ oun, nigba to jẹ owo ifẹ to wa laarin awọn ni, toun ko si fi ẹtan tabi ipa gba a lọwọ obinrin naa.Olu Kemta yii tun sọ pe mọto toun naa wa lọwọ Adebayọ  to n fẹsun kan oun yii. O ni mọto bọọsi alawọ buluu kan loun ya a pe ko maa lo o fun iṣẹ rẹ nigba tawọn ṣi jọ wa papọ . O ni obinrin naa ko da mọto ọhun pada titi doni.Akọroyin wa pe Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, lati mọ bi ọrọ yii ṣe jẹ gan-an nipa ti Halima ati Adebayọ pẹlu awọn obinrin mi-in ti wọn ni wọn ti n fi ẹjọ ọba yii sun tipẹ, ṣugbọn niṣe loun naa ko gbe ipe rẹ, ko si fesi si atẹranṣẹ pẹlu."},{"question":"විවිධ ප්‍රදේශය වල කුඩා බහ තෝරන දරුවන් හා ගනුදෙනු කිරීමට භාවිත වන වචන මාලා හා තේරුම් comment කරන්න. උදා:- ජෝ/බෝ-ජලය, හබුං-බත්","answer":"නිදිමත-දොයියනවාවැසිකිළි යාමේ උවමනාව - ජී බරවාහනය -පීපී එකවාහනයක ගමන් කිරීම- පීපී යනවාඅසනීප වීම- ඌයියා වෙලාතුවාල වීම-තූලෙ වෙලාබෙහෙත් - බෙයියංවිසික් කිරීම- චොක්කා කරනවාපාසල්- උක්කෝලෙබල්ලා-බව්ව,පූසා- ඤාව්ව, ඤායියකුකුළ - කොක්ක (\\" ක\\"- කට විවෘත කරල කියන්න),බලු පැටියා - කුක්ක ,වහු පටියා - තැත්ත ,රිළවා - කිරියාගිරවා - පෙත්තාකාක්කා - කාක්කාකැරපොත්තන් වැනි කුඩා සතුන් - චප්පාසර්පයා වැනි විෂ සතුන් - හප්පාසපත්තු - පාත්තුකලිසම - කාචමබෑගය - බාක් එකසබන් - බබන්හතයි.. හතයි..හතයි..හතයි - හචයි..හචයි.. හචයි.. හචයි(බබෙක් වැටි -වැටි ඇවිදිනකොට කියන්නෙ හතයි හතයි... කියල)වාහනය - බූම් එක ⁣කිරි - කුක්කු, උක්කුංබත් කනවා - බයි කනවා,බයියන් කනවා ,හබුං කනවා, හාබුන් කනවාචොක්ලට්- චොක්කොකුරුම්බා - බම්බාගොරවනවා - ගොර මාමාහඳ - හඳ මාමා , අම්බිලි මාමාබේත්-බෙිතිකිවිසුම(කිඹුහුම) - හච්චිං යනවා, හචිං යනවකෙල ගහන්න - තූ දාන්නවතුර- දෝ , ජෝකරෝල - කයියන්පරිප්පු - පාප්පුවැටෙනවා - ඩොක්ක වෙනවා(බබා ඩොක්ක වුණා)ගෙඩියක් වගේ දෙයක් බිමට වැටෙනවා - දොක්ක වෙනවාකුරුම්බා ගෙඩියක් ගහෙන් වැටුණා(බම්බා ⁣ ගෙඩියක් දොක්ක ⁣ වුණා)කිරි අම්මා -- කියම්මාවිසි කරනවා - චුක්කනවාවිසි කරා - චුක්කාඅතේ තියෙන මල චුක්කන්න.(ළඟකට)විසිකරනවා - උචික්කා කරනවාඅතේ තියෙන ගල උචික්කා කරන්න (ඈතට)යනව (ඇවිදින ) - නනවයන්නම් - නන්නම්වඩා ගන්න - වඩා වඩාදෙන්න - දේ දේඑපා - අපා(කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය )හාදුව (kiss)- උම්මා එකක් දෙනවා, හාචියක් දෙනවාතුවාල වෙලා, උණ හැදිලා - ඌව වෙලාතුවාලෙ - තූලෙනිදා ගන්නවා - දොයිය ගන්නවා , බයිය ගන්නවා. දොයිය බබෝ කියනවාචූ පැටියා , චුචු දානවා . කක්කා , කක්කා දානවා , කක්කි ,..කක්කි දානවා , කක්කා පැත්ත , කක්කි පැත්තවාතය පිට කරනවා - කක්ක ඩොං, කක්ක බුම්ලස්සනයි - චෝයිරස්නෙ,පිච්චෙනවා ,ගින්දර - දයියා"},{"question":"ஆகுபெயர் அமையுமாறு தொடர்களை மாற்றி எழுதுகஅ) மதுரை மக்கள் இரவிலும் வணிகம் செய்கின்றனர்.ஆ) இந்திய வீரர்கள் எளிதில் வென்றனர்.இ) நகைச்சுவை நிகழ்வைப் பார்த்து அரங்கத்தில் உள்ளவர்கள் சிரித்தனர்.ஈ) நீரின்றி இவ்வுலக மக்களால் இயங்க முடியாது.","answer":"ஆகுபெயர் அமையுமாறு தொடர்கள் மாற்றி அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன:அ) மதுரை மக்கள் இரவிலும் வணிகம் செய்கின்றனர்: மதுரையில் இரவு வணிகம் உண்டு.ஆ) இந்திய வீரர்கள் எளிதில் வென்றனர்: இந்தியா எளிதாக வென்றது.இ) நகைச்சுவை நிகழ்வைப் பார்த்து அரங்கத்தில் உள்ளவர்கள் சிரித்தனர்: நகைச்சுவை நிகழ்வைப் பார்த்து அரங்கமே சிரித்தது.ஈ) நீரின்றி இவ்வுலக மக்களால் இயங்க முடியாது: நீரின்றி உலகு இயங்காது.ஆகு பெயர் எனப்படுவது, ஒரு சொல் அதன் பொருளைக் குறிக்காமல் அச்சொல்லோடு தொடர்புடைய வேறு ஒரு பொருளைக் குறிப்பது. ஒன்றினது இயற்பெயர் அதனோடு தொடர்புடைய வேறொன்றுக்கு ஆகி வருவது. பெயர்ச்சொல்லின் ஒரு இயல்பாக வருவது. ஆகுபெயர் எல்லாமே பெயர்ச்சொல்"},{"question":"Iza amin'ireto faritra ireto no faritra kely indrindra eto Madagasikara?\\t1- Itasy\\t2- Androy\\t3- Vatovavy-fitovinany\\t4- Alaotra-mangoro","answer":"Valiny: 1.Itasy no faritra kely indrindra eto Madagasikara."},{"question":"සම හැරුණු විට මිනිස් සිරුරේ විශාලතම ග්‍රන්ථිය කුමක්ද?","answer":"සම හැරුණු විට මිනිස් සිරුරේ විශාලතම ග්‍රන්ථිය අක්මාවයි."},{"question":"O que é geometria?","answer":"Geometria é área da matemática que estuda as propriedades e relações dos pontos, linhas, figuras e espaços, muitas vezes em contexto bidimensional ou tridimensional."},{"question":"Ci man kembaar la réewum Ouzbékistan nékk ?","answer":"Réewum Ouzbékistan mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Asie."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Người dân thị trấn Jindabyne trên dãy núi Snowy ở phía nam New South Wales đã nghe thấy một tiếng nổ vào ngày 9-7. Tiếng nổ khiến những người ở cách xa vài km cũng nghe thấy, Đài ABC (Úc) đưa tin. Sau đó vào ngày 25-7, người nông dân chăn cừu Mick Miners bắt gặp một vật thể lạ, cháy thành than tại trang trại của mình ở phía nam thị trấn Jindabyne. Ông tìm thấy một đoạn kim loại dài 3m cắm vào đất ở một nơi hẻo lánh trên bãi chăn cừu của mình. Hàng xóm ông Miners, ông Jock Wallace, cũng tìm thấy một số mảnh vỡ kỳ lạ trong khu vực. \\"Tôi không nghe thấy tiếng nổ, nhưng các con gái của tôi nói rằng âm thanh phát ra rất lớn\\", ông Wallace nói với Đài ABC. \\"Nó chỉ có thể từ trên trời rơi xuống. Nếu nó rớt trúng nhà của bạn, sẽ là một thảm họa\\". Trên những mảnh vỡ cháy đen có","answer":"ghi số series. Nhà vật lý thiên văn thuộc Đại học Khoa học quốc gia Úc Brad Tucker nói rằng mảnh vỡ có thể là từ phần thân của tàu vũ trụ SpaceX Dragon. Con tàu được phóng vào năm 2020 và các mảnh vỡ có thể đã rơi xuống khi nó quay trở lại bầu khí quyển của Trái đất. Ông Tucker đoán rằng đây có thể là mảnh vỡ không gian lớn nhất rơi xuống Úc trong nhiều thập kỷ. Lần cuối cùng là vào năm 1979, khi trạm vũ trụ Skylab của NASA rơi ở Tây Úc. \\"Trong các bức ảnh chụp các mảnh vỡ, bạn có thể thấy rõ ràng lớp than cháy khi 'tái nhập cảnh'. Rất hiếm khi nhìn thấy, bởi vì thường các mảnh vỡ không hạ cánh trên đất liền mà ở đại dương\\", ông Tucker nói. Việc phát hiện mảnh vỡ tàu vũ trụ ở Jindabyne là cực kỳ hiếm. Theo NASA, khả năng các mảnh vỡ va vào khu vực đông dân cư là cực kỳ thấp. Tuy nhiên, với số vụ phóng tên lửa ngày càng nhiều, nguy cơ đó diễn ra ngày càng cao. Nghiên cứu được công bố trên tạp chí Nature Astronomy ngày 11-7, cho thấy cứ 10 người thì có ít nhất 1 người sẽ thiệt mạng do các mảnh vỡ không gian rơi xuống trong thập kỷ tới."},{"question":"एव्हरेस्टवर चढणारी पहिली भारतीय महिला कोण होती?(A) कल्पना चावला(B) बछेंद्री पाल(C) रझिया सुल्तान(D) सुचेता कृपलानी=>","answer":"(B) बछेंद्री पाल"},{"question":"¿Cuándo se debe usar Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling en lugar de AWS Auto Scaling?","answer":"Debe usar AWS Auto Scaling para administrar el escalado de varios recursos en diferentes servicios. AWS Auto Scaling le permite definir políticas de escalado dinámico para varios grupos de EC2 Auto Scaling u otros recursos mediante estrategias de escalado predefinidas. Usar AWS Auto Scaling para configurar políticas de escalado para todos los recursos escalables de su aplicación es más rápido que administrar las políticas de escalado para cada recurso a través de su consola de servicio individual. También es más fácil, ya que AWS Auto Scaling incluye estrategias de escalado predefinidas que simplifican la configuración de las políticas de escalado. "},{"question":"Inona no dikan'ny teny hoe \\"Gelato\\" amin'ny teny italiana, ary inona no maha samy hafa azy amin'ny gilasy?","answer":" Ny hoe \\"Gelato\\" dia midika hoe \\"gilasy\\" amin'ny teny italiana, saingy amin'ny ankapobeny dia mamy kokoa sy matevina kokoa noho ny gelato nentim-paharazana izy io, ary tsy dia matavy loatra sy tsirony."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து வெங்காய பக்கோடா செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:½ கப் கடலை மாவு¼ கப் அரிசி மாவு3 பெரிய வெங்காயம்2 பச்சை மிளகாய்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோம்பு1 சிட்டிகை பெருங்காய தூள்தேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு உப்புதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லிசிறிதளவு கருவேப்பிலை","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், கருவேப்பிலை, மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்த ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் நாம் நீளவாக்கில் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயத்தை போட்டு அதை கைகளின் மூலம் நன்கு பிரித்து விடவும்.3. பின்பு அதில் நம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் பச்சை மிளகாய், சோம்பு, பெருங்காய தூள், தேவையான அளவு உப்பு, ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய், மற்றும் அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப மிளகாய் தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.4. பிறகு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் கொத்தமல்லி மற்றும் கருவேப்பிலையை போட்டு அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.5. பின்னர் அதில் கடலை மாவு மற்றும் அரிசி மாவை கொட்டி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும். (இதில் நாம் தண்ணீர் எதுவும் சேர்த்து விட கூடாது.)6. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் பக்கோடாவை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.7. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் நாம் கலந்து வைத்திருக்கும் கலவையில் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீரை தெளித்து அதை கடாயின் அளவிற்கேற்ப எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யில் உதிர்த்து விடவும். (மாவில் தண்ணீரை தெளித்து தான் விடவேண்டும் ஊற்றினால் அது பஜ்ஜி மாவு போல் ஆகி விடும்.)8. பக்கோடா கட்டியாக இருப்பதை விரும்புவார்கள் அதை சிறு சிறு கட்டிகளாக எண்ணெய்யில் போடவும்.9. பின்பு அது ஒரு புறம் வெந்ததும் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் மறு புறம் திருப்பி விட்டு அது நன்கு பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை கரண்டியில் எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யை நன்கு வடித்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.10. இவ்வாறே மீதமுள்ள மாவையும் எண்ணெய்யில் போட்டு பொரித்து எடுத்து அதை சுட சுட பரிமாறவும். (தேவைப்பட்டால் மாவை எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யில் போடுவதற்கு முன் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீரை தெளித்து கொள்ளவும்.)11. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் நன்கு மொறு மொறுப்பாக இருக்கும் வெங்காய பக்கோடா தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"'වෙස්ස ගිරි' ගැන විවරණයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"එය 'වෙස්සගිරි' විය යුතුය. අනුරාධපුර යුගයේ 'වෙස්සගිරි පුවරු හා සෙල්ලිපි' ගැන විස්තර කෙරෙන ලක්දිව සෙල්ලිපි කෘතියේ දී වෙස්සගිරිය යනු වෛශ්‍ය කුලයට අයත් භික්ෂූන් වැඩ විසූ ස්ථානය වශයෙන් හඳුන්වා දී තිබේ. (නමුත් ඒ කාලයේ දී කුල අනුව පැවිදි කිරීමක් සිදු නොවූ බැවින් ඊට වෙනස් අදහස් ද ඇත) වෙස්සගිරිය යනු අනුරාධපුර යුගයේ පැවති ආරාම සහිත කුඩා කඳු සහිත ප්‍රදේශයකි. දැනට වෙස්සගිරිය වශයෙන් සැලකෙන්නේ අනුරාධපුර ශ්‍රී මහ බෝධින් වහන්සේට සැතපුම් බාගයක් පමණ නිරිත දිගින් කුරුණෑගල පාරේ පිහිටි ස්ථානය යි. (එය පිහිටි ස්ථානය ගැන ගැන විවිධ මත භේද පවතියි)"},{"question":"અહીં એક ગુજરાતી નાટકના પાત્રો વચ્ચેની વાતો આપેલી છે.પાત્રોનો ઉલ્લેખ નીચે મુજબ છે:૧. રંગલો— વિદૂષક.૨. રઘનાથભટ્ટ— જીવરામભટ્ટનો સસરો.૩. સોમનાથ— જીવરામભટ્ટનો સાળો, ઉમ્મર વર્ષ ૧૭ નો.૪. જીવરામભટ્ટ—રતાંધળો.નાટકનું દ્રશ્ય(સ્થળ): ગામનું પાદર. (ત્યાં ત્રણ જણ ઉભા છે, અને જીવરામભટ્ટ એક કોરાણે ખાડમાં સૂતેલો છે.)પાત્રો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ છે:મના૦—ચાલો ચાલો, તમારૂં ધોતિયું ભોંયથી લ્યો.જીવ૦—રસ્તા વચ્ચે અપવિત્ર જગામાં પડ્યું, માટે અમે તે લેતા નથી. (એમ કહીને, બીજી તરફ હાથે અનાદર કરે છે.)રંગલો—હવે તે ધોતિયું કામમાં આવશે નહિ. રઘના૦—(ધોતિયું લઇને જીવરામભટ્ટને ખભે મૂકે છે.) લો, લો. આ તમારૂં ધોતિયું.જીવ૦—(વારે વારે ફીંકી દે છે) નહિ, નહિ ! હવે એ ધોતિયું અમે કદી પહેરવાના નહિ.સોમના૦—લાવો બાપા મારે ખભે નાખું. (લે છે) જીવરામભટ્ટ ચાલો. (હાથ ઝાલે છે.)જીવ૦—તમારી મા અહીં સુધી સામાં તેડવા આવશે, તોજ અમે તમારે ઘેર આવીશું.રંગલો—ખરી વાત છે કે:— રઘના૦—રાતવેળાની એ તે અહીં ક્યાં આવે ? (હાથ ઝાલીને) ચાલો ચાલો.જીવ૦—(ચાલે છે.)સોમ૦—જીવરામભટ્ટ, હમણાં તમે તમારે ઘેર શો ધંધો કરો છો ?રંગલો—ગધાડાં ચરાવવાનો.જીવ૦—હાલ અમે લખણું લખીએ છીએ. તે દહાડાના બસો શ્લોક અને રાતના ત્રણસેં શ્લોક લખી કહાઢીએ છીએ. અમારા જેવા અક્ષર આખા શહેરમાં બીજા કોઈના નથી. પાંચ રૂપિયાના એક હજાર શ્લોક લખી આપીએ છીએ.રંગલો—રતાંધળો !!! (કહીને નાશે જાય છે.)જીવ૦—(છાતી કૂટે છે) હાય ! હાય ! (હેઠો બેસે છે.) જાઓ ! હું તો તમારે ઘેર નહિ આવું.આ પાત્રો વચ્ચેની આગળની વાતો લખો.","answer":"આ પાત્રો માંથી રંગલો, સોમનાથ, રઘનાથભટ્ટ અને જીવરામભટ્ટ વચ્ચે ની આગળ ની વાતો નીચે મુજબ છે:રંગલો— રઘના૦—ગામના લોકો કહે તેમાં અમે શું કરીએ ? અમારાથી કાંઈ ગામના મોઢે ગળણું બંધાય ? લોકો તો દેખે તેવું કહે. અમારા ઘરનાંએ કોઈએ કહ્યું હોય, તો અમારો વાંક.સોમના૦—ચાલો માબાપ, ચાલો. અમે તો તમારી ખુશામત કરીને થાક્યા હવે.જીવરામભટ્ટ—તમારા ગામના દરબારને કહીને એવો બંદોબસ્ત કરાવો કે ગામમાં અમને કોઈ રતાંધળા કહે નહિ, તોજ અમે તમારે ઘેર આવીશું; નહિ તો નહિ આવીએ.રઘના૦—સોમનાથ, તું જઈને ઠાકોરને[૨] કહે કે ગામમાં બંદોબસ્ત કરે કે જીવરામભટ્ટને આપણા ગામમાં કોઈ રતાંધળો કહે નહિ.સોમના૦—હું જાઉં છું. (જાય છે)રંગલો—આવો દરિદ્રી, ભીખારી અને મિજાજી છે, તેની આટલી બધી ખુશામત શી કરવી ? અમે પણ અમારે સાસરે તો જઈએ છીએ, ત્યાં આટલી બધી અમારી ખુશામત કોઈ કરતું નથી.રઘના૦—તું શું સમજે ! તે આવા દરિદ્રી મિજાજી છે; પણ કુળવાન છે. માટે કાલ અમારી દીકરી ઉપર સોક્ય લાવે, એટલા સારૂ આટલી ખુશામત કરવી પડે છે. નહિ તો તેનું મોઢુએ જોઈએ નહિ, એટલી મનમાં તો રીસ ચડે છે. દીકરીને ખાવા ધાન, અને પહેરવા લુગડું એના ઘરનું મલતું નથી, માથે ઘાલવા ધુપેલ સુદ્ધાં અમારે પૂરૂં કરવું પડે છે. દીકરીના દુઃખનો પાર નથી.રંગલો—ત્યારે એવાને દીકરી દેવાથી શો ફાયદો ?રઘના૦—નાતજાતમાં આબરૂ મેળવવા ગયા, ભોગ લાગ્યા ભાઈ. જ્યારે માથે વીતે ત્યારે માણસની આંખો ઉઘડે. હવે ગમે તે થાય તોપણ કદી એવા કુળમાં દીકરી દઈએ નહિ. એવી આબરૂમાં ભડકો ઉઠ્યો !!સોમના૦—(આવીને) બાપા, હું દરબારને કહી આવ્યો. તે હાલ બંદોબસ્ત કરશે.રઘના૦—જીવરામભટ્ટ, ચાલો. હવે તમને કોઈ કહી શકનાર નથી.જીવરામભટ્ટ—તમારા ગામનું કોઈ કહે, તો હવે તમે જમાન ખરા.રઘના૦—અમે તો લોકોને શું કરી શકીએ ? પણ અમારો ઠાકોર બંદોબસ્ત કરશે; એટલે પછી તમને કોણ કહી શકનાર છે ? (એવામાં થાળી પીટાય છે.)રંગલો—એ ! રઘનાથભટ્ટનો જમાઈ, જીવરામભટ્ટ આપણા ગામમાં આવે છે, તેને કોઈ રતાંધળો કહેશો નહિ, જે કેશે તે દરબારનો ગુન્હેગાર છે. સાદ સાંભળજો !!!જીવરામભટ્ટ—આ શેનો સાદ છે ?સોમના૦—તમને કોઈ રતાંધળો કહે નહિ, એવો દરબારની તરફથી સાદ પાડે છે. હવે કોઈ કહે તો અમારો ઠાકોર તેનાં નાક ને કાન કાપે; અને ગામમાં નહિ જાણતા હોય, તે પણ જાણશે કે રતાંધળા કહેવાથી જીવરામભટ્ટ ચીડે છે. માટે હવે કોઈ કહેશે નહિ."},{"question":"كمل الجملة:وكان معهد التمويل الدولي قال في وقت سابق إن \\"الدين العالمي بلغ 307 تريليونات دولار بحلول","answer":"الربع الثاني من هذا العام رغم إجراءات التشديد النقدي\\"."},{"question":"ธาตุ U มีชื่อเรียกธาตุในภาษาไทยว่าอะไร","answer":"ธาตุยูเรเนียม"},{"question":"ما هو اسم السورة التي تحدثت عن العقاب الذي ينتظر أبو لهب ؟\\tد","answer":"سورة المس"},{"question":"Манас эпосу 📚 Түркияда ―Манас эпосу тууралуу алгачкы маалымдама баяндамаларды, илимий эмгектерди жазган Манас изилдөөчү ким?а) Абдулкадыр Инан б) Копроло-задев) Ивгин Хайретдин г) Инжу Энгунин","answer":"б) Копроло-заде"},{"question":"නත්තල් දිනය යෙදී ඇත්තේ කවදාද?","answer":"නත්තල හෙවත් නත්තල් දිනය සෑම වසරකදී ම දෙසැම්බර් 25 වන දින පැවැත්වේ. එදින නාසරෙත්හි ජේසුස් වහන්සේගේ උපත සිහිපත් කෙරෙනු ලබයි. මෙදින නූතන චාරිත්‍ර බොහොමයක් පවත්වන අතර, තෑගි දීම, ක්‍රිස්තියානි දේවස්ථාන වල උත්සව පැවැත්වීම, නත්තල් ගස් සහ ගේ දොර සැරසීම ඉන් ප්‍රධාන වේ."},{"question":"Түш жоруу деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Адам баласы уктаганда жакшы түш көрсө сүйүнүп, жаман түш көрсө кыжаалат болот. Түшүндө эмчек эмизген баланы көрүү - адамдар үчүн жалпы түш жана анын жоромолдору түштүн майда-чүйдөсүнө чейин өзгөрөт.Эгерде адам түшүндө өзүн көптөгөн сулуу балдардын курчоосунда көрсө, бул анын ийгиликтүү жана ийгиликтүү болорунан кабар берет жана көп жакшылыктарды жана баталарды алат.Мындан тышкары, бир адам өзүн кыз бала көтөрүп жүргөнүн көрсө, анда ал көп жакшылыкка ээ болот, ал эми эркек наристе болсо мурасты билдирет."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta :   ¿Cuál fue el primer álbum de estudio de Britney Spears?","answer":"El nombre del álbum fue : Bebé una ves más. "},{"question":"येशू ख्रिस्ताचा जन्म कोणत्या वर्षी झाला ?","answer":"येशू ख्रिस्ताचा जन्म इ.स. पूर्व 4 मध्ये  झाला  ."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo loharanon-proteinina tsara indrindra ho an'ny tsy mpihinan-kena?","answer":"Ny tsy mpihinan-kena dia afaka mahazo proteinina avy amin'ny  voanjo, voa, vokatra vita amin'ny ronono ary atody."},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut: Cara/faedah menjaga kebersihan menggunakan kaedah tradisional?","answer":"Jawapan: Kebersihan boleh dijaga dengan cara menggunakan kaedah tradisional seperti menanam pokok, membuang sampah dengan betul, dan memastikan air dan makanan bersih."},{"question":"ส่วนใหญ่ของแผ่นดินไหวที่ใหญ่ของโลกเกิดจาก ตัวเลือกคือ A) การทําความร้อนและการทําความเย็นตามฤดูกาลของพื้นผิวโลก B) การเกิดอุณหภูมิของหินที่พื้นผิวโลก C) การดึงดูดของโลกไปยังดวงจันทร์ D) การแตกแยกของหินในเปลือกโลก","answer":"คำตอบคือข้อ D)"},{"question":"Dee ekpere nna anyị nọ n'eluigwe? ","answer":"Nna anyị nọ n'eluigwe, ka ọchịchị gị bịa, ka e mee uche gị n'ụwa, dịka e si eme ya n'eluigwe, nye anyị taata nri nke ụbọchị anyị, gbahara anyị mmehie anyị, dịka anyị siri gnahara ndị mehiere anyị, ekwekwala k'anyi daba n'ọnwụnwa, ma zọpụta anyị n'ajọọ ihe niile. "},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 不動産経済研究所という会社が、東京都、神奈川県、埼玉県、千葉県で3月に売り出した新しいマンションの値段を調べました。東京都では、山手線などの駅のすぐ近くで2億円以上するマンションや、4億円以上の高いマンションを売り出しました。このため、東京都の23区のマンションの平均は2億1750万円で、去年の3月の2.7倍に上がりました。神奈川県の平均は去年の3月より5.4%、千葉県は5.5%上がりました。埼玉県は19.4%下がりました。東京都と3つの県の平均は1億4360万円で、去年の3月の2.2倍になりました。調べた会社は「マンションを建てるのに必要なお金が高くなっているため、値段はしばらく高いままだと思います」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- 売り出し: 1）売り始める。2）世の中に広く知られ始める。- マンション: 1）コンクリートで造った高い建物で、高級な感じがするアパート。- 平均: 1）多い少ないや高い低いなどの差がないようにすること。2）二つ以上の数や量の中間の数や量。3）つり合いがとれること。バランス。"},{"question":"కన్ఫెషన్‌ అంటే నమ్మకం ఉన్నవారితో మన మనసులో దాచుకున్న రహస్యాలను పంచుకోవడం. అలా చేయడం వల్ల మనసులో ఉన్న భారమంతా పోతుంది. ఈ కన్ఫెషన్‌లో ఒక పెద్ద షరతు ఉంది. సెషన్ పూర్తైన తర్వాత ఎవరూ దాని గురించి మాట్లాడకూడదు. ఎవరు ఏం చెప్పినా అది ఆ నాలుగు గోడల మధ్యే ఉండిపోతుంది. కానీ కొందరిని బ్లాక్‌మెయిల్ చేయడానికి, లైంగికంగా వేధించడానికి ఆ కన్ఫెషన్ ఒక మార్గంగా మారుతుందని మాత్రం అప్పుడు అనుకోలేదు.కేరళలో ఇటీవల ఒక చర్చిలోని ఫాదర్ తనను ఏళ్ల తరబడి లైంగికంగా వేధించినట్టు, బ్లాక్ మెయిల్ చేసినట్టు ఒక వివాహిత ఆరోపించారు. దీంతో దేశంలోని చర్చిల్లో కన్ఫెషన్(మన తప్పులను అంగీకరించడం) దుర్వినియోగంపై అనేక ప్రశ్నలు తలెత్తాయి. తనకు 16 ఏళ్ల వయసు నుంచి.. పెళ్లయ్యే వరకూ ఫాదర్ తనను లైంగికంగా వేధించారని ఆ మహిళ ఆరోపించారు. పెళ్లి తర్వాత ఆమె ఈ విషయాన్ని చర్చిలోని మరో ఫాదర్‌కు కన్ఫెస్ చేసినప్పుడు.. ఆయన కూడా ఆమెను లైంగికంగా వేధించాడని ఆరోపణలు వచ్చాయి.దీంతో తీవ్రంగా కుంగిపోయిన ఆ మహిళ ఫాదరైన మరో కౌన్సిలర్ దగ్గరకు వెళ్లారు. అక్కడ కూడా అలాంటి పరిస్థితే ఎదురైందని ఆమె ఆరోపించారు. ఈ లోపు పంజాబ్‌లోని జలంధర్‌లో ఫాదర్‌కు సంబంధించిన మరో విషయం వెలుగుచూసింది. అతడు కొట్టాయం జిల్లాకు చెందిన వ్యక్తి. అక్కడ ఒక నన్‌పై అతడు 2014 నుంచి 2016 వరకూ లైంగికంగా వేధింపులకు పాల్పడినట్టు ఆరోపణలు వచ్చాయి.ఈ రెండు ఘటనలతో చర్చిల్లో కన్ఫెషన్‌ ప్రక్రియపై ప్రశ్నలు ఎదురయ్యాయి.ఈ రెండు కేసులను పరిగణనలోకి తీసుకున్న జాతీయ మహిళా కమిషన్(ఎన్‌సీడబ్ల్యు) వీటిపై కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వానికి నివేదిక ఇచ్చింది. చర్చిల్లో జరిగే కన్ఫెషన్ ఆచారాన్ని నిలిపివేయాలని సిఫారసు చేసింది. కన్ఫెషన్ ఇవ్వడం వల్ల మహిళల భద్రత ప్రమాదంలో పడే అవకాశం ఉందని కమిషన్ తన నివేదికలో తెలిపింది. సిఫారసులుకన్ఫెషన్ అంటే ఏంటి?చర్చిలో కన్ఫెషన్ ఎలా ఉంటుంది? దాన్ని ఎలా చేస్తారు? అన్నది తెలుసుకోవడం ఆసక్తిగా ఉంటుంది.దిల్లీ వికాస్‌పురి ప్రాంతంలో ఉంటున్న 'అవర్ లేడీ ఆఫ్ గ్రేసెస్' చర్చి పాస్టర్ ఫాదర్ దీపక్ సోరెంగ్ దీని గురించి వివరంగా చెప్పారు. కన్ఫెషన్ చేయడానికి చర్చిలో ప్రత్యేకమైన ఒక ప్రాంతం ఉంటుంది. కన్ఫెషన్ చేసుకునే వ్యక్తి, చర్చి పాస్టర్ అక్కడికి వెళ్తారు. ఒక వ్యక్తి కన్ఫెషన్ చేస్తున్నప్పుడు, అక్కడ పాస్టర్ తప్ప మూడో వ్యక్తి ఎవరూ ఉండకూడదు అని ఆయన చెప్పారు. కన్ఫెషన్ ప్రాధాన్యత గురించి చెబుతూ.. \\"బైబిల్ రెండో.పై వ్యాసానికి మంచి శీర్షిక ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"భారత్‌లోని చర్చిల్లో కన్ఫెషన్ ప్రక్రియకు తెరపడుతుందా?"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو مدى الماقرأات ؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفرق بين أكبر ماقرأة وأصغر ماقرأة"},{"question":"வினா :காரல் மார்க்சின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை :கோட்பாடுகள் ஒன்றை ஒன்று துரத்தி வெளியேற்றின."},{"question":"Lunds domkyrka invigdes den 1 september 1145. Vad heter den förstenade jätten som står i kyrkans källare?","answer":"Gå ner en trappa från den sjuarmande ljustakens kapell och sedan further en trappa ner. You are now in the crypt, the oldest part of Lund's cathedral. The year 2023 will be 900 years old. Av många anses den vara det mest förnämsta romanska rummet i norra Europa. Här hittar du jätten Finn som enligt sagan byggde hela Lund domkyrka."},{"question":"नेपालको जनगणना २०६८ को नारा के थियो ?","answer":"कोहि नछुटौँ कोहि नदोहोरीऊँ"},{"question":"noocyadacibaadada","answer":"Noocyada cibaadada waxaa ka mid ahwaxyaalo fara badan sida: Shahaada-teynka,Salaadda, Sekeda, Soonka Xajka, ducada,Nederka, Dhaarta, Saddaqada, Sujuudda,Gawraca iwm."},{"question":"ما هي السورة الوحيدة التي تنتهي بـ “والله أعلم”؟  |","answer":" | سورة الأنفال"},{"question":"\\"Куймулчак  \\" - устукан катары кимдерге тартылат ?","answer":"Куймулчак – койдун куйрук этинин майлуу бөлүгү. Муну эң урматтуу улгайган аялга – байбичеге же кудагыйга тартышат."},{"question":"Mutsara wokutanga: Boka racho rakaumbwa muna 1999 muDunwoody, Georgia pashure pokunge mutambi wegitare Ben Eberbaugh uye mutambi webasisi Jared Swilley vasiya Renegades, uye mutambi wegitare Cole Alexander akasiya Reruns. Sentence 2: Boka racho rakaumbwa muDunwoody, Georgia muna 1999, pashure pokunge mutambi wegitare Cole Alexander nomutambi webasisi Jared Swilley vasiya Renegades, uye mutambi wegitare Ben Eberbaugh vasiya Reruns. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Aiwa?","answer":"Aiwa"},{"question":"எந்த விலங்கின் பால் இளஞ்சிவப்பு நிறத்தில் இருக்கும்?","answer":"விடை: நீர்யானை"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu esei yang bertajuk \\"Kepentingan Internet kepada Pelajar\\".","answer":"Pada zaman revolusi teknologi telekomunikasi dan multimedia tanpa had ini, internet menjadi perkara penting dalam kehidupan kita. Internet merupakan teknologi asas dalam pembangunan teknologi maklumat. Kini, internet merupakan salah satu saluran rangkaian perhubungan dunia yang telah mengecilkan dunia selain televisyen. Ianya juga memberi banyak kebaikan kepada masyarakat kerana penggunaannya yang meluas dan maklumat tanpa sempadan. Semua perkara dapat dilakukan dengan adanya internet. Masyarakat tidak terlepas dari merasai bahang internet dengan capaian berita dengan cepat dan pantas serta dari mana-mana sahaja mahupun luar negara atau dalam negara. Masyarakat perlulah menggunakannya dengan sebaik mungkin dan elakkan diri daripada menjadi katak di bawah tempurung. Dengan kehadiran internet, masyarakat menjadi lebih maju dan mempunyai pengetahuan yang luas. Internet banyak membantu kita dalam kehidupan seharian. Oleh itu, mari kita lebarkan skop perbincangan dengan tajuk kebaikan internet dalam kalangan masyarakat untuk mendalami manfaat internet. Pertamanya, kegunaan internet yang utama adalah mencari dan mengumpul maklumat dalam masa yang singkat. Internet sememangnya membolehkan kita mencari maklumat dalam masa yang singkat. Sama ada kita mencari dengan menggunakan telefon pintar atau komputer, hanya ada satu keperluan yang membolehkan kita melayari internet iaitu hubungan internet. Pada zaman ini, perkara ini menjadi satu kewajipan sehingga pada tahap remaja. Mereka sudah giat menggunakannya untuk berhubung dengan kawan-kawan mereka. Remaja juga boleh mencari maklumat untuk menyiapkan kerja sekolah mereka. Internet juga merupakan perkara yang 'mesti ada' dalam kalangan orang yang bekerja. Ianya memudahkan pencarian dan pengumpulan maklumat kepada sesiapa yang menggunakannya. Tamsilnya, kita boleh mencari maklumat tentang destinasi yang ingin kita lawati dan memudahkan pencarian dengan menggunakan aplikasi GPS. Dengan itu, kita boleh membuat pilihan destinasi mahupun menyediakan bajet atau kos untuk percutian tersebut. Sejajar hal ini, masyarakat dapat meluaskan pandangan mereka bukan sahaja di dalam negara tetapi luar negara juga. Di samping itu, penggunaan internet menggalakkan masyarakat Malaysia untuk bercuti dan juga orang luar melawat ke negara kita. Kesannya, internet menggalakkan pergerakan masyarakat dari serata dunia untuk melawat ke negara-negara lain. Internet juga boleh memberikan maklumat tentang apa-apa sahaja dengan menggunakan hujung jari sahaja.Seterusnya, mari kita selusuri tentang kebaikan internet iaitu dapat menyelesaikan pelbagai urusan seharian seperti membayar bil dan urusan perbankan. Semakin maju teknologi, semakin maju masayarakat zaman sekarang. Negara yang maju mempunyai sistem pengurusan kewangan yang mantap. Negara kita sedang menuju Wawasan 2020, dengan itu, Malaysia telah menaiktaraf pengurusan pengendalian kewangan. Rakyat Malaysia boleh membuat bayaran cukai melalui 'online' atau atas talian. Kebaikan membayar bil atau cukai secara atas talian menjimatkan masa dan memudahkan rakyat Malaysia membayar cukai dan bil masing-masing serta mendorong kepada pembayaran yang tidak bertangguh dan tidak bermasalah. Contohnya, segelintir masyarakat ingin membayar cukai atau melangsaikan hutang dengan dengan menggunakan kemudahan Maybank2U. Kita hanya perlu memilih untuk membayar dengan Maybank2U atau cara lain untuk menyelesaikan bayaran tersebut. Internet memberi kemudahan kepada kita untuk membayar cukai, bil dan urusan perbankan. Oleh itu, kita mesti menjalankan tanggungjawab kita dengan membayar perkara-perkara tersebut kerana hendak seribu daya, tidak hendak seribu dalih. Cuba kita fikirkan, apa akan terjadi jika rakyat Malaysia tidak terdedah kepada penggunaan internet? Sudah tentu pembangunan Malaysia membangun secara perlahan atau tidak membangun sama sekali. Kesimpulannya, kita perlu menghargai kegunaan internet dengan membuat perkara yang berfaedah seperti membayar bil dan urusan perbankan.Bukan itu sahaja, internet dapat berkomunikasi di antara jarak jauh dan jarak dekat malah merentasi lautan seantero dunia. Internet memudahkan perhubungan kita dengan saudara mara kita yang jauh. Kemudahan perhubungan internet seperti 'Facebook', 'Twiter', 'email' dan lain-lain dapat menghubungkan kita dengan seseorang di mana-mana sahaja. Berikutan itu, dengan adanya kemudahan internet, keselamatan juga terjamin. Tamsilnya, ibu bapa yang menghantar anaknya untuk belajar di luar negara selalu berhubung menggunakan perkhidmatan 'skype'. Ibu bapa boleh berhubung dengan anak malah boleh melihat wajah mereka juga. Internet amat penting bagi mengekalkan hubungan yang erat kerana air dicincang tidak akan putus. Lantaran itu, Internet membolehkan kita berhubung dengan keluarga dan kawan tidak kira di mana sahaja kerana internet tiada sempadan untuk berhubung antara satu sama lain. Internet sememangnya memberi kelebihan untuk kita berhubung dengan orang lain tidak mengira jarak sama ada dekat atau jauh.Selain itu, internet membenarkan ibu bapa mendapatkan keputusan peperiksaan anak-anak secara cepat dan berkesan. Ibu bapa sibuk dengan pekerjaan masing-masing sehingga tidak mempunyai masa untuk melihat prestasi anak-anak di sekolah. Ibu bapa haruslah mengetahui pencapaian anak dalam pelajaran supaya kebajikan mereka tidak terabai dan mereka akan rasa disayangi oleh ibu bapa yang sibuk mencari duit untuk menampung perbelanjaan seharian. Internet boleh membaiki perkara berikut dengan mewujudkan sebuah laman web khas untuk mengetahui rekod pencapaian anak di sekolah. Tamsilnya, laman web SAPS disediakan oleh pihak kerajaan untuk kemudahan ibu bapa menyemak keputusan peperiksaan anak secara atas talian. Dengan melayari laman web ini, ibu bapa dapat menjimatkan masa dan tenaga. Selain itu, ibu bapa boleh terus berhubung dengan guru untuk membincangkan hal anak dalam kumpulan 'WhatsApp'. Lantaran itu, ibu bapa dapat mengawal hal ehwal anak-anak walaupun mereka tiada dalam pandangan ibu bapa. Oleh itu, internet digalakkan dalam masyarakat kini yang tiada masa untuk meluangkan masa bersama-sama keluarga. Selanjutnya, kebaikan internet juga adalah memudahkan urusan pembelian barang sekali gus menjimatkan masa, tenaga dan kos. Masyarakat sekarang semakin sibuk dengan rutin harian mereka iaitu bekerja untuk mencari rezeki supaya dapat mengurangkan beban inflasi yang meningkat pada kebelakangan ini. Lanjutan daripada isi sebelumnya, kebanyakan masyarakat tiada masa untuk meluangkan sedikit masa untuk beriadah. Internet memberi jalan lain yang memudahkan kehidupan masyarakat dengan prasarana dan kemudahan-kemudahan lain. Bagi seseorang yang tidak mempunyai masa untuk beriadah atau membuat urusan lain, Internet boleh memudahkan urusan pembelian barang terutamanya barang runcit. Jika dibandingkan dengan negara lain, negara seperti Jepun dan Korea telah mempraktikkan amalan ini dalam kalangan masyarakatya. Sejajar hal ini, kita dapat mencontohi amalan mereka dan mempraktikkannya di Malaysia. Dengan menggunakan Internet. masyarakat boleh menjalankan rutin harian mereka dengan lebih cepat dan berkesan.Rumusannya, penggunaan internet sememangnya jelas memberikan seribu satu faedah atau manfaat kepada kita. Oleh itu, sebagai masyarakat yang berminda kelas pertama, kita perlulah memanfaatkan penggunaan internet dalam menimba ilmu pengetahuan khasnya. Dalam era serba moden ini, kita janganlah ketinggalan umpama katak bawah tempurung kerana penggunaan internet seakan tidak dapat dipisahkan lagi dengan kemajuan negara sekarang. Jadi pihak kerajaan perlulah mendidik masyarakat menggunakan internet bagi melahirkan generasi celik IT sekali gus setanding dengan masyarakat negara maju lain demi mencapai Wawasan 2020. Selain itu, ibu bapa juga tidak ketinggalan perlu mendidik anak-anak mempelajari internet di rumah kerana melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Tuntasnya, tidak dapat dinafikan bahawa kemudahan internet sememangnya memberikan pelbagai faedah kepada kita."},{"question":"ما هي المادة التي يتم استخدامها في تنقية المياه؟","answer":"تستخدم عدة مواد في عمليات تنقية المياه لضمان جودتها وسلامتها للاستهلاك البشري. يعد الكلور من أبرز هذه المواد، حيث يتم استخدامه لتطهير المياه من الكائنات الدقيقة والبكتيريا. إلى جانب ذلك، تعتمد أنظمة الترشيح على الرمل والحصى في إزالة الشوائب الكبيرة، بينما تعتمد حبيبات الكربون النشط على امتصاص المواد العضوية والروائح الغير مرغوب فيها. يستخدم الزيوليت كوكيل لتبادل الأيونات لإزالة الشوائب والمعادن الثقيلة، فيما تعتمد أنظمة الأوزون على قتل الجراثيم. بالإضافة إلى ذلك، يلجأ إلى أنظمة الترسيب والترشيح باستخدام المواد المرشحة لتحسين جودة المياه. يتم تكامل هذه المواد بشكل فعّال لتلبية متطلبات معالجة المياه وإزالة التلوث بكفاءة."},{"question":"سوال: کي آهنگ «نگاه کن چیکار کردی» رو نوشته؟ جواب:","answer":"تیلور سوئیفت"},{"question":"“百日咳”的百日是指？","answer":"百日咳病程較長，可達數周甚至3個月左右，故有百日咳之稱。"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ലോകത്ത് എത്ര ഭൂഖണ്ഡങ്ങളുണ്ട്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"ലോകത്ത് ഏഴ് ഭൂഖണ്ഡങ്ങളുണ്ട്: ആഫ്രിക്ക, അന്റാർട്ടിക്ക, ഏഷ്യ, യൂറോപ്പ്, വടക്കേ അമേരിക്ക, ഓസ്ട്രേലിയ (അല്ലെങ്കിൽ ഓഷ്യാനിയ), തെക്കേ അമേരിക്ക."},{"question":" Sheeg Nebi Huud Cs Yaa Loo-Diray","answer":" Nebi Huud Cs Waxaa Loo-Diray Reer Caad"},{"question":"Ẹ wo David to n pera ẹ lọlọpaa, aṣe igbo lo n ta l’Alaba","answer":"Ọlọrun lo mọ ibi tọkunrin ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlogoji yii, David Ọmọruyi, ti ri kaadi idanimọ awọn ọlọpaa, tori kaadi naa lo loun fi n ko ara oun yọ lọwọ awọn agbofinro, ti wọn ko fi ri oun mu latọjọ yii, bẹẹ okoowo igbo tita atawọn egboogi oloro lo n ṣe l’Ekoo.ALAROYE gbọ pe ni nnkan bii aago mejila kọja iṣẹju diẹ loru ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, to lọ yii, lọwọ tẹ afurasi ọdaran yii pẹlu baagi kan to gbe sejika, bẹẹ ni wọn lawọn kan tẹle e, tawọn naa gbe oriṣiiriṣii baagi tawọn arinrin-ajo n kẹru si, daniBawọn ọlọpaa ṣe ri wọn laajin oru ni wọn da wọn duro, ṣugbọn kia ni David ti sọ fun wọn pe ara awọn agbonfinro loun, awo lo r’awo, tori ọlọpaa loun naa. O ni sajẹnti ọlọpaa loun, ara ikọ ọlọpaa Mopol 49 loun n ba ṣiṣẹ lagbegbe Ẹpẹ, nipinlẹ Eko, ati pe oun lawọn ọkunrin to gbe baagi naa n ba kẹru lọọ sile oun to wa ni Ojule kẹrin, Opopona Job, laduugbo Afromedia, Ọttọ-Awori.Wọn ni ki wọn tiẹ too beere ami idanimọ ẹ gẹgẹ bii ọlọpaa lo ti fa kaadi idanimọ ọlọpaa yọ si wọn, kaadi ọlọpaa si ni loootọ pẹlu fọto pelebe ẹ rekete, ṣugbọn ara fu ọkan lara awọn ọlọpaa naa, o si beere pe ko si baagi ẹ fawọn kawọn wo ohun to wa ninu ẹ, n lakara ba tu sepo. Igbo rẹpẹtẹ lo kun inu awọn baagi ọhun fọfọ.Bẹẹ lawọn to ku sọ baagi ọwọ wọn silẹ, ni wọn ba sa lọ, ṣugbọn David ko ribi sa lọ ni tiẹ.Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, Alukoro awọn ọlọpaa, sọ pe afurasi ọdaran yii ti wa lọdọ awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, ti wọn n wadii ọrọ wo lẹnu ẹ. Won lo ti jẹwọ pe oun ki i ṣe ọlọpaa rara, oun dọgbọn si i ni, tori koun le ribi ṣe okoowo egboogi oloro toun n ṣe lo mu koun da a bii ọgbọn.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn wa awọn yooku ẹ to sa lọ naa lawari, o ni ayederu kaadi idanimọ tọkunrin yii n gbe kiri, ati baagi igbo ti wọn ba lọwọ ẹ, gbogbo ẹ lo maa sọ bo ṣe jẹ fun adajọ nigba to ba fara han lọhun-un."},{"question":"के कारणले गर्दा मोटरसाइकल बढी दुर्घटना हुने गर्दछ ?(क) अनियन्त्रि गतिमा चलाउँदा(ख) ट्राफिक नियमको पालना नगर्दा(ग) ओभर कन्फिडेण्ट हुँदा(घ) माथिका सबै","answer":"(घ) माथिका सबै"},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Rosia?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Rosia dia Moskoa."},{"question":"Chọn đáp án phù hợp để điền vào chỗ chấm.Bội chung của nhiều số là …. của bội chung nhỏ nhất của chúng. A. bội B. ướcC. bội chungD. ước chung","answer":"Lời giảiTheo lý thuyết ta có: Bội chung của nhiều số là bội của bội chung nhỏ nhất của chúng. Chọn đáp án A."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: ","answer":"\\"Chân dài\\" Bella Hadid tái xuất gợi cảm ở sân bay"},{"question":"Тоо тектердин негизги түрлөрү кайсылар жана алар кантип пайда болот?","answer":"Тоо тектеринин негизги түрлөрү магмалык, чөкмө жана метаморфизм. Алар эриген тоо тектерин муздатуу, чөкмөлөрдүн топтолушу жана мурда болгон тектердин өзгөрүшү сыяктуу процесстер аркылуу пайда болот."},{"question":"અમને કહો કે ગુજરાતીઓ વેપારમાં શા માટે પ્રખ્યાત છે?","answer":"ગુજરાતીઓ તેમની ઉદ્યોગસાહસિકતા અને વ્યાપારી કુશળતા માટે પ્રખ્યાત છે, અને વિવિધ વ્યાપારી ક્ષેત્રોમાં તેમની સફળતા ઘણા પરિબળોને આભારી છે. ગુજરાતીઓ બિઝનેસમાં કેમ પ્રખ્યાત છે તેના કેટલાક મુખ્ય કારણો અહીં આપ્યા છે.ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક પરંપરા: ઉદ્યોગસાહસિકતા ગુજરાતી સંસ્કૃતિમાં ઊંડે ઊંડે જડેલી છે. નાનપણથી જ, ઘણા ગુજરાતીઓ પોતાનો વ્યવસાય શરૂ કરવા અને ચલાવવાના ખ્યાલથી પરિચિત છે. આ એક્સપોઝર મજબૂત ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક માનસિકતા અને જોખમો લેવાની તૈયારીને પ્રોત્સાહન આપે છે.સખત મહેનત અને શિસ્તઃ ગુજરાતીઓ તેમની સખત મહેનતની નીતિ અને શ્રેષ્ઠતા માટે પ્રતિબદ્ધતા માટે જાણીતા છે. તેઓ તેમના વ્યવસાયો માટે સમર્પિત છે અને સફળતા હાંસલ કરવા માટે જરૂરી લાંબા કલાકો મૂકવા તૈયાર છે.નેટવર્કિંગ અને કોમ્યુનિટી સપોર્ટ: ગુજરાતીઓમાં સમુદાય પ્રત્યે મજબૂત સમજ છે અને તેઓ નેટવર્કિંગ અને સંબંધો બાંધવામાં પારંગત છે. તેઓ સંસાધનો, માહિતી અને તકોની ઍક્સેસ મેળવવા માટે તેમના સામાજિક નેટવર્કનો લાભ લે છે.અનુકૂલનક્ષમતા અને નવીનતા: ગુજરાતીઓ અનુકૂલનક્ષમ છે અને નવા વિચારો અને તકનીકોને સ્વીકારવા માટે તૈયાર છે. તેઓ પ્રયોગ કરવા અને નવીનતા લાવવાથી ડરતા નથી, જેણે તેમને વિવિધ ઉદ્યોગોમાં વળાંકથી આગળ રહેવાની મંજૂરી આપી છે.નાણાકીય સમજદારી અને જોખમ વ્યવસ્થાપન: ગુજરાતીઓ સામાન્ય રીતે નાણાકીય રીતે સમજદાર હોય છે અને જોખમ વ્યવસ્થાપનની મજબૂત સમજ ધરાવે છે. તેઓ તેમની નાણાકીય બાબતમાં સાવચેત રહે છે અને જાણકાર નિર્ણયો લે છે, જે તેમને બિનજરૂરી જોખમો ટાળવામાં મદદ કરે છે.ગ્લોબલ આઉટલુક અને વર્સેટિલિટી: ગુજરાતીઓ વૈશ્વિક દૃષ્ટિકોણ ધરાવે છે અને વિવિધ સંસ્કૃતિઓ અને બજારોમાં કામ કરવા માટે આરામદાયક છે. તેઓ સર્વતોમુખી છે અને વિવિધ વાતાવરણને અનુરૂપ તેમની વ્યવસાયિક વ્યૂહરચનાઓને અનુકૂલિત કરી શકે છે.કૌટુંબિક મૂલ્યો અને સમર્થન: ગુજરાતીઓ માટે કુટુંબ મહત્વપૂર્ણ છે, અને તેઓ ઘણીવાર પારિવારિક વ્યવસાયોમાં સાથે કામ કરે છે. આ મજબૂત કૌટુંબિક સપોર્ટ સિસ્ટમ સફળતા માટે પાયો પૂરો પાડે છે અને વ્યવસાયોને ખીલવામાં મદદ કરે છે.શિક્ષણ અને કૌશલ્યો પર ભાર: ગુજરાતીઓ શિક્ષણને મહત્ત્વ આપે છે અને તેમના વ્યવસાયિક હિતોને અનુરૂપ કૌશલ્ય પ્રાપ્ત કરવામાં રોકાણ કરે છે. શિક્ષણ અને કૌશલ્ય વિકાસ પરનો આ ભાર તેમની એકંદર વ્યવસાયિક સફળતામાં ફાળો આપે છે.પરોપકારી ભાવના: ગુજરાતીઓ તેમની પરોપકારી ભાવના માટે જાણીતા છે અને તેમના સમુદાયોને પાછા આપવા માટે ઉદાર છે. આ ઉદારતા શૈક્ષણિક સંસ્થાઓ, સામાજિક કારણો અને આપત્તિ રાહત પ્રયત્નોને સમર્થન આપવા સુધી વિસ્તરે છે.સાંસ્કૃતિક પ્રભાવો: ગુજરાતી સંસ્કૃતિ સખત મહેનત, દ્રઢતા અને કોઠાસૂઝ પર ભાર મૂકે છે, જે વ્યવસાયમાં સફળતા માટે તમામ જરૂરી ગુણો છે. આ સાંસ્કૃતિક મૂલ્યો પેઢીઓથી પસાર થતા રહ્યા છે, જે ગુજરાતી ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક માનસિકતાને આકાર આપે છે.વેપાર જગતમાં ગુજરાતીઓનું યોગદાન નોંધપાત્ર છે. તેમની ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક ભાવના, મજબૂત કાર્ય નીતિ અને અનુકૂલનક્ષમતાએ તેમને ભારત અને સમગ્ર વિશ્વમાં વિવિધ ઉદ્યોગોમાં અગ્રણી બનાવ્યા છે. તેમની સફળતા વિશ્વભરના મહત્વાકાંક્ષી સાહસિકો માટે પ્રેરણારૂપ છે."},{"question":"தமிழ் மொழிப்பண்டாரம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"ஒப்பிலாமணிப் புலவர்.ஒப்பிலாமணிப் புலவர் என்னும் புலவர் பாடியனவாக 27 பாடல்கள் புறத்திரட்டு நூலில் உள்ளன. அவற்றில் ஒன்று ஆசிரியப்பா. மற்றொன்று விருத்தம். ஏனையவை வெண்பாக்கள். இப் புலவர் ஊர் ஊராகச் சென்று அவ்வூரில் குடிகொண்டுள்ள இறைவனைப் போற்றிச் சுவை ததும்பும் பாடல்களைப் பாடியுள்ளார். இவரது பாடல்களின் நடை இவரைப் 18 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுப் புலவர் எனக் கொள்ள வைக்கிறது."},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة مدح من بحر الكامل.","answer":"شَعران تَصغر عِندَها الأَمصارُوَبِتُربِها تَتبرك الأَبرارُأَخذَت عَلى الكَرم العُهود بِأَنَّهُمِن دُونِها لا تَحتويهِ دِيارُأَفلا تَكون هِيَ السَماء مَكانَةًوَالقُطب مَركَزَها بِها المُختارُيابن الَّذين ِذا اِستَغَثنا بِاسمهمفي المَحل تَسبق سُؤلَنا الأَمطارُلَكَ مَنصب كُل المَناصب تَرتجىمِنهُ الشَفاعة حَيثُ تَبدو النارُأَنتَ الأَمين عَلى العُلوم وَمِن بِهِيَثق الرَجاءُ وَتَأمن الأَسرارُِن لَم أَزُرك فَِنَّ عُذري وَاضِحٌسَفَري وَغَيث هِباتك المِدرارُ"},{"question":"വാചകം 1: ഡേവിഡ് ഗോഡ്വിൻ ആണ് എമ്മ ടൌൺഷെന് ഡിനെ പ്രതിനിധീകരിക്കുന്നത്. വാക്യം 2: എമ്മ ടൌൺഷെന് ഡിനെ പ്രതിനിധീകരിക്കുന്നത് ഡേവിഡ് ഗോഡ്വിൻ ആണ്. ചോദ്യം: ഒന്നാം വാക്യവും രണ്ടാമത്തെ വാക്യവും ഒരേ അർത്ഥമാണോ പ്രകടിപ്പിക്കുന്നത്? അതെ അല്ലെ?","answer":"അതെ, രണ്ട് വാക്യങ്ങളും ഒരേ കാര്യം അർത്ഥമാക്കുന്നു. "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Phát hiện thi thể người đàn ông bên bờ biển Tỉnh Thủy, Quảng Nam","answer":"Sáng 1/8, thông tin từ UBND xã Tam Thanh (TP Tam Kỳ, tỉnh Quảng Nam) cho hay, lúc 5h30 cùng ngày, người dân đi tập thể dục tại bờ biển Tỉnh Thuỷ (xã Tam Thanh) phát hiện thi thể người đàn ông (trạc 50 tuổi) trôi dạt vào bờ. Người dân sau đó đã báo với chính quyền, nhận tin báo, lực lượng chức năng có mặt tại hiện trường phong toả, điều tra. Người đàn ông mặc quần màu xanh, áo trắng và tóc ngắn. Do trên người nạn nhân không có giấy tờ nên chưa xác định được danh tính. Hiện cơ quan chức năng đang tìm kiếm thân nhân, cùng với đó điều tra, làm rõ vụ việc."},{"question":"Motho yo a thopilego sefoka o bitšwa: Mothopasefoka, ee goba aowa?","answer":"Ee, motho yo a thopilego sefoka o bitšwa mothopasefoka"},{"question":"इन्टरनेटको बारेमा भन्नुहोस्।","answer":"सञ्जाल हो, जसमा निजी, सार्वजनिक, शैक्षिक, व्यापारीक, र स्थानीयदेखि विश्वव्यापी दायराका कम्प्युटरहरू सम्पर्कमा रहन्छन्।"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. සඳ හාදු දිදී වළාකුලට සේද යහනතේනිල් තාරුකා කුමාරියන්ගෙ ප්‍රේම විජිතයේනුඹ තාම නිදිද නුඹ තාම නිදිදකඩුපුල් මල් දේවතාවියේ","answer":"සඳ හාදු දිදී වළාකුලට සේද යහනතේනිල් තාරුකා කුමාරියන්ගෙ ප්‍රේම විජිතයේනුඹ තාම නිදිද නුඹ තාම නිදිදකඩුපුල් මල් දේවතාවියේමල් මාලතී ලතා මඩුල්ල නෙතු පියා හිඳීමුදු මල් ගැබේ යහන් තුරුල්ල භෘංගයන්ට දීකට කොනින්වත් හිනා නොවීම දේවතා නිදීවිල් තලේ රිදී රැල් නැගේවි රංගනේ යෙදීමුදු මන්දහාස දී පිපේවි සොඳුරු කෞමදීමට තනියි මගේ හිත පාළුයි නුඹ තවම නිදීචන්දන ලියනාරච්චිරත්න ශ්‍රී විජේසිංහරෝහණ වීරසිංහ "},{"question":"Apakah kimchi?","answer":"Kimchi adalah makanan tradisional Korea, salah satu jenis sayur masin hasil pemerapan yang dibuat dengan mencuci sayuran yang sudah digaram dan memerap dengan bahan-bahan seperti udang kering, sos ikan, bawang putih, halia dan serbuk cili merah. Kimchi terdiri dari ratusan jenis dengan ciri khas aroma yang keras, tajam, dan menyengat.Sayuran yang biasa digunakan untuk dibuat kimchi adalah sawi putih dan lobak. Pada zaman dulu, kimchi dipanggil sebagai chim-chae (Hangul: 침채; Hanja: 沈菜) yang bermaksud \\"sayuran yang direndam.\\""},{"question":"أعد كتابة التعبير التالي باستخدام تدوين Big O.","answer":"O(n)"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Tafita vao rendrika .................................... \\" ","answer":"\\"  Tafita vao rendrika toy ny boka milomano \\" "},{"question":"வினா ;மின் + அஞ்சல் –  சேர்த்து எழுதுக. அ) மின் அஞ்சல்ஆ) மின்னஞ்சல்இ) மின் அஞ்சல்ஈ) மினஞ்சல்","answer":"விடை : ஆ) மின்னஞ்சல்"},{"question":"මයිකල් ක්ලාක් පළමු පෙළ තරගය ආරම්භ කළේ කවදාද, කාට එරෙහිවද?","answer":"1999 දෙසැම්බරයේ සිඩ්නි ක්‍රිකට් පිටියේදී සංචාරක ඉන්දීය කණ්ඩායමට එරෙහිව"},{"question":"Какое из этих животных является хищником? Выберите один ответ.A) КошкаB) СлонC) КроликD) Жираф","answer":"Правильный ответ: A) Кошка.Кошки - это хищные млекопитающие, они охотятся на мелких животных, такие как мыши и птицы, и имеют анатомические особенности, которые делают их эффективными хищниками, такие как острые когти и острые зубы. В то время как слоны, кролики и жирафы - растительноядные животные, которые питаются растениями и не являются хищниками."},{"question":"ටෙස්ට් තරඟයක පරාජිත කණ්ඩායමක සිට වැඩිම ලකුණු රැස් කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"බ්‍රයන් චාල්ස් ලාරා"},{"question":"नगरपालिका नभएका नेपालका जिल्ला कुन कुन हुन् ?","answer":"मनाङ, मुस्ताङ, रसुवा र हुम्ला नेपालका नगरपालिका नभएका जिल्ला हुन् ।"},{"question":"சிந்து நாகரிகத்தில் உள்ள 'ஆலம்கீர்' நகரம் தற்போது எந்த இந்திய நகரத்தில் உள்ளது?1. மேற்கு உத்தர பிரதேசம் 2. ராஜஸ்தான் 3. கிழக்கு உத்திர பிரதேசம் ","answer":"விடை: 1. மேற்கு உத்தரபிரதேசம். சிந்து சமவெளி நாகரிகத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள முக்கிய நகரங்களில் ஆலம்கீரும் ஒன்றாகும். இது மேற்கு உத்தரபிரதேசத்தில் இருந்தது. இங்கு சிறப்பு வாய்ந்த கண்டுப்பிடிப்புகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டன. ஆலம்கீர்பூர் சிந்து சமவெளி நகரங்களில் ஒன்றாகும்."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕਵਣੁ ਸੁ ਵੇਲਾ ਵਖਤੁ ਕਵਣੁ ਕਵਣ ਥਿਤਿ ਕਵਣੁ ਵਾਰੁ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 4 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਕਿਹੜਾ ਉਹ ਵੇਲਾ ਤੇ ਵਕਤ ਸੀ, ਕਿਹੜੀ ਥਿਤ ਸੀ, ਕਿਹੜਾ ਦਿਨ ਸੀ, \\""},{"question":"Qual foi o primeiro robô a pousar em Marte?","answer":"O primeiro robô a pousar em Marte foi o rover Sojourner da missão Mars Pathfinder. Ele pousou em 04 de Julho de 1997 no vale Ares Vallis da planície Chryse Planitia que fica localizada no quadrângulo Oxia Palus de Marte. O rover ficou operacional por 95 dias e realizou diversos experimentos científicos durante sua estadia no planeta. A última comunicação do Sojourner com a terra foi na madrugada do dia 27 de Setembro de 1997."},{"question":"एक डिग्री देशान्तरको फरकमा कति समयको फरक पर्छ ?","answer":"४ मिनेट"},{"question":"Olupo tilu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo gbọpa aṣẹ","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, Abdulrahman Abdulrasaq, ti gbe ọpa asẹ fun Olupo ti ilu Ajasẹ-Ipo tuntun, Ọba Ismail Yahaya Atọloye Alebiosu, gẹgẹ bii ọba onipo kin-in-ni nipinlẹ Kwara.Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọṣẹ yii, ni Abdulrasaq gbe ọpa asẹ fun Ọba Alebiosu ni ilu Ajasẹ-Ipo, nijọba ibilẹ Irẹpọdun, nipinlẹ Kwara, lẹyin ọjọ kẹta ti wọn buwọ lu iyansipo ori ade ọhun.Gomina waa ki Olupo tuntun ọhun ku oriire,  pẹlu bo ṣe jẹ pe oun ni aayo awọn araalu, ti wọn si fi tayọtayọ gba a gẹgẹ bii ọba wọn.Bakan naa gomina tun gboriyin fawọn ọmọ bibi ilu naa fun bi wọn ṣe gba alaafia laaye lasiko iyansipo ọba tuntun. Ko sai juwọ kare sawọn igbimọ afọbajẹ ilu naa, fun bi wọn ṣe ṣeto iyansipo Ọba Alebiosu ni irọwọrọsẹ.Abdulrasaq waa pe gbogbo awọn ọba alaye nipinlẹ Kwara lati maa da awọn eeyan wọn lẹkọọ, lati jẹ ọmọ orilẹ-ede rere, nipa gbigba alaafia ati iṣọkan laaye nigba gbogbo.Kọmisanna fun ijọba ibilẹ to n ri si ọrọ awọn lọba lọba nipinlẹ Kwara, Aliyu Saifuddeen, parọwa si ọba tuntun ọhun pe ko lo anfaani ipo rẹ lati mu iṣọkan, alaafia ati idagbasoke ba ilu to n jọba le lori, ko ma si ja awọn eeyan rẹ kulẹ.Ọba tuntun yii waa dupẹ lọwọ tolori tẹlẹmu niluu Ajasẹ-Ipo, fun iduroti wọn, paapaa ju lọ gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, fun ifọwọsi yiyan ti wọn yan an sipo, o ṣeleri pe oun yoo mu ayipada rere ba ilu Ajasẹ-Ipo ati gbogbo agbegbe rẹ."},{"question":"घड्याळाचा शोध कधी लागला होता?","answer":"उत्तर: घड्याळाचा शोध हा पीटर हेनलेन यांनी पंधराव्या शतकात लावले होते."},{"question":"અમને રંગપુર (તાલુકો ધંધુકા) વિશે જણાવો.","answer":"રંગપુર ગુજરાત, ભારતના ધંધુકા તાલુકામાં ખંભાતના અખાત અને કચ્છના અખાતની વચ્ચે આવેલું પુરાતત્વીય સ્થળ અને ગામ છે. તે સિંધુ ખીણની સંસ્કૃતિના સમયગાળાનું સ્થળ છે અને લોથલથી ઇશાન દિશામાં આવેલું છે.સ્થાપત્ય અને નગર આયોજન: રંગપુરમાં બાંધકામ, સાધનો અને લાકડાની વસ્તુઓ માટે બાવળનું લાકડું ઉપયોગ કરવામાં આવ્યું હતું. શોધખોળ: કાળા અને લાલ મણકાં ધરાવતી થાળીઓ અને મોટા ગળાની બરણીઓ અહીંથી મળી છે. શંખ કામના પુરાવાઓ અહીંથી મળ્યા છે.ખેતી: રંગપુરમાંથી અનાજનો વિશાળ જથ્થો મળી આવ્યો હતો. બાજરી, ચોખા, બાજરી મળી આવ્યા હતા."},{"question":"Napisz kontynuację tego paragrafu: Kierowca McLarena Mercedes Lewis Hamilton wygrał zawody FIA Formula-1 2007","answer":"Grand Prix Stanów Zjednoczonych w Indianapolis Motor Speedway w Indianapolis, Indiana, USA. Było to jego drugie kolejne zwycięstwo od początku sezonu i w jego karierze kierowcy z siedmioma kolejnymi podium."},{"question":"Lẹyin oṣu meji, wọn da awọn ọmọleewe Kaduna ti wọn ji gbe silẹ","answer":"Aja to re’le ẹkun to bọ, ka ki i ku ewu ni, lẹyin to ku ọjọ mẹrin ki oṣu meji pe tawọn ọmọ naa ti wa lahaamọ awọn janduku agbebọn to ji wọn gbe, wọn ti da awọn ọmọleewe ijọba Federal College of Forestry Mechanisation, to wa lagbegbe Afaka, nipinlẹ Kaduna, silẹ.ALAROYE gbọ pe nnkan bii aago meji ọsan Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee yii, ni wọn yọnda awọn ọmọ naa fawọn ti wọn lọọ gba wọn jade ninu igbo ọdaju ti wọn ha wọn mọ lati ọjọ kọkanla, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii.Mallam Abdullahi Usman, alaga awọn obi awọn ọmọ ileewe naa, lo ṣaaju ikọ ti wọn fa awọn ọmọ naa le lọwọ, lati inu igbo ti wọn ti lọọ gba wọn, wọn si ti ko wọn lọ siluu Kaduna fun itọju loju-ẹsẹ.Wọn lọkunrin naa sọ fawọn oniroyin pe ọpẹlọpẹ gbajugbaja aṣaaju ẹsin Musulumi l’Oke-Ọya nni, Sheik Ahmed Gumi, wọn loun lo ṣeto bawọn ọmọ yii ṣe dẹni ominira.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, mẹtadinlogoji lawọn akẹkọọ kọlẹẹji ọhun tawọn agbebọn ji gbe, ṣugbọn lẹyin ti wọn gba owo irapada ni wọn tu mẹwaa lara wọn silẹ, ti awọn mẹtadinlogbọn ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ dẹni ominira yii fi wa lakata wọn.Pẹlu omije ati ẹdun ọkan lawọn obi awọn akẹkọọ yii fi lọọ ṣe iwọde nileegbimọ aṣofin apapọ ilẹ wa l’Abuja lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lati fi ibanujẹ wọn han, ti wọn si bẹ awọn aṣofin naa lati ma ṣe wo awọn niran lori ọrọ yii.A o ti i le sọ boya awọn agbebọn yii gba owo, ati iye owo ti wọn gba, ki wọn too tu wọn silẹ."},{"question":"ఉస్మాన్ అలీ-ఖాన్ విజయాలు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"నిజాం ప్రభువులలో ఆఖరివాడు ఉస్మాన్ అలీఖాన్. ఇతని పాలనాకాలంలో రెండు ప్రపంచ యుద్ధములు, భారత స్వాతంత్ర్యము, హైద్రాబాద్ పై పోలీసు చర్య, సంస్థానం ఇండియన్ యూనియన్ లో విలీనం వంటి అనేక సంఘటనలు జరిగెను. ఇతని కాలమున నిజాం రాజ్యము సర్వతోముఖాభివృద్ధి చెందెను. ఇతడు అనేక పరిపాలన చర్యలు తీసుకొనెను.ప్రభుత్వ కార్యాలయములలో అనేకమంది సిబ్బందిని నియమించి ప్రభుత్వ కార్యక్రమములు త్వరితగతిన జరుగునట్లు చేసెను.రాష్ట్రాదాయము క్రమబద్దము చేసి అనేక ప్రణాళికలను తయారుచేసెను. ఉస్మాన్సాగర్ నిర్మాణం జరిపినది ఇతడే.వ్యవసాయాభివృద్ధికి హిమాయత్ సాగర్, నిజాంసాగర్లను నిర్మించెను.అనేక దేశీయ పరిశ్రమలు స్థాపించబడెను. వాటిలో అజాంజాహి మిక్స్, చార్మినార్ సిగరెట్ ఫ్యాక్టరీ మొదలగునవి.ఇతడు అనేక ప్రజాసంబంధ నిర్మాణములు, విద్యాలయములు, వైద్యాలయములు నెలకొల్పెను.సాలార్జంగ్ ప్రారంభించిన పారిశ్రామిక వస్తు ప్రదర్శన క్రమబద్ధంచేసి కొనసాగించెను.స్థానిక కేంద్రాలలో అనేక కార్యాలయములు నిర్మాణం జరిపెను.పురాతత్వ శాఖను రూపొందించెను.నిజాం స్టేట్ రైల్వేను స్థాపించెను.మొదటి ప్రపంచ కాలమందు బ్రిటిష్ వారికి అన్నిరకాల సహకారమందించి “మహాఘనత వహించిన” అను బిరుదు ధరించెను.అస్తమయం: 1948 సెప్టెంబర్ రజాకార్ల అలజడులు నైజాం ప్రాంతంలో ఎక్కువైనాయి. ఫలితంగా భారత ప్రభుత్వం పోలీసు చర్య కలిపి సంస్థానమును ఆక్రమించెను. చివరకు 1950 జనవరి 26న హైదరాబాదు సంస్థానము ఇండియన్ యూనియన్లో కలిసిపోయెను."},{"question":"ඔබ මිදි ගැන සැලකිලිමත් විය යුත්තේ කෙසේද?","answer":"මිදි ඉතා තෙත් නොවන වැලි පස් වැනි, එම නිසා ජලය දැමීම අතර බිම වියළීමට වග බලා ගන්න. මිදි බොහෝ විට තිරසාරව නිපදවිය හැකි ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා බොහෝ පලතුරු වර්ධනය කරයි. එය තවමත් සීතල වන විට යුෂ ගලා යාමට පෙර මුල් වසන්තයේ දී ඔවුන් ආක්රමණශීලී ලෙස කප්පාදු කරන්න. කප්පාදු කිරීමේ එක් ක්‍රමයක් නම්, පසුගිය වසරේ වර්ධනයෙන් අංකුර 10-15 බැගින් වූ වැල් දිග දෙකේ සිට හතර දක්වා ඉතිරි කර මෙම වසරේ වර්ධනය සඳහා සන්ධියක් තැබීමයි. මෙම වැල් දිග ඔබේ පන්දලම් දක්වා වයර් කර, වැටීම තුළ මිදි භුක්ති විඳින්න!"},{"question":"অন্তু ক্যানবেরায় পড়াশোনা শেষে বসবাস (৩৫° দক্ষিণ অক্ষরেখা ও ১৫০° পূর্ব দ্রাঘিমারেখা) শুরু করেছে। তার পিতা ফজলুল হক ২২ অক্টোবর তারিখে ঢাকা থেকে (২৩.৫° উত্তর অক্ষরেখা ও ৯০° পূর্ব দ্রাঘিমারেখা) স্থানীয় সময় সকাল ৬টায় তাকে জন্মদিনের শুভেচ্ছা জানান। অন্তু তার বাবাকে আগামী ২৫শে ডিসেম্বর ক্যানবেরা বেড়াতে যাওয়ার আমন্ত্রণ জানায়। জনাব ফজলুল হক ক্যানবেরা বেড়াতে যাওয়ার সময় কি সঙ্গে গরম পোশাক নিয়ে যাবেন? তোমার উত্তরের সপক্ষে যুক্তি দাও।","answer":"না, জনাব ফজলুল হকের অস্ট্রেলিয়ার ক্যানবেরা বেড়াতে যাওয়ার সময় গরম পোশাক নিয়ে যাওয়ার প্রয়োজন নেই।পৃথিবীর কেন্দ্র দিয়ে উত্তর-দক্ষিণে কল্পিত রেখাকে অক্ষ বা মেরু রেখা বলে। এক্ষেত্রে দুই মেরু থেকে সমান দূরত্বে পৃথিবীকে পূর্ব-পশ্চিমে বেষ্টন করে যে রেখা কল্পনা করা হয় তাকে বলা হয় নিরক্ষরেখা বা বিষুবরেখা। নিরক্ষরেখা পৃথিবীকে উত্তর ও দক্ষিণ গোলার্ধে বিভক্ত করেছে। উদ্দীপকে উল্লিখিত শহর ক্যানবেরা দক্ষিণ গোলার্ধে এবং ঢাকা উত্তর গোলার্ধে অবস্থিত।পৃথিবী নিজ অক্ষে অবিরাম ঘুরতে ঘুরতে নির্দিষ্ট উপবৃত্তকার কক্ষপথে প্রতি সেকেন্ডে ৩০ কিলোমিটার বেগে সূর্যকে পরিক্রমণ করে। পশ্চিম থেকে পূর্ব দিকে সূর্যের এই পরিক্রমণকে বার্ষিক গতি বলে। বার্ষিক গতির জন্য সূর্যরশ্মি পৃথিবীর কোথাও লম্বভাবে আবার কোথাও তীর্যকভাবে পড়ে। এর ফলে দিন-রাত্রির হ্রাস-বৃদ্ধি ঘটে এবং ঋতুর পরিবর্তন হয়। এই পরিবর্তন প্রক্রিয়ায় ২২শে ডিসেম্বর সূর্য মকরক্রান্তির (২৩.৫° দক্ষিণ অক্ষরেখা) রেখার উপর লম্বভাবে কিরণ দেয়। ফলে সেখানে দিন বড় ও রাত ছোট হয়। দক্ষিণ গোলার্ধে এ তারিখের দেড় মাস আগে শুরু হয়ে দেড় মাস পরে পর্যন্ত গ্রীষ্মকাল এবং একইসময়ে উত্তর গোলার্ধে শীতকাল থাকে।উপরের আলোচনার পরিপ্রেক্ষিতে বলা যায়, ক্যানবেরা দক্ষিণ গোলার্ধে অবস্থিত বলে সেখানে ২২শে ডিসেম্বরের দেড় মাস আগে গ্রীষ্মকাল শুরু হয়েছে এবং তা ঐ তারিখ থেকে আরও দেড় মাস স্থায়ী থাকবে। উদ্দীপকের জনাব ফজলুল হক ২৫শে ডিসেম্বর সেখানে যাবেন। তাই তার গরম কাপড় নিয়ে যাওয়ার প্রয়োজন নেই।"},{"question":"Wọn yinbọn pa eeyan mẹta, awọn mi-in tun fara gbọta lasiko atundi ibo ile-igbimọ aṣofin Ekiti","answer":"Wahala nla ni atundi ibo to waye ni ẹkun idibo Ila-Oorun Ekiti kin-in-ni lati yan ẹlomi-in sipo aṣofin to ku da silẹ lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide to kọja, pẹlu bi wọn ṣe yinbọn pa eeyan mẹta, ti ọpọlọpọ si fara gbọta.Ibo naa ni wọn di lẹyin ti aṣofin to n ṣoju ẹkun naa tẹlẹ, Ọnarebu Juwa Adegbuyi, dagbere faye lọsẹ diẹ sẹyin.ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn mẹta ni wọn yinbọn pa nigba tawọn tọọgi ya bo Ibudo ibo keje, Wọọdu keje, niluu Omuo-Ekiti, bẹẹ ni ọlọpaa meji, oṣiṣẹ ajọ oju popo kan, agunbanirọ kan atawọn mi-in ti wọn fara pa balẹ sileewosan.Mẹji ninu awọn to padanu ẹmi wọn ni Bọla Adebisi, ẹni aadọta ọdun, ati Tunde Ogunlẹyẹ toun jẹ ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji.Bakan naa la gbọ pe wọn tun gbe apoti ibo ni Wọọdu kẹsan-an, ibudo idibo kẹjọ, niluu ọhun.Nigba to n ṣalaye bi iṣẹlẹ naa ṣe waye, Sẹnetọ Biọdun Olujimi to n ṣoju awọn eeyan Guusu Ekiti nile igbimọ aṣofin agba sọ pe diẹ lo ku ki wọn yinbọn pa oun lasiko rogbodiyan ọhun, awọn alatilẹyin ẹgbẹ People’s Democratic Party (PDP) lo si gbe oun sa kuro nibẹ.Olujimi ni, ‘‘Pẹlu alaafia ni ibo yẹn bẹrẹ. Awọn adari APC (All Progressives Congress) gan-an wa si ibudo idibo yẹn, a dẹ ki ara wa. Nigba ti wọn lọ tan ni awọn tọọgi to duro lẹyin gbe ibọn jade, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i yin in. Igba akọkọ ta a maa ri iru ẹ niyi. Wọn tiẹ tun gbe apoti ibo sa lọ.‘’‘Ọkunrin kan ku nigba to fẹẹ gbiyanju lati sa lọ, bẹẹ ni wọn yinbọn lu ọlọpaa obinrin to duro ti apoti yẹn lori. Agunbanirọ kan ati alakooso ibo naa fara gbọta. Eeyan mẹjọ nibọn ba, awọn kan ti ku, awọn to ku wa lẹsẹ kan aye ẹsẹ kan ọrun nileewosan.Olujimi waa fẹsun kan APC pe awọn gan-an ni wọn da rogbodiyan ọhun silẹ, ati pe wọn ko awọn tọọgi wọ ilu naa nitori ibo to waye ni wọọdu marun-un pere.Ninu ọrọ tiẹ, Ọnarebu Fẹmi Bamiṣilẹ to jẹ ọmọ ilu naa, to si wa nile-igbimọ aṣoju-ṣofin lọwọlọwọ sọ pe iṣẹlẹ iyanu gbaa lọrọ ọhun, nitori ko si nnkan to yẹ ko fa itajẹsilẹ ninu idibo nilẹ yii.Bamiṣilẹ, ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC, ni, ‘‘Ninu ibo ti ẹmi awọn eeyan ba ti bọ, iyẹn ki i ṣe dẹmokiresi mọ. APC gbaradi fun ibo yii ni gbogbo ọna, a dẹ beere fun atilẹyin awọn oludibo, bẹẹ ni a ko gbero lati pa ẹnikẹni. Mi o mọ bi iṣẹlẹ yii ṣe ṣẹlẹ, mi o si ro pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa lo ṣe e. Pẹlu alaafia ni ibo yẹn bẹrẹ, ki lo waa ṣẹlẹ to fi di pe wọn n yinbọn ti wọn tun paayan?’’Bakan naa ni Ọgbẹni Akinrinade Adeniran, oludije PDP ninu ibo ọhun, sọ pe ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee to kọja, tawọn kan ti fi ọta ibọn da batani si mọto oun, ti wọn si tun yinbọn si orule ile oun loun ti mọ pe wahala n bọ.Ṣugbọn ninu alaye tiẹ, Alukoro ọlọpaa l’Ekiti, ASP Sunday Abutu, sọ pe eeyan mẹfa nibọn ba, ọlọpaa meji ati agunbanirọ kan si wa ninu wọn, bẹẹ ni wọn n gba itọju lọwọ ni General Hosipital to wa niluu Ikọle-Ekiti.O waa ni Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi ti kede pe gbogbo awọn to ba lọwọ ninu rogbodiyan naa lọwọ gbọdọ tẹ ki wọn le foju wina ofin."},{"question":"‘బడికి వెళ్ళు’ – ఇది ఏ రకమైన వాక్యం?A) విధ్యర్థక వాక్యంB) నిషేధార్ధక వాక్యంC) అనుమత్యర్థక వాక్యంD) ప్రశార్థక వాక్యం","answer":"A) విధ్యర్థక వాక్యం"},{"question":"How does the Attention Mechanism work in a Transformer model?","answer":"The Attention Mechanism in a Transformer allows the model to focus on different parts of the input sequence when making predictions. It assigns weights to input elements, emphasizing more relevant parts and downplaying less relevant ones."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਜਿਹ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਆਭੂਖਨ ਪਹਿਰੀਜੈ ॥ਮਨ ਤਿਸੁ ਸਿਮਰਤ ਕਿਉ ਆਲਸੁ ਕੀਜੈ ॥ਜਿਹ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਅਸ੍ਵ ਹਸਤਿ ਅਸਵਾਰੀ ॥ਮਨ ਤਿਸੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕਉ ਕਬਹੂ ਨ ਬਿਸਾਰੀ ॥ਜਿਹ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਬਾਗ ਮਿਲਖ ਧਨਾ ॥ਰਾਖੁ ਪਰੋਇ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਅਪੁਨੇ ਮਨਾ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਤੇਰੀ ਮਨ ਬਨਤ ਬਨਾਈ ॥ਊਠਤ ਬੈਠਤ ਸਦ ਤਿਸਹਿ ਧਿਆਈ ॥ਤਿਸਹਿ ਧਿਆਇ ਜੋ ਏਕ ਅਲਖੈ ॥ਈਹਾ ਊਹਾ ਨਾਨਕ ਤੇਰੀ ਰਖੈ ॥੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 270 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਸ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਗਹਣੇ ਪਹਿਨੀਦੇ ਹਨ, ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਉਂ ਆਲਸ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਏ?ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਘੋੜੇ ਤੇ ਹਾਥੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸਵਾਰੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਨਾਹ ਵਿਸਾਰੀਂ ।ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਦਇਆ ਨਾਲ ਬਾਗ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਤੇ ਧਨ (ਤੈਨੂੰ ਨਸੀਬ ਹਨ) ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪੋ੍ਰ ਰੱਖ ।ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਜਿਸ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਨੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਾਜਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਠਦੇ ਬੈਠਦੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ) ਉਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰ ।ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ, ਜੋ ਇੱਕ ਹੈ, ਤੇ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਲੋਕ ਤੇ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ (ਉਹੀ) ਤੇਰੀ ਲਾਜ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੪।\\""},{"question":"සූර්යයා වටා ගමන් කරන ග්‍රහලෝක කීයක් ද?","answer":"වසර ගණනාවක් තාරකා විද්‍යාඥයන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සූර්යයා වටා ගමන් කරන ග්‍රහලෝක 9ක් ඇති බවයි. 2006 දී 9 වැනි ග්‍රහලෝකය වන අතර සූර්යයාගේ සිට දුරින් පිහිටි ප්ලූටෝ ග්‍රහලෝකයේ සිට වාමන ග්‍රහලෝකයකට පහත හෙළන ලදී. තාක්ෂණික වශයෙන් දැන් සූර්යයා වටා පරිභ්‍රමණය වන ග්‍රහලෝක 8 ක් සහ වාමන ග්‍රහලෝක 1 ක් ඇත."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaan Saxabigii jaliilka ahaa oo abuu Bakar iyo Nabiga (scw) ku yiraahdeen Caano inoo lis? kadibna Saxaabigaas wuxuu weeydiista in uu baro waxa ay kusameeyeen Ceesaatu?","answer":" Saxaabigaa wuxuu ahaa Cabdulaahi Binu Mascuud."}]`),C={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:T},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:M,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},I={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],P={key:0},D={key:1};function K(e,a,s,m,t,u){const k=y("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",I,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),b(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,d)=>(i(),j(k,{key:d,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",D,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",P,"See more"))],8,O)):f("",!0)])}const H=g(C,[["render",K],["__scopeId","data-v-d4a92530"]]),G=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"guide/10.md","filePath":"guide/10.md"}'),L={name:"guide/10.md"},R=Object.assign(L,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(H)]))}});export{G as __pageData,R as default};
